import{_ as g,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as l,t as h,C as b,M as w,U as y,F as c,p,e as j,f as v,q as f}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},z={class:"poem-container"},A={class:"review"},T={class:"review-title"},N={class:"review-content"};function S(e,a,s,k,t,u){return i(),o("div",z,[n("div",A,[n("div",T,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",N,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const M=g(q,[["render",S],["__scopeId","data-v-61b53ebf"]]),C=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"சதாவதானம் குறிப்பு வரைக.","answer":"‘சதம்’ என்றால் நூறு என்று பொருள். ஒருவரது புலமையையும் நினைவாற்றலையும் நுண்ணறிவையும் சோதிப்பதற்காக ஒரே நேரத்தில் நிகழ்த்தப்படும் நூறு செயல்களையும் நினைவில் கொண்டு விடையளித்தலே சதாவதானம் ஆகும்."},{"question":"Halk Eğitim Genel Muhasebe Kursu kaç saat?","answer":"Bu branşın eğitim süresi 72 saattir. Finansal yatırım kurs programını tamamlayan bireyin, finansal yatırım araçlarını kullanarak yatırım işlemlerini yapması, mevzuata uygun hisse senedi ve tahvil işlemlerini yapması amaçlanmaktadır."},{"question":"Siapakah ahli ubat?","answer":"Pakar dalam bidang ubat-ubatan"},{"question":"Wọn ti mu ọlọpaa to gbowo lọwọ awakọ to rufin oju popo l’Ekoo","answer":"Ọlọpaa kan ti wọ wahala bayii lori bo ṣe gba owo lọwọ obinrin kan nitori tiyẹn gba ojuna ti ko yẹ l’Ekoo, bẹẹ ni ẹṣọ to n mojuto irinna, iyẹn LASTMA, ti da owo ti ọlọpaa yii gba pada fẹni to ni in.Laipẹ yii ni Ọga agba fun ajọ LASTMA,  Ọgbẹni Ọlajide Oduyọye, kede iṣẹlẹ yii lori ikanni abẹyẹfo ẹ pe wọn fọrọ kan to oun leti pe ọlọpaa kan to n ṣiṣẹ pẹlu LASTMA gba owo rẹpẹtẹ lọwọ awakọ kan lori ẹsun pe ọ gba ọna ti ko yẹ.Ẹgbẹrun mejilelaaadọta (N52,000) naira ni wọn sọ pe ọlọpaa yii gba lọwọ obinrin to n wa mọtọ yii, ati pe ẹrọ apọwo (POS), lo fi gba a lọwọ ẹ.Oduyọye sọ pe ọwọ ti tẹ ọkunrin ọlọpaa naa, ati pe LASTMA ti pe obinrin ti wọn fipa gba owo lọwọ ẹ, awọn si ti da owo ẹ pada fun un.O ni, “Ẹsun to fi kan obinrin to gbowo lọwọ ẹ yii ni pe o wa mọto lojuna ti ko yẹ ko gba, loju ẹsẹ naa ni wọn ti wa ọkọ ẹ wa si olu ileeṣẹ wa. Nibẹ naa ni wọn ti bẹrẹ idunaa-dura, ẹgbẹrun lọna aadọjọ naira (N150,000) gan-an lo ni ko lọọ mu wa, nigba ti wọn si jọ dunnaa-dura daadaa ni iyẹn gba lati fun un ni ẹgbẹrun mejilelaaadọta naira (N52,000). Maṣinni apọwo, iyẹn POS, lo fi gba owo ọhun sapo ara ẹ. Bi ọlọpaa yii ṣe gba owo ọhun tan ni obinrin ti wọn gbowo lọwọ ẹ yii ti pe nọmba ifisun LASTMA.“Nibẹ naa lo ti ṣalaye pe ọlọpaa kan to n ṣiṣẹ pẹlu LASTMA yan oun jẹ, o gba owo lọwọ oun.”Oduyọye sọ pe nibi ti oun ti tara bọ ọrọ ọhun niyẹn o, ti ọwọ si pada tẹ ọlọpaa to huwa idọti ọhun, ti ajọ LASTMA paapaa si ti da owo obinrin naa pada fun un lọjọ ti oun ati iya ẹ waa ba awọn lọfiisi awọn.Oduyọye ti sọ pe LASTMA ko ni i gba irufẹ iwa bẹẹ laaye, ati pe ohun to jẹ ajọ naa logun ni bi eto irinna ọkọ l’Ekoo yoo ṣe maa lọ geere, ti awọn awakọ paapaa yoo maa tẹle ofin irinna lai si wahala kankan.Bakan naa lo sọ pe  LASTMA yoo fa ọkunrin agbofinro to huwa ọdaran yii le awọn alaṣẹ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa lọwọ ki wọn le fi jofin gẹgẹ bo ti yẹ."},{"question":"கடிகை என்பது எந்த கால கல்வி நிறுவனங்கள்?","answer":"காஞ்சிக் கடிகை காஞ்சிபுரத்தின் மேம்பட்ட வேதக் கல்வி மையம் என்று பரவலாக மதிக்கப்பட்டது. இஃது இந்தியாவின் பல பகுதிகளிலிருந்தும் அறிஞர்களைத் தன்பால் ஈர்த்தது. நாளந்தாவில் இருந்த புத்தமத அறிஞரும் துறவியுமானர் தர்மபால காஞ்சியில் இருந்து வந்தவர் ஆவார்."},{"question":"Por quanto tempo esteve Macau sob influência portuguesa?","answer":"Macau foi ocupada, colonizada e administrada por Portugal durante mais de 400 anos (1557 - 1999) e é considerada o primeiro entreposto, bem como a última colónia europeia, na Ásia."},{"question":"Awọn oṣiṣẹ UNIOSUN gba kootu lọ, wọn ni afi ki EFCC yẹ iṣẹ ọga-agba ibẹ wo","answer":"Awọn oṣiṣẹ Osun State University ti lọ si ile-ẹjọ giga ijọba apapọ to wa niluu Oṣogbo, lati gba aṣẹ ti yoo pọn ọn ni dandan fun ajọ to n gbogun ti iwa jẹgudujẹra lorileede yii, EFCC, lati ṣewadii awọn iwa aṣemaṣe ti ọga agba ileewe naa, Ọjọgbọn Labọ Popoọla n hu.Awọn oṣiṣẹ ọhun, labẹ Non-Academic Staff Union of Educational and Associated Institution (NASU), sọ pe owo to to miliọnu lọna ọgọrun-un naira, eleyii to jẹ ti ileewe naa, ni Popoola ti ṣe baṣubaṣu.Nigba ti igbẹjọ naa, eleyii to ni nọmba FHC/OS/CS/44/2020 waye ni kootu ọhun lọjọ Isẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii, agbẹjọro fun awọn olupẹjọ, Kanmi Ajibọla, sọ pe ibeere awọn olupẹjọ wa nibamu pẹlu alakalẹ ofin orileede wa.Ajibọla ṣalaye pe olujẹjọ ti mọ nipa igbẹjọ naa, o si rọ ile-ẹjọ lati gbọ ẹjọ ọhun kiakia, ki wọn si paṣẹ fun EFCC lati bẹrẹ iwadii lori owo ileewe naa ti wọn fẹsun kan Popoọla pe o na ninakunaa.Awọn oṣiṣẹ naa sọ nile-ẹkọ pe lati ọdun 2018 ni awọn ti kọ oniruuru iwe ẹsun to lagbara si EFCC nipa Ọjọgbọn Popoọla, ṣugbọn ti wọn ko gbe igbesẹ kankan.Ṣugbọn ninu ọrọ agbẹjọro fun EFCC, M. S. Usman ati agbẹjọro fun ọga-agba nileewe naa, S. B. Ayẹni rọ kootu lati fun wọn lanfaani diẹ, ki wọn le raaye ṣagbeyẹwo iwe ipẹjọ ti awọn ṣẹṣẹ gba laipẹ yii.Agbẹjọro Kanmi Ajibọla sọ ni tiẹ pe ṣe lawọn agbẹjọro EFCC ati ti Popoọla mọ-ọn-mọ fẹẹ di igbẹjọ lọwọ tori wọn ti ri iwe ipejọ naa lasiko ti wọn ni lati fesi le e lori.O fi kun un pe ti ile-ẹjọ ba ti le gba lati fun wọn lasiko diẹ, wọn gbọdọ san faini ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọrun-un (#100,000) gẹgẹ bii owo gba-ma-binu fun awọn olupẹjọ.Nigba to n gbe idajọ rẹ kalẹ, Onidaajọ Peter Lifu ṣalaye pe ki olujẹjọ kọọkan san ẹgbẹrun lọna ogun naira fun olupẹjọ latari asiko wọn ti wọn fi ṣofo.Lẹyin eyi lo sun igbẹjọ siwaju di ọjọ kẹẹdọgbọn oṣu kọkanla ọdun yii."},{"question":"Woher kommt AC/DC?","answer":"Die Band AC/DC wurde 1973 in Sydney, Australien gegründet."},{"question":"Senegaal ci baan wàllu Afrique la nekk","answer":"Senegaal mu ngui nek fi ñuy wakh Afrique sowu jant"},{"question":"Raha jerena ny fanambarana manaraka: \\"Noraisiny ny elony rehefa nanomboka _____ ny orana.\\" Vinavinao ny teny tokony mipetraka eo amin'ny banga.","answer":"Ny teny tokony ho hita eo amin'ny banga dia nilatsaka."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada bernasi di balik kerak\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud masih ada sesuatu yang belum selesai."},{"question":"Viết bài báo có tiêu đề sau: Ông Kim Jong-un nhận được gì từ 6 ngày thăm Nga","answer":"Ông Kim Jong-un không chỉ nhận được nhiều món quà quý từ chuyến thăm 6 ngày tới Nga, mà còn mở ra tương lai hợp tác quốc phòng, vũ trụ mà Triều Tiên mong muốn.Ông Kim Jong-un ngày 17/9 lên chuyến tàu bọc thép từ vùng Primorye ở vùng Viễn Đông, kết thúc chuyến thăm \\"chính thức và hữu nghị\\" tới Nga từ ngày 12/9. Trong chuyến công du đầu tiên kể từ năm 2019, lãnh đạo Triều Tiên đã gặp Tổng thống Vladimir Putin và các quan chức cấp cao Nga, cũng như thăm loạt địa điểm quân sự, công nghệ quan trọng của nước này.Trước khi rời Nga, Thống đốc vùng Primorye đã tặng lãnh đạo Triều Tiên một chiếc áo chống đạn \\"nhẹ hơn nhiều so với phiên bản trước đây\\", cũng như 5 máy bay không người lái (UAV) tự sát và một UAV trinh sát Geranium-25, cùng một bộ đồ có khả năng tàng hình trước thiết bị ảnh nhiệt, theo TASS.Ông Kim cũng được Tổng thống Putin tặng một khẩu súng trường do Nga sản xuất cùng một chiếc găng tay từ bộ đồ phi hành gia. Bộ trưởng Quốc phòng Nga Sergei Shoigu còn tặng lãnh đạo Triều Tiên một chiếc mũ lông.Nhưng đó không phải là toàn bộ những gì ông Kim nhận được từ chuyến thăm. Ngoài cuộc hội đàm với Tổng thống Putin, lãnh đạo Triều Tiên đã dành phần lớn thời gian để tham quan các cơ sở công nghiệp quốc phòng của Nga.Một ngày sau khi đến nhà máy sản xuất máy bay ở Komsomolsk-on-Amur, nơi chế tạo những chiến đấu cơ hiện đại nhất của Nga, ông Kim tới sân bay gần Vladivostok hôm 16/9. Tại đây, Bộ trưởng Quốc phòng Shoigu và các quan chức quân sự cấp cao đã giới thiệu cho ông về các mẫu oanh tạc cơ chiến lược có thể mang vũ khí hạt nhân."},{"question":"Complete o último tipo de produto desta lista de produtos e tipo de produto que eles são:Produto: Arroz Tipo: AlimentoProduct: Feijão Tipo: AlimentoProduct: Boneca Tipo: BrinquedoProduto: Lego Tipo:","answer":"Brinquedo"},{"question":" Sheeg waa maxay Sheyga Kaliya ee uu Arko Indhoolaha?","answer":"Sheyga Kaliya Ee Uu Indhoolaha Arka Waa Riyada."},{"question":"Apakah soalan untuk ayat berikut tentang topik Baklaka: \\"Baklava (atau Baklawa) ialah pastri yang kaya dan manis dibuat daripada lapisan pastri phyllo yang diisi dengan kacang cincang dan dimaniskan dengan sirap dan madu.\\"?","answer":"\\"Apakah baklava?\\""},{"question":"الجملة 1: العمدة هو ريتشارد كلارك ونائب العمدة هو بروس ستيبينز. الجملة 2: العمدة بروس ستيبينز ونائب العمدة ريتشارد كلارك. سؤال: الجملة 1 والجملة 2 بيعبروا عن نفس المعنى؟ أيوة ولا لأ؟","answer":"لأ، الجملة 1 و الجملة 2 مش بيعبروا عن نفس المعنى."},{"question":"කිතුනු තර්කවේදය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ඉංග්‍රීසි බසින් “Apology” යන වචනය ග්‍රීක වචනයකින් අර්ථ ගැන්වී ඇති අතර එහි තේරුම “ආරක්ෂාව දීම” යන්නයි. එදා කිතුනු තර්කදය කිතුනු විශ්වාසය ආරක්ෂා කිරීමෙහිලා උපයෝගි විය. දෙවියන් වහන්සේගේ ජීවමාන භාවය මෙන්ම බයිබලය තුල දෙවියන් වහන්සේ ක්‍රියා කිරීම හැසිරීම පිළිබඳව සැකසහිතවූ දෘෂ්ඨීන් ඇති අය බොහෝසේ ප්‍රශ්න කරනු ලබයි. ඒ අතරම බයිබලයේ සත්‍යතාවය හා අන්තර්ගතය පිළිබඳව බොහෝ අය විවේචනයට ලක් කරයි. වැරදි ඉගැන්වීම් මගින් බයිබලයේ අන්තර්ගතය විකෘති කර ඉදිරිපත් කරන අතරම කිතුනු විශ්වාසයන්ද වචනයට ලක් කරයි. මෙවැනිවූ කාර්යයන් සඳහා විරුද්ධ වෙමින් ඊට ප්‍රති උත්තර දීමක් ලෙසට කිතුනු තර්කවේදය හඳුන්වාදීමට පුළුවන. කිතුනු තර්කවේදය කිතුනු විශ්වාසය ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට වඩාත් ඉවහල් වන අතර මෙය කිතුනු ජීවිතයට වඩාත් වැදගත් අංශයකි."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Ngày 8 tháng 4 năm 2017, The Shadow Brokers công bố thêm nhiều công cụ hacking cho là của NSA và cả mật khẩu để mở. Bài đăng nói rõ công bố này một phần là để trả lời lệnh","answer":"tấn công tên lửa vào sân bay Shayrat, nơi cũng được lực lượng không quân Nga sử dụng."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Sơn La dự kiến xây nghĩa trang thành phố tại xã Chiềng Ngần","answer":"Cụ thể, theo đồ án quy hoạch chung xây dựng thành phố Sơn La, tỉnh Sơn La đến năm 2045 đã được UBND tỉnh Sơn La phê duyệt tại Quyết định số 915/QĐ-UBND ngày 24/5/2022, Nghĩa trang nhân dân thành phố Sơn La được quy hoạch xây dựng tại khu vực xã Chiềng Ngần, thành phố Sơn La, với quy mô khoảng 164,5ha. Vị trí khu đất này nằm ở khu vực nông thôn, không thuộc khu vực nội thành TP Sơn La. Do quy mô diện tích nghĩa trang mới này tương đối lớn; nhu cầu sử dụng đất nghĩa trang của thành phố trong giai đoạn hiện nay không nhiều, chỉ khoảng 15ha-20ha, nếu lập quy hoạch chi tiết toàn bộ 164,5ha vào thời điểm này sẽ lãng phí chi phí lập quy hoạch và hạn chế quyền sử dụng đất của người dân. Mặt khác, nếu đưa quy hoạch nghĩa trang vào quy hoạch phân khu thì sẽ làm chậm tiến độ triển khai dự án. Vì vậy, UBND TP Sơn La đề xuất với tỉnh không lập quy hoạch phân khu nghĩa trang, mà lập quy hoạch chi tiết luôn. Việc lập quy hoạch chi tiết tỷ lệ 1/500 trước mắt cũng được đề xuất thực hiện trong phạm vi đất của Công ty Hợp Lực, quy mô khoảng 9,81ha. Trong diện tích này có bố trí đầy đủ các hạng mục như: Công trình Nhà hỏa táng (02 lò/dự kiến 06 lò); 01 nhà quản trang; 01 nhà dịch vụ; 01 nhà lưu tro; 01 điện thờ trung tâm; 01 nhà bảo vệ; 5 chòi nghỉ, cùng đất bố trí cho các loại hình táng như: cát táng, hỏa táng, hung táng và chôn một lần; đất hạ tầng, cây xanh, cảnh quan môi trường... Theo Lãnh đạo UBND TP Sơn La, việc lập hồ sơ Đề xuất dự án đầu tư quy mô dự án khoảng 9,81ha sẽ được triển khai cùng với quy hoạch chi tiết; trong quá trình xin ý kiến các sở ban ngành về quy hoạch, sẽ xin ý kiến đồng thời cả hồ sơ đề xuất chủ trương đầu tư. Dự kiến, dự án sẽ được khởi công vào quý II năm 2023. Phát biểu tại cuộc họp về phương án và kế hoạch triển khai dự án Nghĩa trang nhân dân thành phố Sơn La với đại diện lãnh đạo một số sở, ngành và UBND TP Sơn La mới đây, Chủ tịch UBND tỉnh Sơn La Hoàng Quốc Khánh đề nghị các sở, ngành của tỉnh, UBND thành phố tập trung nghiên cứu phương án và kế hoạch để triển khai các bước đảm bảo quy hoạch, đáp ứng yêu cầu và đúng quy định của pháp luật. Sớm tham mưu phương án thu hồi đất, giải phòng mặt bằng trong khu vực được quy hoạch. Đồng thời, tiến hành khảo sát sơ bộ hệ thống các công trình hạ tầng kỹ thuật; tuyên truyền vận động nhân dân tự nguyện hiến đất làm đường giao thông. UBND thành phố chủ động xây dựng kế hoạch cụ thể trong phối hợp triển khai thực hiện, nâng cao trách nhiệm của người đứng đầu và các cơ quan, đơn vị liên quan để triển khai thực hiện dự án đảm bảo kế hoạch. Trước đó, như VOV đã phản ánh, từ nhu cầu thực tế của địa phương (nghĩa trang nhân dân TP. Sơn La ở Bó Ẩn sắp không còn khả năng khai thác); trên cơ sở tham mưu, đề xuất của ngành chức năng, UBND tỉnh Sơn La đã phê duyệt quy hoạch Nghĩa trang nhân dân TP. Sơn La tại khu vực Phiêng Khá, bản Buổn, phường Chiềng Cơi, TP. Sơn La theo mô hình công viên nghĩa trang văn minh, hiện đại, thân thiện với môi trường, phù hợp với văn hóa tín ngưỡng của người Việt. Nghĩa trang này được quy hoạch trên diện tích 40 ha, gồm các hạng mục: Khu cát táng; khu lưu tro; khu tâm linh; khu vực phục vụ nghi lễ truyền thống; công trình công cộng; hệ thống cây xanh công viên; hệ thống hạ tầng kỹ thuật phụ gồm điện, nước, sân bãi đỗ xe, đường giao thông… Tuy nhiên, việc triển khai dự án tại khu vực Phiêng Khá có nhiều ý kiến trái chiều, cho rằng vị trí xây nghĩa trang quá gần khu dân cư. Đặc biệt, cán bộ, giảng viên trường Đại học Tây Bắc không đồng thuận với lý do vị trí xây dựng nghĩa trang mới nằm quá gần với nhà trường, ảnh hưởng nghiêm trọng đến việc học tập, tâm lý, sức khỏe của học sinh, sinh viên và cán bộ, giáo viên của  trường... Được biết, thực hiện ý kiến chỉ đạo của Thường trực Tỉnh ủy Sơn La tại công văn số 306, ngày 9/3/2021, Ban cán sự Đảng UBND tỉnh Sơn La ngoài chỉ đạo UBND tỉnh nghiên cứu, xem xét, đề xuất việc dừng triển khai dự án Nghĩa trang TP. Sơn La tại khu vực Phiêng Khá, đã nghiên cứu các khu vực có đủ các điều kiện để đầu tư dự án nghĩa trang công viên vĩnh hằng có quy mô, vị trí phù hợp với quy hoạch của tỉnh./."},{"question":"Tỉnh, thành phố nào có nhiều huyện nhất ở Việt Nam?A. Thanh HoáB. TP HCMC. Trà Vinh","answer":"Câu trả lời đúng: A. Thanh HoáGiải thích: tỉnh Thanh Hoá rộng hơn 11.129 km2, nằm ở khu vực Bắc Trung Bộ. Thanh Hoá hiện có 27 đơn vị hành chính cấp huyện, gồm hai thành phố, hai thị xã và 23 huyện. Đây là tỉnh có số huyện nhiều nhất cả nước.Trong khi đó, Hà Nam là tỉnh có số huyện ít nhất. Tỉnh có 6 đơn vị hành chính cấp huyện, trong đó có thành phố Phủ Lý, thị xã Duy Tiên và các huyện Kim Bảng, Lý Nhân, Thanh Liêm, Bình Lục."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en está categoría: deporte. ","answer":"¿Cuántos años tiene el mánager de Pittburgh Pirates? 51 años. "},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Tin tức 24h: Bất thường vụ nữ sinh \\"có nồng độ cồn cao\\" bị tông chết ở Ninh Thuận","answer":"Bất thường vụ nữ sinh \\"có nồng độ cồn cao\\" bị tông chết ở Ninh Thuận Ngày 31-7, ông Hồ Hoàng Hùng, cha của em Hồ Hoàng Anh, học sinh lớp 12 của một trường chuyên ở TP Phan Rang - Tháp Chàm, tỉnh Ninh Thuận, cho biết: Gia đình đã có đơn khiếu nại về kết quả giám định nồng độ cồn trong máu của em Anh sau khi em qua đời. Đơn khiếu nại mà gia đình nữ sinh gửi đến Bí thư tỉnh ủy, Chủ tịch UBND tỉnh Ninh Thuận và các cơ quan liên quan, đặt vấn đề: Vì sao một học sinh đến trường lúc 7 giờ sáng lại có nồng độ cồn lên đến 0,79mg/100ml máu, tương đương với người uống rượu bia thuộc loại tửu lượng cao.  Ông Hoàng Văn Minh (áo xanh) nghe điện thoại sau khi gây tai nạn. Ảnh: AK Gia đình cũng yêu cầu tiến hành giám định, đối chiếu mẫu máu mà Bệnh viện đa khoa tỉnh Ninh Thuận đã xét nghiệm và vì sao lấy mẫu máu mà không có sự chứng kiến của gia đình, người làm chứng, thân nhân hay Viện Kiểm sát. Đồng thời, gia đình nạn nhân cũng đề nghị tiến hành giám định nồng độ cồn của nữ sinh tại Viện Khoa học hình sự - Bộ Công an và có biện pháp xử lý, truy cứu trách nhiệm hình sự những người cố tình làm sai lệch hồ sơ vụ án (nếu có). Được biết, gia đình nhận được thông báo ngày 13-7 của Cơ quan CSĐT Công an TP Phan Rang – Tháp Chàm cho biết nồng độ cồn của em Anh là 0,79 mg/100 ml máu, do bệnh viện đa khoa tỉnh Ninh Thuận làm xét nghiệm. Trong khi đó, theo nguồn tin của Báo Người Lao Động, nhóm bạn học của nữ sinh này đã làm cam kết và chịu trách nhiệm về bản tự khai với nội dung tối hôm trước khi xảy ra tai nạn, nhóm bạn này có học nhóm tại một quán cà phê nhưng không ai sử dụng thức uống có cồn. Riêng nữ sinh Hồ Hoàng Anh chỉ uống nước lọc tự mang theo. Ngoài những yêu cầu trên, gia đình cũng thắc mắc vì sao không tiến hành đo và công bố nồng độ cồn của ông Hoàng Văn Minh là người cầm lái ô tô gây tai nạn. Vì sao TP HCM liên tục oi bức dù không phải cao điểm nắng nóng?  Đài Khí tượng Thủy văn khu vực Nam bộ cho biết trong 24 giờ qua thời tiết tại TP HCM có mây thay đổi, ngày nắng, chiều tối có mưa rào và dông rải rác. Tại khu vực Tân Sơn Nhất, nhiệt độ cao nhất là 34 độ C, nhiệt độ thấp nhất là 27 độ C. Trong khi đó, nhiệt độ cao nhất tại khu vực Nhà Bè là 34,5 độ C, nhiệt độ thấp nhất là 26,4 độ C. Trong những ngày qua, nhiệt độ tại TP HCM dao động từ 33-34 độ C. Tuy vẫn chưa đạt ngưỡng nắng nóng (từ 35 độ trở lên) nhưng người dân TP HCM vẫn cảm thấy không khí oi bức, khó chịu.  Hiên tượng oi bức diễn ra trong những ngày gần đây, gây khó chịu cho người dân. Theo ông Lê Đình Quyết, Phó trưởng Phòng Dự báo Đài Khí tượng Thủy văn khu vực Nam bộ, trong khoảng thời gian cuối tháng 7 và tháng 8, nhiệt độ tại TP HCM hiếm khi đạt trên 35 độ C (đạt ngưỡng nắng nóng). Nói về hiện tượng oi bức, khó chịu trong những ngày qua tại TP HCM, ông Quyết cho rằng nguyên nhân là do những cơn mưa xuất hiện vào buổi trưa hoặc đầu giờ chiều và trời nắng mạnh lên ngay sau đó \\"Khi mưa vừa xuống xong mà trời nắng mạnh lên liền làm cho hơi nước bốc lên trong nền nhiệt cao. Thêm vào đó là TP HCM có nhiều tòa nhà, đường sá bằng bê tông. Những khối bê tông khổng lồ này hấp thụ nhiệt cả ngày, khi gặp mưa thì sẽ làm nước mưa nhanh bốc hơi lên. Từ đó, cảm giác nhiệt độ cao, oi bức, khó chịu cho người dân xảy ra\\" – ông Quyết giải thích. \\"Cũng một trận mưa đó nhưng nếu xảy ra vào chiều tối thì cảm giác oi bức sẽ ít hơn. Còn nếu trận mưa xảy ra vào buổi trưa hoặc đầu giờ chiều thì sẽ gây ra cảm giác oi bức, khó chịu cho người dân\\" – ông Quyết nói thêm. Nam bộ có đợt mưa lớn diện rộng trong tháng 8 Theo Đài Khí tượng Thủy văn khu vực Nam bộ, thời tiết khu vực Nam bộ trong tháng 8-2022 chịu ảnh hưởng của gió mùa Tây Nam cường độ trung bình đến mạnh. Rãnh áp thấp và dải hội tụ nhiệt đới hoạt động phổ biến ở khoảng 15-20 độ vĩ bắc với khả năng cao xuất hiện 1-2 xoáy thấp nhiệt đới trên dải hội tụ mạnh lên thành bão hoặc áp thấp nhiệt đới. Ngoài ra, khả năng xảy ra một đợt mưa lớn diện rộng với tổng lượng mưa phổ biến 100-200 mm trên khu vực Nam bộ trong khoảng từ ngày 5 đến 12-8. Tổng lượng mưa tháng phổ biến xấp xỉ đến cao hơn trung bình nhiều năm ở hầu hết khu vực. Phó Giám đốc Công an tỉnh trực tiếp thuyết phục tên cướp tiệm vàng buông súng AK đầu hàng Đối tượng dùng súng cướp tại tiệm vàng Hoàng Đức và tiệm vàng Thái Lợi chợ Đông Ba (TP Huế, Thừa Thiên-Huế) gây hoang mang dư luận đã sa lưới lực lượng Công an Thừa Thiên-Huế chỉ sau 1 tiếng đồng hồ gây án. Đại tá Đặng Ngọc Sơn, Phó Giám đốc Công an tỉnh Thừa Thiên-Huế cho biết, vào khoảng 13h, cơ quan Công an Thừa Thiên-Huế nhận được tin báo của người dân, có đối tượng dùng súng cướp tiệm vàng tại chợ Đông Ba khiến tiểu thương, người dân rất hoang mang.  Tiệm vàng Hoàng Đức nơi kẻ cướp nổ súng vào khoảng 13h trưa 31/7. Ngay sau khi nhận được tin báo, Đại tá Đặng Ngọc Sơn trực tiếp có mặt tại hiện trường, chỉ đạo lực lượng CSHS Công an tỉnh, Công an TP Huế, Cảnh sát Cơ động Công an tỉnh và Công an phường Đông Ba khẩn trương khám nghiệm hiện trường, chốt chặn các tuyến đường, nhanh chóng truy tìm đối tượng gây án. Từ 13h10 ngày 31/7, lực lượng Công an TP Huế đã tổ chức phong tỏa toàn bộ tuyến đường trước chợ Đông Ba (TP Huế). Tại hai tiệm hàng vàng bị cướp, lực lượng chức năng cũng đã phong tỏa để khám nghiệm hiện trường. Theo thông tin ban đầu từ cơ quan điều tra, kẻ cướp đã cầm súng AK và nổ súng lần lượt vào hai tiệm vàng lớn là Hoàng Đức và Thái Lợi nằm trước cổng chợ Đông Ba (phía mặt tiền đường Trần Hưng Đạo, TP Huế). Được biết, hai tiệm vàng này cách nhau 4 cửa hàng. Thời gian, đối tượng nổ súng tại hai tiệm vàng chỉ cách nhau khoảng 1 phút. Sau khi nổ súng, kẻ cướp vơ nhiều vàng rồi vứt các khay đựng vàng ra phía trước đường. Thời điểm đối tượng nổ súng AK, tại 2 tiệm vàng Hoàng Đức và Thái Lợi đều có chủ cửa hàng và nhân viên trông coi. Bước đầu, Công an xác định, có 1 nạn nhân tại tiệm vàng Thái Lợi bị thương. Sau khoảng 1 tiếng đồng hồ nỗ lực truy bắt, Công an xác định đối tượng đang lẩn trốn tại nhà lục giác công viên Trịnh Công Sơn ở phường Gia Hội, TP Huế - cách địa điểm gây án khoảng 1 km. Ngay lúc này, từ lời đề nghị của đối tượng, Đại tá Đặng Ngọc Sơn đã trực tiếp gặp đối tượng và sau khi thuyết phục, đối tượng đồng ý buông súng ra đầu thú. Danh tính đối tượng được xác định là Ngô Văn Quốc (SN 1984, trú tại tỉnh Thừa Thiên-Huế). Hiện, cơ quan Công an Thừa Thiên-Huế đang tiếp tục điều tra làm rõ vụ án. Xót xa học sinh vừa đỗ cấp 3 gặp nạn tử vong khi tắm ở cống Thông tin cho PV, đại diện thị trấn Trường Sơn, huyện An Lão (TP. Hải Phòng) cho biết, sau gần 1 ngày nổ lực, lực lượng chức năng đã tìm thấy thi thể cháu bé 15 tuổi gặp nạn vào chiều hôm qua khi đi tắm tại khu vực cống Trường Sơn. Hiện thi thể nạn nhân đã được bàn giao cho gia đình lo hậu sự. Cụ thể, vào chiều qua (30/7), trong quá trình tắm tại khu vực cống Trường Sơn (thị trấn Trường Sơn), cháu Tr.N.K.H. (SN 2007), trú tại Đường Đỏ, phường Văn Đẩu, quận Kiến An (TP. Hải Phòng) bị mất tích dưới khu vực cống. Ngay sau đó vụ việc được cấp báo cho chính quyền địa phương và người thân.  Chiều nay, lực lượng chức năng đã tìm thấy thi thể cháu bé gặp nạn trong quá trình tắm ở khu vực cống Trường Sơn. Ngay khi nhận được tin báo, UBND thị trấn Trường Sơn đã điều động lực lượng, phương tiện phối hợp với gia đình nạn nhân tổ chức kìm kiếm. Đến 13h40 chiều nay (31/7), thi thể cháu H. đã được tìm thấy. Đáng chú ý, trước khi gặp nạn, cháu H. vừa trúng tuyển và hoàn thành làm thủ tục nhập học vào một trường THPT trên địa bàn quận Kiến An. Sau khi hoàn thiện các thủ tục cần thiết, thi thể nạn nhân xấu số được bàn giao cho gia đình lo hậu sự; đồng thời cơ quan chức năng tiến hành xác minh làm rõ nguyên nhân vụ việc. Trước đó, vào 15/7, trong quá trình tắm tại khu vực cống Xiếc ở thôn Hạ Câu, xã Quốc Tuấn, huyện An Lão (Hải Phòng), hai chị em họ N.X.M (13 tuổi) và N.T.H. (12 tuổi) không may gặp nạn tử vong. Gần đây nhất, vào chiều 27/7, tại khu vực cống Ba Đồng, thuộc địa bàn xã Trung Lập (huyện Vĩnh Bảo (Hải Phòng), cháu P. P. Y (SN 2008), trú tại thôn 4, xã Việt Tiến (huyện Vĩnh Bảo) cùng nhóm bạn đi chơi, chụp ảnh. Sau đó, cháu Y. bị trượt chân rơi xuống kênh Ba Đồng dẫn đến tử vong. Theo cơ quan chức năng, trong vòng 1 tháng qua, trên địa bàn TP. Hải Phòng xảy ra 4 vụ đuối nước khiến 6 nạn nhân tử vong. Vàng SJC tăng gần 1 triệu đồng/lượng Mở cửa phiên giao dịch ngày 31/7, giá vàng miếng SJC trong nước được Tập đoàn vàng bạc đá quý Doji niêm yết ở mức 65,8 - 66,8 triệu đồng/lượng. Mức giá này tăng 900.000 đồng/lượng ở cả 2 chiều mua vào và bán ra so với phiên giao dịch trước đó. Tập đoàn Phú Quý niêm yết giá vàng miếng ở mức 66,1 - 67,1 triệu đồng/lượng. Mức giá này tăng 400.000 đồng/lượng ở cả 2 chiều mua vào và bán ra so với hôm qua. Nhẫn tròn trơn niêm yết ở mức 52,4 - 53,2 triệu đồng/lượng, tăng 100.000 đồng/lượng so với phiên giao dịch trước đó. Trên thị trường quốc tế, sáng ngày 31/7 (giờ Việt Nam), giá vàng thế giới ở mức 1.766 USD/ounce, tăng 4 USD/ounce so với cuối phiên giao dịch hôm qua. Theo tỷ giá hiện hành tại Vietcombank (23.550 đồng/USD), giá vàng thế giới khoảng 48,8 triệu đồng/lượng (chưa tính thuế, phí). Giá vàng tương lai giao tháng 8/2022 trên sàn Comex New York tăng 31,2 USD lên 1.750,3 USD/ounce. Ủy ban Thị trường Mở Liên bang Mỹ (FOMC) đã đồng thuận tăng lãi suất 75 điểm cơ bản trong nỗ lực chống lạm phát đang ở mức cao nhất trong 41 năm qua (9,1% ghi nhận hồi tháng 6/2022). Vàng được hỗ trợ nhờ động thái thận trọng của Cục Dự trữ liên bang Mỹ (Fed). Tuy nhiên, ngân hàng trung ương Mỹ cho hay sẽ tiếp tục kế hoạch nâng lãi suất. Điều này đồng nghĩa với việc đồng USD vẫn có được sự hỗ trợ trong thời gian tới. Theo báo cáo của Hội đồng Vàng Thế giới (WGC), trong quý II/2022 nhu cầu vàng vật chất đã giảm khoảng 948 tấn (8%) so với mức của quý II/2021. Tuy nhiên, nhu cầu vàng trong nửa đầu năm 2022 đạt 2.189 tấn, tăng 12% so với cùng kỳ năm 2021. Ông Phillip Streible - chiến lược gia tại Blue Line Futures cho biết, sau khi số liệu GDP xác nhận những lo ngại suy thoái, các nhà giao dịch dự đoán Fed sẽ chậm tăng lãi suất, qua đó làm tăng sức hấp dẫn cho vàng. Trên thị trường tiền tệ trong nước, ngày 31/7, tỷ giá trung tâm được Ngân hàng Nhà nước niêm yết ở mức 23.176 đồng/USD, giữ nguyên so với phiên giao dịch trước đó. Tỷ giá tham khảo tại Sở giao dịch Ngân hàng Nhà nước ở mức 22.550 - 23.400 đồng/USD (mua vào - bán ra). Tỷ giá USD được Ngân hàng TMCP Ngoại thương (VCB) niêm yết ở mức 23.170 - 23.480 đồng/USD (mua vào - bán ra). Mức giá này giữ nguyên so với phiên giao dịch trước đó.  Nguồn: https://phunuphapluat.nguoiduatin.vn/tin-tuc-24h-bat-thuong-vu-nu-sinh-co-nong-do-con-c...Nguồn: https://phunuphapluat.nguoiduatin.vn/tin-tuc-24h-bat-thuong-vu-nu-sinh-co-nong-do-con-cao-bi-tong-chet-o-ninh-thuan-a572208.html"},{"question":"විද්යුත් යාන්ත්‍රික යුගය (1840 – 1940) ගැන කියන්න.","answer":"විද්යුත් යාන්ත්‍රික යුගයේ ආරම්භක අවස්ථාව විද්යුත් චුම්බක පණිවුඩ ක්‍රමයයි. 1876 දී ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර් ග්‍රැහැම්බෙල් විසින් දුරකථනය සොයා ගැනීම, 1897 දී ගුග්ලි ඇල්මෝ මාර්කෝනි විසින් ගුවන්විදුලි යන්ත්‍රය සොයාගැනීම ආදිය තොරතුරු තාක්ෂණයේ වැදගත් අවස්ථා ලෙස දැක්විය හැකිය."},{"question":"ਵਾਰਾਂ ਭਾਈ ਗੁਰਦਾਸ : ਵਾਰ ੧ ਪਉੜੀ ੮ ਪੰ. ੧ਖਟ ਸ਼ਾਸਤ੍ਰਚਹੁ ਬੇਦਾਂ ਕੇ ਧਰਮ ਮਥਿ ਖਟਿ ਸਾਸਤ੍ਰ ਕਥਿ ਰਿਖਿ ਸੁਣਾਵੈ।ਬ੍ਰਹਮਾਦਿਕ ਸਨਕਾਦਿਕਾ ਜਿਉ ਤਿਹਿ ਕਹਾ ਤਿਵੈ ਜਗੁ ਗਾਵੈ।ਗਾਵਨਿ ਪੜਨਿ ਬਿਚਾਰਿ ਬਹੁ ਕੋਟਿ ਮਧੇ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਗਤਿ ਪਾਵੈ।ਇਹਿ ਅਚਰਜ ਮਨ ਆਵਦੀ ਪੜਤਿ ਗੁਣਤਿ ਕਛੁ ਭੇਦੁ ਨ ਪਾਵੈ।ਜਗੁ ਜੁਗ ਇਕੋ ਵਰਨ ਹੈ ਕਲਿਜੁਗਿ ਕਿਉ ਬਹੁਤੇ ਦਿਖਲਾਵੈ।ਜੰਦ੍ਰੇ ਵਜੇ ਤ੍ਰਿਹੁ ਜੁਗੀ ਕਥਿ ਪੜ੍ਹਿ ਰਹੈ ਭਰਮ ਨਹਿ ਜਾਵੈ।ਜਿਉ ਕਰਿ ਕਥਿਆ ਚਾਰਿ ਬੇਦਿ ਖਟਿ ਸਾਸਤ੍ਰਿ ਸੰਗਿ ਸਾਖ ਸੁਣਾਵੈ।ਆਪੋ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਤ ਸਭਿ ਗਾਵੈ ॥੮॥","answer":"ਚਾਰ ਬੇਦਾਂ ਦੇ ਧਰਮਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਚਾਰਕੇ ਤੇ ਛੀ ਸ਼ਾਸਤ੍ਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ (ਮਥਿ=) ਸੋਧਕੇ (ਬਿਆਸ ਆਦਿ ਛੇ) ਰਿਖੀ ਸੁਣਾਂਵਦੇ ਹਨ।ਬ੍ਰਹਮਾਦਿਕ ਦੇਵਤੇ, ਸਨਕ, ਸਨੰਦਨ, ਸਨਾਤਨ, ਸਨਤ ਕੁਮਾਰ (ਬ੍ਰਹਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਪੁੱਤ੍ਰਾਂ ਨੇ) ਜਿੱਕੁਰ ਕਹਿ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ ਉਸੇ ਭਾਂਤ ਜਗਤ ਬੀ ਪਿਆ ਗਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਗਾਂਵਦੇ, ਪੜ੍ਹਦੇ ਤੇ ਵਿਚਾਰਦੇ ਬਾਹਲੇ ਹਨ (ਪਰੰਤੂ ਈਸ਼੍ਵਰੀ) ਗਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਹੀ ਕੋਟਾਂ ਮੱਧੇ ਪਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਇਹ ਮਨ (ਵਿਖੇ ਬੜੀ) ਅਚਰਜ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ (ਭਈ) ਪੜ੍ਹਦਿਆਂ ਵਿਚਾਰਦਿਆਂ ਕੁਛ ਭੇਦ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ।ਜੁਗਾਂ, (ਚਹੁੰ) ਜੁਗਾਂ ਵਿਖੇ ਈਸ਼੍ਵਰ ਦਾ ਇਕੋ ਰੂਪ ਹੈ, (ਪਰ) ਕਲਜੁਗ ਵਿਖੇ ਲੋਕ ਕਿਉਂ ਬਾਹਲੇ ਦੱਸਦੇ ਹਨ?ਤਿੰਨਾਂ ਜੁੱਗਾਂ ਵਿਖੇ ਜੰਦਰੇ ਹੀ ਵਜੇ ਰਹੇ, (ਕਬਿ=) ਵਖਯਾਨ (ਕਰਕੇ) ਤੇ ਪੜ੍ਹਕੇ (ਲੋਕ) ਥੱਕ ਗਏ ਪਰ ਭਰਮ ਨਾ ਹਟਿਆ।ਜਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਚਾਰ ਵੇਦਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਵਰਣਨ ਕੀਤਾ, ਛੀ ਸ਼ਾਸਤ੍ਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਂਖ ਵਾਲੇ ਸੁਨਾਂਵਦੇ ਹਨ,ਆਪੋ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਏ ਗਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ।"},{"question":"Tarjamahkeun kalimah ieu tina basa Sunda kana basa Indonésia:Pemilihan umum yang adil dan jujur adalah prasyarat dalam demokrasi yang sehat.","answer":"Pamilihan umum anu adil sareng jujur ​​mangrupikeun prasyarat pikeun démokrasi anu séhat."},{"question":"با توجه به متن زیر به سؤال پرسیده شده پاسخ دهید:  متن: تیم ملی والیبال زنان ایران از ساعت 12:30 امروز (چهارشنبه 15 شهریور) و در آخرین دیدار خود در مسابقات قهرمانی آسیا به مصاف چین‌تایپه رفت و با نتیجه سه بر صفر و امتیازات 14 بر 25، 19 بر 25 و 24 بر 26 مغلوب حریف شد تا با کسب عنوان دهمی به کار خود در این رقابت‌ها پایان دهد.سؤال: نتیجه آخرین بازی تیم والیبال بانوان ایران در بازی‌های قهرمانی آسیا چه بود؟","answer":"تیم والیبال بانوان ایران آخرین بازی خود در مسابقات فهرمانی آسیا را به رقیب خود چین تایپه واگذار کرد."},{"question":"Sông băng ngày tận thế khiến bao nhiêu băng tan mỗi năm?","answer":"Thwaites đang khiến khoảng 45,5 tỷ tấn băng tan vào nước mỗi năm. Cơ quan Khảo sát Nam Cực Anh (BAS) cho biết, sông băng này đóng góp 4% lượng nước biển dâng toàn cầu và các yếu tố khiến nó mất nhiều băng hơn đang gia tăng, theo nhà khoa học Ted Scambos tại Đại học Colorado."},{"question":"Dans quel pays est né le chanteur Stromae ? ","answer":"Le chanteur Stromae (Paul van Haver) est né à Etterbeek, en Belgique, en 1985."},{"question":"A là anh trai của B, B là chị gái của C và C là mẹ của D. Hỏi D có mối quan hệ thế nào với A?","answer":"A là bác (uncle) của D"},{"question":"Nitori owo ina ijọba to gbẹnu soke, awọn araalu fẹhonu han ni Kwara","answer":"Latari bi ileeṣẹ to n pin ina ka (Ibadan Electricity), ṣe fowo kun owo ina oṣu kẹwaa, nipinlẹ Kwara, awọn onibaara niluu Ilọrin, fẹhonu han, wọn ni owo naa ti fẹẹ ju agbara awọn lọ.Niṣe ni awọn onibaara ọhun ya bo agbegbe Muritala, niluu Ilọrin, ti wọn si n pe fun ki wọn din owo naa ku tori pe ina ti wọn n mu wa ko yatọ si tatẹyinwa, ki waa lo mu ki owo gbẹnu soke si i. Awọn onibaara ọhun sọ pe iye ti wọn n san lowo ina losoosu ni naiara mejidinlaaadọta ati kọbọ mọkandinlogoji (N58.39k), ṣugbọn ni osu kẹwaa yii, o ti fo fẹrẹ si ọgọta naira ati naira mọkandinlogoji (60.39k), ti ina ọhun si fi bẹẹ duro ire. Iwadii fi han pe ni awọn ipinlẹ bii Ọsun, Ọyọ, Ogun, Ekiti ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ, ni ileesẹ apinaka IBEDC ti fi kun idiyele owo wọn.Ọkan lara awọn onibaara to ba awọn oniroyin sọrọ lorukọ awọn ẹlẹgbẹ wọn, Arabinrin Aisat Bello, bu ẹnu atẹ lu igbesẹ naa pẹlu bi ileeṣẹ naa ṣe sadeede fi owo kun un lai fi to awọn onibaara leti tẹlẹ. Bello tẹsiwaju pe ileeṣẹ ọhun ko wo ipo ti eto ọrọ aje de duro bayii, wọn kan ṣa a fowo kun ina ni tiwọn ni. O wa pe fun iwadii to nipọn lori bi wọn ṣe fowo kun un lai sọ fun awọn onibara."},{"question":"වෘත්තීය සෆාරි ඡායාරූපකරණය සඳහා හොඳම උපදෙස් මොනවාද?","answer":"වෘත්තීය සෆාරි ඡායාරූපකරණය සඳහා හොඳම උපදෙස ඉවසීම ප්‍රධාන වේ, බොහෝ සතුන්ට පුරෝකථනය කළ හැකි සංක්‍රමණ රටා ඇති අතර, එය කඩාකප්පල් කිරීමට සාධක ගණනාවක් ඇති විය හැක. ඔබ වාහනයක සිටින්නේ නම්, එහා මෙහා ගෙන ගොස් වෙනත් ස්ථාන සොයා ගැනීමට උත්සාහ කරන්න. -අවම වශයෙන් කැමරා 2ක් රැගෙන යන්න, එකක් පුළුල් කෝණ කාචයක් සහ එකක් ටෙලිෆොටෝ කාචයක් සහිතයි. විවිධ සතුන් ඔබ වටා ගමන් කරන විට කාච මාරු කිරීමට ඔබට කාලය නොමැති නිසා. -ආම්පන්න ඉතා බර විය හැක, ඒ නිසා වාහනයකින් වෙඩි තැබීම අභියෝගාත්මක විය හැකි බැවින්, විශාල ටෙලිෆොටෝ කාචයක් රැගෙන නොයන්න. -ඔබේ වටපිටාව ගැන දැනුවත් වන්න, ඔබ තවමත් ක්‍රියාශීලී පරිසරයක සිටින නිසාත් සතුන්ට ඔබට ප්‍රතිචාර දැක්විය හැකි නිසාත් අවධානය වෙනතකට යොමු නොකරන්න."},{"question":"क्षते प्रहारा निपतंत्यभीक्ष्णं  धनक्षये दीप्यति जाठराग्निः ।आपत्सु वैराणि समुल्लसंति  छिद्रेष्वनर्था बहुलीभवंति ","answer":"लहानशा जखमेला पुन्हा पुन्हा धक्का लागून ती चिघळते, पैसे नसतांना जोरातच भूक लागते, संकट आले तर वैरी आनंदाने जल्लोश करतात, तेंव्हा लहानशा छिद्रापासून खूप अनर्थ होत असतात. लहानसहान त्रासाकडेही दुर्लक्ष करणे घातक ठरू शकते."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai apa kurang pada belida; sisik pun ada, tulang pun ada\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud cukup serba-serbi"},{"question":"Cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿En qué película de Iron Man no aparece Don Cheadle?. ","answer":"Es saber en cual película de Iron man esta aucente el actor Don Cheadle. "},{"question":"A que categoría corresponde la pregunta : ¿En qué estados de Nueva Inglaterra no ganó Biden las primarias del partido demócrata en el 2020?.","answer":"La categoría corresponde a política. "},{"question":"在加拿大，哪一种手势讯号是表示慢驶或停车？","answer":"手臂伸出向下"},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH da Costa do Marfim?","answer":"0,550."},{"question":"Эң кооз кыргыз улуттук акчасы 💸кайсы?","answer":"Көлөмү боюнча эң чоң беш миң сомдук акчада СССРдин эл артисти Сүймөнкул Чокморовдун сүрөтү тартылган.  Эл аралык банкноттук коомчулук беш миң сомду эң кооз акчалардын бири катары тааныган. "},{"question":"O tweet a seguir expressa um sentimento positivo, negativo ou neutro?*#TotalCripplesWalk* Quando o SENHOR levanta os coxos , você devia temer a DEUS https://t.co/W7Z5baKPuY","answer":"Esse tweet expressa um sentimento neutro"},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：人体最长的神经是什么？","answer":"答案：人体最长的神经是坐骨神经。"},{"question":"Viết bài luận về chủ đề: Ý nghĩa của tình yêu trong cuộc sống. ","answer":"Tình yêu thương chính là một trong những điều không thể nào thiếu được trong cuộc sống. Thật không sai chút nào khi người ta nói rằng một con người biết yêu thương chính là người có nhân cách đẹp, và luôn hướng đến những thứ tốt đẹp, hoàn mỹ hơn.Đầu tiên chúng ta phải hiểu được tình yêu thương là gì? Tình yêu thương được hiểu đó chính là sự sẻ chia mà mỗi người dành cho nhau, một thứ tình cảm thiêng liêng xuất phát từ nơi con tim. Tình yêu thương định nghĩa dễ nhất đó cũng chính là sự đồng cảm và như cũng chất chứa được tinh thần nhân loại mà con người dành cho con người. Thực sự trong cuộc sống này thì chính tình yêu thương có vô vàn hình trạng, nó như một viên đá ngũ sắc lung linh và đẹp đến mê mẩn. Những điều này dường như tuy nó vô hình nhưng lại hữu hình, đồng thời tình thương cũng như lại luôn luôn xuất hiện vào cuộc sống hằng ngày. Ta như nhận thấy được rằng, chắc chính mỗi người chúng ta có thể dễ dàng nhận ra hay không thể nhận ra bởi tình yêu thương nó vô cùng đơn giản, và gần gũi biết bao nhiêu. Ta dường như cũng lại nhận thấy được cũng chính là người thân yêu mẹ bạn yêu bạn, anh chị người thân bạn chăm sóc cho bạn, bạn bè bạn lo lắng cho bạn…. Tình yêu thương cũng được hiểu đó chính là tình thân, tình nghĩa. Mỗi con người chúng ta đều sinh ra may mắn được sống trong tình yêu của cha của mẹ, chúng ta được gắn kết bởi tình yêu nồng nàn từ cha mẹ thân yêu của chúng ta. Thế rồi ta như cũng nhận thấy được cũng chính từ những người mang chung dòng máu với ta. Và mỗi khi chúng ta như lại chập chững vào lớp học, chúng ta biết đến tình yêu thương mới đó chính là tình bạn. Tình yêu thương thực sự nó được ví như thật giống như một chiếc túi khổng lồ mà nhân loại không định nghĩa sao cho tường tận được. Ta như nhận thấy được tình yêu thương thực sự trìu tượng đến mức khó hiểu. Tình yêu thương đơn giản đó cũng chính là khi chúng ta mà nhìn đứa trẻ mồ côi như đang lặng lẽ nằm ở hàng ghế đá, nhìn cụ già đang mon men đi xin ăn. Và làm sao ta có thể không động lòng khi chúng ta nhìn người dân miền trung đang chịu những cơn bão, người thì bị chết, gia đình li tán và của cải bị mất mát. Ta như nhận thấy được cũng chính vì tình yêu thương chính là sự lo lắng cho người với người, dù chưa từng gặp mặt, dù chị là sự lướt qua nhanh chóng. Còn có những người luôn cố gắng cho đi mà không bao giờ nghĩ nhận lại cho riêng mình cả. Thật tuyệt vời biết bao nhiêu vì trên thế giới con người luôn xuất hiện tình yêu thương. Mỗi ngày trong mỗi chúng ta hãy nuôi dưỡng trong trái tim mình những viên đá ngũ sắc yêu thương để tô vẻ cho cuộc sống của chính mình. Cuộc sống sẽ thật đẹp biết bao nhiêu khi có tình thương."},{"question":"Uthe angaqeda ukukhuluma nocingo lwakhe lolo, waluvala.'Baba nawe Mama, ithanda ukungesinda mina le nto. Lo mnumzane uthi ufunangimelekelele. Ungibalisela ngokuhlupheka kwakhe. Ungitshela ukuthiakanayo imali ngenxa yokuthi wadilizwa emsebenzini. Ungitshela ukuthiwethembele kimi njengomkhwenyana wakwakhe. Ungitshela ukuthi akanayoimali eyanele. Kuyacaca ukuthi uyabona ukuthi lo msebenzi ubhekene nayengqo. Uzama ukungifaka ngekhanda nje. Ngeke ngiyivume mina leyo nto.Ufunani kimi?''Uphendule wathini wena kuyena ngenkathi nixoxa?' kubuza uyise.'Angimethembisanga lutho Baba. Ngithe ngizobona. Okokuqala, yenaakafanelanga ukukhuluma nami. Kufanele akhulume nani, hhayi mina.Ngibona sengathi ufuna ukungiqinela ngoba azi ukuthi ngiyamhlonipha. Utheuzobuye ashaye emva kwesikhashana.Yinina okufanele nikhulume naye,hhayi mina.''Ngiyakuzwa lokho okushoyo, kodwa ngibona sengathi usezohlalelaethembeni njengoba wena uthe usazobona nje,' kusho unina.'Kulungile. Akahlalele kulelo themba lakhe aze ayofa njengoba esihlaliseethembeni kwaze kwafa omunye nje. Elami lithi, ngeke ngize ngifake ngishoelimnyama isenti. Ningamelekelela nina uma ninemali eningi. Lo muntusisanda kumnikeza inqwaba yemali. Akasebenzise yona. Ukuba wayidedelaingane yakhe, ngabe asihluphani ngalutho nale ndoda. Bengizozithwalangikhululekile izindleko zomngcwabo. Bengingeke ngimeme omunye umuntu.'1. Lwaluvelaphi ucingo ayeqeda ukuluphendula uMandlenkosi? ","answer":"Lwaluvela kumukhwe wakhe"},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన దానిని సంగ్రహించండి చైనా టిబెట్‌లో ఏం చేస్తోంది... లక్షలాది మంది ప్రజలను శిక్షణ శిబిరాలకు ఎందుకు తరలిస్తోంది?టిబెట్ లాసాలోని పోటాలా ప్యాలెస్స్థానిక మీడియా కథనాలు, పాలసీ పత్రాలు, రాయిటర్స్ వార్తా సంస్థ సమకూర్చిన ఉపగ్రహ చిత్రాలను ఆధారం చేసుకుని జేమ్స్‌టౌన్ ఫౌండేషన్ ఈ నివేదికను రూపొందించింది.  చైనా షిన్‌జియాంగ్ ప్రాంతంలోని వీగర్ ముస్లింలకు ఏర్పాటు చేసిన శిబిరాల్లాగే, టిబెట్‌లోని శిబిరాలు ఉన్నాయని ఈ నివేదిక అభిప్రాయపడింది.అయితే, ఈ నివేదిక ఫలితాలపై చైనా ప్రభుత్వం ఇంతవరకూ స్పందించలేదు. ఈ ఏడాది చివరికల్లా చైనాలో పేదరికాన్ని నిర్మూలిస్తామని చైనా అధ్యక్షుడు షీ జిన్ పింగ్ ప్రకటించారు. గ్రామీణ ప్రాంతాలనుంచి ఇలా కార్మికులను భారీగా తరలించడం కూడా అందులో భాగమేనని కొందరు వ్యాఖ్యానిస్తున్నారు. హిమాలయ ప్రాంతంలో ఎన్నో అభివృద్ధి కార్యక్రమాలు చేపడుతున్నామని చైనా ప్రభుత్వం చెబుతోంది.చైనా సరిహద్దు వెంబడి మారుమూల ప్రాంతంగా ఉండే టిబెట్ ప్రధానంగా బౌద్ధ మతస్థుల ప్రాంతం. చైనాకు చెందిన స్వయం ప్రతిపత్తి కలిగిన ప్రాంతంగా టిబెట్ చాలా కాలంగా చైనా ఆధిపత్యాన్ని ప్రశ్నిస్తోంది. తమ సంస్కృతి, మత స్వేచ్ఛలను అణచివేయాలని చైనా ప్రయత్నిస్తోందని ఆరోపిస్తుంటుంది.\\"చదువు\\" పేరుతో టిబెట్ ప్రజలను బలవంతంగా శ్రామిక శిక్షణ శిబిరాల్లోకి తీసుకుపోతున్నారని ప్రస్తుతం ప్రవాసంలో ఉన్న టిబెట్ అధ్యక్షుడు లోబ్సాంగ్ సాంగే కూడా ఆరోపించారు. అయితే, తాజా అధ్యయనం ప్రకారం ఈ శిక్షణ శిబిరాల స్థాయి ఊహించిన దానికన్నా చాలా ఎక్కువగా ఉన్నట్లు తెలుస్తోంది. టిబెట్, షిన్‌జియాంగ్‌కు చెందిన పరిశోధకులు ఆడ్రియన్ జెంజ్ ఈ నివేదికను తయారుచేసారు. టిబెట్ స్వతంత్ర పోరుకు ప్రపంచవ్యాప్తంగా మద్దతుదారులున్నారు2020 సంవత్సరం మొదటి ఏడు నెలల్లో 5,00,000 ల మంది రైతులు, పశువుల కాపర్లకు శిక్షణ ఇచ్చారని, వీరందరినీ శిక్షణ అనంతరం టిబెట్, చైనాలలోని పలు ప్రాంతాలకు తరలించనున్నారని ఆడ్రియన్ జెంజ్ ఈ నివేదికలో తెలిపారు.\\"క్రమ శిక్షణ, చైనా భాష, పని విలువల\\" అభివృద్ధికే ఈ శిక్షణా కేంద్రాలను నడుపుతున్నట్లుగా చైనా ప్రభుత్వం పేర్కొందని నివేదకి చెబుతోంది. కొందరు టిబెటన్లు ఇష్టపూర్వకంగానే ఈ శిక్షణా శిబిరాల్లో చేరారని, కొందరు తమ ఆదాయం మెరుగైందని చెబుతున్నారని కూడా ఈ నివేదిక తెలిపింది.అయితే, ఈ కార్యక్రమం అంతా ప్రణాళిక బద్ధంగా, వ్యవస్థీకృతం చేసే స్థాయిలో జరుగుతోందని, అది ఇక్కడి ప్రజల జీవన విధానాన్ని శాశ్వతంగా మార్చేలా ఉండడం తీవ్ర సమస్యలకు దారితీయవచ్చని కూడా ఈ నివేదిక స్పష్టం చేసింది.'కశ్మీర్‌ విషయంలో జోక్యం.","answer":"చైనా ప్రభుత్వం టిబెట్‌లోని లక్షలాది మంది ప్రజలను మిలటరీ తరహా శిక్షణ శిబిరాలకు తరలిస్తోందని, అవి 'లేబర్ క్యాంపుల' మాదిరిగా ఉన్నాయని నిపుణులు చెబుతున్నారని ఇటీవలి ఒక అధ్యయనం వెల్లడించింది."},{"question":"Жусуп Баласагындын \\"Куттуу билим\\" эмгегинен 1-2 сап жазып бере аласыңбы ?","answer":"Жаштык өтөт, өмүр бүтөт элирген,Бу дүйнө — түш, сен да өтөсүң өмүрдөн."},{"question":" Dowladii Ugu Horeesay Ee Soo Saarta Sokorta?","answer":"Dowladdii Ugu Horeesay Ee Soo Saartay Sokorta Waa Dowladda Kuuba (Cuba)."},{"question":"Waye ya fara mulkin Nigeria?","answer":"Nnamdi Azikwe shi ne shugaba na farko a Nigeria, bayan barin mulkin Turawa."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న: “సహజ పర్యావరణం, మానవ నిర్మిత పర్యావరణానికి భిన్నంగా ఉంటుంది.” మీ సమాధానాన్ని సమర్ధించుకోండి.","answer":"సహజ పర్యావరణం మానవ నిర్మిత పర్యావరణానికి భిన్నంగా ఉంటుంది.ఆదిమ మానవులు సహజ పరిసరాలతో మనుగడ సాగించటంలో తమను తాము అలవాటు చేసుకున్నారు. వారు సాధారణమైన జీవితాన్ని గడిపారు.వారి చుట్టూ ఉన్న ప్రకృతిని ఉపయోగించుకుని వారి అవసరాలను తీర్చుకున్నారు.స్థిర నివాసం మరియు. పారిశ్రామిక విప్లవం ఫలితంగా, మానవులు, సహజ వాతావరణాన్ని తమకు అనుకూలంగా ఎలా ఉపయోగించుకోవాలో మరియు ఎలా మార్చుకోవాలో నేర్చుకున్నారు.ఇది మానవ నిర్మిత పర్యావరణానికి సంబంధించిన అనేక అంశాలు ఏర్పడటానికి మరియు సహజ వాతావరణంలో మార్పులకు దారితీసింది.సహజ పర్యావరణం మానవ నిర్మిత పర్యావరణానికి భిన్నంగా ఉంటుంది.మానవులు తయారు చేసిన పరిసరాలను మానవ నిర్మిత పర్యావరణం అంటారు.సహజంగా ప్రకృతి సిద్ధంగా ఏర్పడిన పరిసరాలను సహజ పర్యావరణం అనవచ్చు.మానవులు సహజ వాతావరణాన్ని తమకు అనుకూలంగా మార్చుకుని ఏర్పరచుకున్నదే మానవ నిర్మిత పర్యావరణం.సహజ పర్యావరణం భూమి మీద జీవుల మనుగడకు ఆధారం.మానవ నిర్మిత పర్యావరణం లేకపోయినా జీవనం సాగించవచ్చు కానీ, సహజ పర్యావరణం లేకపోతే జీవం లేదు, ఉండదు."},{"question":"Ọlọpaa bẹrẹ iwadii lori afurasi ajinigbe ti wọn pa l’Omuo-Ekiti","answer":"Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ekiti to bẹrẹ iwadii lori ọrọ afurasi ajinigbe tawọn eeyan lu pa niluu Omuo-Ekiti, ti i ṣe olu-ilu ijọba ibilẹ Ila-Oorun Ekiti.Lopin ọsẹ to kọja niṣẹlẹ naa waye ni Iludọfin, pẹlu bi wọn ṣe ni ọkunrin ti ọjọ ori ẹ ko ti i ju ogoji ọdun lọ naa gbiyanju lati ji ọmọ ọdun meje kan gbe, ṣugbọn tawọn eeyan mu un, ti wọn si lu u pa.Ẹnikan to mọ nipa iṣẹlẹ ọhun sọ fun wa pe ileewe lọmọdekunrin naa ti n bọ pẹlu awọn ẹgbẹ rẹ ni nnkan bii aago meji ọsan ti onikaluku si n ya sọna ile ẹ, ṣugbọn wọn ko mọ pe ajinigbe kan n tẹle wọn.Bi ọkan ninu wọn ṣe kuro laarin awọn to ku, to si n gba ọna kan to da diẹ lọ sile ni afurasi naa tẹle e, bo si ṣe ki i mọlẹ lo wọ ọ wọ inu igbo, ṣugbọn ẹnikan ri i nigba to ṣe bẹẹ.Ariwo la gbọ pe ẹni to ri i pa, awọn eeyan si ya jade lati mu afurasi ajinigbe naa, bẹẹ ni wọn lu u titi to fi daku.Nigba to ya lawọn ọlọpaa de, ti wọn gba a silẹ lọwọ ọgọọrọ eeyan to n lu u, ṣugbọn bi wọn ṣe gbe e de teṣan lo dagbere faye.Nigba to n fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ, Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa Ekiti, ASP Sunday Abutu, ṣalaye pe oloye Iludọfin kan lo fọrọ naa to awọn ọlọpaa leti ti wọn fi lọ sibẹ, o si gba wọn lasiko diẹ ki wọn too ri afurasi naa gba lọwọ awọn araalu. O ni wọn sare gbe e lọ si teṣan lati daabo bo o, ṣugbọn bi wọn ṣe ni kawọn gbe e lọ sileewosan lo dakẹ.Abutu waa bẹnu atẹ lu iwa kawọn eeyan maa ṣedajọ fun afurasi, o ni ki wọn maa fa ẹni ti wọn ba mu pe o huwa ọdaran lọ teṣan nikan ni igbesẹ to tọna."},{"question":"“Өзүм өлсөмда, өлбөстөн сөзүм калсын соңума” деп кайсы акын аткан?","answer":"“Өзүм өлсөмда, өлбөстөн сөзүм калсын соңума” деп Тоголок Молдо айткан экен."},{"question":"Исхак Раззаковдун учкул сөзүнөн жазып бере аласыңбы ?","answer":"Бул дүйнөгө мен жылаңач бойдон келгем, ошол бойдон кетемин. Мага малдын да, толгон байлыктын да кереги жок. Элим үчүн эмгегим гана калса болду, ошого ыраазымын, ошол мага дөөлөт."},{"question":"එක්සත් ජර්මනියේ ප්‍රථම චාන්සල්වරයා කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"හෙල්මුට් කෝල් එක්සත් ජර්මනියේ ප්‍රථම චාන්සල්වරයා විය."},{"question":" ඉන්දියාවේ ජාතික උරගයා නම් කරන්න?","answer":" කිං නාගයා"},{"question":"Монгол империясынын биринчи башкаруучусу ким болгон?","answer":"Монгол империясынын биринчи башкаруучусу Чыңгызхан болгон."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Ia boleh sebesar istana, juga boleh sekecil semut, yang pelik ia tak muncul pada malam. Apakah ia?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah bayang. "},{"question":"Viết một đoạn văn ngắn (5câu-7câu) chủ đề về gia đình,trong đó phải có một câu cụm danh từ đầy đủ và ko đầy đủ.","answer":"Gia đình có vai trò thật quan trọng đối với con người. Vậy đâu là những việc cần làm để gia đình trở thành một tổ ấm yêu thương? Trước hết, chúng ta cần phải hiểu được rằng một gia đình luôn yêu thương, đầm ấm thì sẽ tạo ra những thành viên tích cực. Họ sẽ biết chia sẻ buồn vui cùng nhau, giúp đỡ nhau vượt qua khó khăn và bảo vệ nhau trong cuộc sống. Đặc biệt, khi con người trưởng thành sẽ phải đối mặt với nhiều khó khăn, chông gai. Nhưng nếu có gia đình luôn đứng phía sau động viên, khích lệ thì sẽ có được nguồn động lực to lớn để vượt qua. Tình cảm gia đình là thứ thiêng liêng nhất không gì có thể sánh được. Của cải, vật chất là những thứ có thể mua được, nhưng những tình cảm gia đình thì thật sự là vô giá. Nhưng để có một gia đình bình yên, hạnh phúc phải đến từ sự cố gắng của các thành viên trong gia đình. Chúng ta cần biết yêu thương, chia sẻ và thấu hiểu lẫn nhau để tình cảm gia đình trở nên gắn kết hơn."},{"question":"(ਏ) 1 ਮੋਲ ਨਾਈਟ੍ਰੋਜਨ ਪਰਮਾਣੂ ਦਾ ਪੁੰਜ ਕੀ ਹੈ ?(ਬੀ) ਐਲੂਮੀਨੀਅਮ ਦੇ ਪਰਮਾਣੂਆਂ ਦੇ 4 ਮੋਲ (ਐਲੂਮੀਨੀਅਮ ਦਾ ਪਰਮਾਣੂ ਪੁੰਜ = 27)?(c) ਸੋਡੀਅਮ ਸਲਫਾਈਟ ਦੇ 10 ਮੋਲ (Na 2 S0 3 )?","answer":"(ਏ) 1 ਮੋਲ ਨਾਈਟ੍ਰੋਜਨ ਪਰਮਾਣੂਆਂ ਦਾ ਪੁੰਜ = 14 ਗ੍ਰਾਮ(ਬੀ) 4 ਮੋਲ ਐਲੂਮੀਨੀਅਮ ਪਰਮਾਣੂਆਂ ਦਾ ਪੁੰਜ= 27 ਗ੍ਰਾਮ∴ 4 ਮੋਲ ਐਲੂਮੀਨੀਅਮ ਪਰਮਾਣੂਆਂ ਦਾ ਪੁੰਜ = 27 x 4 = 108 ਗ੍ਰਾਮ(c) 10 ਮੋਲ ਸੋਡੀਅਮ ਸਲਫਾਈਟ (Na2 ) SO 3 )1 ਮੋਲ ਦਾ ਪੁੰਜ Na 2 SO 3 = 2 x 23 + 32 + 3 x 16 = 46 + 32 + 48 = 126 g ∴ Na 2 SO 3 = 126 x 10 = 1260 ਗ੍ਰਾਮਦੇ 10 ਮੋਲ ਦਾ ਪੁੰਜ"},{"question":"Inona no fiantson’ny Malagasy ny mponina any an-dafy?","answer":"Ny fiantson’ny Malagasy ny mponina any an-dafy dia vazaha."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Jaką pojemność posiada Jezioro Czerniańskie?","answer":"Odpowiedź. Jezioro Czerniańskie to sztuczny zbiornik zaporowy; pojemność zbiornika to 4,5 mln m³, a powierzchnia wynosi 360 tys. m²."},{"question":"Manana teny mikotorana ianao\\"yrats\\"Omeo ary teny marina.","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"ratsy\\"."},{"question":"Tukarkan ayat aktif berikut kepada ayat pasif. Ayat aktif:  Mereka mengecat bangunan.","answer":"Ayat pasif yang betul ialah 'Bangunan dicat oleh mereka.' Ayat pasif ini adalah ayat pasif dengan kata ganti nama diri ketiga. Perkataan 'mereka' adalah kata ganti nama diri ketiga."},{"question":"கேள்வி: உமது ஊரில் உள்ள மிகப் பழைமையான இடம் எது? அதுபற்றி வகுப்பறையில் கலந்துரையாடுக.","answer":"பதில் : கலை : விமல்! நமது ஊரில் உள்ள மிகப்பழமையான இடம் என்று எதை நினைக்கிறாய்?விமல் : மதுரை மீனாட்சியம்மன் கோவில் என்று நினைக்கின்றேன்.கலை : சரி, கோவிலைப்பற்றி உனக்கு ஏதாவது தெரியுமா?விமல் : தெரியுமே, மதுரை மீனாட்சி சுந்தரேசுவரர் கோயில் என்பது வைகை ஆற்றின் கரையில் அமைந்துள்ள கோயில் நகரமான மதுரையின் மத்தியில் அமைந்துள்ள சிவாலயமாகும். இச்சிவாலயத்தின் மூலவர் சுந்தரேசுவரர் மற்றும் அம்பிகை மீனாட்சியம்மன். இக்கோயிலை மதுரை மீனாட்சியம்மன் கோயில் என்றும் அழைக்கின்றனர்.கலை : ஆமாம், இக்கோயிலே தமிழகத்தில் உள்ள முந்நூற்று அறுபத்தாறு மீனாட்சி சுந்தரேசுவரர் கோயில்களின் மூலகோயிலாக உள்ளது.விமல் : இக்கோயில் திராவிடக் கட்டக்கலைக்கு ஓர் எடுத்துக்காட்டாவும் விளங்குகிறது. இரண்டாயிரம் ஆண்டுகள் தொன்மை வாய்ந்ததாகவும் கருதப்படுகின்றது.கலை : தேவலோகத்தின் அரசனான இந்திரனால் கட்டப்பட்டது என்பது நம்பிக்கையாக உள்ளது.கலை : இக்கோயில் பதினைந்து ஏக்கர் பரப்பளவில் அமைந்துள்ளது. எட்டு கோபுரங்களையும் இரண்டு விமானங்களையும் உடையது. இங்குள்ள கருவறை விமானங்கள், இந்திர விமானம் என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. முப்பத்தி இரண்டு சிங்கங்களும், அறுபத்து நான்கு சிவகணங்களும் எட்டு வெள்ளை யானைகளும் இந்த கருவறை விமானங்களைத் தாங்குகின்றன.விமல் : இக்கோயில் கிழக்கு மேற்காக எண்ணூற்று நாற்பத்தேழு அடியும், தெற்கு வடக்காக எழுநூற்று தொண்ணூற்று இரண்டு அடியும் உடையது. இக்கோயிலின் ஆடி வீதிகளில் நான்கு புறமும் ஒன்பது நிலைகளை உடைய நான்கு கோபுரங்கள் மிக உயர்ந்த நிலையில் இருக்கிறது.கலை : அவற்றுள் தெற்குக் கோபுரம் மிக உயரமானதாகும். இதன் உயரம் நூற்று அறுபது அடியாக இருக்கிறது.விமல் : உண்மையிலேயே இக்கலந்துரையாடல் மிகவும் பயனுள்ளதாக அமைந்துள்ளது. நன்றி!"},{"question":"Pizza Đà Lạt là tên gọi đồ ăn vặt nào?","answer":"Lúc mới xuất hiện, bánh tráng nướng được dân ăn vặt gọi là pizza Đà Lạt vì hình dạng, tương tự món pizza Italy.Các thành phần chính tạo nên món ăn là bánh tráng và trứng gà, được điểm xuyết thêm ít hành lá và tép khô. Không chỉ đơn giản về thành phần, món ăn này còn rất đơn giản trong cách chế biến. Đầu tiên, chiếc bánh tráng được đặt lên vỉ nướng, trứng gà đánh tơi với hành lá, tép khô rồi dàn đều lên bề mặt bánh. Người bán xoay tròn đều chiếc bánh trên vỉ, đến khi phần trứng trên mặt bắt đầu chín vàng và dậy mùi thơm là bánh đã chín. Người bán chỉ cần cho lên một ít tương ớt, gấp tròn lại là thực khách đã có thể thưởng thức món ăn."},{"question":"கேள்வி:சு. தியோடர் பாஸ்கரன் அவர்களின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"பதில்: சு. தியடோர் பாஸ்கரன் ஒரு தமிழக எழுத்தாளர், தமிழ்த் திரைப்பட வரலாற்றாளர், சூழலியல் ஆர்வலர் என அறியப்படுபவர்.பாஸ்கரன் தாராபுரத்தில் 1940இல் பிறந்தார். பாளையங்கோட்டை சென். ஜான் கல்லூரியில் இடைநிலை வகுப்புப் படித்து பின்னர் சென்னைக் கிறிஸ்தவக் கல்லூரியில் முதுகலை (வரலாறு) பட்டம் பெற்றார். பட்டம் பெற்றவுடன், தமிழக அரசு ஆவணக் காப்பகத்தில் ஆய்வாளராக இரண்டாண்டுகள் பணி புரிந்தார். 1964ல் இந்திய தபால் துறையில் சேர்ந்தார். திருச்சியில் இரண்டாண்டுகள் கோட்ட மேலாளராகப் பணிபுரிந்தபின் வேலூருக்கும் பின்னர் மேகாலயாவிற்கும் பணிமாற்றம் செய்யப்பட்டார். அவர் மேகாலயாவிலிருந்த போது 1971ல் வங்காளதேச விடுதலைப் போர் மூண்டது. அப்போது பாஸ்கரன் தபால் தந்தித் துறையையும் பாதுகாப்புத் துறையையும் இணைக்கும் தனி அதிகாரியாக (Special Officer For War Efforts) நியமிக்கப்பட்டார். தபால் துறையில் பணிபுரிந்து கொண்டே திரைப்பட வரலாற்று ஆராய்ச்சியில் ஈடுபட்டார். தபால் துறையில் படிப்படியாக உயர்ந்து தமிழ் நாட்டின் தலைமை தபால் அதிகாரியாக (Chief Postmaster General) ஓய்வு பெற்றார். தற்பொழுது தன் மனைவி திலகாவுடன் பெங்களூரில் வசித்து வருகிறார்."},{"question":"A ina aka fara waƙar hip hop?","answer":"A gundumar Bronx na birnin New York."},{"question":"வினா: அதிகக் காரத் தன்மையுடைய சேர்மம்?","answer":"விடை: எத்தில் அமின்"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ਰਾਗੁ ਗਉੜੀ ਗੁਆਰੇਰੀ ਚਉਪਦੇੴ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ॥ਕਿਨ ਬਿਧਿ ਕੁਸਲੁ ਹੋਤ ਮੇਰੇ ਭਾਈ ॥ਕਿਉ ਪਾਈਐ ਹਰਿ ਰਾਮ ਸਹਾਈ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਕੁਸਲੁ ਨ ਗ੍ਰਿਹਿ ਮੇਰੀ ਸਭ ਮਾਇਆ ॥ਊਚੇ ਮੰਦਰ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਛਾਇਆ ॥ਝੂਠੇ ਲਾਲਚਿ ਜਨਮੁ ਗਵਾਇਆ ॥੧॥ਹਸਤੀ ਘੋੜੇ ਦੇਖਿ ਵਿਗਾਸਾ ॥ਲਸਕਰ ਜੋੜੇ ਨੇਬ ਖਵਾਸਾ ॥ਗਲਿ ਜੇਵੜੀ ਹਉਮੈ ਕੇ ਫਾਸਾ ॥੨॥ਰਾਜੁ ਕਮਾਵੈ ਦਹ ਦਿਸ ਸਾਰੀ ॥ਮਾਣੈ ਰੰਗ ਭੋਗ ਬਹੁ ਨਾਰੀ ॥ਜਿਉ ਨਰਪਤਿ ਸੁਪਨੈ ਭੇਖਾਰੀ ॥੩॥ਏਕੁ ਕੁਸਲੁ ਮੋ ਕਉ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਬਤਾਇਆ ॥ਹਰਿ ਜੋ ਕਿਛੁ ਕਰੇ ਸੁ ਹਰਿ ਕਿਆ ਭਗਤਾ ਭਾਇਆ ॥ਜਨ ਨਾਨਕ ਹਉਮੈ ਮਾਰਿ ਸਮਾਇਆ ॥੪॥ਇਨਿ ਬਿਧਿ ਕੁਸਲ ਹੋਤ ਮੇਰੇ ਭਾਈ ॥ਇਉ ਪਾਈਐ ਹਰਿ ਰਾਮ ਸਹਾਈ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ਦੂਜਾ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 175 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਵੀਰ ! (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ) ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਕਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਤਰੀਕਿਆਂ ਨਾਲ (ਪੈਦਾ) ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ?(ਅਸਲ) ਮਿੱਤਰ ਹਰੀ-ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਮਿਲ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ? ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਘਰ (ਦੇ ਮੋਹ) ਵਿਚ ਆਤਮਕ ਸੁਖ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਸਮਝਣ ਵਿਚ ਭੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਸੁਖ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਸਾਰੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਮੇਰੀ ਹੈ । ਉੱਚੇ ਮਹਲ-ਮਾੜੀਆਂ ਤੇ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਬਾਗਾਂ ਦੀ ਛਾਂ ਮਾਣਨ ਵਿਚ ਭੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਨਹੀਂ ।(ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਆਤਮਕ ਸੁਖ ਸਮਝਿਆ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੇ) ਝੂਠੇ ਲਾਲਚ ਵਿਚ (ਆਪਣਾ ਮਨੁੱਖਾ) ਜਨਮ ਗਵਾ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ ।ਮਨੁੱਖ ਹਾਥੀ ਘੋੜੇ ਵੇਖ ਕੇ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀ (ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ),ਫ਼ੌਜਾਂ ਇਕੱਠੀਆਂ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਮੰਤਰੀ ਤੇ ਸ਼ਾਹੀ ਨੌਕਰ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਗਲ ਵਿਚ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੀ ਰੱਸੀ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੇ ਫਾਹੇ ਹੀ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੨।(ਰਾਜਾ ਬਣ ਕੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਦਸੀਂ ਪਾਸੀਂ ਸਾਰੀ ਧਰਤੀ ਦਾ ਰਾਜ ਕਮਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਮੌਜਾਂ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀਆਂ ਭੋਗਦਾ ਹੈ (ਪਰ ਇਹ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਇਉਂ ਹੀ ਹੈ) ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕੋਈ ਰਾਜਾ ਮੰਗਤਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਦੁਖੀ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਆਤਮਕ ਸੁਖ ਦੇ ਥਾਂ ਰਾਜ ਵਿਚ ਤੇ ਭੋਗਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਭੀ ਦੁੱਖ ਹੀ ਦੁੱਖ ਹੈ) ।੩।ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਅਸਲ ਆਤਮਕ ਸੁਖ (ਦਾ ਮੂਲ) ਦੱਸਿਆ ਹੈ (ਉਹ ਹੈ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਰਾਜ਼ੀ ਰਹਿਣਾ) ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਭਗਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਉਹ ਮਿੱਠਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਆਤਮਕ ਸੁਖ ਮਾਣਦੇ ਹਨ) । ਹੇ ਦਾਸ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਹਉਮੈ ਮਾਰ ਕੇ (ਵਡ-ਭਾਗੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ) ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਵੀਰ ! ਇਸ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ (ਭਾਵ, ਰਜ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਰਾਜ਼ੀ ਰਹਿਣ ਨਾਲ) ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ (ਹੀ) ਅਸਲ ਮਿੱਤਰ ਹਰੀ-ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧। ਰਹਾਉ ਦੂਜਾ ।੧।\\""},{"question":"Iza no mpanjakan’i Madagasikara nahavita nampiray ny ampahany betsaka tamin’ny Nosy?","answer":"Radama I no  mpanjakan’i Madagasikara nahavita nampiray ny ampahany betsaka tamin’ny Nosy"},{"question":"வினா: இலக்கணக்குறிப்புத் தருக “இரவும் பகலும்” என்பது?","answer":"விடை:  “இரவும் பகலும்” என்பது 'எண்ணும்மை' ஆகும். எண்ணும்மை: 'உம்' எனும் சொல் வெளிப்படையாக வந்தால் அது எண்ணும்மை ஆகும்."},{"question":"Iza no anaran'ilay mpanakanto surrealista espaniola fantatra amin'ny sanganasa toy ny \\"The Persistence of Memory\\"?","answer":"Ilay mpanakanto surrealista Espaniola fantatra amin'ny asa toy ny \\"The Persistence of Memory\\" dia Salvador Dalí."},{"question":"问题：三星耳机的音频控制方式有哪些？","answer":"答案：三星耳机的音频控制方式可以通过线控按钮、触摸操作或配对的移动设备进行控制。"},{"question":"Ao amin'ny orinasam-pitaterana dia misy mpamily kamiao, mpanamory fiaramanidina ary mpamily fiaran-dalamby. Ny mpamily kamiao rehetra dia manana taratasy fahazoan-dàlana, manana fahazoan-dàlana koa ny mpanamory fiaramanidina rehetra, ary manaraka fiofanana manokana ny mpamily fiaran-dalamby rehetra.Inona no azontsika tsoahina avy amin’ireo fanambarana etsy ambony ireo?A. Ny mpamily fiaran-dalamby rehetra dia manana fahazoan-dàlana mpanamory.B. Tsy manaraka fiofanana manokana ny mpanamory fiaramanidina.D. Ny mpiasa rehetra manana taratasy fahazoan-dalana mamily dia mpamily kamiao.E. Ny mpamily fiaran-dalamby sasany dia manana fahazoan-dàlana mitondra fiara.","answer":"Ny valiny marina dia D. Ny mpiasa rehetra manana taratasy fahazoan-dàlana dia mpamily kamiao."},{"question":"ਰੋਡਾ ਜਲਾਲੀ : ਲੋਕ ਕਹਾਣੀ","answer":"'ਰੋਡਾ ਜਲਾਲੀ' ਦਿਲ ਹੂਲਵੀਂ ਪਾਕ ਮੁਹੱਬਤ ਦੀ ਲੋਕ ਗਾਥਾ ਹੈ। 17ਵੀਂ ਸਦੀ ਦੇ ਅੰਤ ਵਿਚ ਇਹ ਵਾਰਤਾ ਹੁਸ਼ਿਆਰਪੁਰ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹੇ ਦੇ ਪਿੰਡ ਲਾਲ ਸਿੰਙੀ ਵਿਖੇ ਵਾਪਰੀ। ਕਿਸ਼ੋਰ ਚੰਦ ਅਤੇ ਬੂਟਾ ਗੁਜਰਾਤੀ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੋ ਕਿੱਸੇ ਜੋੜੇ ਹਨ। ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿੱਸਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਰੋਡਾ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਦੀਆਂ ਸੁਆਣੀਆਂ ਲੋਕ ਗੀਤ ਵੀ ਗਾਉਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ।ਬਲਖ ਬੁਖ਼ਾਰੇ ਦਾ ਜੰਮਪਲ, ਆਪਣੀ ਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਦੇ ਵੈਰਾਗ ਵਿਚ ਫ਼ਕੀਰ ਬਣਿਆ ਰੋਡਾ ਪਾਕ ਪਟਣੋਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੁਸ਼ਿਆਰਪੁਰ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹੇ ਦੇ ਪਿੰਡ ਲਾਲ ਸਿੰਙੀ ਆਣ ਪੁੱਜਾ। ਪਿੰਡ ਤੋਂ ਅੱਧ ਕੁ ਮੀਲ ਦੀ ਦੂਰੀ 'ਤੇ ਪੂਰਬ ਵੱਲ ਦੇ ਪਾਸੇ ਸੁਹਾਂ ਨਦੀ ਦੇ ਕੰਢੇ ਸ਼ਾਨਦਾਰ ਬਾਗ਼ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਬਾਗ਼ ਵਿਚ ਇਸ ਫਕੀਰ ਨੇ ਜਾ ਡੇਰੇ ਲਾਏ।ਫਕੀਰ ਇੱਕੀ-ਬਾਈ ਵਰ੍ਹੇ ਦਾ ਸੁਨੱਖਾ ਜੁਆਨ ਸੀ। ਗੇਰੂਏ ਕੱਪੜੇ ਉਹਦੇ ਸਿਓ ਜਿਹੇ ਦਗ਼-ਦਗ਼ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਰੀਰ 'ਤੇ ਬਣ-ਬਣ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਸਨ। ਰੂਪ ਉਹਦਾ ਝੱਲਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਜਾਂਦਾ। ਇਕ ਅਨੋਖਾ ਜਲਾਲ ਉਹਦੇ ਮਸਤਕ 'ਤੇ ਟਪਕ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ, ਅੱਖੀਆਂ ਰੱਜ-ਰੱਜ ਜਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਸਨ।ਪਿੰਡ ਵਿਚ ਫਕੀਰ ਦੀ ਆਮਦ ਦੀ ਚਰਚਾ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋ ਗਈ। ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਨਵੇਂ ਸ਼ਰਧਾਲੂ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਗਏ। ਬੜੀਆਂ ਪਿਆਰੀਆਂ ਕਰਾਮਾਤੀ ਕਥਾਵਾਂ ਉਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਘੜੀਆਂ ਜਾਣ ਲੱਗੀਆਂ। ਕਿਸੇ ਦੀ ਮੱਝ ਗੁਆਚ ਗਈ, ਰੋਡੇ ਮੰਤਰ ਪੜ੍ਹਿਆ, ਮੱਝ ਆਪਣੇ-ਆਪ ਅਗਲੇ ਦੇ ਕੀਲੇ ਜਾ ਖੜ੍ਹੀ। ਕਿਸੇ ਦੀ ਗਊ ਨੇ ਦੁੱਧ ਨਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ, ਫ਼ਕੀਰ ਨੇ ਪੇੜਾ ਕੀਤਾ, ਗਊ ਧਾਰੀਂ ਪੈ ਗਈ। ਕਿਸੇ ਦਾ ਜੁਆਕ ਢਿੱਲਾ-ਮੱਠਾ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ, ਰੋਡੇ ਝਾੜਾ ਝਾੜਿਆ, ਮੁੰਡਾ ਨੌ-ਬਰ-ਨੌ। ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਰੋਡੇ ਫਕੀਰ ਦੀ ਮਹਿਮਾ ਘਰ-ਘਰ ਹੋਣ ਲੱਗ ਪਈ। ਪਿੰਡ ਦੇ ਲੋਕੀਂ ਅਪਾਰ ਸ਼ਰਧਾ ਨਾਲ ਰੋਡੇ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਜਣ ਲੱਗੇ। ਮਾਈਆਂ ਬਣ-ਸੰਵਰ ਕੇ ਸੰਤਾਂ ਦੇ ਦਰਸ਼ਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਂਦੀਆਂ। ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੀਆਂ ਮੁਰਾਦਾਂ ਲਈ ਰੋਡੇ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਅਸੀਸਾਂ ਮੰਗਦੀਆਂ। ਆਪਣੇ ਦੁੱਖ-ਸੁੱਖ ਫੋਲਦੀਆਂ। ਰੋਡਾ ਬੜੇ ਧਿਆਨ ਨਾਲ ਸੁਣਦਾ, ਸ਼ਹਿਦ ਜਿਹੇ ਮਿੱਠੇ ਬੋਲ ਬੋਲਦਾ। ਸਾਰਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਦਿਲ ਮੋਹੇ ਜਾਂਦਾ।ਇਸੇ ਪਿੰਡ ਦੇ ਲੁਹਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਧੀ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਦੀ ਬੜੀ ਚਰਚਾ ਸੀ। ਕੋਈ ਗੱਭਰੂ ਅਜੇ ਤੀਕ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਜਚਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ। ਕਿਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਨੱਕ ਥੱਲੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਲਿਆਉਂਦੀ। ਸਾਰੇ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਨੂੰ ਪਿੰਡ ਦਾ ਸ਼ਿੰਗਾਰ ਸੱਦਦੇ ਸਨ। ਪਹਾੜਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਰੀ ਨਾਲ ਤੁਲਨਾ ਦਿੰਦੇ ਸਨ,ਜਲਾਲੀਏ ਲੁਹਾਰੀਏ ਨੀਕੀ ਤੂੰ ਪਰੀ ਪਹਾੜ ਦੀਕੀ ਅਸਮਾਨੀ ਹੂਰ।ਸੁਹਣੀ ਦਿੱਸੇਂ ਫੁੱਲ ਵਾਂਗਤੈਥੋਂ ਮੈਲ਼ ਰਹੀ ਏ ਦੂਰ।ਤੈਨੂੰ ਵੇਖਣ ਆਉਂਦੇਹੋ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਚੂਰ।ਤਾਬ ਨਾ ਕੋਈ ਝੱਲਦਾਤੇਰਾ ਏਡਾ ਚਮਕੇ ਨੂਰ।ਘਰ ਲੁਹਾਰਾਂ ਜੰਮੀਓਂਜਿਵੇਂ ਕੱਲਰ ਉੱਗਾ ਰੁੱਖ।ਜੀਵਨ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਵੇਖ ਕੇਤੇ ਭੁੱਲਣ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੁੱਖ।ਫਟਕਣ ਪੰਛੀ ਵੇਖ ਕੇਤੇਰਾ ਸੁਹਣਾ ਮੁੱਖ।ਜੇ ਵੇਖੇ ਵਿਚ ਸੁਹਾਂ ਦੇਤੇਰੀ ਵੀ ਲਹਿਜੇ ਭੁੱਖ।ਜਲਾਲੀ ਨੇ ਵੀ ਰੋਡੇ ਫਕੀਰ ਦੀ ਮਹਿਮਾ ਸੁਣੀ। ਇਕ ਦਿਨ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਸਹੇਲੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਬਾਗ ਵਿਚ ਜਾ ਪੁੱਜੀ। ਰੋਡਾ ਸਮਾਧੀ ਲਾਈ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ। ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਨਮਸਕਾਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਬੈਠ ਗਈਆਂ। ਰੋਡੇ ਅੱਖ ਨਾ ਝਮਕੀ। ਬਸ ਮਸਤ ਰਿਹਾ।ਜਲਾਲੀ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰੇਂਦੇ ਰੋਡੇ ਵੱਲ ਤੱਕਦੀ ਰਹੀ, ਮੁਸਕਾਨਾਂ ਬਖੇਰਦੀ ਰਹੀ। ਕੋਈ ਰਾਂਗਲਾ ਸੁਪਨਾ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਸਾਕਾਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਜਾਪਿਆ। ਹੁਸਨ ਦਾ ਬੁੱਤ ਬਣਿਆ ਰੋਡਾ, ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦੇ ਧੁਰ ਅੰਦਰ ਦਿਲ ਵਿਚ ਲਹਿ ਗਿਆ। ਜਲਾਲੀ ਆਪਣੇ-ਆਪ ਮੁਸਕਰਾਈ। ਉਹ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਜਾਣ ਲਈ ਖੜੋ ਗਈਆਂ। ਰੋਡੇ ਅੱਖ ਖੋਲ੍ਹੀ। ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਹੱਥ ਜੋੜੀ ਖੜ੍ਹੀ ਸੀ।ਗੁਲਾਬ ਦੇ ਫੁੱਲ ਵਾਂਗ ਖਿੜਿਆ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਮੁਖੜਾ ਰੋਡੇ ਦੀ ਬਿਰਤੀ ਉਖੇੜ ਗਿਆ। ਰੋਡਾ ਸੁਆਦ-ਸੁਆਦ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ। ਸਾਰੀ ਰਾਤ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਰੋਡੇ ਵਿਚ ਖੋਈ ਰਹੀ। ਸਵੇਰ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਸਾਰ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਬਾਗ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਰੋਡੇ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਜਦਾ ਕੀਤਾ। ਹੁਸਨ ਇਸ਼ਕ ਦੇ ਗਲ਼ ਬਾਹੀਂ ਪਾ ਲਈਆਂ।“ਰੋਡਿਆ! ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰੇ ‘ਤੇ ਕੀ ਜਾਦੂ ਧੂੜ ਦਿੱਤੈ... ਮੈਂ ਸਾਰੀ ਰਾਤ ਪਲ ਲਈ ਵੀ ਸੌਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕੀ। ਤੇਰੇ ਖਿਆਲਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਮਗਨ ਰਹੀ ਆਂ।” ਹੁਸਨ ਮਚਲਿਆ।“ਹੁਸਨ ਪਰੀਏ! ਧੰਨੇ ਨੇ ਪੱਥਰ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਰੱਬ ਪਾ ਲਿਆ ਏ। ਅੱਜ ਮੇਰੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਏ। ਤੇਰੇ ‘ਚ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਦਾਤਾਰ ਨਜ਼ਰੀਂ ਪਿਆ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਏ। ਜਦੋਂ ਦੀ ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰੇ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਗਈ ਏਂ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਚੈਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਇਆ। ਹੁਣ ਤੂੰ ਆ ਗਈ ਏਂ, ਜਾਣੀਂ ਸੱਤੇ ਬਹਿਸ਼ਤਾਂ ਮੇਰੀ ਝੋਲੀ ਵਿਚ ਨੇ।” ਰੋਡਾ ਹੁਸੀਨ ਤੋਂ ਹੁਸੀਨ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ।“ਰੋਡਿਆ ਅੱਜ ਅਸੀਂ ਦਿਲਾਂ ਦੇ ਸੌਦੇ ਕਰ ਲਏ ਨੇ। ਤੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਉਤਰੀਂ। ਕਿਧਰੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਕੱਚ ਜਿਹਾ ਦਿਲ ਤੋੜ ਕੇ ਅਗਾਂਹ ਨਾ ਟੁਰ ਜਾਵੀਂ।”“ਜਲਾਲੀਏ... ਇਹ ਕੀ ਆਂਹਦੀ ਏਂ ਤੂੰ। ਮੈਂ ਏਥੋਂ ਟੁਰ ਜਾਵਾਂਗਾ! ਇਕੋ ਇਕ ਦਿਲ ਸੀ ਮੇਰਾ, ਉਹ ਤੂੰ ਖੱਸ ਲਿਆ ਏ। ਹੋਰ ਕੀ ਏ ਇਸ ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ? ਬਸ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਏਂ, ਭਲਾ ਮੈਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਛੱਡ ਸਕਦਾ ਹਾਂ। ਤੂੰ ਤੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਏਂ, ਮੇਰਾ ਇਸ਼ਟ ਏਂ। ਡਰ ਹੈ ਜਲਾਲੀਏ... ਕਿਧਰੇ ਤੂੰ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਬਦਨਾਮੀ ਤੋਂ ਡਰਦੀ ਆਪਣਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੈਥੋਂ ਨਾ ਮੋੜ ਲਵੀਂ।”“ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਜਵਾਨੀ ਦੀ ਸਹੁੰ ਰੋਡਿਆ। ਮੈਂ ਲੱਗੀਆਂ ਤੋੜ ਨਿਭਾਵਾਂਗੀ। ਮਰ ਜਾਵਾਂਗੀ ਪਰ ਪਿਛਾਂਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਰਤਾਂਗੀ। ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰਾ ਹਰ ਰੋਜ਼ ਤੜਕਸਾਰ ਸੁਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੰਢੇ ਇੰਤਜ਼ਾਰ ਕਰਿਆ ਕਰੀਂ। ਅਹੁ ਕੋਈ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਪਿਆ ਏ, ਆਹ ਸਾਂਭ ਲੈ ਮੇਰੀ ਨਿਸ਼ਾਨੀ...।” ... ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦਾ ਛੱਲਾ ਰੋਡੇ ਦੀ ਉਂਗਲ 'ਤੇ ਸੀ।ਜਲਾਲੀ ਹਰ ਰੋਜ਼ ਸੁਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੰਢੇ ਜਾ ਪੁੱਜਦੀ, ਤੇ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਰੋਡੇ ਦਾ ਜਾ ਦੀਦਾਰ ਕਰਦੀ,ਉਤੇ ਨਦੀ ਦੇ ਜਾਇਕੇ ਰੋਜ਼ ਮਿਲਦੀਬਿਨਾਂ ਮਿਲੇ ਦੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਅਧਾਰ ਹੈ ਜੀ।ਹੋਏ ਘੜੀ ਵਿਛੋੜੇ ਦੇ ਵਾਂਗ ਸੂਲੀਜਾਨ ਹੋਂਵਦੀ ਜੋ ਆਵਾਜ਼ਾਰ ਹੈ ਜੀ।ਬਿਨਾਂ ਲੱਗੀਆਂ ਕੋਈ ਨਾ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈਜੀਹਨੂੰ ਲੱਗੀਆਂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਰ ਹੈ ਜੀ।ਹੋਈ ਭੁੱਜ ਮਨੂਰ ਲੁਹਾਰ ਬੱਚੀਬਣੇ ਘੜੀ ਦਾ ਜੁੱਗ ਚਾਰ ਹੈ ਜੀ।ਹੁੰਦੇ ਨਾਗ਼ ਮਲੂਮ ਨੇ ਪੂਣੀਆਂ ਦੇਜਦੋਂ ਕੱਤਣ ਜਾਏ ਭੰਡਾਰ ਹੈ ਜੀ।ਪਾਇਆ ਭੱਠ ਕਸੀਦੇ ਦੇ ਕੱਢਣੇ ਨੂੰਪੈਂਦੀ ਭੁੱਲ ਕੇ ਨਾ ਇਕ ਤਾਰ ਹੈ ਜੀ।ਮਿਲੇ ਜਦੋਂ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਜਾ ਯਾਰ ਤਾਈਂਓਦੋਂ ਵਸਦਾ ਦਿਸੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਹੈ ਜੀ।ਕਿਸੇ ਕੰਮ ਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਨਾ ਚਿੱਤ ਲੱਗੇਕਰੇ ਆਸ਼ਕੀ ਅਤੀ ਲਾਚਾਰ ਹੈ ਜੀ।(ਕਿਸ਼ੋਰ ਚੰਦ)ਇਸ਼ਕ ਮੁਸ਼ਕ ਕਦੋਂ ਛੁਪਾਇਆਂ ਛੁਪਦੇ ਨੇ। ਜਲਾਲੀ ਅਤੇ ਰੋਡੇ ਦੇ ਇਸ਼ਕ ਦੀ ਚਰਚਾ ਪਿੰਡ ਵਿਚ ਛਿੜ ਪਈ। ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦੇ ਮਾਪਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਕੰਨੀਂ ਵੀ ਉਡਦੀ-ਉਡਦੀ ਭਿਣਕ ਪੈ ਗਈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਇਸ਼ਕ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਵਾਨ ਨਾ ਕੀਤਾ। ਉਹ ਤਾਂ ਨਮੋਸ਼ੀ ਦੇ ਮਾਰੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਮੂੰਹ ਲਕੋਈ ਫਿਰਦੇ ਸਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਨੂੰ ਲੱਖ ਸਮਝਾਇਆ ਪਰ ਉਹ ਪਿਛਾਂਹ ਮੁੜਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਕਿੱਥੇ ਸੀ। ਉਹਦੇ ਲਈ ਤਾਂ ਰੋਡਾ ਹੀ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਸੀ। ਆਖ਼ਰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਨੂੰ ਡਰਾਇਆ, ਧਮਕਾਇਆ ਅਤੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਨਿਗਰਾਨੀ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਖਣਾ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦਾ ਘਰੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਨਿਕਲਣਾ ਬੰਦ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ... ਓਧਰ ਰੋਡਾ ਵੀ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ਮੁਖੜਾ ਤੱਕਣ ਲਈ ਬੇਕਰਾਰ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ। ਆਖ਼ਰ ਉਹਨੇ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਅੱਗੇ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਅਲਖ ਜਗਾਉਣੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ। ਉਹ ਉਹਦੇ ਹੱਥੋਂ ਖੈਰਾਤ ਲਏ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਅਗਾਂਹ ਇਕ ਕਦਮ ਵੀ ਨਾ ਪੁੱਟਦਾ। ਗੱਲ ਏਥੋਂ ਤੱਕ ਅੱਪੜ ਗਈ ਕਿ ਇਕ ਦਿਨ ਉਹਨੇ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਹੱਥੋਂ ਖੈਰਾਤ ਲੈਣ ਤੋਂ ਇਨਕਾਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਪਰ ਉਹਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਅੜੀ ਰਹੀ... ਸਾਧਾਂ ਦਾ ਹਠ ਵੀ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਐ... ਰੋਡਾ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਦਰਾਂ ਅੱਗੇ ਹੀ ਧੂਣਾ ਤਪਾ ਕੇ ਬੈਠ ਗਿਆ, ਤੇ ਸਮਾਧੀ ਲਾ ਲਈ। ਲੋਕਾਂ ਲਈ ਤਾਂ ਇਹ ਜਗਤ ਤਮਾਸ਼ਾ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਤਾਂ ਨਮੋਸ਼ੀ ਦੀ ਮਾਰੀ ਧਰਤੀ ਵਿਚ ਨਿਘਰਦੀ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਸੀ। ਉਹਨੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਧੂਣਾ ਚੁੱਕਣ ਲਈ ਬਹੁਤੇਰੇ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਪਾਏ। ਜਲਾਲੀ ਨੇ ਵੀ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਬੜਾ ਆਖਿਆ ਪਰ ਰੋਡਾ ਤਾਂ ਉਹਦੇ ਦੀਦਾਰ ਲਈ ਤੜਫ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ,ਕਿੱਥੋਂ ਵੇ ਤੇ ਤੂੰ ਆਇਆਜਾਣਾ ਕਿਹੜੇ ਦੇਸ ਵੇ ਫ਼ਕੀਰਾਭਲਾ ਵੇ ਦਲਾਲਿਆ ਵੇ ਰੋਡਿਆ।ਪੱਛਮ ਤੋਂ ਨੀ ਮੈਂ ਆਇਆਜਾਣਾ ਦੱਖਣ ਦੇਸ ਨੀ ਲੁਹਾਰੀਏਭਲਾ ਸਾਲੂ ਵਾਲੀਏ ਨੀ ਗੋਰੀਏ।ਜੇ ਤੂੰ ਭੁੱਖਾ ਰੋਟੀ ਦਾ ਵੇਲੱਡੂਆ ਦਿੰਨੀ ਆਂ ਮੰਗਾਵੇ ਫ਼ਕੀਰਾ...।ਭਲਾ ਵੇ ਦਲਾਲਿਆ ਵੇ ਰੋਡਿਆ।ਨਾ ਮੈਂ ਭੁੱਖਾ ਰੋਟੀ ਦਾ ਨੀਲੈਣਾ ਤੇਰਾ ਦੀਦਾਰ ਨੀ ਲੁਹਾਰੀਏਭਲਾ ਸਾਲੂ ਵਾਲੀਏ ਨੀ ਗੋਰੀਏ।ਜੇ ਤੂੰ ਪਿਆਸਾ ਪਾਣੀ ਦਾ ਵੇਦੁਧੂਆ ਦਿੰਨੀ ਆਂ ਮੰਗਾ ਵੇ ਫਕੀਰਾਭਲਾ ਵੇ ਦਲਾਲਿਆ ਵੇ ਰੋਡਿਆ।ਨਾ ਮੈਂ ਪਿਆਸਾ ਪਾਣੀ ਦਾ ਨੀਲੈਣਾ ਤੇਰਾ ਦੀਦਾਰ ਨੀ ਲੁਹਾਰੀਏਭਲਾ ਸਾਲੂ ਵਾਲੀਏ ਨੀ ਗੋਰੀਏ।ਜੇ ਤੂੰ ਨੰਗਾ ਬਸਤਰ ਦਾ ਵੇਬਸਤਰ ਦਿੰਨੀ ਆਂ ਸਮਾਵੇ ਫਕੀਰਾਭਲਾ ਵੇ ਦਲਾਲਿਆ ਵੇ ਰੋਡਿਆ।ਨਾ ਮੈਂ ਨੰਗਾ ਬਸਤਰ ਦਾ ਨੀਲੈਣਾ ਤੇਰਾ ਦੀਦਾਰ ਨੀ ਲੁਹਾਰੀਏਭਲਾ ਸਾਲੂ ਵਾਲੀਏ ਨੀ ਗੋਰੀਏ।ਜੇ ਤੂੰ ਭੁੱਖਾ ਰੰਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਵੇਵਿਆਹ ਦਿੰਨੀ ਆਂ ਕਰਵਾਵੇ ਫਕੀਰਾਭਲਾ ਵੇ ਦਲਾਲਿਆ ਵੇ ਰੋਡਿਆ।ਨਾ ਮੈਂ ਭੁੱਖਾ ਰੰਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਨੀਲੈਣਾ ਤੇਰਾ ਦੀਦਾਰ ਨੀ ਲੁਹਾਰੀਏਭਲਾ ਸਾਲੂ ਵਾਲੀਏ ਨੀ ਗੋਰੀਏ।ਦਰ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਧੂਣਾ ਚੁੱਕ ਲੈ ਵੇਬਾਹਰੋਂ ਆਜੂ ਮੇਰਾ ਬਾਪਵੇ ਫਕੀਰਾਭਲਾ ਵੇ ਦਲਾਲਿਆ ਵੇ ਰੋਡਿਆ।ਦਰ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਧੂਣਾ ਨਾ ਚੁੱਕਣਾ ਨੀਲੈਣਾ ਤੇਰਾ ਦੀਦਾਰ ਨੀ ਲੁਹਾਰੀਏਭਲਾ ਸਾਲੂ ਵਾਲੀਏ ਨੀ ਗੋਰੀਏ।ਰੋਡੇ ਨੇ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦੇ ਦਰਾਂ ਅੱਗਿਉਂ ਧੂਣਾ ਨਾ ਚੁੱਕਿਆ। ਗੁੱਸੇ ਵਿਚ ਆਏ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦੇ ਭਰਾਵਾਂ ਨੇ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਮਾਰ ਮਾਰ ਕੇ ਅਧਮੋਇਆ ਕਰ ਸੁੱਟਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਰਾਤ ਸਮੇਂ ਸੁਹਾਂ ਨਦੀ ਵਿਚ ਹੜ੍ਹਾ ਆਏ। ਕੁਦਰਤ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਪਾਰਾਵਾਰ ਨਹੀਂ, ਰੋਡਾ ਨਦੀ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਬਚ ਨਿਕਲਿਆ ਤੇ ਅਗਲੀ ਭਲਕ ਆ ਕੇ ਉਹਨੇ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦੇ ਦਰਾਂ ਅੱਗੇ ਮੁੜ ਧੂਣਾ ਤਪਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਜਲਾਲੀ ਅੰਦਰ ਨਰੜੀ ਪਈ ਤੜਪਦੀ ਰਹੀ। ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਨੇ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦੇ ਭਰਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਰੋਡੇ ਦੇ ਦੁਬਾਰਾ ਮੁੜ ਆਣ 'ਤੇ ਐਨਾ ਗੁੱਸਾ ਚੜ੍ਹਿਆ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਉਹਦੇ ਟੁਕੜੇ-ਟੁਕੜੇ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਖੂਹ ਵਿਚ ਸੁੱਟ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਮਾਰ ਮੁਕਾਇਆ।ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਕਥਾ ਦਾ ਅੰਤ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਵੀ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਨੇ ਰੋਡੇ ਨੂੰ ਗਲੋਂ ਲਾਹੁਣ ਲਈ ਧੂਣਾ ਤਾਪਦੇ ਰੋਡੇ ਕੋਲ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਆਖਿਆ, “ਰੋਡਿਆ ਤੇਰੀ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਕਈ ਦਿਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਅੰਦਰ ਬਿਮਾਰ ਪਈ ਹੈ, ਹਕੀਮ ਆਂਹਦੇ ਨੇ ਉਹ ਤਦ ਹੀ ਬਚ ਸਕਦੀ ਐ ਜੇ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਕਿਧਰੋਂ ਸ਼ੇਰਨੀ ਦਾ ਦੁੱਧ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਵੇ। ਜੇ ਤੂੰ ਸ਼ੇਰਨੀ ਦਾ ਦੁੱਧ ਲਿਆ ਦੇਵੇਂ ਤਾਂ ਅਸੀਂ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦਾ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰ ਦੇਵਾਂਗੇ।”ਇਹ ਸੁਣਦੇ ਸਾਰ ਹੀ ਰੋਡਾ ਸ਼ੇਰਨੀ ਦੇ ਦੁੱਧ ਦੀ ਭਾਲ ਵਿਚ ਜੰਗਲਾਂ ਵਲ ਨੱਸ ਟੁਰਿਆ।ਜਦੋਂ ਜਲਾਲੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਰੋਡੇ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ੇਰਾਂ ਕੋਲੋਂ ਮਰਵਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਵਿਉਂਤ ਸੁਣੀ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਵੀ ਰੋਡਾ ਰੋਡਾ ਕੂਕਦੀ ਰੋਡੇ ਦੇ ਮਗਰ ਜੰਗਲ ਵਿਚ ਜਾ ਪੁੱਜੀ। ਜੰਗਲ ਵਿਚ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਮਿਲ ਪਏ, ਜਾਂ ਦੋਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਜੰਗਲੀ ਜਾਨਵਰਾਂ ਨੇ ਮਾਰ ਮੁਕਾਇਆ, ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੋਈ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਪਰ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਗਾਥਾ ਨੂੰ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਲੋਕ ਮਨ ਨੇ ਅਜੇ ਤੀਕਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਵਿਸਾਰਿਆ। ਜਲਾਲੀ ਦਾ ਗੀਤ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਚੇਤਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਅੱਜ ਵੀ ਸੱਜਰਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"வினா: ”செந்தமிழ் நாடெனும் போதினிலே”-பாடலின் ஆசிரியர்?","answer":"விடை: பாரதியார்"},{"question":"Kíni colour purple ní èdè Yorùbá? ","answer":"Àwọ̀ Àlùkò"},{"question":"问：关羽在历史上是什么身份？","answer":"答：关羽是中国历史上著名的军事将领，是东汉末年刘备的重要将领，被封为蜀汉的五虎上将之一。"},{"question":"Sheeg magaca saddexan ee halgame Xalane, meesha uu ku geeriyooday iyo            sanadkii  uu geeriyooday? ","answer":" Waxay mamnuucday sanadkii 1983kii.Sheeg xubnihii saraakiisha ee dhaliyey Kacaankii Hanti Wadaagga ee Soomaaliya? "},{"question":"په طبیعت کې د هر عمل (قوت) لپاره یو مساوي او مخالف عکس العمل شتون لري، دا د نیوټن کوم قانون دی؟ 1. لومړی قانون 2. دویم قانون 3. دریم قانون","answer":"3. دریم قانون"},{"question":"Apakah nama bangunan tertinggi di dunia?","answer":"Burj Khalifa"},{"question":"Siapakah Sheila Majid? Jelaskan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 290 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Dato' Sheila Majid (lahir Shaheila Abdul Majid; 3 Januari 1965) ialah seorang penyanyi wanita Malaysia. Dilahirkan di Kuala Lumpur, bakatnya dikesan oleh penerbit muzik yang tertarik dengan suaranya, lantas mempelawa beliau menghadiri ujibakat, kemudian menerima kontrak rakaman pada 1982. Sheila menandatangani kontrak bersama Titra Industries dan muncul bersama album pertama, Dimensi Baru pada 1985 dengan lagu \\"Pengemis Muda\\" dikeluarkan sebagai single pertama.Selepas menandatangani kontrak rakaman bersama EMI Music Malaysia, beliau muncul dengan album kedua, Emosi (1986) yang mana ia berjaya menembusi pasaran muzik Indonesia. Lagu-lagu seperti \\"Sinaran\\" dan \\"Antara Anyer dan Jakarta\\" dikeluarkan sebagai single utama dan berjaya menjulang nama Sheila sekaligus menjadi antara singlenya paling berjaya pada 1980-an serta melayakkan beliau memenangi Anugerah BASF sebagai Artis R&B Wanita Terbaik pada 1987. Sheila kemudian menyertai Roslan Aziz Productions (RAP) sebagai salah seorang artis rakamannya dan pada 1992, beliau bersama teman-teman seperjuangan Zainal Abidin, Afdlin Shauki, Zubir Ali, Azman Warren dan Amir Yussof membuat persembahan di konsert paling berjaya, Konsert Ikhlas 1992 di bawah pimpinan penerbit rakaman, Roslan Aziz.Antara pencapaian peribadi dalam kerjaya beliau ialah menjadi artis Malaysia pertama yang berjaya di Jepun, dan mengadakan konsert yang habis dijual di Royal Theater di West End London pada 1996. Beliau juga menjadi penyanyi Malaysia pertama yang merakamkan sebuah kaset single, serta merupakan artis tempatan pertama yang membuat persembahan di Dewan Filharmonik Petronas (DFP). Sheila turut berjinak-jinak dalam bidang lakonan dengan membintangi filem-filem seperti Ali Setan (1985) dan Sinaran (2015). Dikenali oleh media sebagai Ratu Jazz Malaysia, Sheila telah memukau jutaan peminat di rantau Asia dengan \\"suaranya yang lunak dan memiliki repertoir irama pop, jaz dan R&B kontemporari yang lebih besar\\".Selain itu, beliau juga ialah antara artis yang menerima bayaran tertinggi dan termahal bagi suatu undangan nyanyian."},{"question":"రెండవ మెదడుగా దేనిని పరిగణిస్తున్నారు?","answer":"ఆహారవాహిక నుండి పాయువు వరకు 9 మీటర్ల పొడవునా, జీర్ణవ్యవస్థకు అనుబంధంగా నాడీవ్యవస్థ వ్యాపించి ఉంది. దీనిని రెండవ మెదడుగా పరిగణిస్తున్నారు."},{"question":"fenoy ny banga : \\" Aleo misoroka _ \\"","answer":"Toy izao ny tohin'ny fanambarana: \\" toa izay mitsabo \\""},{"question":"Inona no zavamaneno tranainy indrindra eran-tany?","answer":"Ny zavamaneno tranainy indrindra fantatra dia ny sodina, vita tamin’ny taolan’ny vorona ary efa 35 000 taona lasa izay. Tany Alemaina no nahitana azy io."},{"question":"सोशल मीडिया के प्रभाव के बारे में व्यक्तिगत संवाद और मानसिक स्वास्थ्य पर चर्चा करें।","answer":"सोशल मीडिया के प्रभाव के बारे में व्यक्तिगत संवाद और मानसिक स्वास्थ्य पर चर्चा करते समय हमें यह समझने में मदद मिलती है कि आजकल की तेजी से बदलती दुनिया में सोशल मीडिया की क्या भूमिका है और इसके प्रभाव कैसे हमारे मानसिक स्वास्थ्य पर पड़ते हैं।सोशल मीडिया के माध्यम से हम दुनियाभर में अपने विचारों, खुशियों और खो दिए गए समय की जानकारी को साझा करते हैं। यह हमें अपने परिवार और दोस्तों से जुड़े रहने का एक आसान तरीका प्रदान करता है, लेकिन इसके साथ ही हम अनजाने लोगों से भी जुड़ते हैं जो हमारे असली दोस्त नहीं होते। यह जानकारी और संवाद की अधिकता की ओर ले जाता है, जिसके परिणामस्वरूप हम अपने मानसिक स्वास्थ्य को खतरे में डाल सकते हैं।आजकल की भागदौड़ भरी जिंदगी में लोग सोशल मीडिया पर अपने जीवन के सभी पहलुओं को प्रदर्शित करने का प्रयास करते हैं, जिससे उन्हें अपने आपसी मानसिक तुलनात्मकता और आत्म-मूल्य की समस्याएं हो सकती हैं। दूसरी ओर, जब हम सोशल मीडिया पर अपने साथीयों की तुलना में या नकारात्मक टिप्पणियों के शिकार होते हैं, तो यह हमारे स्वान्त्र्य और मानसिक स्वास्थ्य को प्रभावित कर सकता है।इसके अलावा, बच्चों और युवाओं के लिए सोशल मीडिया के प्रभाव केवल नकारात्मक नहीं होते, बल्कि इससे उनकी ताक़तें बढ़ सकती हैं और वे अपने रूचिकर्मों और रूचियों के बारे में और भी अधिक जान सकते हैं।"},{"question":"Chọn đáp án đúng:Nguyên nhân nào khiến Quixada quyết tâm trở thành hiệp sĩ và đổi tên thành Don Quixote ?a. Do ước mơ từ bé của ông ta trở thành hiệp sĩ, cứu giúp kẻ yếub. Do bị mê hoặc bởi các câu chuyện hoang đường về hiệp sĩ","answer":"Đáp án: b. Do bị mê hoặc bởi các câu chuyện hoang đường về hiệp sĩTiểu thuyết kể về Quixada - một nhà quý tộc nghèo khoảng 50 tuổi sống ở miền Aragon và Castile, lấy bối cảnh thế kỷ 15 tại Tây Ban Nha. Hồi đó, những câu chuyện hoang đường, phi lý về các hiệp sĩ rất thịnh hành.Quixada say mê những truyện này đến độ cuồng si, bao nhiêu tiền bỏ ra mua truyện hết. Đầu óc ông lúc nào cũng đầy những ý tưởng về sự mê hoặc, đánh nhau, thách đấu, thương vong, oán trách, tình tứ, dằn vặt, người khổng lồ, lâu đài tráng lệ, những thiếu nữ bị bắt cóc và các cuộc giải cứu người đẹp.Mọi sự tầm thường trong con mắt và suy nghĩ của ông lại trở nên hoành tráng, mỗi chủ quán là một vị đại thần, mỗi người cưỡi la là một chàng hiệp sĩ, quán trọ là lâu đài tráng lệ.Vì danh dự bản thân và vì nhiệm vụ đối với quần chúng, Quixada quyết định trở thành hiệp sĩ lang thang, chu du khắp bốn phương trời để cứu khốn phò nguy, diệt trừ yêu quái, thiết lập trật tự và công lý.Ông thử thách mình bằng các hiểm nguy như trong các truyện kiếm hiệp, đổi tên mình là Don Quixote de la Mancha (nhà hiệp sĩ Don Quixote xứ Mancha). Ông nhờ một chủ quán, vốn xuất thân từ tầng lớp hạ lưu phong cho mình là hiệp sĩ."},{"question":"「当て布」という意味がある、既に出来上がっているプログラムに修正を加えることを何というでしょう？","answer":"パッチ"},{"question":"Kedụ ìhè bụ ọrịa Obi?","answer":"Ọrịa obi nke kacha emetụta ụmụnwoke bụ nke a kpọrọ 'coronary heart disease' na Bekee.Ihe na-akpata ya bụ mgbe ọbara anaghị erucha n'obi mmadụ otu o kwesịrị.Ọtụtụ ihe na-akpata mkpọnwụ ahụ (stroke) bụkwa ha na-akpata ọrịa obi.Nnyocha gosiri na ọrịa obi na-aka ejitu ụmụnwoke karịa ndị nwaanyị.Ụzọ kacha mfe e si agwọta ọrịa obi bụ ma a chọpụta ya n'oge.Ya kpatara ime nnyocha kwa mgbe kwa mgbe ji dị ezigbo mkpa."},{"question":"Bedelsiz sermaye artırımı olunca ne olur?","answer":"Hissedarlar, önceden sahip oldukları hisselerin yanında bedelsiz olarak verilen yeni hisse senetleri sayesinde şirketin ödenmiş sermayesindeki artışa da katkıda bulunurlar. Bedelsiz sermaye artırımı, şirketin piyasa değerini değiştirmez. Ancak hisse senetlerinin piyasadaki dağılımını değiştirebilir."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਦੂਜੈ ਭਾਇ ਲਗੇ ਦੁਖੁ ਪਾਇਆ ॥ਬਿਨੁ ਸਬਦੈ ਬਿਰਥਾ ਜਨਮੁ ਗਵਾਇਆ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵੈ ਸੋਝੀ ਹੋਇ ॥ਦੂਜੈ ਭਾਇ ਨ ਲਾਗੈ ਕੋਇ ॥੧॥ਮੂਲਿ ਲਾਗੇ ਸੇ ਜਨ ਪਰਵਾਣੁ ॥ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਰਾਮ ਨਾਮੁ ਜਪਿ ਹਿਰਦੈ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦੀ ਹਰਿ ਏਕੋ ਜਾਣੁ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਡਾਲੀ ਲਾਗੈ ਨਿਹਫਲੁ ਜਾਇ ॥ਅੰਧਂੀ ਕੰਮੀ ਅੰਧ ਸਜਾਇ ॥ਮਨਮੁਖੁ ਅੰਧਾ ਠਉਰ ਨ ਪਾਇ ॥ਬਿਸਟਾ ਕਾ ਕੀੜਾ ਬਿਸਟਾ ਮਾਹਿ ਪਚਾਇ ॥੨॥ਗੁਰ ਕੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਸਦਾ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਏ ॥ਸੰਤਸੰਗਤਿ ਮਿਲਿ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਏ ॥ਨਾਮੇ ਨਾਮਿ ਕਰੇ ਵੀਚਾਰੁ ॥ਆਪਿ ਤਰੈ ਕੁਲ ਉਧਰਣਹਾਰੁ ॥੩॥ਗੁਰ ਕੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਨਾਮਿ ਵਜਾਏ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਮਹਲੁ ਸਬਦਿ ਘਰੁ ਪਾਏ ॥ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਸਤ ਸਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਜਲਿ ਨਾਇਆ ॥ਦੁਰਮਤਿ ਮੈਲੁ ਸਭੁ ਦੁਰਤੁ ਗਵਾਇਆ ॥੪॥੫॥੪੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 362 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ) ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ ਮੱਤੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਦੁੱਖ ਹੀ ਦੁੱਖ ਸਹੇੜਿਆ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਤੋਂ ਵਾਂਜੇ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਗਵਾ ਲਈ । ਜੇਹੜਾ ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਦੱਸੇ ਰਾਹ ਉਤੇ ਤੁਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ (ਸਹੀ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੀ) ਸਮਝ ਆ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਫਿਰ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਗਦਾ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਜਗਤ ਦੇ ਰਚਨਹਾਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੀ ਯਾਦ) ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀਆਂ ਨਜ਼ਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਕਬੂਲ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਜਪ ਕੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਇਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜਗਤ ਦੇ ਮੂਲ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਰੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਰਚੀ ਮਾਇਆ-ਰੂਪ) ਟਹਣੀ ਨੂੰ ਚੰਬੜਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਅੱਫਲ ਹੀ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜੀਵਨ-ਫਲ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ),ਬੇ-ਸਮਝੀ ਦੇ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਪੈ ਕੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ)(ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ) ਅੰਨ੍ਹਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਣ ਦਾ) ਟਿਕਾਣਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭ ਸਕਦਾ(ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਇਉਂ ਹੀ) ਖ਼ੁਆਰ ਹੰੁਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜਿਵੇਂ) ਗੰਦ ਦਾ ਕੀੜਾ ਗੰਦ ਵਿਚ ।੨।ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਦੱਸੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ) । ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੀ) ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ) ਉਹ ਆਪ (ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ) ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਕੁਲਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘਾਣ ਜੋਗਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ (ਦਾ ਵਾਜਾ) ਵਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਦਾ ਪੂਰਨ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਪਾਈ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ), ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਘਰ ਮਹਲ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਸਤਸੰਗ-ਸਰੋਵਰ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ-ਜਲ ਨਾਲ ਇਸ਼ਨਾਨ ਕੀਤਾਉਸ ਨੇ ਭੈੜੀ ਖੋਟੀ ਮਤਿ ਦੀ ਮੈਲ ਧੋ ਲਈ ਉਸ ਨੇ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਸਾਰਾ ਪਾਪ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ।੪।੫।੪੪।\\""},{"question":"இந்தியாவின் மிக உயரமான கோவில் கோபுரம் எது?","answer":"இந்தியாவின் மிக உயரமான கோபுரம் ஸ்ரீரங்கத்தில் (திருச்சி, தமிழ்நாடு) உள்ள ஸ்ரீ ரங்கநாதஸ்வாமி கோயிலின் கோபுரம் ஆகும். இந்த ஆலயத்தில் மொத்தம் 21 கோபுரங்கள் இருக்கின்றன. மேலும் இக்கோவிலின் ராஜகோபுரம் 239.501 அடி உயரத்தில் ஆசியாவிலேயே மிக உயரமான கோபுரமாக அழைக்கப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"அதிக பத்திரிக்கைகள் வெளிவரும் மாநிலம் எது?","answer":"விடை: உத்திரபிரதேசம்"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Đồng hồ nghi của Hitler bán đấu giá 1,1 triệu USD","answer":"Vụ đấu giá chiếc đồng hồ Huber được báo cáo đã hoàn thành hôm 26/7 tại nhà đấu giá Alexander Historical Auctions ở thành phố Chesapeake, bang Maryland, Mỹ. Đơn vị tổ chức đấu giá cho biết chiếc đồng hồ có thể đã được tặng cho trùm phát xít Đức Adolf Hitler vào sinh nhật của ông ta năm 1933, sau đó bị một binh sĩ Pháp thu giữ vào năm 1945 từ nhà nghỉ dưỡng của Hitler trên dãy Alps. Alexander Historical Auctions lưu ý tính xác thực về nguồn gốc hiện vật đấu giá chỉ đến từ đánh giá của các chuyên gia đồng hồ và nhà sử học. Chiếc đồng hồ được bán đấu giá là một phần trong danh mục gồm một chiếc váy màu xanh lam của vợ Hitler, Eva Braun, hình ảnh và thư từ có chữ ký của các quan chức Đức Quốc xã cùng các vật phẩm khác thuộc về Hitler. Các cuộc đấu giá này đã bị chỉ trích trong một bức thư ngỏ có chữ ký của 34 lãnh đạo Do Thái, cáo buộc nhà đấu giá thực hiện những giao dịch \\"ghê tởm\\", lợi dụng \\"ký ức, nỗi đau khổ và vết thương\\" của người khác để thu lợi. Trong một cuộc phỏng vấn qua điện thoại, Chủ tịch Alexander Historical Auctions Bill Panagopulos cho hay ông đánh giá cao quan điểm của các lãnh đạo Do Thái, song thêm rằng khách hàng mua đồng hồ thực tế chính là một người Do Thái ở châu Âu. Nhà đấu giá ở Maryland từng bán các hiện vật khác liên quan đến phát xít Đức trong quá khứ, như một con dao găm của Hitler Youth, tổ chức thanh niên Đức Quốc xã, với giá 120 USD hay một lá cờ Đức Quốc xã với giá 260 USD. Vũ Hoàng (Theo Washington Post)"},{"question":"Sheeg kuwii islaamka ugu horeeyey ee muhaajiriin ah?","answer":"Waxay kala ahaayeen:1- Hooyo Khadiijo Bintu Khuweylad Rc,2- Cali Bin Abii Daalib Rc,3- Abuu-Bakar Rc,4- Sayid Binu Thaabit Rc,5- Cusmaan Bin Cafaan Rc,6- Subeyr Bin Cawaam Rc,7- Cabdi Raxmaan Bin Cowf Rc,8- Sacad Bin Abii Waqaas Rc,9- Dalxa Bin Cubeydillah Rc."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਭਗਤਾ ਪਰਤੀਤਿ ਹਰਿ ਸਭ ਕਿਛੁ ਜਾਣਦਾ ॥ਹਰਿ ਜੇਵਡੁ ਨਾਹੀ ਕੋਈ ਜਾਣੁ ਹਰਿ ਧਰਮੁ ਬੀਚਾਰਦਾ ॥ਕਾੜਾ ਅੰਦੇਸਾ ਕਿਉ ਕੀਜੈ ਜਾ ਨਾਹੀ ਅਧਰਮਿ ਮਾਰਦਾ ॥ਸਚਾ ਸਾਹਿਬੁ ਸਚੁ ਨਿਆਉ ਪਾਪੀ ਨਰੁ ਹਾਰਦਾ ॥ਸਾਲਾਹਿਹੁ ਭਗਤਹੁ ਕਰ ਜੋੜਿ ਹਰਿ ਭਗਤ ਜਨ ਤਾਰਦਾ ॥੧੮॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 90 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਭਗਤ ਜਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਉੱਤੇ (ਇਹ) ਭਰੋਸਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਅੰਤਰਜਾਮੀ ਹੈਉਸ ਦੇ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ (ਹਿਰਦਿਆਂ ਦਾ) ਜਾਣੂ ਨਹੀਂ, (ਤੇ ਇਸੇ ਕਰਕੇ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਜੇ (ਇਹ ਭਰੋਸਾ ਹੋਵੇ ਕਿ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਅਨਿਆਊਂ ਨਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਾਰਦਾ, ਤਾਂ ਕੋਈ ਫ਼ਿਕਰ ਡਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਅਭੁੱਲ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨਿਆਂ ਭੀ ਅਭੁੱਲ ਹੈ, (ਇਸ ‘ਮਾਰ’ ਦਾ ਸਦਕਾ ਹੀ) ਪਾਪੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਪਾਪਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ) ਹਾਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਹੇ ਭਗਤ ਜਨੋ ! ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰੋ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪਣੇ ਭਗਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧੮।\\""},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి వ్యుత్పత్య అర్ధం రాయండి: దేహుడు","answer":"దేహము కలవాడు (ప్రాణి)"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਕਾ ਕੀ ਮਾਈ ਕਾ ਕੋ ਬਾਪ ॥ਨਾਮ ਧਾਰੀਕ ਝੂਠੇ ਸਭਿ ਸਾਕ ॥੧॥ਕਾਹੇ ਕਉ ਮੂਰਖ ਭਖਲਾਇਆ ॥ਮਿਲਿ ਸੰਜੋਗਿ ਹੁਕਮਿ ਤੂੰ ਆਇਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਏਕਾ ਮਾਟੀ ਏਕਾ ਜੋਤਿ ॥ਏਕੋ ਪਵਨੁ ਕਹਾ ਕਉਨੁ ਰੋਤਿ ॥੨॥ਮੇਰਾ ਮੇਰਾ ਕਰਿ ਬਿਲਲਾਹੀ ॥ਮਰਣਹਾਰੁ ਇਹੁ ਜੀਅਰਾ ਨਾਹੀ ॥੩॥ਕਹੁ ਨਾਨਕ ਗੁਰਿ ਖੋਲੇ ਕਪਾਟ ॥ਮੁਕਤੁ ਭਏ ਬਿਨਸੇ ਭ੍ਰਮ ਥਾਟ ॥੪॥੪੩॥੧੧੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 188 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਅਸਲ ਵਿਚ ਸਦਾ ਲਈ) ਨਾਹ ਕੋਈ ਕਿਸੇ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਹੈ, ਨਾਹ ਕੋਈ ਕਿਸੇ ਦਾ ਪਿਉ ਹੈ । (ਮਾਂ, ਪਿਉ, ਪੁਤ੍ਰ, ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਆਦਿਕ ਇਹ) ਸਾਰੇ ਸਾਕ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਨ, ਕਹਿਣ-ਮਾਤ੍ਰ ਹੀ ਹਨ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੂਰਖ ! ਤੂੰ ਕਿਉਂ (ਵਿਲਕ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈਂ, ਜਿਵੇਂ) ਸੁਪਨੇ ਦੇ ਅਸਰ ਹੇਠ ਬੋਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈਂ ?(ਤੈਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਸੂਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਿ) ਤੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਵਿਚ (ਪਿਛਲੇ) ਸੰਜੋਗ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ (ਇਹਨਾਂ ਮਾਂ ਪਿਉ ਆਦਿਕ ਸੰਬੰਧੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ) ਮਿਲ ਕੇ (ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ) ਆਇਆ ਹੈਂ (ਜਿਤਨਾ ਚਿਰ ਇਹ ਸੰਜੋਗ ਕਾਇਮ ਹੈ ਉਤਨਾ ਚਿਰ ਹੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਸੰਬੰਧੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਮੇਲ ਰਹਿ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ) ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਇਕੋ ਹੀ ਮਿੱਟੀ ਹੈ, ਸਭ ਵਿਚ (ਕਰਤਾਰ ਦੀ) ਇਕੋ ਹੀ ਜੋਤਿ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੈ, ਸਭ ਵਿਚ ਇਕੋ ਹੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਣ ਹਨ (ਜਿਤਨਾ ਚਿਰ ਸੰਜੋਗ ਕਾਇਮ ਹੈ ਉਤਨਾ ਚਿਰ ਇਹ ਤੱਤ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਹਨ । ਸੰਜੋਗ ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਣ ਤੇ ਤੱਤ ਵੱਖ ਵੱਖ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਕਿਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਸੇ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਰੋਣ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦੀ (ਰੋਣ ਦਾ ਲਾਭ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ) ।੨।(ਕਿਸੇ ਸੰਬੰਧੀ ਦੇ ਵਿਛੋੜੇ ਤੇ ਲੋਕ) ‘ਮੇਰਾ, ਮੇਰਾ’ ਆਖ ਕੇ ਵਿਲਕਦੇ ਹਨ(ਪਰ ਇਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਮਝਦੇ ਕਿ ਸਦਾ ਲਈ ਕੋਈ ਕਿਸੇ ਦਾ ‘ਮੇਰਾ’ ਨਹੀਂ ਤੇ) ਇਹ ਜੀਵਾਤਮਾ ਮਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ।੩।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਆਖ—ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਦੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਨਾਲ ਜਕੜੇ ਹੋਏ) ਕਵਾੜ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਖੋਲ੍ਹ ਦਿੱਤੇਉਹ ਮੋਹ ਦੇ ਬੰਧਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਸੁਤੰਤਰ ਹੋ ਗਏ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦੀ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਵਾਲੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਸਾਰੇ ਮੁੱਕ ਗਏ ।੪।੪੩।੧੧੨।\\""},{"question":"Kunjani slaelo?","answer":"Ngiyaphila, unjani wena keTembi?"},{"question":"Indil péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Jëwriñ Sëñ Aadama Gày ndaysaan!","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Jëwriñ Sëñ Aadama Gày ndaysaan!\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Jëwriñ: NOUNSëñ: NOUNAadama: PROPNGày: PROPNndaysaan: INTJ!: PUNCT"},{"question":"ماهو تشكيل النص التالي: رهم فيه فيشترط ارتفاع كل منهما بحيث يمر تحته الماشي منتصبا من غير احتياج إلى أن يطأطئ رأسه لأن ما يمنع ذلك إضرار حقيقي ويشترط مع هذا أن يكون على رأسه الحمولة العالية كما قاله الماوردي وإن كان ممر الفرسان والقوافل فليرفع ذلك بحيث يمر تحته المحمل على البعير مع أخشاب المظلة لأن ذلك قد يتفق وإن كان.","answer":"تشكيل النص السابق:رِهِمْ فِيهِ فَيُشْتَرَطُ ارْتِفَاعُ كُلٍ مِنْهُمَا بِحَيْثُ يَمُرُ تَحْتَهُ الْمَاشِي مُنْتَصِبًا مِنْ غَيْرِ احْتِيَاجٍ إلَى أَنْ يُطَأْطِئَ رَأْسَهُ لِأَنَ مَا يَمْنَعُ ذَلِكَ إضْرَارٌ حَقِيقِيٌ وَيُشْتَرَطُ مَعَ هَذَا أَنْ يَكُونَ عَلَى رَأْسِهِ الْحُمُولَةُ الْعَالِيَةُ كَمَا قَالَهُ الْمَاوَرْدِيُ وَإِنْ كَانَ مَمَرُ الْفُرْسَانِ وَالْقَوَافِلِ فَلْيَرْفَعْ ذَلِكَ بِحَيْثُ يَمُرُ تَحْتَهُ الْمُحْمِلُ عَلَى الْبَعِيرِ مَعَ أَخْشَابِ الْمِظَلَةِ لِأَنَ ذَلِكَ قَدْ يَتَفِقُ وَإِنْ كَانَ."},{"question":"මහපොළ සංකල්පයේ නිර්මාතෘ කවුද?","answer":"මහපොළ සංකල්පයේ නිර්මාතෘ ලලින්‌ ඇතුලත්මුදලි මහතාය. ලලිත් ඇතුලත්මුදලි ශ්‍රී ලාංකික දේශපාලනඥයෙකි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ හිටපු වෙළෙඳ, ජාතික ආරක්ෂක, කෘෂිකර්ම කැබිනට් අමාත්‍ය හා ආරක්ෂක නියෝජ්‍ය අමාත්‍ය ලලිත් ඇතුලත්මුදලි, 1993 අප්‍රේල් 23 වන දින කිරුලපන දී ශ්‍රී ලංකා වේලාවෙන් ප. ව. 8.10 ට (2.10 ප.ව. UTC) ඝාතනය කෙරිණි."},{"question":"*ماذا يسمى الجزء الملون من العين ؟","answer":"القزحية"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸੁਣਿਐ ਧਰਤਿ ਧਵਲ ਆਕਾਸ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 2 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਸੋਝੀ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਧਰਤੀ ਆਕਾਸ਼ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਹੈ।\\""},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Goorma Ayaa La Farad Yeelay Zakaatul Fidriga?","answer":"Jawaab, Waxa La Farad Yeelay Sanadkii Labaad Ee Hijriyada"},{"question":"பருத்தியை முதன் முதலில் உற்பத்தி செய்தவர்கள் யாவர் ?","answer":"பருத்தியை முதன் முதலில் உற்பத்தி செய்தவர்கள் சிந்து சமவெளி மக்கள். .பருத்தி முதன்முதலில் இந்தியாவில் குறைந்தது 7,000 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு சிந்து சமவெளி நாகரிகத்தில் விளைந்தது. பருத்திச் செடியானது இந்தியத் துணைக்கண்டத்தைச் சேர்ந்ததாக இருக்கலாம்.மிக முந்திய பழைய உலகப் பருத்தியின் பயன்பாடு கிமு 5500 ஆண்டளவுக்கும் முந்தையதாகும். இது புதிய கற்காலக் களமான மெக்ரகாரில் செம்பு மணிகளில் இன்றைய பக்கித்தான், பலூச்சித்தானில் போலன் கணவாயின் மலைச் சாரலில் கிடைத்தது.கி.மு 1500 ஆம் ஆண்டளவில் எழுதப்பட்ட ரிக்-வேதத்திலும் பருத்தி பற்றிய குறிப்புகள் உள்ளன. கி.மு. 2500 ஆம் ஆண்டு இந்தியப் பருத்தி பற்றிப் புகழ்பெற்ற கிரேக்க வரலாற்றாளர் எரோடோட்டசு \\"அங்கு செம்மறி ஆட்டிலிருந்து கிடைப்பதை விட அழகான, அதே அளவு தரமான கம்பளி, காடு போல் வளரும் மரங்களில் இருந்து கிடைக்கிறது. இந்திய மக்கள் இம் மரக் கம்பளி இழையிலிருந்து உடைகள் நெய்து கொள்கின்றனர்\\" என்று குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்.மெக்சிகோவில் பியூபுளாவின் தெகுக்கானில் உள்ள பழைய குகையருகில் பருத்திப் பந்துகள் கிமு 5500 ஆண்டுக்கு முன்பானவை கிடைத்துள்ளன. எனினும் இந்தக் காலக்கணிப்பு கேள்விக்குள்ளாகியுள்ளது. மெக்சிகோவில் கிடைத்த கோசிப்பியம் கிர்சுட்டம் பருத்தியின் காலம் கிமு3400 இல் இருந்து கிமு2300 வரையிலான கால இடைவெளியினது எனக் கணிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.பெரு நாட்டில், கோசிப்பியம் பார்படென்சு எனும் தாயகப் பருத்திப் பயிர்விளைச்சல் அன்கானில் கண்டுபிடித்த சான்றுவழி கிமு 4200 எனக் காலக்கணிப்பு செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது,[9]இது கடற்கரைப் பண்பாடுகளான நார்தே சிக்கு, மோச்சே, நாசுக்காஆகிய பண்பாடுகளின் முதுகெலும்பாக விளங்கியுள்ளது.. பருத்தி ஆற்றின் கரைகளில் பயிரிட்டு வலைகள் செய்து, கடற்கரையோர மீன்பிடிக்கும் ஊர்களில் விற்ரு ஏராளமான மீன்கள் பிடிக்கப்பட்டன. 16 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் மெக்சொகோவுக்கும் பெரு நாட்டுக்கும் வந்த எசுப்பானியர்கள் அங்கு மக்கள் பருத்தி விளவிப்பதையும் அவர்கள் பருத்தியடைகள் அணிவதையும் கண்டனர்.தாயக அமெரிக்கர்களும் பருத்தியிலிருந்து ஆடைகளை நெய்ய அறிந்திருந்தனர். பெரு நாட்டுக் கல்லறைகளில் காணப்பட்ட பருத்தித் துணிகள் இன்காப் பண்பாட்டுக் காலத்துக்கு முந்தியவை."},{"question":"Descreva o símbolo do Grêmio.","answer":"O símbolo do Grêmio é um escudo azul com detalhes em branco e preto. No centro, há a inscrição \\"GFBPA\\", que significa Grêmio Foot-Ball Porto Alegrense. Acima do escudo, há uma faixa azul com a inscrição \\"1903\\", indicando o ano de fundação do clube."},{"question":"Which French city is its capital?","answer":"Paris is the capital city of France."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ചോദ്യം: നെൽകൃഷി കേരളത്തിന്റെ പരിസ്ഥിതിക്ക് എന്ത് സംഭാവന നൽകുന്നു?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: തണ്ണീർത്തടങ്ങൾ സംരക്ഷിച്ചും ജൈവവൈവിധ്യത്തെ പിന്തുണച്ചും കാർബൺ സിങ്കായി പ്രവർത്തിച്ചും നെൽക്കൃഷി കേരളത്തിലെ പാരിസ്ഥിതിക സന്തുലിതാവസ്ഥ നിലനിർത്താൻ സഹായിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"Siapakah Perdana Menteri Malaysia yang kesembilan? ","answer":"Dato' Sri Ismail Sabri bin Yaakob (18 Jan 1960 - ) ialah Perdana Menteri Malaysia yang kesembilan. Beliau berkhidmat pada Beliau berkhidmat pada 21 Ogos 2021 hingga 23 November 2022."},{"question":"জীববিজ্ঞান শিক্ষক মি. হাসান তাঁর ছাত্রদের নিয়ে বিদ্যালয়ের চারপাশে গাছগুলো পর্যবেক্ষণ করলেন। পরবর্তীতে তিনি নানা রকম গাছ দেখিয়ে একটি বিষয় সম্পর্কে আলোচনা করলেন যার জনক বিজ্ঞানী ক্যারোলাস লিনিয়াস। অবশেষে তিনি উক্ত বিজ্ঞানীর প্রবর্তিত নামকরণ পদ্ধতির নিয়মাবলি আলোচনা করলেন।শিক্ষকের আলোচিত মূল বিষয়বস্তুর উদ্দেশ্য বর্ণনা করো।","answer":"শিক্ষকের আলোচিত মূল বিষয়বস্তুটি হলো জীবের শ্রেণিবিন্যাস। শ্রেণিবিন্যাসের উদ্দেশ্য হলো প্রতিটি জীবের দল ও উপদল সম্বন্ধে জ্ঞান আহরণ করা। জীবজগতের ভিন্নতার প্রতি আলোকপাত করে আহরিত জ্ঞানকে সঠিকভাবে সংরক্ষণ করা, পূর্ণাঙ্গ জ্ঞানকে সংক্ষিপ্তভাবে উপস্থাপন করা এবং প্রতিটি জীবকে শনাক্ত করে তার নামকরণের ব্যবস্থা করা। সর্বোপরি, জীবজগৎ ও মানব কল্যাণে প্রয়োজনীয় জীবসমূহকে শনাক্ত করে তাদের সংরক্ষণ অথবা প্রজাতিগত সংখ্যা বৃদ্ধির ব্যবস্থা নেওয়া।"},{"question":"السؤال: في أي عام كانت هزيمة الأمريكيين في المدينة الفيتنامية أو يشار إليها عادة بسقوط سايغون أثناء حرب فيتنام؟","answer":"الإجابة: 1975"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe Tanindrazana?","answer":"Tsy tany fe tany fotsiny no antsoina ho tanindrazana fa tany miampy olona velona sy maty. Tany miampy tantara. Tantara mirakitra fahatsiarovana iombonana."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو الأفضل للمسافر الفطر أم الصيام؟","answer":"لإجابة: المسافر مخير، لكن إن لم يكن في السفر مشقة فالصيام أولى، أما إن وجد مشقة الفطر خير له فهي رخصة من الله تعالىله. "},{"question":"کلیسا در رژیم نظامی چه چیزی را حمایت می کند؟ با توجه به سوال قبلی، زمینه ای را بنویسید که شامل پاسخ باشد. می تونه 1 تا 20 جمله باشه. زمینه:","answer":"کلیسای متودیستی متحد، با رژیم نظامی، مخالف است و آن را با آموزه های کتاب مقدس ناسازگار می داند. بنابراین، کلیسا از کسانی که با وجدان مخالف همه جنگ ها یا هر جنگ خاص هستند و بنابراین از خدمت در نیروهای مسلح یا همکاری با سیستم های اجباری نظامی امتناع می کنند، حمایت می کند و خدمت خود را گسترش می دهد. با این حال، کلیسای متدیست متحد نیز از کسانی که به خاطر وجدانشان خدمت در نیروهای مسلح را انتخاب کرده اند یا خدمات جایگزین را قبول کرده اند، حمایت می کند و خدمت خود را گسترش می دهد. کلیسا همچنین می گوید که \\"به عنوان مسیحیان آنها آگاه هستند که نه راه عمل نظامی، و نه راه بی عمل همیشه در نظر خدا درست است\\"."},{"question":"வினா: 15 நிமிடங்கள் மட்டுமே அரசராக இருந்தவர் யார்?","answer":"விடை: 14-ம் லூயி"},{"question":"रसायनशास्त्रमा आवधिक तालिकाको महत्त्व के हो?","answer":"आवधिक तालिकाले तत्वहरूलाई तिनीहरूको आणविक संख्या र गुणहरूको आधारमा व्यवस्थित गर्दछ, विभिन्न तत्वहरूको सम्बन्ध र व्यवहारहरू बुझ्न व्यवस्थित तरिका प्रदान गर्दछ।"},{"question":"Doc to summarize: శశిథరూర్, హేమామాలినిపార్లమెంటు ఆవరణలో వాళ్లిద్దరూ ఏం మాట్లాడుకుంటున్నారో ఏమో కానీ ఆయన మెడలో ఉన్న గాడ్జెట్‌ను ఓసారి చూడండి. కొద్ది నెలలుగా శశి థరూర్ ఆ గాడ్జెట్ లేకుండా బయటకు అడుగుపెట్టడం లేదు. ప్రస్తుతం జరుగుతున్న పార్లమెంటు సమావేశాలకూ ఆయన ఈ గాడ్జెట్ మెడలో వేసుకునే హాజరవుతున్నారు. చూడ్డానికి సెల్‌ఫోన్‌లా కనిపిస్తున్న ఈ గాడ్జెట్‌ మీలో కొందరికి తెలిసి ఉండొచ్చు.. కానీ, ఎంతోమంది ఇదేంటో తెలుసుకోవాలన్న ఆసక్తి ప్రదర్శిస్తున్నారు. కొందరైతే ఏకంగా ఆయన్నే అడుగుతున్నారు సోషల్ మీడియాలో. దానికి ఆయన సమాధానం ఇచ్చారు కూడా.శశిథరూర్. మెడలో పర్సనల్ ఎయిర్ ప్యూరిఫయర్(ఎర్రని వృత్తంలో కనిపిస్తున్నది)శశిథరూర్ మెడలో కనిపిస్తున్న ఈ గాడ్జెట్ ఎయిర్ ప్యూరిఫయర్. దీన్నే నెగటివ్ అయోనైజర్ అని కూడా పిలుస్తారు. ఒక్క మాటలో చెప్పాలంటే పర్సనల్ ఎయిర్‌ప్యూరిఫయర్. దీన్ని తయారుచేసిన సంస్థ పేరుతో ఎయిర్ టేమర్ అని  కూడా అంటున్నారు.అవును, పెరుగుతున్న వాయుకాలుష్య ప్రభావం నుంచి రక్షించుకోవడానికి ఇటీవల కాలంలో ఇళ్లలో, ఆఫీసుల్లో, చివరికి కార్లలో కూడా ఎయిర్‌ప్యూరిఫయర్ల వాడకం పెరిగింది. కానీ, మనది కాని ప్రదేశానికి వెళ్లినప్పుడో, బహిరంగ ప్రదేశాలకు వెళ్తున్నప్పుడో ఈ ఎయిర్‌ప్యూరిఫయర్లను వెంట తీసుకెళ్లడం కుదరదు కదా. ఆ సమస్యకు పరిష్కారమే ఈ ఎయిర్ టేమర్లు.ల్యాండ్ ఫోన్ల తరువాత మొబైల్ ఫోన్లు వచ్చి ప్రతి ఒక్కరి చేతికి చేరినట్లే ఇప్పుడీ ఎయిర్ టేమర్ల వాడకం కూడా మెల్లమెల్లగా పెరుగుతోంది. ముఖ్యంగా వాయు కాలుష్యం అధికంగా ఉండే ఆసియా దేశాల్లోని నాయకుల మెడల్లో ఇవి కనిపిస్తున్నాయి. వైరస్‌లు సోకకుండా ఇది కాపాడుతుందన్న ఉద్దేశంతోనూ వీటిని వినియోగిస్తున్నారు. ప్రస్తుతం ప్రపంచవ్యాప్తంగా కరోనా వైరస్ ప్రభావం తీవ్రంగా ఉన్న సమయంలో దీని వినియోగం ప్రాధాన్యం సంతరించుకుంటోంది. ఫిబ్రవరిలో పార్లమెంటు సమావేశాలు జరిగిన సమయంలోనే @MATTSMATTS అనే ఒక నెటిజన్ ట్విటర్ వేదికగా శశిథరూర్‌ను దీని గురించి అడిగారు. మెడలో ఈ గాడ్జెట్ వేసుకున్న శశిథరూర్ ఫొటోను ట్వీట్ చేసి 'ఈ గాడ్జెట్ ఏమిటి థరూర్ గారూ' అంటూ ఆయన్నే ట్యాగ్ చేశారు.దానికి స్పందించిన థరూర్ ''అది ఎయిర్ ప్యూరిఫయర్(నెగటివ్ అయోనైజర్). దిల్లీ గాలిలో శ్వాస తీసుకోవడం కష్టంగా ఉంది. తిరువనంతపురంలో ఉంటే నాకిది అవసరం లేదు'' అని సమాధానం ఇచ్చారు.ఇతర దేశాలకు చెందిన కొందరు నాయకులూ ఇలాంటివి వినియోగించిన దాఖలాలు కనిపిస్తున్నాయి.","answer":"బీజేపీ ఎంపీ హేమామాలినితో మాట్లాడుతున్న కాంగ్రెస్ ఎంపీ శశిథరూర్‌ను చూశారా.."},{"question":"ජාත්‍යන්තර රුධිර පාරවිලයන සංගමය විසින් දැනට රුධිර කණ්ඩායම් පද්ධති කීයක් පිළිගෙන තිබේද?","answer":"රුධිර පාරවිලයනය පිළිබඳ ජාත්‍යන්තර සංගමය රුධිර කණ්ඩායම් පද්ධති 33 ක් හඳුනා ගනී."},{"question":"Cảm xúc của người viết đoạn văn sau là gì?Từ lúc đang yêu cho tới khi về làm dâu, Lê Thủy luôn thấy bản thân may mắn vì gặp được người mẹ chồng theo cô đánh giá \\"đạt điểm 10\\". Cô gái 27 tuổi quê Thanh Hóa lần đầu gặp bà Phạm Thị Minh, 49 tuổi, khi được chồng dẫn về ra mắt 5 năm trước. Trước đó, biết con trai có tình cảm với cô gái ở xa, bà Minh cũng rất trăn trở. Nhưng sau thấy các con yêu nhau và quyết tâm gắn bó, bà lại ủng hộ.","answer":"Cảm xúc của người viết trong đoạn văn này là tích cực và trạng thái tâm trạng của họ đối với tình cảm gia đình và mối quan hệ gia đình là rất tích cực. Họ tỏ ra rất biết ơn và hạnh phúc với việc gặp được một người mẹ chồng tốt và ủng hộ trong mối quan hệ của họ."},{"question":"Liūtas: \\"Žmogus priešais verslą su moters statula su buteliu\\". Remiantis šia prielaida, ar galime daryti išvadą, kad hipotezė \\"Ji tyrinėja miestą\\" yra teisinga? Pasirinkimai: - Taip - neįmanoma pasakyti - Ne Gerai, pirmiausia pagalvokime.","answer":"Neaišku, kad tai moteris, tyrinėjanti miestą. Taigi atsakymas yra toks, kad neįmanoma pasakyti."},{"question":"Yaoundé moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Yaoundé moy péeyu réwum Cameroun"},{"question":"Vợ chồng tôi làm ngành xuất nhập khẩu 14 năm, đã có nhà ở ổn định tại quận 12, TP HCM, hiện tích lũy được 2,5 tỷ đồng. Chúng tôi đang gửi tiết kiệm số tiền này đến cuối tháng 9 đáo hạn. Do lo ngại trượt giá, vợ chồng dự định rút ra tìm mua đất vườn, nhà vườn hoặc đất vườn vùng xa với giá trên dưới 2,5 tỷ đồng. Nếu thiếu một ít vốn, chúng tôi có thể huy động vay mượn từ người thân và trả dần bằng tiền lương hàng tháng.Xin tư vấn giúp có sự khác biệt gì về cơ hội và rủi ro giữa đầu tư nhà vườn và đất vườn hay không? Với số vốn 2,5 tỷ đồng, vợ chồng tôi có thể đầu tư nhà vườn hoặc đất vườn ở những khu vực, tỉnh thành nào tiềm năng hiện nay? Nếu nắm giữ 5-10 năm, cơ hội tăng giá là bao nhiêu và chúng tôi nên làm gì để đảm bảo an toàn cho suất đầu tư này? Xin cảm ơn!","answer":"Khái niệm đầu tư nhà vườn hay đất vườn vùng ven đã xuất hiện cùng thời điểm với các đợt sóng nhỏ mang tên bỏ phố về quê hay bỏ phố về rừng cách đây nửa thập niên nhưng khi đó còn nhỏ lẻ và manh mún. Loại tài sản này đã thật sự bùng nổ trong đợt dịch Covid-19 vừa qua, khi mục tiêu mua tài sản được mở rộng, vừa để đầu tư tích lũy, sử dụng, thậm chí khai thác cho thuê. Tâm lý cách ly phòng dịch khiến khá nhiều người mong muốn có thêm một mảnh vườn ở nơi xa đô thị để cuối tuần về trồng rau, nghỉ ngơi thư giãn, tách biệt với đô thị ồn ào ngột ngạt khói bụi.Nhà vườn là loại bất động sản liền thổ (tài sản gắn liền với đất), quy mô thửa đất lớn, chức năng trồng cây hàng năm hoặc lâu năm, trong đó có một phần diện tích xây nhà. Đất vườn là đất trồng cây hàng năm hoặc lâu năm, chưa có công trình nhà ở nào trên đó.Hai loại tài sản này đều là thửa đất nông nghiệp lô lớn, diện tích phổ biến khoảng 1.000-2.000 m2 trở lên. Sự khác biệt nằm ở chỗ nhà vườn là đất nông nghiệp có một phần diện tích đất đã lên thổ cư, có thể xây công trình nhà ở; còn đất vườn là đất nông nghiệp 100%.Với tài chính 2,5 tỷ đồng, bạn không cần phải vay mà vẫn có khá nhiều phương án lựa chọn để đầu tư nhà vườn hay đất vườn, tùy vào sở thích đi xa hoặc gần.Phương án đi gần: bạn có thể lựa chọn khu vực như Bình Chánh, Củ Chi, Nhà Bè là các huyện ven đô TP HCM hoặc tỉnh giáp ranh kế cận phía Nam thành phố là tỉnh Long An. Nếu chọn cự ly đi gần, bạn có thể thuận tiện di chuyển đi về thăm nhà vườn hay đất vườn trong ngày dễ dàng.Phương án đi xa: bạn có thể lựa chọn tỉnh Đồng Nai, di chuyển ra các khu vực có vùng làm vườn phổ biến như: Long Khánh, Cẩm Mỹ, Cẩm Đường... hoặc phía huyện Thống Nhất. Nếu thích đi xa hơn nữa có vùng Bảo Lộc, Lâm Hà, tỉnh Lâm Đồng: từ khu vực Madaguoi trở lên tới Bảo Lộc, thời tiết mát mẻ, cây trái dễ trồng. Với phương án đi xa, bán kính di chuyển mở rộng ra 200-300 km, phù hợp đi vào 2 ngày cuối tuần."},{"question":"వేరు పీడనం ప్రయోగం చేసేటప్పుడు నీవు తీసుకునే జాగ్రత్త ఏది?A) మొక్క కొమ్మలను కలిగి ఉండాలి.B) మొక్కను చీకటిలో ఉంచాలి.C) గాజు గొట్టం పరిమాణం, కాండ పరిమాణం ఒకే విధంగా ఉండాలి.D) గాజు గొట్టం పరిమాణం, కాండం పరిమాణం కన్నా పెద్దదిగా ఉండాలి.","answer":"C) గాజు గొట్టం పరిమాణం, కాండ పరిమాణం ఒకే విధంగా ఉండాలి."},{"question":"வினா: உலோகங்களுடன் காரம் வினை புரிந்து கிடைப்பது?","answer":"விடை: ஹைட்ரஜன் வாயு வெளியேறுகிறது மற்றும் உப்பு கிடைக்கிறது."},{"question":"Talo caafimaad","answer":"KANSARKA JIDIINKA / DHUUNTA/ HUNGURIGA (ESOPHAGEAL CANCER)Waa maxay kansarka jidiinka? ( what is esophageal cancer)?Waa kansarka kudhaca unugyada ku weeqaaran gudaha dhuunta , lagabilaabo cunaha ilaa caloosha inta u dhexaysa.EPIDEMIOLOGY (sidee kuyahay bulshada soomaalida)Kansarka jidiinka oo aad ugusii kordhaya bulshada soomaalida wuxuu kudhacaa sida badan dadka waayeelka ah oo da’dooda 60 sano tahay celcelis. Wuxuuna kudhaca inta badan raga boqolkiiba 80 ( prevalence Male:female = 4:1 )NOOCYADIISA (TYPES) Wuxuu ukalabaxaa labo nooc, kuwaas oo kala aha :1. Squamous– noocan oo kabilaaban kara meel walbo oo jidiinka kamid aha2. Adenocarcoma - noocan wuxuu kabilowda isgoyska udhexeeya caloosha iyo jidiinka,gaaska caloosha daraadeed oo dib ugusoo noqda jidiinkaARRIMAHA SABABA/KEENA (RISK FACTORS)1. Sigaarka oo lacabo ( tobacco smoking )2. Khamra badan oo lacabo ( high alcohol intake )3. Cabitaanka kulul oo mudo dheer lacabo sida shaaha mise qaxwada ( long term consumption of hot beverages for example tea or coffee)4. Nafaqo xumo – sida cuno ay kuyartahay fiitamiinka A , C , iyo cunada leh kiimikada looyaqaano Nitrosamines sida cuntada qiiqa lagukariyo ( consumption of diet deficient in vitamins A , C and nitrosamine containing foods found in smoked and pickled foods )5. Shucaac mar hore qof lagudaaweeyay ( prior radiation therapy)6. Cayilka (obesity)7. Cunada saliida xoolaha kubadantahay ( diet rich in animal fat and cholesterol)CALAAMADAHA LAGUGARTO QOFKA QABA KANSARKA JIDIINKA(SYMPTOMS)1. Qofka oo liqida dhibto ama xanuujiso ( difficulty or pain while swallowing )2. Cunada oo dib jidiinka ugusoonoqota ( regurgitation)3. Qofka oo miizaankiisa hoos udhoco ( loss of weight)4. Feedho xanuun ( chest pain )5. Mantaq ( vomiting )6. Iyo calaamadaha markuu jidhka kufaafo lagu garto sidha Higo ( hiccoughs), bog xanuun (abdominal pain)dhabar xanuun(back pain), xabeeb (hoarseness of voice ) cagaarshow (jaundice) neefta oo qofka dhibta ( difficulty in breathing ) saxarada oo madoobaata (melena)SIDA LOOGA HORTAGO (PREVENTION)1. In aadan cabin khamrada iyo sigaarka ( do not consume alcohol and smoke cigarette )2. Cabitaanka kulul ood iskayarayso ama iskadhaafto ( stop consuming hot beverages)3. In aad iskajoojiso cunada warshadaha lasoomariyay ama kuwa qiiqa lagukariyay ( stop consuming processed and smoked foods)4. In aad cuntid cuno dheelitiran oo iskugujirta noocyada cuntada oo dhan sida khudaarta iyo miraha ( take balance diet rich in vitamins e.g vegetables and fruits )5. In aad kudadaasho sida aad iskagabadali lahayd hab dhaqameedka nooleed sida jimicsiga jidhka (lifestyle changes e.g regular exercise)6. In aad iskayarayso saliida xoolaha lagadhaliyo ( minimize consumption of animal fats and cholesterol intake)SIDA LAGU OGAADO(INVESTIGATIONS)1. Diiga guud – dig yari (anemia)2. Barium swallow3. In tuubo bukaanka jidiinka lagagaliyo (Endoscopy )4. CT scan5. In qofka hilib yar ama dhaacaan lagaqaado ( biopsy)DAAWEYNTIISA (MANAGEMENT)1. Qalniin hadii uu bukaanka xili quman xaaladiisa laogaado ( surgery )2. Radiotherapy3. Chemotherapy4. Iyo in bukaanka lalatacaalo si uuna cudurka usiifaafin ama dhibka xanuunka lagabar yareeyo (palliative care)F.G : mar walbo laxariir dhakhtarka si aad u hubsato heerka caafimaadkaaga hadaad iskashakido, waxaadna ogaataa cudurada qaarkood waa isku calaamado!!"},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Cộng hòa Séc đoạt giải nhì Euro 96, lọt vào bán kết Euro 2004","answer":"và vị trí thứ 3 của Confed Cup 1997. Đội lọt vào vòng chung kết World Cup lần đầu tiên với tư cách là quốc gia độc lập năm 2006."},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa: Denmark wani yanki ne na yankin Schengen, yana ba da izinin tafiya kyauta a cikin ƙasashen Turai masu shiga. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: Gaskiya"},{"question":"இலங்கையில் கடையடைப்பு: கிழக்கிலும் இயல்பு நிலை பாதிப்பு வெறிச்சோடிய மட்டக்களப்பு நகர்வடக்கு - கிழக்கு மாகாணங்களில் கடந்த ஒரு மாதத்திற்கும் மேலாக  வலிந்து  காணாமல் ஆக்கப்பட்டவர்கள் தொடர்பாக உண்மை நிலையை வெளிப்படுத்தப்பட வேண்டும். அரச படையினர் நிலை கொண்டுள்ள தனியார் காணிகள் விடுவிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் போன்ற கோரிக்கைகளை அரசாங்கத்திடம் முன்வைத்து காணாமல் போனவர்களின் உறவினரும், காணிகளின் உரிமையாளர்களும் போராட்டங்களில் ஈடுபட்டுள்ளனர்.இலங்கை இனமோதலில் காணாமல் போனோர் குறித்த 10 முக்கிய தகவல்கள்  இயங்காத சந்தைஇந்தப் போராட்டங்களுக்கு வலுச்சேர்க்கும் வகையில் ஏற்பாட்டாளர்களினால் கடையடைப்பு மற்றும் ஹர்தாலுக்கான  அழைப்பு  விடுக்கப்பட்டிருந்தது.இலங்கை : கடையடைப்பு போராட்டத்தால் ஸ்தம்பித்த இயல்பு வாழ்க்கை  (புகைப்படத் தொகுப்பு)கிழக்கு மாகாணத்தில்  கடையடைப்பு மற்றும் ஹர்த்தால்  அனுசரிக்கப்பட்ட தமிழ்  பிரதேசங்களில் மாணவர்கள் வராததால் அரச மற்றும் தனியார் பள்ளிக் கூடங்கள் வெறிச்சோடிச் காணப்படுகின்றன. அரச, தனியார் அலுவலகங்களிலும் வழமை நிலை பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. வங்கிகள், வர்த்தக நிலையங்கள் மூடப்பட்டுள்ளன.  மூடப்பட்டுள்ள கடைகள்போக்குவரத்து சேவைகளை பொறுத்தவரை ஆட்டோ சேவை முற்றாக நிறுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. அரச, தனியார் உள்ளுர் பேருந்து சேவைகள் தடைப்பட்டுள்ளன. தூர இடங்களுக்கு செல்லும் போக்குவரத்து சேவை   மட்டுப்படுத்தப்பட்டிருந்தது.காணாமல் போனோர் பிரச்சனை : கிளிநொச்சியில் சாலை மறியல் போராட்டம்பயணிகள் இன்றி காணப்படும் மட்டக்களப்பு பேருந்து நிலையம்வடக்கு - கிழக்கு மாகாணங்களில் இன்று வியாழக்கிழமை அனுசரிக்கப்படும் ஹர்த்தாலுக்கு தமிழ் தேசிய கூட்டமைப்பு, ஈ.பி.டி.பி, ஶ்ரீ லங்கா முஸ்லிம் காங்கிரஸ், அகில இலங்கை மக்கள் காங்கிரஸ் உட்பட தமிழ் - முஸ்லிம் அரசியல் கட்சிகள் மற்றும் சிவில் அமைப்புகள் தங்கள் ஆதரவை வெளிப்படுத்தியிருந்தன.இந்த செய்திகளும் உங்களுக்கு  ஆர்வத்தை ஏற்படுத்தலாம்திராவிடக் கட்சிகளின் 50 ஆண்டு ஆட்சி : நிதி நெருக்கடியிலும் வளர்ச்சி வாக்கைக் காப்பாற்றினாரா அதிபர் டிரம்ப்? வட கொரியா மீதான தடைகளை  இறுக்க அமெரிக்கா  திட்டம்பட்டுப்பூச்சியின் மூலம் புரதத்தை பெறலாம்: சீனத் தொழில் முனைவர் யோசனைசமூக ஊடகங்களில் பிபிசி தமிழ் : ஃபேஸ்புக்கில் படித்து கருத்துகள் தெரிவிக்க : பிபிசி தமிழ் முகநூல்டிவிட்டரில் பிபிசி தமிழை பின்தொடர : பிபிசி தமிழ் ட்விட்டர்","answer":"இலங்கையில்  வடக்கு -  கிழக்கு மாகாணங்களில் அனு சரிக்கப்படும்  கடையடைப்பு  மற்றும் ஹர்த்தால்  காரணமாக கிழக்கு மாகாணத்தில் தமிழர் வாழும்  பிரதேசங்களில் இயல்பு நிலை பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."},{"question":"ಕೆಳಗಿನ ವರ್ಗವನ್ನು ಪರಿಗಣಿಸಿ ಉತ್ತರವನ್ನು ನೀಡಿ:ಅನಂತಸ್ವಾಮಿ 1960 ರಲ್ಲಿ ಕರ್ನಾಟಕ ರಾಜ್ಯ ಗೀತೆ ಜಯ ಭಾರತ ಜನನಿಯ ತನುಜಾತೆ ಗೆ ಸಂಗೀತ ಸಂಯೋಜಿಸಿದರು. ಮೈಸೂರಿನ ಮಹಾರಾಜ ಕಾಲೇಜಿನಲ್ಲಿ ನಾಡಗೀತೆಯನ್ನು ಬರೆದ ಕುವೆಂಪು ಅವರ ಮುಂದೆ ಒಮ್ಮೆ ಅವರು ತಮ್ಮ ರಚನೆಯನ್ನು ಹಾಡಿದರು. ಅನಂತಸ್ವಾಮಿಯವರ ದಿನಚರಿಯಲ್ಲಿರುವ ಟಿಪ್ಪಣಿಯೊಂದು ಕುವೆಂಪು ಅವರ ರಾಗದಿಂದ ಸಂತೋಷಪಟ್ಟು ಅವರ ರಾಗವನ್ನು ಅನುಮೋದಿಸಿದರು ಮತ್ತು ಅದನ್ನು ಗುಂಪಿನಲ್ಲಿ ಹಾಡಬೇಕೆಂದು ಸಲಹೆಯನ್ನು ಸೇರಿಸಿದ್ದಾರೆ. ಅನಂತಸ್ವಾಮಿಯವರು ರಚಿಸಿದ ರಾಗವನ್ನು ಕರ್ನಾಟಕ ರಾಜ್ಯ ಗೀತೆಯ ಅಧಿಕೃತ ರಾಗವಾಗಿ ಗುರುತಿಸಲು ಹಲವಾರು ಸಮಿತಿಗಳು ಶಿಫಾರಸು ಮಾಡಿವೆ.ಅನಂತಸ್ವಾಮಿ ಅವರು ಕರ್ನಾಟಕ ರಾಜ್ಯ ಗೀತೆಯನ್ನು ಯಾರ ಮುಂದೆ ಹಾಡಿದರು ","answer":"ಮೈಸೂರಿನ ಮಹಾರಾಜ ಕಾಲೇಜಿನಲ್ಲಿ ನಾಡಗೀತೆಯನ್ನು ಬರೆದ ಕುವೆಂಪು ಅವರ ಮುಂದೆ ಹಾಡಿದರು"},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකා  ජාතික රාජ්‍ය සභාවේ , පළමුවැනි කථානායක වරයා කවුද ?","answer":"ස්ටැන්ලි තිලකරත්න මැතිතුමා ( 1972 - 05 - 22 දින සිට )"},{"question":"மூன்றடிச் சிற்றெல்லையும் ஆறடிப் பேரெல்லையும் கொண்ட அகவற்பாக்களால் ஆன நூல் எது?(1) ஐங்குறுநூறு(2) குறுந்தொகை(3) கலித்தொகை(4) புறநானூறு.","answer":"(1) ஐங்குறுநூறு."},{"question":"Uthe angaqeda ukukhuluma nocingo lwakhe lolo, waluvala.'Baba nawe Mama, ithanda ukungesinda mina le nto. Lo mnumzane uthi ufunangimelekelele. Ungibalisela ngokuhlupheka kwakhe. Ungitshela ukuthiakanayo imali ngenxa yokuthi wadilizwa emsebenzini. Ungitshela ukuthiwethembele kimi njengomkhwenyana wakwakhe. Ungitshela ukuthi akanayoimali eyanele. Kuyacaca ukuthi uyabona ukuthi lo msebenzi ubhekene nayengqo. Uzama ukungifaka ngekhanda nje. Ngeke ngiyivume mina leyo nto.Ufunani kimi?''Uphendule wathini wena kuyena ngenkathi nixoxa?' kubuza uyise.'Angimethembisanga lutho Baba. Ngithe ngizobona. Okokuqala, yenaakafanelanga ukukhuluma nami. Kufanele akhulume nani, hhayi mina.Ngibona sengathi ufuna ukungiqinela ngoba azi ukuthi ngiyamhlonipha. Utheuzobuye ashaye emva kwesikhashana.Yinina okufanele nikhulume naye,hhayi mina.''Ngiyakuzwa lokho okushoyo, kodwa ngibona sengathi usezohlalelaethembeni njengoba wena uthe usazobona nje,' kusho unina.'Kulungile. Akahlalele kulelo themba lakhe aze ayofa njengoba esihlaliseethembeni kwaze kwafa omunye nje. Elami lithi, ngeke ngize ngifake ngishoelimnyama isenti. Ningamelekelela nina uma ninemali eningi. Lo muntusisanda kumnikeza inqwaba yemali. Akasebenzise yona. Ukuba wayidedelaingane yakhe, ngabe asihluphani ngalutho nale ndoda. Bengizozithwalangikhululekile izindleko zomngcwabo. Bengingeke ngimeme omunye umuntu.'1. Yiliphi isu ayesecabanga ukulenza uMandlenkosi ukuze ahlalendawonye nomakoti wakhe? ","answer":"Wayesecabanga ukuyintshontsha ingoduso yakhe baye kudelapho ayesebenza khona.√/• Wayesecabanga ukuvele ayeke ukuba imvu yasesontweni,avele abe yindlavini uqobo, avele athathe umfazi wakheayomfaka endlini. √"},{"question":"Yaraanshaha Macdanta Birta.","answer":"Hoos u dhaca ama la’aanta macdanta birta ee jirka ku jirta waxay horseedda yaraanshaheeda. la’aanshaha aad u ba’an ee macdanta birtawuxuu horseedaa dhiig yaraanta ay feeradukeento (IDA). Yaraanta birta waa nafaqodarradaugu caansan. Carruurta yar yar iyo haweenka uurka leh waxey la dhibtoodaan dhiigyari aad uu saraysa oo ku dhacda. Calaamadaha ugu waaweyn waa Caddaad, daal, ciddiyo burbur,nabarro carrabka {sore tongue}, and timahoo jajaba , neef, hamuunta cuntada loo qabo ooncaadi hayn, hoos u dhicid cadaadiska dhiigga,wadna garaac aad deg deg u ah, difaaca jirka oohooseeya, madax xanuun, hoos u dhacrabitaanka cunto , xanuun ba’an oo yimaada xilliga caadada iyo dhiig bax iyo hurdadooqasanta.Ilaha cuntada laga helo macdanta birta Qaar ka mid ah ilahaas waa Hilib (Beer-yaro,kelyo and gaar ahaan beerka), digaag, kalluun,ukun, miro la qallajiyey, digir (digir, salbuko),kookaha iyo waxaa ka soo baxa iyo khudaartacaleemaha aadka u cagaaran. Firiley (Galley, Bariis iyo Qamadi) waxaa ku jira bir cadaddhexdhexaad ah hase yeeshee maadaama cadadfara badan laga cuno waxay bixiyaan macdanta birta ee ugu badan. Waxaa kaloo laga heli karaadheriyada wax lagu karsado ee birta kasameysan. "},{"question":"Mẹ em hiện đang điều trị bệnh liên quan đến hệ Miễn dịch (Lupus ban đỏ, xơ cứng bì), tháng 10/2021 có tiêm một mũi, 10 ngày phát hiện bệnh trên nên chưa tiêm mũi 2, nhờ bác sĩ tư vấn giúp mẹ em có tiêm được thuốc này không? Thời gian được bao lâu? Em ở Bình Dương thì tiêm ở đâu là gần nhất? Chi phí tiêm như thế nào? Sau có phải tiêm nhắc lại không? Và trong thời gian bao lâu phải nhắc lại?","answer":"Đối với trường hợp của người thân bạn, bị Lupus ban đỏ, xơ cứng bì, thì thường phải sử dụng nhóm thuốc corticoid kéo dài ít nhất trên vài tháng. Đồng thời, đối với những bệnh này cũng là bệnh tự miễn, tức là cơ thể tự sinh ra kháng thể để chống lại khớp, thận, đa cơ quan. Trong trường hợp này, chích vaccine hiệu qủa sẽ rất kém do phải sử dụng corticoid lâu dài. bạn có thể chích kháng thể đơn dòng của AstraZeneca.Ở Bình Dương, bạn có thể đến BVĐK Tâm Anh TP HCM, ở địa chỉ số 2B Phổ Quang để được đăng ký. Tại đây, bạn sẽ được các bác sĩ nội khoa tầm soát và thực hiện các xét nghiệm, nếu đủ tiêu chuẩn để tiêm kháng thể đơn dòng AstraZeneca, bạn có thể tiêm ngay tại bệnh viện. Kháng thể đơn dòng có hiệu quả bảo vệ trong vòng 6 tháng đến 1 năm. Hiện AstraZeneca cũng đang có nhiều nghiên cứu khác về kháng thể đơn dòng. Lúc đó sẽ ó thêm những thông tin mới để bạn tiến hành chích những mũi kế tiếp hoặc có thể sử dụng các loại thuốc kháng thể đơn dòng khác."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：在地質學中，什麼是火山口？","answer":"答案：火山口是火山的頂部開口，通常是由岩漿和氣體噴發形成的。它是火山活動的主要出口，可以釋放岩漿、氣體和火山碎屑物質，形成火山噴發。"},{"question":"Inona no tendrombohitra avo indrindra eto an-tany, any amin’ny tandavan-tendrombohitra Himalaya?","answer":"Ny tendrombohitra avo indrindra eran-tany, any amin’ny tandavan-tendrombohitra Himalaya, dia ny Tendrombohitra Everest."},{"question":"Cá ndeachaigh Archie Manning ar scoil ard? ","answer":"D'imir sé peile in Ollscoil Mississippi, sna 1960í."},{"question":"２００８年４月１２日に最後の航海を終えて帰国した南極観測船の名前は何？","answer":"しらせです。"},{"question":"नेपालमा सिक्श्यको बारेमा कानुन भन्नुहोस्","answer":"प्रत्येक व्यक्तिलाई शिक्षाको अधिकार छ । कमसेकम प्रारम्भिक र आधारभूत शिक्षा निःशुल्क हुनेछ । प्रारम्भिक शिक्षा अनिवार्य हुनेछ । प्रविधिक र व्यवसायिक शिक्षा सबै सुलभ हुनेछ र उच्च शिक्षामा योग्यताको आधारमा सबैको समान पहुँच हुनेछ ।"},{"question":"Бриз деген эмне ?","answer":"Бриз-деңиздердин,көлдөрдүн,ошондой эле чоң дарыялардын жээгиндеги суткасына багытын эки жолу күндүзү- суудан жээкке, түнкүсүн- жээктен сууну коздой озгорткон шамал."},{"question":"Usuku lomshado wawungathi kushada inkosi. Kugcwele kuthe swi izimotoegcekeni. UBheki ungathi uyaphupha. Uma elokhu eqalaza uyababona abantuabaziyo. Usebona noLindiwe egone ingane. Ethembe ukuthi uLindiwe ngekeamsusele umsindo sekubhaliswa.'Kanti oTholi babanjwe yini?' UBheki obuzayo. Akabonakali phela umakoti manje.Acabange uPamella uBheki. Kokunye nguye nje oselibazise uTholi. Bagcwelemanje abantu umakoti akabonwa. Aqalaze futhi uBheki.'Ubani–ke lo baba ohamba ethetha laphaya Sifiso?''Sengathi ubaba kaTholi impela loya. Konje nathi wavuma ukuba uTholi azoshadanawe futhi?''Ngiyaqala ukumbona mina Sifiso. Umuntu obehla enyuka namalobolo yilo babaokuthiwa uZenze.'Athule uSifiso. Kubonakale ukuthi kukhona okungamenelisi kahle.1. Ngokucabanga kwakho ngabe yisiphi isizathu sikaTholakele sokufunaukushada noBhekani? Bhala amaphuzu AMABILI.","answer":"Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo: Wayefuna ukumqola kahle imali yakhe. Wayemthanda naye umuntu ofundile ukuba abe khona empilweniyakhe. Ukushada nomuntu onesithunzi kwakuzomenza afihleke ubugebengubakhe."},{"question":"வினா:  நாளந்தா பல்கலைக் கழகத்தின் தலைவராக இருந்த தர்ம பாலரின் இருப்பிடமானது1. காஞ்சிபுரம்2. கடலூர்3. சிதம்பரம்4. காரைக்கால்","answer":"விடை:1. காஞ்சிபுரம்"},{"question":"冬天使用電火鍋，當水煮乾時應加入什麼水？","answer":"熱水"},{"question":"சு. தியோடர் பாஸ்கரன் அவர்களின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"புலி மற்றும் யானை பற்றிய விவரங்களை இந்த இரு உயிரினங்களுமே இல்லாத ஒரு நாட்டின் மொழி மூலமாகவே நம் மாணவர்கள் கற்றுக்கொள்ள வேண்டிய நிலை வேதனை அளிக்கக் கூடியது."},{"question":"ＪＲの駅にある指定券売り場のことを、ある色を使って何というでしょう？","answer":"みどりの窓口"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Membawa langit lebit dekat dengan kita.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah teleskop"},{"question":"Кто является автором фразы: \\"Российский корабль, иди домой\\"?","answer":"Эта фраза не принадлежит какой-либо конкретной личности. Однако она использовалась  в различных средствах массовой информации для выражения антироссийской позиции во время Российско-Украинской войны."},{"question":"Iza no renivohitry ny faritra Sofia ?","answer":"I Antsohihy no renivohitry ny faritra Sofia ."},{"question":"Hees jaceyl ","answer":"Maalintaad baxeyseeeMagaalada ka dhoftanMuxibo kuu jaleecoooMiirkaan lahaay iyo 😶Maankiii ku raaceee😑Intad 2x iga maqanteeMaseexdoo habeenkii Waan soo mir kacayaaMeelan dhaweyn baadIiga muuqaneysaaa👀 2xYaanan madi ahaanineMarwadaan jeclaayey💔Kala maarmi mayneeeMar uun nabad kuso noqo."},{"question":"Raha jerena ireto fehezanteny roa ireto:Fehezanteny A: \\"Na dia teo aza ny fahasahiranana maharitra, dia nahavita nanangana fototra mafy ho an'ny orinasan'izy ireo izy ireo, ary nony farany dia niroborobo izy ireo.\\"Fehezanteny B: \\"Nandritra ny fahasahiranana maharitra, dia nahomby tamin'ny fametrahana orinasa miroborobo izy ireo.\\"Mitovy ve ny dikany?","answer":"Eny, mitovy ny dikan'ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"Given the below title and summary of an article, generate a short article or the beginning of a long article to go along with them. Title: ਸਵਾਈਨ ਫਲੂ ਦੀ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਤੇ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ 'ਚ ਆਹਟ, ਕੀ ਨੇ ਬਚਣ ਦੇ ਤਰੀਕੇnSummary: ਅੰਜਨਾ ਮਿਸ਼ਰਾ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਹਫ਼ਤੇ ਐਚ-1 ਐਨ-1 (ਸਵਾਈਨ ਫਲੂ) ਵਾਇਰਸ ਦਾ ਸ਼ਿਕਾਰ ਹੋ ਗਈ। ਅੰਜਨਾ ਮਹਾਰਿਸ਼ੀ ਦਯਾਨੰਦ ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ, ਰੋਹਤਕ ਵਿੱਚ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਵਿਭਾਗ ਦੀ ਮੁਖੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਹੁਣ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦੇ ਦੂਜੇ ਮੈਂਬਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਪਰਕ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਣ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ ਕਮਰੇ ਤੱਕ ਹੀ ਸੀਮਤ ਹੈ।nArticle (Max 500 characters):","answer":"ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ  ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹਾ ਸਿਹਤ ਵਿਭਾਗ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਪਹੁੰਚੇ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ਼ਤਿਹਾਰ ਹਥ ਵਿਚ ਫੜਾ ਦਿੱਤੇ। ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਵਾਈਨ ਫਲੂ ਦੇ ਵਾਇਰਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਣ ਲਈ ਕੀ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਕੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ।ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਮਰੀਜ਼ ਨਾਲ ਇੱਕ ਛੱਤ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਲਈ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ ਕਿ ਕੀ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਲਈ ਵੀ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਸਕ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਵੇਗਾ। ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਨਕਾਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਪਰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਕੁਝ ਸਲਾਹਾਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਦਿੱਤੀਆਂ। ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ ਘਰ ਅਤੇ ਨੇੜੇ-ਤੇੜੇ ਦੀ ਸਾਫ਼-ਸਫਾਈ ਰੱਖਣਾ, ਸਾਬਣ ਨਾਲ ਹੱਥ ਧੌਣਾ ਅਤੇ ਘਰ ਅੰਦਰ ਮਾਸਕ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ"},{"question":"Кыл курт","answer":"Астыртан билинбей ич арада жүргөн душман.Арабызда жүргөн кыл курттун бири Асанбай дегенде, эл таң калды. (А.Т.)"},{"question":"Avadio mivadi-drafitra ity fehezanteny ity:\\"Madio mangarahara ny rano.\\"","answer":"Ity ny fehezanteny rehefa avadika mivadi-drafitra:\\"Ny rano dia madio mangarahara.\\""},{"question":"Escribe el evento más importante del texto : La victoria de la Marina Real Británica en la Batalla de Tarento fue un momento clave, ya que fue la primera muestra real del poder naval aéreo. Después del 7 de diciembre de 1941, cuando los Estados Unidos de América entraron en la Segunda Guerra Mundial, el hundimiento del HMS Prince of Wales (53) y del HMS Repulse (1916) marcaron el final de la era del acorazado, y la nueva importancia del avión y de su transporte, el portaaviones. Durante la Guerra del Pacífico, los acorazados y cruceros estuvieron gran parte de su servicio bombardeando posiciones costeras, mientras que los portaaviones fueron las estrellas en las batallas claves del Mar del Coral, Batalla de Midway, Batalla del Mar de Filipinas, y en la fundamental Batalla del Golfo de Leyte, que fue la batalla naval más grande de la historia.","answer":"La Batalla del Golfo de Leyte, una de las más grandes  de la historia. "},{"question":"برای یادگیری نواختن یک ساز روزانه چقدر تمرین لازم است؟","answer":"اوه، چه سوال خوبی! به طور معمول، تمرین روزانه حداقل ۳۰ تا ۶۰ دقیقه خوبه. البته اهمیت داره که تمریناتت متنوع باشه و از درسها و موزیکهای مختلف استفاده کنی. تمرین منظم بهت کمک می‌کنه تا به تدریج مهارتتو بالا ببری.اگر این تمرین روزانه رو هر روز در یک ساعت خاصی انجام بدی بطور مثال هر روز بین ساعت ٥ تا ٦ عصر تمرین کنی بازدهی کارت بسیار بالا میره"},{"question":"第１回サミットが行われた時の日本の総理大臣は誰でしょう？","answer":"三木武夫です。"},{"question":"Ọmọdé gbọdọ̀ bọ̀wọ̀ fún àwọn ọ̀bí rẹ̀ àti àwọn àgbàlagbà nílẹ̀ Yorùbá. Bẹ́ẹ́ ni àbí bẹ́ẹ́ kọ?","answer":"Bẹ́ẹ́ ni."},{"question":"පහත නාම පදයට අදාළ පුරුෂ ලිංග නාම පාදක කුමක්ද? මාතෘ ","answer":"පීතෘ"},{"question":"సహకార సంస్థలకు, భాగస్వామ్యానికి మధ్య గల వ్యత్యాసములేవి ?","answer":"సహకార సంస్థలకు, భాగస్వామ్య సంస్థలకు గల తేడాలు:సహకార సంస్థస్థాషన: సహకార సంస్థల చట్టం 1912 క్రింద ఇవి స్థాపించబడతాయి..సభ్యత్వము: కనిష్ట సభ్యుల సంఖ్య 10, గరిష్ట సభ్యుల సంఖ్య అపరిమితము.ముఖ్య ఉద్దేశ్యము: సేవాశయము.ఋణ బాధ్యత: పరిమితము.నిర్వహణ: ప్రజాస్వామ్యబద్ధముగా సంస్థ నిర్వహించబడుతుంది.మినహాయింపులు, సౌకర్యములు ; ఆదాయపు పన్ను చెల్లింపులో, స్టాంపు రిజిస్ట్రేషన్ ఫీజులో మినహాయింపు ఉంటుంది.మిగులు లాభాల పంపిణీ: లాభాలలో కొంత శాతము మాత్రమే సభ్యులకు డివిడెండ్లుగా పంచుతారు.మూలధనము: మొత్తము వాటాలలో 10%నకు మించిన వాటాలను ఏ వ్యక్తి కొనరాదు.భాగస్వామ్య సంస్థభారత భాగస్వామ్య చట్టం 1932 క్రింద ఇవి ఏర్పడతాయి.కనిష్ట సభ్యుల సంఖ్య 2. గరిష్ట సభ్యుల సంఖ్య బ్యాంకింగ్ వ్యాపారము అయితే 10, ఇతర వ్యాపారాలలో 20.ముఖ్య ఉద్దేశ్యము లాభాశయము.ఋణబాధ్యత అపరిమితము, వ్యక్తిగతము, సమిష్టిభాగస్వామ్య ఒప్పందము సంస్థ నిర్వహణలో పాల్గొనవచ్చు.ఎలాంటి సౌకర్యాలు, మినహాయింపులు ఉండవు.మొత్తము లాభాలను ఒప్పందము ప్రకారం భాగస్తులకు పంపిణీ చేస్తారు.ఒప్పందము ప్రకారము మూలధనాన్ని తేవడం జరుగుతుంది."},{"question":"Goorma ayuu dhacay dagaalkii la magac baxay Jidbaale ee u dhaxeeyey dhaqdhaqaaqii Daraawiishta  iyo gumeystihii Ingiriiska?","answer":"Dagaalkii idbaale ee u dhaxeeyey dhaqdhaqaaqii Daraawiishta  iyo gumeystihii Ingiriiska waxa uu dhacay sanadkii 1904-tii."},{"question":"පහත යෙදුමේ තේරුම කුමක්ද?(කිතුල් කර්මාන්තය හා  සම්බන්ධවේ)තෙලිදිය/ තෙලිජ්ජ/ මීරා","answer":"මේ ගැන නම් හැම දෙනාම වාගේ අසා ඇති . ගසෙන් වෑස්සුණු දියරය මෙනමින් හැඳින්වේ. පැණි හකුරු සැකසීමේදී මේවා උණුකරණු ලැබේ."},{"question":"Qual o nome da fortaleza onde ocorre a batalha final no livro \\"O Senhor dos Anéis 3: O Retorno do Rei\\"?","answer":"A fortaleza onde ocorre a batalha final no livro \\"O Senhor dos Anéis 3: O Retorno do Rei\\" é chamada de \\"Mordor\\""},{"question":"కప్పల పెళ్లికి, వానకు గల సంబంధమేమిటో మీ సొంతమాటల్లో రాయండి.","answer":"కప్పల పెళ్లికి, వానకు గల సంబంధం ప్రకృతి సిద్ధమైనది. వర్షాకాలం రానంత వరకూ కప్పలెక్కడా ఎక్కువగా కనబడవు. వాటి బెకబెకలు వినబడవు. వర్షాలు ఎక్కువగా పడినపుడే కప్పలు అన్నీ పెళ్లివారిలా కలకలలాడుతూ వస్తాయి. బోదురు కప్పలు బెకబెకలాడుతూ పెళ్లి హడావుడి చేస్తాయి. సంతానం కలుగుతుంది. అందుకే కప్పలకు పెళ్లి చేస్తే వర్షం వస్తుందనే ఆచారం ఏర్పడింది."},{"question":"Sheeg syradaha loo yaqano lixda libaax?","answer":"Waa Baqarah ilaa Acraaf."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：人体最大的肌肉是什么？","answer":"答案：人体最大的肌肉是臀大肌。"},{"question":"Chitoro chinopa 20% kuderedzwa pachinhu chinodhura 80. Mutengo wakaderedzwa chii?","answer":"Discount = 20% ye 80 = 0.20 × 80 = 16Mutengo wakaderedzwa = Mutengo Wepakutanga - Discount = 80 - 16 = 64Mutengo wakaderedzwa i64."},{"question":"ဘယ်ဟာက ရေချိုအရင်းအမြစ်တစ်ခုအဖြစ် အသုံးပြုတဲ့ ကန်ရဲ့ ကျန်းမာရေးကို အကောင်းဆုံး ဆုံးဖြတ်ပေးလဲ။ သင့်အဖြေကို ရွေးပါ။ (၁) ၎င်းရဲ့ အနက်နဲ့ အနံ (၂) အပူချိန်နဲ့ pH (၃) ၎င်းရဲ့ တည်နေရာနဲ့ နက်ရှိုင်းမှု (၄) အပူချိန်နဲ့ နက်ရှိုင်းမှု ","answer":"အဖြေမှန်က (၂) အပူချိန်နဲ့ pH ပါ။"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fandoroana?","answer":"Ny fandoroana dia ny dingan'ny simika izay iatrehan'ny zavatra iray amin'ny oxidizer (matetika oksizenina eny amin'ny rivotra) mamokatra hafanana sy hazavana."},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?සුසිල්වත් ","answer":"දුසිල්වත්"},{"question":"Theo kế hoạch, Tập đoàn Dầu khí Quốc gia Việt Nam khai thác 12,37 triệu tấn dầu thô trong năm 2019.a) Hãy tính thể tích của lượng dầu thô khai thác năm 2019 theo kế hoạch, biết rằng khối lượng riêng của dầu thô (lấy tròn) là 900 kg/m3 và thể tích của một chất thì bằng khối lượng của chất đó chia cho khối lượng riêng của nó.b) Giả sử chúng ta phải vận chuyển hết lượng dầu thô khai thác năm 2019 đến các nhà máy lọc dầu bằng các tàu chở dầu thô có tải trọng 104 530 DWT (viết tắt của cụm từ tiếng Anh Deadweigit Tonnage, là đơn vị đo năng lực vận tải an toàn của tàu thuỷ). Biết rằng 1 DWT tương đương với 1,13 m3 (thể tích của khoang chứa dầu thô của tàu chở dầu). Cần ít nhất bao nhiêu chuyến tàu chở dầu thô như thế?","answer":"Lời giải:a) Đổi 12,37 triệu tấn = 12 370 000 000(kg)Thể tích của lượng dầu thô khai thác năm 2019 theo kế hoạch là:12 370 000 000: 900 ≈ 13 744 444,4 (m3).Vậy thể tích của lượng dầu thô khai thác năm 2019 theo kế hoạch là 13 744 444,4 m3.b) Đổi 13 744 444,4 m3 = 12 163 225,17 (DWT).Ta có: 12 163 225,2 : 104 503 ≈ 116,4.Do đó cần ít nhất 117 chuyến tàu chở dầu thô như thế.Vậy cần ít nhất 117 chuyến tàu chở dầu thô như thế."},{"question":"Qui était l'artiste Lawren Harris ?","answer":"Lawren Harris, membre du Groupe des Sept, était un peintre moderniste canadien pionnier. Ses paysages, comme « North Shore, Lake Superior », mettent l'accent sur des formes audacieuses et des couleurs vives pour capturer la grandeur de la nature sauvage canadienne. Le lien spirituel de Harris avec la nature et ses efforts pour établir une identité artistique canadienne distincte ont laissé un héritage durable."},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε το παρακάτω κείμενο. \\"Η προεδρία της Ευρωπαϊκής Ένωσης ασκείται ανά μισό χρόνο από\\"","answer":"Απάντηση: \\"ένα διαφορετικό κράτος μέλος\\""},{"question":"Qual ator americano estrelou ao lado de Kim Bassinger no filme 9½ Weeks?","answer":"O ator americano que estrelou ao lado de Kim Basinger no filme \\"9½ Weeks\\" (ou \\"Nove e Meia Semanas de Amor\\" em português) é Mickey Rourke. O filme foi lançado em 1986 e é um drama erótico que narra um relacionamento apaixonado e tumultuado entre os personagens interpretados por Rourke e Basinger."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：什麼是地震帶？","answer":"答案：地震帶是指地球上分布著許多地震活躍的區域，通常與板塊邊界、斷層帶或火山帶相關，這些地區發生地震的頻率較高。"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਃ ੧ ॥ਨ ਦਾਦੇ ਦਿਹੰਦ ਆਦਮੀ ॥ ਨ ਸਪਤ ਜੇਰ ਜਿਮੀ ॥ਅਸਤਿ ਏਕ ਦਿਗਰਿ ਕੁਈ ॥ਏਕ ਤੁਈ ਏਕ ਤੁਈ ॥੩॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 144 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਨਾਹ ਹੀ ਇਨਸਾਫ਼ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ (ਭਾਵ, ਦੂਜਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਝਗੜੇ ਨਿਬੇੜਨ ਵਾਲੇ) ਆਦਮੀ ਸਦਾ ਟਿਕੇ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਹਨ, ਨਾਹ ਹੀ ਧਰਤੀ ਦੇ ਹੇਠਲੇ ਸੱਤ (ਪਤਾਲ ਹੀ) ਸਦਾ ਰਹਿ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਸਦਾ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੋਰ ਦੂਜਾ ਕੌਣ ਹੈ ?ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਇਕ ਤੂੰ ਹੀ ਹੈ ।੩।\\""},{"question":"Kodi Malawi imadziwikanso ndi dzina loti chani?","answer":"Dzina lakuti Malawi likuchokera ku mawu akuti Maruvi, lomwe ndi dzina lakale la Achewa omwe amakhala m'Malawi. Dzina lotchulidwira la dzikoli ndi mtima wachikondi wa ku Africa chifukwa cha anthu ake ochezeka komanso olandira bwino."},{"question":"Rujuk petikan di bawah dan kemudian jawab soalan dalam bahasa yang sama seperti petikan:  Petikan: Bandar ini bermula dari penempatan yang diasaskan oleh Mon yang berhijrah dari Mottama (Thai) di Myanmar sekitar tahun 1650. Nama asalnya adalah \\"Sam Khok\\". Pada tahun 1815, Raja Rama II melawat bandar ini dan rakyat menawarkan kepadanya banyak bunga teratai, ini mendorong raja untuk menamakan bandar itu \\"Pathum Thani\\", yang bermaksud \\"bandar bunga teratai\\".  Soalan: Apa yang ditawarkan oleh rakyat kepada Raja Rama II semasa lawatan beliau?","answer":"bunga teratai"},{"question":"ජොහාන්‌ ලොමු ප්‍රසිද්ධවූ ක්‍රීඩාව කුමක්ද?","answer":"ජොහාන්‌ ලොමු ප්‍රසිද්ධවූ ක්‍රීඩාව රගර්‌ ක්‍රීඩාවය. රග්බි ලෝක කුසලානය අන්තර්ජාතික රග්බි කමිටුව මඟින් සංවිධානය කරනු ලබන ජාත්‍යන්තර රග්බි යූනියන් තරඟයක් වන අතර එය 1987 සිට සෑම අවුරුදු 4කට වරක් පවත්වාගෙන එනු ලැබේ. ජයග්‍රහයකයින් හට විලියම් වෙබ් එලිස් කුසලනය ප්‍රධානය කරනු ලැබේ."},{"question":"살면서 맨물로 세수만 해왔지 피부관리를 아예 안하고살다가.. 22살이 되어서야 스킨로션, 달팽이크림이란걸 처음써봤습니다(피부가 넘 건조해져서)얼마전엔 토너도 써보다가 보습효과가 별로인거 같아서 오늘부터 다시 달팽이크림만 바르기로 했는데 달팽이크림만 발라도 피부관리엔 문제없는 수준일까요? 피부관리에 관심도 없고 아는게 없어서요 ㅜㅜ","answer":"화장품보다 일찍 자고, 물을 많이 마시고, 잘 씻는 습관이 중요합니다. "},{"question":"ਸਵਾਲ – ਜੇਕਰ ਆਪਾਂ ਸਿੱਧੂ ਮੂਸੇਵਾਲੇ ਦੇ ਕਤਲ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਕਰੀਏ ਤਾਂ ਉਹਦੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿੰਨੇ ਜਿਆਦਾ ਗੈਂਗਸਟਰਜ਼, ਇੰਡੀਆ ਦੀਆਂ ਕਿੰਨੀਆਂ ਸਟੇਟਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਸਨ ਪਰ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਈ ਅਜਿਹੀ ਸਟੇਟ ਆ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਦੇ ਗੈਂਗਸਟਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਾ ਬਣਿਆਂ ਤੇ ਫੋਟੋਆਂ ਵੀ ਅਜਿਹੀਆਂ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਈਆਂ ਜਿਸਦੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਗਦਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਾ ਸਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰੇ ਗਵਾਹ ਵੀ ਹਨ ਜਿਹੜੇ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਧਾਰਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੱਸਦੇ, ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਸਮਝਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਜਵਾਬ – ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਗੱਲ ਦੇ ਜਵਾਬ ’ਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਕਿ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਾ ਅਸਲੀ ਸੀ ਜਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਰ ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਬੜੀ ਸਧਾਰਨ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜੇ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਜਾਂ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਬੰਦੇ ਜਿਉਂਦੇ ਫੜਨੇ ਹਨ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਕੋਈ ਮੁਸ਼ਕਿਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ । ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕੋਲ ਇੱਕ ਏ.ਕੇ. ੪੭ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਤੂਸ ਸੀ । ਸਰਕਾਰ ਕੋਲ ਤਾਂ ਹੁਣ ਬਹੁਤ ਜਿਆਦਾ ਹਥਿਆਰ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਸਰਕਾਰ ਬੜੇ ਅਰਾਮ ਨਾਲ ਦੂਰੀ ’ਤੇ ਮਾਰ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਹਥਿਆਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ’ਚ ਬੰਨ੍ਹ ਕੇ ਰੱਖ ਸਕਦੀ ਸੀ । ਪਰ ਮੇਰੇ ਖਿਆਲ ਨਾਲ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਨੀਤੀ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਾ ਚਾਹੇ ਅਸਲੀ, ਚਾਹੇ ਨਕਲੀ ’ਚ ਮਾਰਨ ਦੀ ਸੀ।ਮੈਂ ਇੱਕ ਉਦਾਹਰਣ ਦੇ ਸਕਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਜੇ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਆਤਮ ਸਮਰਪਣ ਹੀ ਕਰਵਾਉਣਾ ਹੋਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੱਦ ਤੱਕ ਵੀ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ । ਜਦੋਂ ਮਈ ੧੯੮੮ ਦੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਦਰਬਾਰ ਸਾਹਿਬ ‘ਬਲੈਕ ਥੰਡਰ’ ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਹਮਲਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਤਾਂ ਅੰਦਰ ਜਿਹੜੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਸਨ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਥੋੜ੍ਹਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਬਹੁਤਾ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਜਿਹੜਾ ਕਮਜੋਰ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਦੇ ਤੌਰ ’ਤੇ ਥੋੜ੍ਹਾ ਹੋਛਾ ਵੀ ਸੀ, ਉਹ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਅੰਦਰ ਜਾਣ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਸੀ । ਸੋ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਮਿਥਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਇਹਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਜਿਉਂਦੇ ਹੀ ਫੜ੍ਹਨਾ ਹੈ ਇਸ ਲਈ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਦਰਬਾਰ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਅੰਦਰ ਲੜਾਕੂਆਂ ਦੀ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਇੰਨਾ ਸੰਜੀਦਾ ਮਸਲਾ ਹੋਣ ਦੇ ਬਾਵਜੂਦ ਦੋ-ਤਿੰਨ ਦਿਨ ਲਾ ਕੇ, ਲੰਬੀ ਦੂਰੀ ਤੋਂ ਮਾਰ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਹਥਿਆਰ (ਸਨਾਈਪਰ ਬੰਦੂਕਾਂ) ਵਰਤ ਕੇ, ਓਹਨਾ ਤੋਂ ਆਤਮ ਸਮਰਪਣ ਕਰਵਾ ਲਿਆ ਸੀ।ਮੈਂ ਇਹ ਉਦਾਹਰਣ ਇਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜੇ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਨੀਤੀ ਆਤਮ ਸਮਰਪਣ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਹੋਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਤਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਰ ਬਹੁਤੀ ਵਾਰ ਆਤਮ ਸਮਰਪਣ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਵਿਚ ਸਫਲ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਸੋ ਜਿਸ ਘਟਨਾ ਬਾਰੇ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਸਵਾਲ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ ਹੈ ਮੇਰੇ ਖਿਆਲ ’ਚ ਇਥੇ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਨੀਤੀ ਆਤਮ ਸਮਰਪਣ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ, ਸਗੋਂ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਦੀ ਸੀ । ਇਹਦੇ ’ਚੋਂ ਮਿਲ ਰਹੇ ਸੁਨੇਹੇ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਝਣ ਦੀ ਆਪਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਲੋੜ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"O ma ṣe o, kọmisanna Akeredolu mi-in tun ku lojiji","answer":"Iyalẹnu nla lo jẹ fawọn eeyan ipinlẹ Ondo lati gbọ ikede iku kọmisanna mi-in ninu iṣejọba Gomina Rotimi Akeredolu lẹyin bii oṣu marun-un pere ti kọmisanna feto ilera, Dokita Wahab Adegbenro, jade laye.Ọjọgbọn Bayọnle Ademodi to jẹ kọmisanna to n ri sọrọ ibaṣepọ to wa laarin ipinlẹ Ondo atawọn orilẹ-ede mi-in lagbaaye lo deedee fo sanlẹ, to si gba ọrun lọ nileewosan kan niluu Ọba.Alaga afunsọ fun ijọba ibilẹ Ila-Oorun Ondo tẹlẹ, Wale Akinlọsotu, lo kọkọ tufọ iku agba oloṣelu ọhun lọsan-an ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide.Lati fidi iṣẹlẹ iku ọmọ bibi ilu Ondo ọhun mulẹ, Kọmisanna feto iroyin, Donald Ọjọgo, ti ranṣẹ ibanikẹdun sawọn ẹbi rẹ lorukọ Gomina Akeredolu.Ninu ọrọ ibanikẹdun wọn, ẹgbẹ APC, ẹka tipinlẹ Ondo, juwe iku Ọjọgbọn Ademodi bii adanu nla fẹgbẹ wọn."},{"question":"කැඩුණු බිඳුණු දෙයක් යළි සැකසීම  යන්නට තනි වචනයක් දෙන්න.","answer":"ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය "},{"question":"ਸਵਾਲਃ ਕਿਨ ਵਸਤੂਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਰਤਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਪਲਾਸਟਿਕ?","answer":"ਜਵਾਬਃ ਵੱਖ ਵੱਖ ਵਸਤੂਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਰਤਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਪਲਾਸਟਿਕ |ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਵਰਤੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਪਲਾਸਟਿਕ ਉਤਪਾਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਲਾਸਟਿਕ ਦੇ ਬੈਗ (ਪੰਜਾਹ ਮਾਈਕਰੋਨ ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ) ਸ਼ਾਮਿਲ ਹਨ। ਫਿਰ ਪੈਕਿੰਗ ਫਿਲਮ, ਫੋਮ ਕੱਪ, ਲੈਮੀਨੇਟਡ ਕਟੋਰੇ ਅਤੇ ਪਲੇਟਾਂ, ਛੋਟੇ ਪਲਾਸਟਿਕ ਦੇ ਕੱਪ ਅਤੇ ਡੱਬੇ (ਕੰਟੇਨਰ) (150 ਮਿਲੀਗ੍ਰਾਮ ਅਤੇ ਪੰਜ ਗ੍ਰਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ), ਪਲਾਸਟਿਕ ਦੀਆਂ ਖਾਣ ਲਈ ਵਰਤੀਆਂ ਜਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਛੋਟੀਆਂ ਡੰਡੀਆਂ (ਸਟਿਕਸ) ਅਤੇ ਈਅਰ ਬਡਜ਼, ਗੁਬਾਰੇ, ਝੰਡੇ ਅਤੇ ਪਲਾਸਟਿਕ ਦੇ ਉਤਪਾਦ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ ਕੈਂਡੀ, ਪੀਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਲਈ ਛੋਟੇ ਪਲਾਸਟਿਕ ਦੇ ਪੈਕੇਟ (ਦੋ ਸੌ ਮਾਈਕਰੋਨ ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ) ਅਤੇ ਸੜਕ ਕਿਨਾਰੇ ਬੇੈਨਰ (ਇੱਕ ਸੌ ਮਾਈਕਰੋਨ ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ) ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹਨ।"},{"question":"Wymień cztery pory roku.","answer":"Cztery pory roku to: zima, wiosna, lato, jesień."},{"question":"Qual é a capital do Chile?","answer":"A capital do Chile é Santiago. Santiago é a maior cidade do Chile e o centro político, econômico e cultural do país."},{"question":"मानव शरीरमा मुटुको काम के हो?","answer":"मुटुले शरीरभर रगत पम्प गर्छ, कोशिकाहरूमा अक्सिजन र पोषक तत्वहरू पुर्‍याउँछ र फोहोर उत्पादनहरू हटाउँछ।"},{"question":"Umi entabeni yedwa ulindele ingoduso yakhe uNtombi, uyacabanga.'Omama bathanda ukwazi ukuthi uganwa nini. Okungidina kakhulu, ilo othandaukukukhombisa intombi ethandwa uyena ukuthi igane mina. Kanti bona abazi yiniukuthi induku enhle igawulwa ezizweni na? Hoo! Ngikhumbula ngiqala ukufika kulendawo yaseMvoti izinsizwa zisho ukungiqeda ngenduku. Kwakungadlalwa.Ngadlel'ogageni. Ngake ngavika kwavuthuka izandla, bela abafokazi.1. Yiziphi izinto EZIMBILI ezadina/ezacasula uManyoba ngokwalesi siqephu? ","answer":"Ucasulwa omama abathanda ukwazi ukuthi uganwa nini. • Uphinde acasulwe kakhulu umama othanda ukumkhombisa intombiethandwa nguye ukuthi imgane."},{"question":"Ahoana no fampahafantarana ny voka-pifidianana amin’ny vahoaka?","answer":"Amin'ny alàlan'ny haino aman-jery, tranokala ofisialy ary fanambarana ofisialy no fomba fampahafantarana ny voka-pifidianana amin'ny vahoaka."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය ගයනා  කරන්නේ කව්ද ?මිරිවැඩි සඟලක් ඉල්ලා හැඬුවෙමිපායුග නැති ඔබ දකින තුරාකුංකුම අංජන ඉල්ලා හැඬුවෙමිනෙත් යුග නැති ඔබ දකින තුරාමාවත කටු අතු බොරළු මතක නැතදෙපා රැඳුණු විට බුමුතුරුණේදොරකඩ යදියන් ඉඳුල් යදින සඳමැදුරේ දෙසවන් අගුළු වැටේසඳ කිඳුරන් ඇත සඳළු තලාවේරස මසවුළු වල සුවඳ පිරේඒ රස සුවඳට දෑස අයාගෙනබත් ඇට ඇහිඳිති පොඩි දරුවෝ","answer":"නන්දා  මාලිනී"},{"question":"プロ野球で２００７年からセ・リーグ、パ・リーグともに採用した、レギュラーシーズンの上位３チームによる日本シリーズ出場権を争うゲームの名称を何シリーズと言うでしょう？","answer":"クライマックスシリーズです。"},{"question":"Gava hono inonzi chii?","answer":"gava"},{"question":"మీ పాఠశాలను గురించి మీ మిత్రునకు లేఖ రాయండి.","answer":"తెనాలి,x x x x x.పి. రామచంద్ర,10వ తరగతి, శారదా కాన్వెంట్,రాజావీధి, తెనాలి,గుంటూరు జిల్లా, ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్.మిత్రుడు రవికాంత్ కు,నేను కొత్తగా చేరిన శారదా కాన్వెంట్ అందాల బృందావనంలా ఉంది. మా కాన్వెంట్ 5 ఎకరాల స్థలంలో ఉంది. ఎత్తైన భవనాలు ఉన్నాయి. ప్రతి తరగతి గదిలోనూ ఫ్యాన్లు, ట్యూబ్ లైట్లు ఉన్నాయి. ముఖ్యంగా మా సైన్సు ప్రయోగశాలలు చక్కగా అన్ని పరికరాలతో అందంగా తీర్చిదిద్దినట్లుంటాయి.నిత్యం అసెంబ్లీ జరిగేచోట సరస్వతీ దేవి విగ్రహం రంగురంగుల అలంకరణలతో అద్భుతంగా ఉంటుంది. మా కాన్వెంటు అందం అంతా క్రీడా మైదానంలో ఉంది. అన్ని ఆటలకూ కోర్సులు ఉన్నాయి. మైదానం అంతా శుభ్రంగా ఉంటుంది.కాన్వెంటులో పూలతోట ఉంది. అక్కడ అన్ని రకాల పూల మొక్కలు ఉన్నాయి. కుళాయి నీరు 24 గంటలు వస్తుంది. బాలబాలికలకు వేరువేరుగా మరుగుదొడ్లు ఉన్నాయి.మా ప్రధానోపాధ్యాయుల గది చాలా ఆకర్షణీయంగా ఉంటుంది. ఈ కాన్వెంట్ లో చేరినందులకు సంతోషంగా ఉంది. ఉంటా.ఇట్లు,నీ మిత్రుడు,పి.రామచంద్ర.చిరునామా:యస్. రవికాంత్,C/O. యస్. వెంకట్రావుగారు,తాశీల్దార్, అమలాపురం,తూ. గో. జిల్లా, ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్."},{"question":"तुळजापूर येथील तुळजाभवानी मंदिराचा इतिहास काय आहे?","answer":"तुळजा भवानी मंदिर हे भारतातील महाराष्ट्रातील उस्मानाबाद जिल्ह्यातील तुळजापूर शहरात असलेले तुळजा भवानी देवीला समर्पित एक प्रमुख हिंदू मंदिर आहे. हिंदू पौराणिक कथा आणि इतिहासात मंदिराला विशेष महत्त्व आहे, विशेषतः मराठा योद्धा राजा छत्रपती शिवाजी महाराज आणि मराठा साम्राज्याच्या संबंधात. तुळजाभवानी मंदिराच्या इतिहासाचा हा थोडक्यात आढावा:प्राचीन उत्पत्ती: मंदिराची नेमकी उत्पत्ती योग्यरित्या दस्तऐवजीकरण केलेली नाही, परंतु ती प्राचीन मुळे असल्याचे मानले जाते. तुळजा भवानी ही देवी दुर्गा किंवा पार्वतीच्या रूपांपैकी एक मानली जाते. देवी महाराष्ट्रात अत्यंत पूजनीय आहे आणि मराठी भाषिक लोकांच्या हृदयात तिचे विशेष स्थान आहे.छत्रपती शिवाजी महाराजांशी संबंध: तुळजा भवानी मंदिराच्या सर्वात महत्त्वाच्या ऐतिहासिक पैलूंपैकी एक म्हणजे त्याचा मराठा साम्राज्याचे संस्थापक छत्रपती शिवाजी महाराज यांच्याशी असलेला संबंध. अशी आख्यायिका आहे की देवी शिवाजीच्या स्वप्नात दिसली आणि तिला तलवार शोधण्याची सूचना दिली, जी त्याला त्याच्या प्रयत्नात मदत करेल. त्याने देवीच्या सूचनांचे पालन केले आणि त्याला एक तलवार सापडली, जी \\"भवानी तलवार\\" (भवानीची तलवार) म्हणून ओळखली गेली. असे मानले जाते की शिवरायांच्या यशात देवीच्या आशीर्वादाने महत्त्वपूर्ण भूमिका बजावली.स्थापत्य आणि नूतनीकरण: मंदिराच्या संकुलात पारंपारिक मराठी वास्तुकला आहे, ज्यामध्ये गर्भगृह (गर्भगृह) देवतेचे निवासस्थान आहे. भाविकांच्या वाढत्या संख्येला सामावून घेण्यासाठी शतकानुशतके मंदिराचे विविध नूतनीकरण आणि विस्तार करण्यात आले आहेत. सध्याची रचना ही या सलग नूतनीकरणाचा परिणाम आहे.सण आणि भक्ती: मंदिरात वर्षभर भाविकांची मोठी गर्दी असते, नवरात्रोत्सवादरम्यान विशेष महत्त्व असते. नवरात्रीच्या दरम्यान, मंदिर एका भव्य उत्सवाचे साक्षीदार आहे, देशाच्या विविध भागातून यात्रेकरूंना आकर्षित करते.सांस्कृतिक महत्त्व: तुळजा भवानी मंदिर हे केवळ धार्मिक महत्त्वाचे ठिकाण नाही तर महाराष्ट्रातील सांस्कृतिक महत्त्वही आहे. छत्रपती शिवाजी महाराज यांच्याशी आणि मराठा साम्राज्याच्या स्थापनेसाठी त्यांनी केलेल्या संघर्षांमुळे हे मराठी अभिमान आणि इतिहासाशी संबंधित आहे.तीर्थक्षेत्र: विशेषत: महाराष्ट्रातील भक्त आशीर्वाद, शक्ती आणि संरक्षण मिळविण्यासाठी तीर्थक्षेत्र म्हणून तुळजा भवानी मंदिराला भेट देतात. मंदिर हे दैवी शक्ती आणि धैर्याचे प्रतीक मानले जाते.संरक्षण: मंदिराचे ऐतिहासिक आणि धार्मिक महत्त्व टिकून राहावे यासाठी सरकार आणि विविध धार्मिक ट्रस्ट यांनी मंदिराचे जतन आणि देखभाल केली आहे.सारांश, तुळजापूर येथील तुळजाभवानी मंदिराचा इतिहास हिंदू पौराणिक कथा आणि छत्रपती शिवाजी महाराजांचा वारसा यांत गुंफलेला समृद्ध इतिहास आहे. हे भक्त आणि इतिहासप्रेमींसाठी एक आदरणीय धार्मिक आणि सांस्कृतिक स्थळ आहे."},{"question":"නැගෙනහිර පාකිස්ථානය බංග්ලාදේශය බවට පත් වූයේ කිනම් වසරේද?","answer":"1971 වසරේ නැගෙනහිර පාකිස්ථානය බංග්ලාදේශය බවට පත් වූවා ."},{"question":"\\"kugadzirisa pachinzvimbo chekugadzirisa\\" ipa pfungwa shanu kutsigira nharo iyi","answer":"\\"1) inochengetedza mutengo2) inoderedza kutambisa3) yakanaka kune zvakatipoteredza4) inokurudzira basa remunharaunda5) kushandiswa zvakanaka kwezviwanikwa\\""},{"question":"Maine ma’anar \\"Abdomen\\" a Hausa?","answer":"Abdomen na nufi ciki"},{"question":"KUNJALO-KE – ME WandaXoxa ngempumelelo yombhali ekwethuleni isizinda senoveli ethi: Kunjalo-ke","answer":"KUNJALO-KE – ME WandaXoxa ngempumelelo yombhali ekwethuleni isizinda senoveli ethi: Kunjalo-ke.UKheswa uvumela uDumazile ukuba aye kofunda eMbumbulu ngokubonisana noMaNdovela.  UMaNdovela uxoshwa uKheswa uma uDumazile ebuya esikoleni ekhulelwe.UDumazile usebenza esitolo sikaSithole. ULizy utshela uMaNzimande ukuthi uDumazile uthandana noSithole.  UMaNzimande uxabana noSithole ngodaba lukaDumazile.  USithole ushiya umuzi wakhe noMaNzimande uhlala noDumazile eMlazi eMafezini. USithole ubuyela kwakhe ngenkathi ephuma ejele, ufica uMaNzimande esesebenza futhi sebehlupheka..Dumazile uhlala noSithole, uSithole uyaboshwa, agcine ehleli noMtalaselwa emzini kaSithole. UMoloi noSithole bayalwa baze baphume emaphepheni.KwaNongomaUDumazile ulaliswe esibhedlela, ushonela khona.EMid-Illovo (kwaJilafohlo)UDumazile ungcwatshelwa emzini, kubo kaMtalaselwa.Isikhathi sanamuhlaLe ndaba yenzeka esikhathini sanamuhla. Kuningi okwenziwa abalingiswa abehlukene kule ndaba okufakazela isikhathi samanje.UDumazile ufunda amabanga aphezulu eZenzele High School uhlala emqashweni.UMoloi uthandana noDumazile ebe eyingane yesikole uze uyamkhulelisaUDumazile uya emsebenzini ngemoto "},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--का ग बाई रोड (तर म्हणे) गावाची ओढ","answer":"निरर्थक गोष्टींची काळजी करणे."},{"question":"Ẹ wo ọmọ iya meji ti wọn n ṣẹgbẹ okunkun l’Ondo","answer":"Ọwọ awọn ẹsọ alaabo ilu Ondo ti tẹ tẹgbọn-taburo kan, Sẹgun ati Azeez Adeoye, ti wọn fẹsun kan pe wọn lọwọ ninu bawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun ṣe n para wọn nipakupa niluu Ondo ti i ṣe ibujokoo ijọba ibilẹ Iwọ-Oorun Ondo lati bii oṣu diẹ sẹyin.Gẹgẹ ba a ṣe gbọ, awọn ọmọ iya meji ọhun ati ẹnikan ti wọn n pe ni Isaiah ni wọn fẹsun kan pe wọn ṣeku pa fijilante kan, Ṣeun Akinsiku, si agbegbe Oke-Agunla, niluu Ondo, lọjọ kẹtalelogun, oṣu keje, ọdun ta a wa yii.Ọjọ kẹrin lẹyin eyi, iyẹn lalẹ ọjọ kẹrindinlọgbọn, osu kan naa, ni wọn lawọn mẹtẹẹta tun pa ẹlomi-in tawọn eeyan mọ si, Owolabi Ọladele.Ọladele to jẹ akẹkọọ ọlọdun kẹta lẹka ti wọn ti n kọ nipa ẹṣin Kristiẹni nile-iwe olukọni agba Adeyẹmi la gbọ pe wọn pa si adugbo Tẹrẹrẹ, lagbegbe New Town, l’Ondo.Ọjọ kẹtadinlọgbọn lọwọ tẹ Isaiah ti wọn jọ n ṣiṣẹ ibi, oun lo si darukọ Sẹgun ati Azeez lasiko ti wọn n fọrọ wa a lẹnu wo.Awọn ikọ ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun naa ni wọn tun mori le gbọngan Civic Centre to wa lagbegbe Sabo lọjọ yii kan naa, nibi ti wọn ti ṣe ọkan ninu awọn ẹsọ Peace Corps to n ṣọ ibẹ leṣe yannayanna ki wọn too sa lọ.Ṣe ni idunnu ṣubu layọ fawọn ọdọ ilu Ondo l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee ọsẹ yii, nigba tọwọ apapọ awọn ẹsọ alaabo, ninu eyi ta a ti ri, ẹsọ Amọtẹkun, awọn ọlọpaa, OPC atawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ to n mojuto eto aabo ilu Ondo pada tẹ ọmọ iya kan naa ti wọn n huwa buruku yii.Awọn mejeeji ni wọn ti n ṣeto ati fi ṣọwọ si olu ileesẹ ọlọpaa to n gbogun ti awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun l’Akurẹ lasiko ti a n ko iroyin yii jọ lọwọ."},{"question":"పెరిప్లానెటాలో ఆహారనాళం నత్రజని సంబంధ వ్యర్థాలను తొలగిస్తుంది. ఎందుకు?","answer":"పెరిప్లానెటా ఆహార నాళం నత్రజని సంబంధిత వ్యర్థాలను తొలగించే ప్రక్రియ. వ్యర్థాలనుంచి నీటిని పునః శోషణ చేయడానికి అనార్థ యూరిక్ ఆమ్లం తయారవడానికి తోడ్పడుతుంది. ఇది దేహంలోని నీటిని సంరక్షించుకునే అనుకూలనం."},{"question":"Schrijf een voortzetting van de paragraaf: Na de Slag bij Cerro Gordo in april 1847 werd hij gepromoveerd tot majoor. Hij vocht ook bij Contreras, Churubusco","answer":"en Chapultepec, en raakte gewond in de laatste van deze drie. Tegen het einde van de oorlog was hij luitenant-kolonel."},{"question":"Awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun yii n lọọ gbẹsan iku ọkan lara wọn lọwọ tẹ wọn l’Ọta","answer":"Bi awo ba ku awo ni i sinku awo ni wọn fẹẹ fọrọ ṣe ko too bu wọn lọwọ o, iyẹn awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun marun-un ti mọto pa ọkan lara wọn ti wọn si fẹẹ lọọ gbẹsan iku naa, ti wọn waa n gbe oku kiri ninu kẹkẹ Marwa, lagbegbe Ọta, nipinlẹ Ogun, lọjọ Mọnde, ọjọ kẹrinla oṣu kejila ọdun 2020.Awọn ti wọn n gbe oku kiri naa ni: Babatunde Shittu; ẹni ọdun mẹẹẹdọgbọn(25), Ayọbami Morẹnikeji; ọmọ ọdun mẹẹẹdogun,(15) Fidelis John; ẹni ọdun mẹtalelogun(23) Abdullah Adegbenro; ọmọ ọdun mẹtadinlogun (17) ati Oyeyẹmi Bakare ti oun jẹ ọmọ ogun ọdún(20)DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, Alukoro ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun, ṣalaye pe awọn eeyan ni wọn ta awọn ọlọpaa lolobo pe awọn kan n gbe oku èèyàn kiri ninu kẹkẹ Maruwa, wọn mu ori le ọna Ọta, ṣugbọn pẹlu nnkan ija bii ada ati kumọ ni wọn n lọ.Eyi lo mu ACP Monday Agbonika ti i ṣe ọga ọlọpaa agbegbe Sango ko awọn eeyan rẹ lẹyin, ni wọn ba ri awọn to n gbe oku kiri naa loju ọna Ilo Awẹla, nibi ti wọn ti n ba dukia awọn eeyan jẹ, ti wọn n ja awọn ẹni ẹlẹni to n kọja lọ lole pelu awọn nnkan ija ti wọn ni lọwọ.Awọn marun-un lọwọ ba ninu wọn, wọn ṣalaye pe pati lawọn lọ ni Muṣin, l’Ekoo, bi ija ṣe ṣẹlẹ nigba tawọn n pada bọ niyẹn, to di pe àwọn alatako awọn fi mọto pa ọmọkunrin tawọn n gbe oku ẹ kiri yii. Wọn ni ile ẹbi awọn to pa a lawọn n gbe oku naa lọ lati gbẹsan iku rẹ. Orukọ awọn to pa a naa gẹgẹ bi wọn ṣe da a ni: Ọmọ ẹkùn, Lampard àti Anko.Alukoro ọlọpaa sọ pe kawọn eeyan oun too de ibi ti wọn ti mu awọn ọmọ yii, awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun naa ti ba mọto jiipu Highlander kan jẹ. Emmanuel Adekọya lorukọ ẹni to ni mọto naa, KJA 275GD si ni nọmba rẹ bi Oyeyẹmi ṣe wi. O ni wọn ti ja foonu Infinix gba lọwọ Falọla Olushọla, wọn si ti gba ẹgbẹrun lọ́na àádọ́ta naira lọwọ ẹnikan to n jẹ Emmanuel Agbaje.Àwọn ọlọpaa ti gba oku naa lọwọ wọn, wọn ti gbe e lọ si mọṣuari Ifọ, wọn si ko awọn agbokuukiri naa lọ sẹka itọpinpin gẹgẹ bii aṣẹ CP Edward Ajogun."},{"question":"ما هي السورة التي يبلغ عدد آياتها ١١ آية فقط؟.\\tسورة الجمعة.","answer":"\\tسورة الجمعة."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Bước sang tháng Ngâu, thị trường xe máy đã bắt đầu có dấu hiệu hạ nhiệt. Không đứng ngoài cuộc, mới đây, \\"xe nhà giàu\\" Honda Vision đã được nhiều đại lý giảm mạnh tới gần 20 triệu đồng. Cụ thể, tại khu vực Hà Nội, Honda Vision 2021 bản tiêu chuẩn có giá 40 triệu đồng, bản cao cấp giá 43,25 triệu đồng, bản đặc biệt có giá 46,15 triệu đồng và bản cá tính có giá 46-49 triệu đồng (tuỳ từng đại lý). Đây là một trong những tin vui đối với khách hàng có ý định mua Honda Vision sau một thời gian dài đội giá cao ngất. Trước đó vào thời điểm cuối tháng 6, Honda Vision bản tiêu chuẩn có giá 47,55  triệu đồng, bản cao cấp có giá 49,195 triệu đồng, bản đặc biệt có giá 50,2 triệu đồng. Riêng bản cá tính vẫn giữ giá bán là 53,173 triệu đồng, thậm chí có thời điểm lên đến 60 triệu đồng. Được biết, Honda Vision là mẫu xe tay ga giá rẻ được giới trẻ ưa chuộng. Mẫu xe máy luôn đạt thành tích doanh số ấn tượng tại thị trường Việt Nam nhờ kiểu dáng thanh lịch, nhỏ gọn và trẻ trung. Thiết kế trên xe có nhiều trang bị tiện ích. Điển hình như đèn chiếu sáng bằng bóng LED tự động bật sáng, chìa khóa thông minh Smartkey, phía trước có hộc đựng đồ với nắp đậy... Trong khi đó dưới yên ngồi cốp đựng đồ rộng rãi và có trang bị ổ sạc điện thoại. Xe sử dụng động cơ eSP tiên tiến, phun xăng điện tử PGM-Fi, bộ đề ACG và hệ thống ngắt động cơ tạm thời Idling Stop, giúp xe tiết kiệm xăng và vận hành linh hoạt. Việc Honda Vision liên tục tăng nóng trong thời gian qua khiến mẫu xe này lép vế trước các đối thủ cạnh tranh như Yamaha Janus khi mà dòng xe này có giá bán hấp dẫn hơn. Từng có thời điểm, nhiều người dùng không khỏi cảm thán cho rằng ngày trước đi SH thể hiện đẳng cấp, giờ đi Vision mới là đại gia. Theo Quỳnh Anh","answer":"Honda Vision bất ngờ giảm mạnh tới 20 triệu đồng, rời khỏi hội 'xe nhà giàu'"},{"question":"Жети ата кандай аталган?","answer":" Жети ата төмөнкүдөй  аталышы, элдин аң-сезимине абдан терең сиңген: 1. ата, 2.чоң ата, 3. баба, 4. буба, 5. кубаар, 6. жото, 7. жете. Элдин эсинде сакталып калган «кубаарыңдын куу чокусу, мадериңдин баш териси» (мадер түштүк диалектиде эне), «кудай кылса кубаарыңдын акысы барбы?», «жото-жетесиз кул», «жетеге жетчү кек», «жети атасынан бери жиликтеп сура» деген сыяктуу көөнө түшүнүктөр болгон."},{"question":"Zein da euskal hizkuntzaren jatorri teoriarik ezagunena eta zer eragin du ikerketan?","answer":"Euskal hizkuntzaren jatorri teoriarik ezagunena isolatua dela da, hau da, ez du hizkuntza familia jakin batekin harremanik. Ikerketan eragin handia izan du, hainbat ikerketa linguistiko eta historiko abian jartzeko."},{"question":"من فضلك ادينى نبذة عن أم كلثوم.","answer":"ده شئ يسعدنى. أدي نبذه عن أم كلثوم.ام كلثوم هى مطربة مصرية اتلقبت بـ \\" كوكب الشرق \\" و سماها المصريين \\" الست \\". اتولدت فى قريه بسيطه من قرى مصر اسمها \\" طماى الزهايره \\" و حبت الغنا من صغرها فكانت بتغنى بين مروج القطن فى قريتها و سحرت الفلاحين بجمال صوتها و اتعرفت فى القرى المجاوره فابتدت تغنى فى الحفلات اللى كان بيعملها الموظفين و اشتهرت فى الاقاليم. راحت القاهره سنة 1920 ، و اعجب الموسيقيين بصوتها ، و كان منهم محمد القصبجى فشجعها بألحانه. الف ليها الشعرا احمد شوقى و احمد رامى و بيرم التونسى و غيرهم اغانى و قصايد و اناشيد، و لحن ليها الملحنيين المصريين الكبار رياض السنباطى و زكريا احمد و محمد عبد الوهاب و بليغ حمدى و سيد مكاوى. اشتركت فى كذا فيلم مصرى زى فيلم \\" سلامه \\" و شاركت بصوتها بس فى فيلم رابعه العدويه.أم كلثوم بتتربع على قمة الغناء المصرى و بتعتبراكبر مغنيه ظهرت فى مصر فى العصر الحديث. من أشهر أغانيها: ألف ليلة و ليلة، يا ليلة العيد، حب أيه، انت عمرى."},{"question":"Continua - Nel 1929-30 risultò decisivo per la vittoria del terzo scudetto interista. Negli anni successivi fece da riserva prima a Carlo Ceresoli, poi a","answer":" Giuseppe Peruchetti. Giocò la sua ultima partita in nerazzuro nel 1937, contro la Roma, in Coppa Italia."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Bencana alam yang berlaku dalam tengkorak manusia.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah sakit kepala. "},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH do Haiti?","answer":"0,535."},{"question":"Ndeipi nzvimbo yakanakisa yekushanyira muGreece","answer":"\\"Santorini kana chero Greek IslandAtene\\""},{"question":"புத்தரின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"ஒவ்வொரு மாற்றத்திற்கும் ஒரு காரணம் உண்டு. காரணமின்றி விளைவில்லை. இவை இரண்டும் இணைந்து செல்கின்றன. நிரந்தரமானது என்று எதையும் ஏற்க முடியாது."},{"question":"વડોદરા શહેરનો ઇતિહાસ","answer":"વડોદરા  ગુજરાત રાજ્યના મધ્ય ભાગમાં આવેલું અને વિશ્વામિત્રી નદીને કિનારે વસેલું શહેર  છે, જે ઐતિહાસિક, સાંસ્કૃતિક અને આર્થિક દ્રષ્ટિએ મહત્વપૂર્ણ છે.વડોદરા શહેર પ્રાચીન અસ્મિતા તથા અદ્યતન પ્રગતિશીલતાનો સમન્વય છે. મહારાજા સયાજીરાવ ગાયકવાડના સમયનાં મહેલો, મંદિરો તથા સ્મારકો અને અદ્યતન શોપિંગ કોમ્પ્લેક્સ તથા મલ્ટીપ્લેક્સ સિનેમાઘરો તેનો પુરાવો છે. વડોદરાને ભારતની 'સંસ્કાર નગરી' તરીકે પણ ઓળખવામાં આવે છે.લક્ષ્મી વિલાસ મહેલ, વડોદરા મ્યુઝિયમ એન્ડ પિક્ચર ગેલરી, નજરબાગ પ્રાકૃતિ પર્ક,નજર બાગ મહેલ, કંધેરી મહાદેવ મંદિર, સયાજી બાગ (કમાટી બાગ), મહારાજા ફતેહસિંહ મ્યુજીયમ જેવ સ્થળો વડોદરામાં આપ્યા છે.વડોદરા ગુજરાત રાજ્યનું મહત્વનું ઔદ્યોગિક કેન્દ્ર પણ છે જેમાં પેટ્રોકેમિકલ્સ, રાસાયણિક, ટેક્સટાઇલ્સ તથા ઇજનેરી ઉદ્યોગોનો સમાવેશ થાય છે.ડોદરા જિલ્લાનું તાજેતરમાં વિભાજન થયું છે અને નવો છોટાઉદેપુર જિલ્લો વડોદરા જીલ્લાની પૂર્વમાં અસ્તિત્વમાં આવ્યો છે."},{"question":"‘మానవా? నీ ప్రయత్నం మానవా?’ ఈ వాక్యంలో అలంకారం గుర్తించి, లక్షణం రాయండి.","answer":"యమకము : ఒకే పదం, అర్థభేదంతో ప్రయోగించడం యమకం."},{"question":"Nahazo ny fahaleovantenany tamin’i Frantsa i Madagasikara tamin’ny 1960. Marina sa diso?","answer":"Marina. Nahazo ny fahaleovantenany tamin’i Frantsa i Madagasikara tamin’ny 26 jona 1960."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : సౌర కుటుంబం అనగానేమి?","answer":"సూర్యుడు, ఎనిమిది గ్రహాలు, ఉపగ్రహాలు, గ్రహశకలాలు, ఉల్కలు అని పిలువబడే కొన్ని ఖగోళ వస్తువులు సౌర వ్యవస్థను ఏర్పరుస్తాయి. సూర్యుడు యజమానిగా ఉన్న దీనిని మనం ‘సౌర కుటుంబం’ అని పిలుస్తాం."},{"question":"కింది వాక్యాల్లో సమానమైన అర్థాన్నిచ్చే పదాలున్నాయి. వాటిని గుర్తించండి.అ) హృదయం మంచిదైతే అతడు మంచి మనిషి. అతని డెందములో అందరి పట్ల అభిమానమే ఉంటుంది. ఎదలో కల్మషం లేకుండా మాట్లాడితే అందరి చిత్రాలు సంతోషిస్తాయి.ఆ) మిడుతలు చిచ్చుపైకి ఎగిసిపడ్డాయి. అడవిలో వహ్ని రగులుకొన్నది. అగ్నిలో చేయిపెడితే కాలుతుంది.","answer":"అ) హృదయం మంచిదైతే అతడు మంచి మనిషి. అతని డెందములో అందరి పట్ల అభిమానమే ఉంటుంది. ఎదలో కల్మషం లేకుండా మాట్లాడితే అందరి చిత్రాలు సంతోషిస్తాయి.జవాబు:హృదయం మంచిదైతే అతడు మంచి మనిషి. అతని డెందములో అందరి పట్ల అభిమానమే ఉంటుంది. ఎదలో కల్మషం లేకుండా మాట్లాడిన అతని మాటలకి అందరి చిత్తాలు సంతోషిస్తాయి.హృదయం, డెందము, ఎద, చిత్తముఆ) మిడుతలు చిచ్చుపైకి ఎగిసిపడ్డాయి. అడవిలో వహ్ని రగులుకొన్నది. అగ్నిలో చేయిపెడితే కాలుతుంది.జవాబు:మిడుతలు చిచ్చు పైకి ఎగిసిపడ్డాయి. అడవిలో వహ్ని రగులుకొన్నది. అగ్నిలో చేయిపెడితే కాలుతుంది.చిచ్చు, వహ్ని, అగ్ని"},{"question":"ਇਸ ਬੰਦ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖਦਿਆਂ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਤੇ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਸਣੇ ਦੇਸ਼ ਭਰ ਵਿਚ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਦੇ ਪੁਖ਼ਤਾ ਇੰਤਜ਼ਾਮ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ ਹਨ। ਮੱਧ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਅਤੇ ਬਿਹਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਬੰਦ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਹਿੰਸਾ ਰੋਕਣ ਲਈ ਧਾਰਾ 144 ਲਗਾਈ ਗਈ ਹੈ। ਮੱਧ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਵਿਚ 2 ਅਪ੍ਰੈਲ 2018 ਨੂੰ ਦਲਿਤ ਸੰਗਠਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਬੰਦ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਕਈ ਥਾਵਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਹਿੰਸਾ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ।ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਦੇ ਆਲੋਚਕ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਗਲਤ ਇਸਤੇਮਾਲ ਦੇ ਇਲਜ਼ਾਮ ਲਾਉਂਦੇ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਸਮਰਥਕ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਇਹ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਦਲਿਤਾਂ ਦੇ ਖਿਲਾਫ਼ ਇਸਤੇਮਾਲ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਜਾਤੀ ਸੂਚਕ ਸ਼ਬਦਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਹਜ਼ਾਰਾਂ ਸਾਲਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਚੱਲੇ ਆ ਰਹੇ ਜ਼ੁਲਮ ਨੂੰ ਰੋਕਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਦਦ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ।ਇਸ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਬਾਰੇ ਸੁਪਰੀਮ ਕੋਰਟ ਨੇ ਸੁਣਵਾਈ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਕੁਝ ਖਾਸ ਬਦਲਾਅ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਕਿਹਾ ਸੀ।ਪਰ ਕਥਿਤ ਸਵਰਨ ਸੰਗਠਨ ਇਸ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਦਾ ਵਿਰੋਧ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਆਓ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਸੁਪਰੀਮ ਕੋਰਟ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਦੀਆਂ ਮੁੱਖ ਗੱਲਾਂ। ਮਾਮਲੇ ਦਾ ਪਿਛੋਕੜ। ਮਾਮਲਾ ਮਹਾਰਾਸ਼ਟਰ ਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਅਨੁਸੂਚਿਤ ਜਾਤੀ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਸ਼ਖ਼ਸ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੀਨੀਅਰ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਖਿਲਾਫ਼ ਮਾਮਲਾ ਦਰਜ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ। ਗੈਰ-ਅਨੁਸੂਚਿਤ ਜਾਤੀ ਦੇ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਸ਼ਖ਼ਸ ਦੀ ਸਾਲਾਨਾ ਖੂਫ਼ੀਆ ਰਿਪੋਰਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਖਿਲਾਫ਼ ਟਿੱਪਣੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ। ਜਦੋਂ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਨੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਖਿਲਾਫ਼ ਕਾਰਵਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ ਤਾਂ ਸੀਨੀਅਰ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਤੋਂ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਮੰਗੀ ਤਾਂ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਗਈ। ਇਸ 'ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਖਿਲਾਫ਼ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਾਮਲਾ ਦਰਜ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਬਚਾਅ ਪੱਖ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਅਨੁਸੂਚਿਤ ਜਾਤੀ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਖ਼ਸ ਖਿਲਾਫ਼ ਇਮਾਨਦਾਰ ਟਿੱਪਣੀ ਕਰਨਾ ਅਪਰਾਧ ਹੋ ਜਾਵੇਗਾ ਤਾਂ ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨਾ ਔਖਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਵੇਗਾ।","answer":"ਸੰਸਦ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਪਾਸ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ ਐੱਸਸੀ/ਐੱਸਟੀ ਸੋਧ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਨੂੰ ਮੂਲ ਰੂਪ ਵਿਚ ਬਹਾਲ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾਣ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ 35 ਦੇ ਕਰੀਬ ਸੰਗਠਨਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਅੱਜ ਭਾਰਤ ਬੰਦ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Qual país dominou os Jogos Olímpicos de Natação Sincronizada com cinco medalhas de ouro desde sua reintrodução aos jogos em 2000?","answer":"De Sydney-2000, passando por Atenas-2004 e Pequim-2008, até chegar a Londres-2012 e Rio-2016, a Rússia levou para casa todas as medalhas de ouro disputadas."},{"question":"જેહ ચરણ ભક્તનિંદે કાવ્ય નુ વર્ણન કરો.","answer":"જેહ ચરણ ભક્તનિંદેકવિ: મીરાંબાઈશીર્ષક: જેહ ચરણ ભક્તનિંદેજેહ ચરણ ભક્તનિંદે,તેહ ચરણ મારા નહીં,જેહ ચરણ ભક્તને દુઃખ દે,તેહ ચરણ મારા નહીં,જેહ ચરણ ભક્તને સુખ આપે,તેહ ચરણ મારા છે,જેહ ચરણ ભક્તને ભોળા બનાવે,તેહ ચરણ મારા છે,જેહ ચરણ ભક્તને દુનિયાથી છુટા કરે,તેહ ચરણ મારા છે,જેહ ચરણ ભક્તને ભગવાન સાથે જોડે,તેહ ચરણ મારા છે."},{"question":"firy ny isan'ny tongotry ny saobakaka?","answer":"ny isan'ny tongotry ny saobakaka dia efatra"},{"question":"Welke spelers hebben de Grand Slam tennistoernooien voor mannen gewonnen in 2022?","answer":"De volgende spelers hebben de Grand Slam tennistoernooien voor mannen gewonnen in 2022: - Rafael Nadal won de Australian Open en de French Open;- Novak Djokovic won Wimbledon;- Carlos Alcaraz won de US Open;"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي البقعة اللينة على رأس الطفل المعروفة؟","answer":"الإجابة: الفونتانيلي"},{"question":"মহিলাদের চেয়ে পুরুষদের মাথা বেশি টাক হয় কেন?","answer":"মায়ের কাছ থেকে আসা টাক পড়া সম্পর্কিত জিনের স্বল্পতা, চুলের গোড়ার লোমকূপে (গ্রন্থি) টেস্টোস্টেরন সম্পর্কিত ডাইহাইড্রোটেস্টোস্টেরন নামক হরমোনের উপস্থিতি বা অন্য কোনো বিশেষ প্রতিক্রিয়ায় পুরুষদের মাথা বেশি টাক হয়।"},{"question":"ਰਸੋਈ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਾਈ ਕਿਉਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਰਸੋਈ ਦੀ ਸਾਫ਼-ਸਫ਼ਾਈ ਇਸ ਲਈ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਜੇ ਰਸੋਈ ਗੰਦੀ ਹੋਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਕਈ ਜੀਵ ਜੰਤੂਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਘਰ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਮੌਕਾ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਵੇਗਾ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਖਾਧ-ਪਦਾਰਥ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਸਾਨੀ ਨਾਲ ਉਪਲੱਬਧ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ । ਰਸੋਈ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ‘ ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਜ਼ਹਿਰੀਲੀਆਂ ਦਵਾਈਆਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ ਇਸ ਲਈ ਇਹ ਅਤਿ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਰਸੋਈ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਾਈ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਖ਼ਿਆਲ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਜਾਵੇ ।"},{"question":"Quem foi o treinador principal do time que ganhou o Campeonato da NBA em 2020?","answer":"Frank Vogel"},{"question":"سوال: زمین پر سب سے بڑا ممالیہ کون سا ہے؟الف) ہاتھی۔ب) بلیو وہیلج) زرافہ","answer":"جواب: ب) بلیو وہیلنیلی وہیل سب سے بڑے جانور ہیں جو اب تک زمین پر رہتے ہیں۔ یہ شاندار سمندری ممالیہ 100 فٹ لمبے اور 200 ٹن سے اوپر تک سمندروں پر راج کرتے ہیں۔ اکیلے ان کی زبان کا وزن ہاتھی جتنا ہو سکتا ہے۔ ان کے دل، ایک آٹوموبائل کے طور پر."},{"question":"Жаңыл Мырза туурасындагы факты...","answer":"Гендердик маселеге да кайрылган. Тарыхка көз жүгүртсөк, элдин баатырдык идеалы да элдин дүйнөгө, айлана-чөйрөгө болгон көз караштарынын негизинде улам өзгөрүлүп, эволюциялык баскычтардан өтүп турушу мыйзамдуу көрүнүш. Ошондуктан элибиз кыздар темасын өз айтымдарында чагылдыруу менен бирге бүгүнкү күндөгү гендердик маселелерге да кайрылып келишкендигин \\"Жаңыл Мырзадан\\" байкоого болот. Бул туурасында адабиятчы Абдырасулова белгилеген. "},{"question":"UMandlenkosi ubesalokhu elulindile lolu suku lomshado olungafiki. Okubikakhulu ukuthi umukhwe wakhe ubegodle ilobolo, wagodla nomakoti waseengezelela ngokugodla nosuku lomshado. Okwenza ibe buhlungu kakhuluinhliziyo kaMandlenkosi ukuthi umukhwe wakhe unesandla esiqine kakhulu.Akafuni ukuthi ingane yakhe ihlangane nomkhwenyana wayo kungakayiwaesontweni. Wasikhipha leso sexwayiso, waze wagcizelela. Waze wafungawathi buyochitheka bugayiwe uma bengatholakala bendawonye laba bobabili.Kwancwajana yomshado ayisho lutho lapha kuyena, yinto asengayihliphizakalula nje lena.Umukhwe wayeqhosha ngokuthi uMandlenkosi akaqedile ukukhokha.Kwaleyo madlana aseyikhokhile angabuyiselwa yona kungabi ndaba zaluthonje, kuqhosha umukhwe.1. Bhala inhloso yombhali yokusibhalela le ndatshana","answer":"Ukusifundisa ukuba sibahloniphe abantu ngoba asazi ukuthiikusasa lisiphatheleni."},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Pologne","answer":"Péeyum réwum Pologne mu ngi tudu Varsovie"},{"question":"Iza no tendrombohitra avo indrindra any Afrika?a) Atlasb) Kenyac) Ruwenzorid) Kilimanjaro","answer":"I Kilimanjaro no tendrombohitra avo indrindra any Afrika."},{"question":"Awọn agbebọn ya bo ileewe ijọba ni Niger, wọn pa ọmọleewe kan, wọn si ji tiṣa atawọn to ku gbe","answer":"Awọn janduku agbebọn ti ṣakọlu si ileewe ijọba, Government Science College, to wa ni lagbegbe Kagara, nijọba ibilẹ Rafi, nipinlẹ Niger, wọn yinbọn pa ọmọleewe kan, wọn si ji awọn ọmọleewe to ku atawọn tiṣa wọn gbe sa lọ.Oru mọju Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii ni wọn ni iṣẹlẹ ibanujẹ naa waye, wọn ni nnkan bii aago meji ọganjọ oru tọwọ ti pa, tẹsẹ ti pa, lo ṣẹlẹ.Gẹgẹ ba a ṣe gbọ, wọn niru aṣọ ileewe (yunifọọmu) tawọn akẹkọọ naa n wọ lawọn agbebọn naa wọ, eyi si ni ko jẹ kawọn eeyan to ṣee ṣe ko ri wọn fura pe iwa laabi kan ni wọn fẹẹ lọọ hu.Benjamin Doma ni wọn porukọ majeṣin ọmọleewe ti wọn da ẹmi ẹ legbodo ọhun, wọn si fipa ja geeti ọgba tawọn olukọ ileewe naa n gbe pẹlu awọn mọlẹbi wọn, wọn ko gbogbo wọn wọ’gbo lọ.Ajọ Akoroyinjọ ilẹ wa (NAN) to jẹ ka gbọ nipa iṣẹlẹ yii sọ pe titi di bayii, ko ti i ṣee ṣe lati sọ pato iye eeyan ti wọn ji gbe, ati iye ọmọleewe tọrọ naa kan.Sẹnetọ tẹlẹ kan lati apa Oke-Ọya, Sẹnetọ Shehu Sanni fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ. O sọ lori atẹ ayelujara (tuita) rẹ pe loootọ niṣẹlẹ naa waye, o loun ṣẹṣẹ ba ọga agba (Principal) ileewe naa sọrọ lori aago tan ni, o lo fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ foun. Sanni ni ọkan lara ileewe toun lọ nigba toun wa lọmọde nileewe ọhun.Awọn agbofinro ko ti i sọrọ lori iṣẹlẹ yii, lasiko ti a fi n ko iroyin yii jọ."},{"question":"Дүйнөдөгү эң жеңил материал кайсыл?","answer":"Дүйнөдөгү эң жеңил материал  - Аэрогель деп аталат."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: \\"Holy Motors\\" producerades genom Pierre Grise Productions för en budget på 3,9 miljoner euro, vilken inbegrep pengar från CNC, Île-de-Frances filmfond, franska Arte","answer":", franska Canal+ och Ciné+. Filmen är till 20% en tysk samproduktion genom bolaget Pandora, och mottog 350 000 euro från den fransk-tyska kommittén för samproduktionsstöd."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bacang dibungkus tentu baunya keluar juga\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut.","answer":"Ia bermaksud merahsiakan perkara yang telah diketahui umum. Contoh ayat: Bacang dibungkus tentu baunya keluar juga.  Begitulah yang terjadi kepada Atan yang telah  gagal di dalam peperiksaan SPM dengan mendapat Pangkat  ke-IV menyebabkan dia merasa amat malu dan tidak  memberitahu kepada sesiapa pun di kampunnya sedangkan  orang kampung sudah mengetahuinya melalui seorang guru di  kampungnya."},{"question":"De jongen was aan het spelen met zijn speelgoed. Is de zin grammaticaal correct?","answer":"Ja, de zin is grammaticaal correct."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi William Wyndham Grenville, 1ú Bharún Grenville. ","answer":"Ba pholaiteoir agus Phríomh-Aire na Ríochta Aontaithe é William Wyndham Grenville, 1ú Bharún Grenville, a rugadh ar an 25 Deireadh Fómhair 1759 go dtí 12 Eanáir 1834."},{"question":" كم سنة عاش سيدنا يحيى ؟","answer":"30 سنة"},{"question":"Pewarna makanan sering digunakan untuk menjadikan makanan kelihatan lebih menarik. Antara berilut, yang manakah merupakah contoh pewarna makanan?A. CukaB. VanilaC. KunyitD. Asid borik","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah C. Kunyit. Cuka, vanila dan asid borik tidak digunakan sebagai pewarna makanan. "},{"question":"Las naciones de Azerbaiyán, Kenia, Macedonia, Uruguay y Venezuela participaron en sus primeros Juegos Olímpicos de Invierno. Las naciones de Azerbaiyán, Kenia, Macedonia, Uruguay y Venezuela participaron por primera vez en los Juegos Olímpicos de Invierno. Pregunta: ¿Expresan la frase 1 y la frase 2 el mismo significado?A) SíB) NoC) No lo sé","answer":"A) Sí."},{"question":"Tambaya: Awa nawa ne tafiya mafi tsawo da jirgin sama yayi bai tsaya ba?","answer":"Amsa: Awa 16, da minti 20"},{"question":"Hãy viết 1 bài văn nghị luận khoảng 500 chữ về cách tự cân bằng cuộc sống cho bản thân.","answer":"Xã hội ngày càng phát triển khiến cho cuộc sống của con người bị xoáy vào vòng xoay của tiền bạc và địa vị. Chính vì thế, con người rất cần tới sự cân bằng trong cuộc sống. Cân bằng giữa công việc và cuộc sống là trạng thái cân bằng trong đó một người ưu tiên cho nhu cầu của sự nghiệp và nhu cầu của cuộc sống cá nhân là như nhau. Lợi ích của việc cân bằng cuộc sống: Thứ nhất ít vấn đề về sức khỏe. Việc cân bằng giữa công việc và cuộc sống có thể giúp giảm thiểu các vấn đề về sức khỏe bao gồm: trầm cảm, rối loạn lo âu, huyết áp cao, tim mạch, chấn thương dây thần kinh, tăng cân không kiểm soát...Thứ hai nâng cao hiệu suất công việc: Tập trung quá nhiều vào công việc có thể dẫn tới mệt mỏi, kiệt sức và hiệu quả công việc kém. Cân bằng giữa công việc và cuộc sống có thể giúp bạn giảm căng thẳng, cải thiện khả năng tập trung, trí nhớ, nâng cao kỹ năng phân tích và giải quyết vấn đề để làm việc hiệu quả hơn. Thứ ba Ít kiệt sức hơn: Quá tải công việc đã dẫn tới nhiều trường hợp bị kiệt sức nơi làm việc. Việc cân bằng giữa công việc và cuộc sống có ý nghĩa đặc biệt quan trọng trong việc giảm thiểu các tình trạng tiêu cực trên. Thứ tư Hạnh phúc hơn: Khi có thời gian nghỉ ngơi và thư giãn, bạn sẽ cảm thấy hạnh phúc hơn. Việc cân bằng giữa công việc và cuộc sống sẽ giúp bạn duy trì trạng thái tinh thần tích cực và lạc quan trong cuộc sống.Có nhiều nguyên nhân dẫn tới sự mất cân bằng trong cuộc sống. Dưới đây là các nguyên nhân phổ biến dẫn đến việc mất cân bằng trong cuộc sống: Một là tăng chi phí mà không tăng lương. Ngày nay, kinh tế bất ổn, lạm phát tăng cao khiến cho chi phí đồng loạt tăng. Nếu như thu nhập giậm chân tại chỗ, cuộc sống của nhiều người sẽ bị đảo lộn, mất cân bằng do phải đối mặt với áp lực đồng tiền.Hai là tăng trách nhiệm công việc. Việc tăng nhiệm vụ và trách nhiệm trong công việc có thể là nguyên do trực tiếp gây ra tình trạng mất cân bằng giữa công việc và cuộc sống, chất lượng cuộc sống bị suy giảm theo thời gian. Ba là tăng trách nhiệm đối với gia đình. Việc có thêm nhiều trách nhiệm hơn ở nhà, chẳng hạn như chăm sóc con cái và người thân lớn tuổi, khiến việc cân bằng giữa công việc và cuộc sống trở nên khó khăn hơn. Bốn là làm việc nhiều giờ hơn. Phải làm việc nhiều giờ hơn là lý do trực tiếp dẫn đến hiện trạng mất cân bằng trong cuộc sống, khi mà thời gian dành cho gia đình, bạn bè, người thân và chính bản mình đã bị công việc chiếm hết. Năm là có con. Sau khi có con, phụ nữ phải làm việc nhiều hơn để lo cho gia đình và chăm sóc con cái. Thời gian làm việc và chăm con gần như chiếm toàn bộ quỹ thời gian khiến họ rơi vào trạng thái mất cân bằng trong cuộc sống.Có nhiều cách để chúng ta cân bằng cuộc sống, cụ thể là:Học cách nói KHÔNG: Học cách nói không là một kỹ năng mềm quan trọng trong việc thiết lập ranh giới của bạn với người khác. Để bắt đầu, trước tiên bạn phải đánh giá các nhu cầu điển hình trong ngày của mình và ưu tiên thực hiện những việc quan trọng trước rồi mới nghĩ đến việc giúp đỡ người khác.Nghỉ giải lao: Ngay cả một khoảng thời gian nghỉ ngơi ngắn trong vòng 30 giây cũng có thể giúp bạn cải thiện sự tập trung, giảm căng thẳng và lấy lại tinh thần. Vậy nên, hãy biết nghỉ ngơi đúng lúc để không bị kiệt sức và mất cân bằng trong công việc và cuộc sống.Nghỉ trưa: Khoảng thời gian nghỉ trưa là thời điểm để cơ thể bạn được nghỉ ngơi, thư giãn và nạp lại năng lượng, vậy nên đừng bỏ qua nó. Bạn có thể thưởng thức bữa trưa của mình trong chánh niệm, hoặc thực hiện các bài thiền ngắn hoặc các bài tập thở vào khoảng thời gian này nếu như mức độ căng thẳng trong công việc quá cao.Chăm sóc sức khỏe bản thân: Sức khỏe của bản thân bạn cần phải được ưu tiên hàng đầu, đặt lên trên mọi công việc. Bạn cần thiết lập cho mình các thói quen lành mạnh, bao gồm việc ăn uống đúng giờ, ngủ đủ giấc, tập thể dục, thiền, thực hành lòng biết ơn đều đặn hàng ngày. Các thói quen này đóng vai trò quan trọng trong việc khôi phục sự cân bằng từ bên trong. Hãy đảm bảo rằng bạn thực hiện đầy đủ để có sức khỏe thể chất và tinh thần tốt nhất. Thực hành lòng trắc ẩn: Một trong những cách quan trọng nhất để đạt được sự cân bằng giữa công việc và cuộc sống đó là từ bỏ chủ nghĩa hoàn hảo. Hãy biết cách chọn lọc một mục tiêu quan trọng nhất và tập trung thực hiện nó thật tốt, rồi mới tiếp tục hoàn thành các mục tiêu tiếp theo.Ranh giới rõ ràng: Bạn cần thiết lập ranh giới rõ ràng giữa bạn và công việc bằng cách đặt và thông báo giờ làm việc của bạn với đồng nghiệp và khách hàng để họ biết rằng ngoài khoảng thời gian này bạn không sẵn sàng phản hồi. Ngoài ra, bạn cũng có thể thiết lập một trình trả lời tự động để thông báo cho những người liên hệ với bạn qua email rằng bạn đang ngoại tuyến. Thông báo này cũng có thể cho họ biết khi nào bạn sẽ trả lời.Đầu tư vào các mối quan hệ: Lời khuyên dành cho bạn là hãy tập trung đầu tư vào mạng lưới quan hệ trong cuộc sống. Có được những mối quan hệ chất lượng sẽ giúp bạn giảm bớt gánh nặng công việc và giải quyết công việc một cách nhanh chóng hơn.Dành thời gian cho gia đình: Công việc chỉ là một phần của cuộc sống, gia đình mới là thứ ta cần trân trọng. Dành thời gian cho gia đình và những người thân yêu, ta sẽ thấy áp lực và mệt mỏi tan biến, và rồi dần lấy lại sự cân bằng trong công việc và cuộc sống.Ưu tiên thời gian chất lượng: Thời gian mỗi người là có hạn, hãy biết cách phân bổ thời gian hợp lý vào những việc quan trọng và cần thiết, trong đó đặc biệt ưu tiên các mối quan hệ và hoạt động có giá trị cao. Và cũng đừng quên dành thời gian cho chính bản thân mình. Hãy cho phép bản thân tận hưởng những khoảng thời gian nghỉ ngơi chất lượng để tái tạo lại năng lượng.Bắt đầu từ những việc nhỏ: Để thiết lập lại sự cân bằng giữa công việc và cuộc sống, ta cần bắt đầu từ những việc làm nhỏ nhất như tự nhắc nhở bản thân nghỉ ngơi đúng giờ, dành thời gian cho những thói quen tốt, ưu tiên những việc quan trọng trong ngày... để có được cuộc sống chất lượng hơn.Sự cân bằng giữa sinh hoạt và công việc giúp đảm bảo sức khỏe và nâng cấp chất lượng cuộc sống. Hy vọng bài viết sẽ giúp bạn tìm ra hướng cân bằng cuộc sống và công việc hiện tại."},{"question":"கேள்வி : இத்தாலி நாட்டின் தேசிய மலர்? ","answer":"பதில் : லில்லி"},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Chiến tranh Triều Tiên chính thức ","answer":"bắt đầu từ năm 1950 và cho đến nay vẫn chưa có sự kết thúc. Mặc dù đã có một thỏa thuận ngừng bắn vào năm 1953, song không có hiệp ước hòa bình chính thức được thỏa thuận. Tại cuộc hội nghị thượng đỉnh ngày 27 tháng 4, các nhà lãnh đạo đã bàn thảo về việc giải trừ vũ khí hạt nhân, hướng tới việc đoàn tụ các gia đình bị chia cắt bởi sự phân chia và tìm kiếm cơ hội cải thiện mối quan hệ chung giữa hai nước."},{"question":"Awọn obi Dada ti wọn pa l’Oke-Igbo bẹbẹ fun idajọ ododo","answer":"Awọn obi ọmọkunrin ẹni ọdun mẹrindinlọgbọn ti wọn pa sinu igbo kan niluu Oke-Igbo loṣu to kọja ti ni idajọ ododo lawọn n fẹ lori awọn to ṣeku pa ọmọ wọn.Gẹgẹ bi alaye ti Abilekọ Bọsẹde Ọmọniyi to jẹ iya oloogbe, Dada Pius Ọmọniyi, ṣe f’ALAROYE lọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ ta a wa yii, o ni ile loun wa ni nnkan bii aago mejila ọsan ọjọ kẹrinla, oṣu to kọja, nigba ti ẹnikan to porukọ rẹ ni Abbey Ojo waa tan ọmọ oun jade kuro nile wọn to wa lagbegbe Okesa, Oke-Igbo.O ni oun tun pade Dada ati ọrẹ rẹ yii nibi ti wọn ti n ṣere lasiko ti oun kiri ẹja lọ saarin ọja lalẹ ọjọ kan naa lai mọ pe ko ni i pada wale mọ.Lẹyin ti ko ri i ko wale waa sun lọjọ keji lo too ṣẹṣẹ pariwo ọrọ naa sita, tawọn eeyan si tọpasẹ Abbey to waa pe e nile lọ sile awọn obi rẹ.Wọn fi iṣẹlẹ yii to awọn ọlọpaa Oke-Igbo leti, nibẹ ni wọn si ti sọ fun wọn pe awọn ri oku ẹnikan lọna abule Awọ, ni nnkan bii ọjọ mẹta sẹyin.Wọn gba wọn nimọran ati lọọ wo oku ọhun ni mọṣuari ileewosan ijọba to wa l’Ondo.Abilekọ Bọsẹde ni awọn ba oku ọmọ awọn ni mọsuari naa loootọ ti wọn ti ge ori, apa ati ẹsẹ rẹ mejeeji lọ.O ni Abbey pada jẹwọ ni tesan pe oloogbe ọhun ati ẹnikan ti wọn n pe ni Tobi Amọdu ni wọn jọ lọ soko lọjọ ti awọn jọ jade.Loju ẹsẹ lawọn ọlọpaa ti fi panpẹ ofin gbe Tobi, ti wọn si fi oun ati Abbey ṣọwọ si olu ileesẹ wọn to wa l’Akurẹ fun ẹkunrẹrẹ iwadii.Awọn afurasi mejeeji yii la gbọ pe wọn jẹwọ fawọn ọlọpaa lasiko ti wọn n fọrọ wa wọn lẹnu wo pe iṣẹ Babalawo lawọn n kọ lọwọ.Alagba Pius Ọmọniyi to jẹ baba oloogbe ni o to bii ọsẹ kan lẹyin tisẹlẹ yii waye ki oun too gbọ nipa rẹ.O ni iṣẹ awọn to n tun bata ṣe ni Dada kọ, ati pe nigba to ku ọjọ mẹfa pere ko di ọga ara rẹ ni wọn pa a nipakupa.O ni ibi toun atawọn ọlọpaa jọ fi ọrọ si ni pe ki awọn mejeeji tọwọ tẹ ṣi wa lọdọ wọn titi ti wọn yoo fi ri awọn afurasi mẹta ti wọn lawọn n wa mu.Alagba Pius ni kayefi lo ṣi n jẹ foun bi wọn ṣe pada yọnda Abbey ati ekeji rẹ ni kete ti oun pada sẹnu iṣẹ lẹyin ọjọ mẹrin pere ti wọn ti wa latimọle, ti wọn si tun n gba oun nimọran lati tete gbe igbesẹ lori ati gbe oku ọmọ oun kuro ni mọsuari ki oun si lọọ sin in.O ni awawi awọn ọlọpaa ni pe o ṣee ṣe ki awọn ti wọn mu ọhun ma mọ ohunkohun nipa ẹsun ti wọn fi kan wọn.Ọsẹ to kọja yii to ni awọn pada lọ ni ri Alukoro ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ondo, Tee-Leo Ikoro, pasẹ ki wọn tun lọọ mu awọn ọmọkunrin naa, ki wọn si da wọn pada si atimọle lẹyẹ-o-ṣọka, bo tilẹ jẹ pe awọn mejeeji ṣi wa nigboro tí wọn n rin kiri bo ṣe wu wọn titi di ba a ṣe n sọrọ yii.Bakan naa lo tun fi aidunnu rẹ han si bi Olu Oke tiluu Oke-Igbo, Ọba Lawrence Babajide, ṣe kuna lati gbe igbesẹ lori ọrọ naa lẹyin ti wọn ti ṣalaye ohun gbogbo to ṣẹlẹ ni aafin.Alagba Ọmọniyi ni ọmọ oun lẹni kẹta ti awọn onisẹẹbi wọnyi ṣeku pa, ti wọn si yọ ẹya ara wọn lọ laarin oṣu mẹta pere niluu Oke-Igbo.Idi ree to fi n rọ ijọba ati ọga ọlọpaa patapata lorilẹ-ede yii lati dìde si ọrọ naa, ki iku ọmọ rẹ ma baa ja si asan."},{"question":"* شحال كاينة من بسملة (بسم الله الرحمان الرحيم) في القرآن الكريم؟","answer":"114 بسملة."},{"question":"Түш тууралуу кызыктуу фактыларды жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Адам түш көрүп жатканда денеси дээрлик шал сыяктуу кыймылдабай калат. Бул мээнин элестетүүсү кайталанбашы үчүн жасалган табигый нерсе. Бул функция эс алуу үчүн жана ар кандай жарат алуудан коргонуу үчүн жасалат."},{"question":"A que categoría corresponde la siguiente pregunta : ¿Cuántas veces Spud Webb ganó la competencia de Slam Dunk?.","answer":"La categoría corresponde a deportes. "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bendera putih\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud mengaku kalah. Contoh ayat: Tentera musuh terpaksa mengibarkan bendera putih kerana tidak sanggup menentang serangan kerajaan Melaka yang hebat itu."},{"question":"iza no matanjaka kokoa ka mahavita mibata ny zavatra mavesatra kokoa amin'ny lahy sy ny vavy ?","answer":"Ny lahy no matanjaka kokoa ary mahavita mibata zavatra mavesatra kokoa noho ny vavy. "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai api dengan asap\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut.","answer":"Ia bermaksud pertalian yang tak dapat dipisahkan. Contoh ayat: Hubungan Siti dan Aminah amat rapat bagai api dengan asap kerana mereka sudah berkawan sejak dari kecil."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Bị bao phủ trong tuyết, băng và những dòng sông băng, bề mặt của Greenland chủ yếu là màu trắng nhưng nơi đây lại có tên gọi là vùng đất xanh. Theo Visit Greenland, tên gọi này được đặt cách đây 1.000 năm","answer":", bởi một người đàn ông tên Erik the Red. Sau khi bị trục xuất khỏi Iceland vì tội ngộ sát, người này tới Greenland và đặt tên là vùng đất xanh với hy vọng thu hút người tới định cư. Nhưng theo một số báo cáo khoa học, Greenland từng được phủ xanh cách đây 2,5 triệu năm trước. Các nhà nghiên cứu đã phát hiện ra lớp đất cổ, nằm sâu bên lớp băng dày 3 km trong suốt hàng triệu năm."},{"question":"जैन धर्मातील सम्यक ज्ञान, सम्यक दर्शन व सम्यक चरित्र या त्रिरत्नांचा उपदेश देणाऱ्या वर्धमान महावीरांचा जन्म केव्हा झाला?","answer":"जैन धर्मातील सम्यक ज्ञान, सम्यक दर्शन व सम्यक चरित्र या त्रिरत्नांचा उपदेश देणाऱ्या वर्धमान महावीरांचा जन्म  इ.स. पूर्व 599 मध्ये झाला."},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Tường thuật chi tết Bàn thắngMU: Amad Diallo (48')Vallecano: Alvaro Garcia (57') Đúng như tuyên bố ngay sau trận thua Atletico Madrid chiều thứ Bảy, HLV Erik ten Hag đã tung ra sân đội hình chính với nhiều cầu thủ trẻ cũng như siêu sao Ronaldo. Ngoài thủ quân ĐT Bồ Đào Nha còn có sự góp mặt của hai tân binh Christian Eriksen và Lisandro Martinez. Tuy nhiên, quãng thời gian 45 phút của hiệp thi đấu đầu tiên, các cầu thủ Man Uited không tạo ra được cơ hội thực sự ngn ăn. Tính huống nguy hiểm đầu tiên của trận đấu đến ở phút 15, khi tài năng trẻ Chong đã có cú dứt điểm trúng khung thành duy nhât trong hiệp 1 nhưng không thể thắng được thủ thành Dimitrievski. Trong khi đó, về phía đội khách Vallecano, việc chủ động thi đấu phòng ngự phản công khiến đại diện La Liga cũng chẳng tạo ra được cơ hội nào thực sự ngon ăn và hai đội rời sân nghỉ mà không có bàn thắng nào được ghi. Nếu như 45 phút đầu tiên diễn ra nghèo nàn bao nhiêu thì ở nửa sau của trận đấu diễn ra rất bùng nổ bấy nhiêu. Phút 48, cầu thủ vào sân thay Ronaldo, Amad Diallo đã có tình huống dứt điểm bồi tung lưới Vallecano sau pha bắt bóng không tốt của thủ thành kỳ cựu Diego Lopez.  Bốn phút sau bàn thắng mở tỷ số của Amad, cựu tiền đạo MU, Radamel Falcao đã có tình huống dứt điểm ở đẳng cấp cao đưa bóng tìm đúng xà ngang khung thành đội chủ nhà. Thế nhưng, may mắn không thể mỉm cười mãi với MU, khi 5 phút sau trận đấu được đưa về vạch xuất phát. Sau cú dứt điểm đẳng cấp của Isi Palazón bị thủ thành Heaton bên phía MU bay người cản phá thành công, Alvaro Garcia đã kịp băng vào đá bồi cân bằng tỷ số trận đấu. Sau bàn thắng cân bằng tỷ số của Vallecano, tốc độ trận đấu được diễn ra nhanh hơn, nhưng các pha bong nguy hiểm không diễn ra thường xuyên. Chung cuộc, trận đấu kết thúc với tỷ số hòa 1-1. Như vậy Man United khép lại giai đoạn giao hữu mùa hè với 3 trận thắng, 2 trận hòa và 1 thất bại. Đội hình thi đấuMU: Heaton; Telles, Laird, Varane, Martinez, Garner, Chong, Van de Beek, Eriksen, Garnacho, RonaldoVallecano: Dimitrievski; Balliu, Fran García, Catena, Unai Lopez, Mario Suárez, Ciss, Álvaro García, Trejo, Isi Palazón, Falcao","answer":"Kết quả MU 1-1 Vallecano: Hòa bạc nhược"},{"question":"Kìnìún ni ọba ẹranko. Kí ni ọkín?","answer":"Ọba ẹyẹ ni."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo antony mety mitarika ny fahasimban'ny voa?","answer":"Ireto no anisan'ny antony manimba ny voa:-tsy fahampiana rano-ny fiakaran'ny tosi-dra-fihinanana fanafody \\"antibiotiques\\" mahery-fahatezerana misesy sy hakizitinana-\\"stress\\" matetika sy harerahana be-tsy fanaovana fanatanjahantena mihitsy-alahelo be loatra ..."},{"question":"Elim é um aeroporto localizado no Aeroporto de Moses Point, uma cidade na Área de Censo de Nome do estado americano do Alasca. Frases 2: O Aeroporto de Moses Point é um aeroporto em Elim, uma cidade na Área de Censo de Nome, no estado americano do Alasca. Pergunta: A frase 1 e a frase 2 expressam o mesmo significado? Sim ou não?","answer":"Não."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fanabeazana lavitra?","answer":"Ny fanabeazana lavitra dia ahafahan'ny mpianatra mianatra ivelan'ny tontolo mahazatra ao an-dakilasy, matetika amin'ny alalan'ny loharano an-tserasera."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _« Ny _ ny fahombiazan’ny orinasa dia ireo mpiasa tia azy. »","answer":"Ny fototry ny fahombiazan’ny orinasa dia ireo mpiasa tia azy."},{"question":"ゴルフやテニスでは観客のことを指し、美術では作品を展示する画廊を意味する言葉は何でしょう？","answer":"ギャラリーです。"},{"question":"Завершите параграф: Новости 24 сентября 2023 года. Польша готова обеспечить транзит украинского зерна через польскую территорию для его последующей отправки в нуждающиеся страны Африки и Азии, заявил президент республики Анджей Дуда.","answer":"По словам Дуды, для решения проблемы созданы специальные коридоры, по которым украинское зерно будут перевозить через Польшу, а после отправлять \\"туда, где оно действительно необходимо\\". Еврокомиссия ранее решила снять запрет на импорт зерна с Украины в пять приграничных стран, обязав Киев ввести меры контроля за экспортом. Однако Польша в одностороннем порядке продлила с 16 сентября запрет на ввоз украинского зерна. Премьер-министр страны Матеуш Моравецкий подчеркнул, что Варшава не намерена слушать ни Берлин, ни Брюссель."},{"question":" बेलायतको ग्रिनविच कति डिग्री देशान्तर रेखामा पर्दछ ?","answer":" 0 डिग्री"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bernafas keluar badan'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud lebih percaya kepada pendapat orang lain daripada pendapat sendiri"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga :\\"Tsy misy mahery noho ny _, fa rehefa sembanin-drahona dia folaka ihany. \\"","answer":"\\"Tsy misy mahery noho ny masoandro, fa rehefa sembanin-drahona dia folaka ihany. \\""},{"question":"“Obinrin Ki Ṣe Ẹrú Tabi Ẹrù Ti Wọn Njẹ Mọ́ Ogún – Àsikò Tó Lati Dáwọ́ Àṣà Ṣì Ṣúpó Dúró” – “Women Are Not Slaves Nor Property That Can Be Inherited – “It Is Time To Stop Bequeathing Widows To The Next-Of-Kin.”","answer":"Ni ayé àtijọ́, àṣà ṣì ṣúpó wọ́pọ̀ ni Ilẹ̀ Yorùbá. Obinrin ti ọkọ rẹ̀ bá kú wọn yio fi jogún gẹ́gẹ́ bi iyàwó fún ọmọ ọkọ ọkùnrin tàbi ẹbi ọkọ ọkùnrin. Eleyi wọ́pọ̀, pàtàki ni idilé Ọba, Ìjòyè nla, Ọlọ́rọ̀ ni àwùjọ àti àgbàlagbà ti ó fẹ́ iyàwó púpọ̀.  Bi Ọba bá wàjà, Ọba titun yio ṣu gbogbo iyàwó ti ó bá láàfin lópó.Ni ayé ọ̀làjú ti òde òni, àṣà ṣì ṣúpó ti din kù púpọ̀, nitori ẹ̀sìn àti àwọn obinrin ti ó kàwé ti ó si ni iṣẹ́ lọ́wọ́ kò ni gbà ki wọn ṣú ohun lópó fún ẹbi ọkọ ti kò ni ìfẹ́ si.  Ọkùnrin ni ẹbi ọkọ na a ti bẹ̀rẹ̀ si kọ àṣà ṣì ṣúpó silẹ̀ pàtàki àwọn ti ó bá kàwé, nitori ó ti lè ni iyàwó tàbi ki ó ni àfẹ́sọ́nà.  Lai ti ẹ ni iyàwó, ọkùnrin ẹbi ọkọ lè ma ni ìfẹ́ si iyàwó ti ọkọ rẹ̀ kú.  Àṣa ṣì ṣúpó kò wọ́pọ̀ mọ laarin àwọn ti ó jade, àwọn ti ó ngbé ilú nla àti Òkè-òkun tàbi àwọn ti ó kàwé, ṣùgbọ́n ó wọ́pọ̀ laarin àwọn ti kò jade kúrò ni Abúlé àti àwọn ti kò kàwé.Idilé ti ifẹ bá wà laarin ẹbi, iyàwó pàápàá kò ni fẹ́ kúrò ni irú ẹbi bẹ́ ẹ̀ lati lọ fẹ́ ọkọ si idilé miran pàtàki nitori àwọn ọmọ tàbi ó dàgbà jù lati tun lọ fẹ ọkọ miran.  Ọmọ ọkọ tàbi ẹbi ọkọ ọkùnrin lè fi àṣà yi kẹ́wọ́ lati fẹ opó ni tipátipá, omiran lè pa ọkọ lati lè jogún iyàwó. Bi iyàwó bá kú, wọn kò jẹ́ fi ọkọ rẹ jogún fún ẹbi iyàwó.Àsikò tó lati dáwọ́ àṣà ṣì ṣúpó dúró nitori obinrin ki ṣe ẹrú tàbi ẹrù ti wọn njẹ mọ́ ogún."},{"question":"Iya Rainbow ṣọjọọbi, o ni ẹbẹ pataki kan loun n bẹ Ọlọrun","answer":"Ayẹyẹ ọjọọbi awọn gbajumọ oṣere ki i ṣe tuntun, tilu-tifọn lọpọ maa n ṣe e, wọn si maa n lo anfaani asiko naa lati dupẹ lọwọ Ọlọrun fun aṣeyọri yoowu ti wọn ti ṣe nigbesi aye wọn ati lẹnu iṣẹ tiata, wọn tun maa n sọ erongba ọkan wọn ati afojusun wọn jade.Iru asiko yii lo ṣẹlẹ si Abilekọ Idowu Philips, tawọn eeyan mọ si Iya Rainbow. Odu ni mama ẹni ọdun mọkandinlọgọrin yii nidii iṣẹ tiata, ki i ṣaimọ foloko rara. Bo tilẹ jẹ pe mama naa ko fi bẹẹ ṣere tiata rẹpẹtẹ mọ bii tigba kan, sibẹ bi onirese ko ba fingba mọ ni, eyi to ti fin silẹ ko le parun rara.Ṣugbọn lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide yii, ni irawọ oṣere yii ṣọjọọbi ọdun mọkandinlọgọrin loke eepẹ, bo ṣe n dupẹ lọwọ Ọlọrun atawọn ololufẹ rẹ, mama naa sọ pe ẹyọ ẹbẹ kan ṣoṣo pere lo ku nigbesi aye oun toun fẹ k’Ọlọrun ṣe foun. Bayii lo ṣe sọrọ ọhun:“Mo n ṣọọọbi mi lonii, ọjọ kẹrindinlogun, oṣu (October), 1942 ni wọn bi mi. Ọjọọbi yii ni ọdun mọkandinlaaadọrin mi, inu mi si dun pe gbogbo agbaye lo n ba mi yọ. Mo ṣadura s’Ọlọrun Eledumare pe ko da ẹmi mi si, ẹbẹ pataki kan ṣoṣo ti mo ni si Ọlọrun ni pe ko da ẹmi mi si, ko daabo bo mi ki n pe ọgọrin ọdun, aadọrun-un ọdun titi di ọgọfa (120) ọdun loke eepẹ. Mo fẹẹ pe ọgọfa ọdun laye, paapaa tori iṣẹ ojiṣẹ Oluwa ti Ọlọrun ti gbe le mi lọwọ bayii. Mo ti da ijọ silẹ, mo si ṣadura k’Ọlọrun jẹ ki n pẹ laye lati ṣaṣeyọri iṣẹ mi.Pẹlu bi mo ṣe dẹni ọdun mọkandinlọgọrin yii, mo ṣi lokun daadaa, mo ṣi n lọ soko ere, mo ṣi n ṣaraloge, mo ṣepolowo ọja gẹgẹ bii aṣoju ileeṣẹ, awọn iṣẹ wọnyi si n jẹ ki n maa ta kebekebe, ki n ṣi wa pa. Ṣugbọn bi mo ṣe maa n sọ, oore-ọfẹ Ọlọrun ni, keeyan ni ilera niru ọjọ-ori yii, ẹbun Ọlọrun ni. Oore-ọfẹ Ọlọrun ni pe mo ṣi wulo nidii iṣẹ tiata.”"},{"question":"Tilmaamida hogaamiye/hogaamiso.","answer":"Ku:- Asxaabta aan Bartan Saaxiibada ku nahayUjeedo:- Tilmaamid Hogaamiye/HogaamisoMarkaad aragtay:  Aqoonta iyo Waaya aragnimadiisaMarkaad Tixgelisay:  Kartida iyo Dadnimada uu leeyahay/ay leedahayMarkaad garwaaqsaday:   Sumcada iyo Xushmada uu Bulshada ku dhex leeyahayWaxaad Xeerisay:1. In aad u garatay Hebel ………. Ama Heblaayo ……… oo Asxaabtaada ka mid ah in uu leeyahay/leedahay sifooyinki Hogaamiyenimo, mustaqbalka dhowna uu noqon karo Madax meel sare gaaraXeerkani waxa uu dhaqangelayaa marka aad halkan ku mention-gareyso (ku xusto) qofkaa Mahadsanidiin."},{"question":"মি. জামান ১০ম শ্রেণির 'বাংলাদেশ ও বিশ্বপরিচয়' বিষয়ের একজন শিক্ষক। তিনি আজ শ্রেণিতে একটি নির্বাচন নিয়ে আলোচনা করেন। ঐ নির্বাচনে চারটি দল যুক্ত হয়ে একটি জোট গঠন করে। অতঃপর, = তিনি অপর একটি সাধারণ নির্বাচনের কথা বলেন যা “এক ব্যক্তির এক ভোটের ভিত্তিতে” অনুষ্ঠিত হয়। এতে একটি দল জাতীয় পরিষদে একক সংখ্যাগরিষ্ঠতা অর্জন করে।উদ্দীপকের শেষাংশে আলোচিত নির্বাচনের হাত ধরে আজকের স্বাধীন সার্বভৌম বাংলাদেশ— মতামত দাও।","answer":"উদ্দীপকের শেষাংশে আলোচিত নির্বাচনটি হলো পাকিস্তানের ১৯৭০ সালের সাধারণ নির্বাচন। স্বাধীন বাংলাদেশের অভ্যুদয়ের পেছনে এই নির্বাচনের গুরুত্ব অপরিসীম।১৯৭০ সালের ডিসেম্বর মাসে জাতীয় এবং প্রাদেশিক পরিষদের নির্বাচন অনুষ্ঠিত হয় । নির্বাচনে পূর্ব পাকিস্তানে আওয়ামী লীগ নজিরবিহীন বিজয় লাভ করে। এটি ছিল বাঙালি জাতীয়তাবাদ ও বঙ্গবন্ধুর স্বায়ত্তশাসনের দাবির রাজনৈতিক বিজয়।উদ্দীপকে দেখা যায়, শিক্ষক মি. জামান উদ্দীপকের শেষাংশে “এক ব্যক্তির একভোটের ভিত্তিতে” অনুষ্ঠিত নির্বাচনের কথা বলেন। তীব্র গণ আন্দোলনের ফলে ১৯৬৯ সালের ২৫শে মার্চ আইয়ুব খানের পদত্যাগের পর ১৯৭০ সালের ৭ই ডিসেম্বর পাকিস্তানে সর্বপ্রথম এক ব্যক্তির এক ভোটের ভিত্তিতে নির্বাচন অনুষ্ঠিত হয়। আওয়ামী লীগ এই নির্বাচনকে ৬ দফার পক্ষে গণভোট হিসেবে অভিহিত করে। এ নির্বাচনে আওয়ামী লীগের নিরঙ্কুশ সংখ্যাগরিষ্ঠতা লাভ পাকিস্তানি সরকারকে বিচলিত করে তোলে। তারা বাঙালির হাতে ক্ষমতা হস্তান্তর না করার জন্য ষড়যন্ত্র করতে থাকে। কিন্তু পূর্ব পাকিস্তানের জনগণ পশ্চিম পাকিস্তানি ষড়যন্ত্র নস্যাৎ করতে রাজপথে নামে। জবাবে পাকিস্তানিরা শুরু করে গণহত্যা। এর প্রতিক্রিয়াতেই বঙ্গবন্ধুর ডাকে মুক্তিযুদ্ধে ঝাঁপিয়ে পড়ে পূর্ব পাকিস্তানের বাঙালিরা।উপরের আলোচনা থেকে বলা যায়, ১৯৭০ সালের নির্বাচনে পাকিস্তানি শাসনশোষণে অতিষ্ঠ মুক্তিকামী বাঙালি স্বায়ত্তশাসনের পক্ষে রায় দেয়। আর এর ধারাবাহিকতায়ই মুক্তিযুদ্ধের মাধ্যমে স্বাধীন সার্বভৌম বাংলাদেশ জন্মলাভ করে।"},{"question":"உங்களுக்கு சொந்தமானத ஒன்று ஆனால் உங்களை விட மற்றவர்களே அதிகம் உபயோகிப்பார்கள்?","answer":"விடை: பெயர்"},{"question":"اكتب قصة اليوم الأول لشاب في المدرسة الابتدائية.","answer":"\\"كان الشاب الصغير يشعر بالحماس والخوف معًا، فقد كان هذا اليوم الأول له في المدرسة الابتدائية. كان يرتدي كنزة حمراء ساطعة وبنطلون أسود جديد، وحمل حقيبته الصغيرة على ظهره، ووجهه يبدو متوترًا بينما كان يمشي مع والداه نحو باب المدرسة.عندما دخل الفصل الدراسي الخاص به، وجد أن كل شيء جديد ومثير. كانت الصفوف مصفوفة بشكل مثالي، والطاولات والكراسي الصغيرة تظاهر بأنها بانتظار طالب جديد. تعرف الشاب على معلمته الجديدة، والتي كانت تشعر بنفس الحماس تجاه السنة الدراسية الجديدة.بدأت الدروس، وأصبح الفصل ممتلئًا بالكلام والأصوات. كان الشاب متحمسًا بشكل خاص لدرس الرياضيات، وهو ما وجد بعض الصعوبة في حل المسائل الجديدة، لكن فرحته عندما حل المسألة بنفسه كانت كبيرة جدًا.بعد الصلاة والغذاء، جاءت فترة الاستراحة، والتي كانت مناسبة للشاب لتكوين صداقات جديدة مع زملائه الجدد، واللعب معهم في الفناء الخارجي. بينما كان يلعب، وجد شخصين يلعبان بطريقة غريبة، حيث كانوا يستخدمون الإعداد الذهني لحل المسائل الرياضية بسرعة. سألهم الشاب عن هذا الأسلوب، وشرح لهم أنهم كانوا يحضّرون للمسابقة المدرسية القادمة.بمجرد انتهاء اليوم، خرج الشاب مع والديه من المدرسة، وكان يشعر بالرضا والاستيعاب بعد يوم أول رائع في المدرسة الابتدائية. كان يتطلع إلى المزيد من الأيام المثيرة والمليئة بالتحديات والفرص الجديدة.\\""},{"question":"請回答這個問題：什麼是社會學中的「族群」？","answer":"答案：族群是指在一個社會或文化中具有共同特徵和身份認同的人群。它可以基於種族、民族、語言、宗教等因素來定義，並在社會結構和文化中扮演特定的角色。"},{"question":"தமிழ்நாட்டின் எந்தப் பிரபலமான சுற்றுலாத் தலம் “மலைவாசஸ்தலங்களின் ராணி” என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறது?","answer":"ஊட்டி"},{"question":"尿是怎樣產生的？","answer":"　我們的身體裡有兩個腎，分別長在腰部腎柱的兩側，形狀像豆子。它們能把血液中沒有用的東西過濾出來，並且和體內多餘的水分一起排出體外，這些廢水就是尿。尿一滴滴地經過輸尿管進入膀胱，並且暫時存放在那裡。當膀胱里的尿液達到一定程度時，你就要去小便了。　　這時，大腦會發出排尿的命令，尿便排出來了。"},{"question":"Por favor complete este parágrafo - O ex-presidente Hastings Banda estabeleceu uma política externa pró-ocidental que continuou até o início de 2011. Ele incluía","answer":"boas relações diplomáticas com muitos países ocidentais. A transição de um estado de partido único para uma democracia multipartidária fortaleceu os laços do Malawi com os Estados Unidos. Um número significativo de estudantes de Malawi viajam para os Estados Unidos para a obtenção de ensino superior, e os EUA tem filiais ativas do Corpo de Paz, dos Centros de Controle e Prevenção de Doenças, do Departamento de Saúde e Serviços Humanos e a Agência para o Desenvolvimento Internacional no Malawi."},{"question":"Мотивация (дем-күч) бере турган сөздөрдөн жазып берчи","answer":"Бактылуу болуу максат болбош керек, ал адат болуш керек!"},{"question":"Адамдардын мүнөзүндөгү оң сапаттарды чагылдырган  фразеологизмдер кайсылар?","answer":"Адамдардын мүнөзүндөгү оң сапаттарды чагылдырган  фразеологизмдер: ала жипти аттабаган, кара кылды как жарган, ак жолтой, жабуулуу кара инген, колунан көөрү төгүлгөн, колу жеңил ж.б.у.с."},{"question":"ਮਾਈਏਂ ਪਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਰਸਮ ਕੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਵਿਆਹ ਤੋਂ ਕੁੱਝ ਦਿਨ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਵਿਆਂਹਦੜ ਮੁੰਡੇ ਜਾਂ ਕੁੜੀ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਈਏਂ ਪਾਇਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਲਈ ਹਲਦੀ, ਤੇਲ ਤੇ ਵੇਸਣ ਦੇ ਮਿਸ਼ਰਨ ਦਾ ਵਟਣਾ ਤਿਆਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਵਿਆਂਹਦੜ ਦੇ ਪਿੰਡੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਮਲਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਪਿੰਡਾ ਨਿੱਖਰ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Tranoben'Antananarivo ka .............................................................. \\"","answer":"\\"  Tranoben'Antananarivo ka izay mahavita aloha no manenina. \\""},{"question":"Nahoana no sarotra vahana ny ady an-trano?","answer":"Ny fisaratsarahana lalina eo amin'ny fiaraha-monina, ary koa ny olana saro-bahana ara-politika, ara-toekarena ary ara-poko, dia matetika manasarotra ny famahana."},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp nội dung cho đoạn văn sau: Xây dựng kịch bản ứng phó với mọi tình huống dịch Các chuyên gia cảnh báo việc xuất hiện các biến thể mới của virus SARS-CoV-2, trong thời gian tới virus này có khả năng tiếp tục tiến hóa theo hướng làm giảm miễn dịch qua thời gian, dẫn đến tăng nguy cơ dịch bệnh bùng phát trở lại. Các biến thể phụ BA.4, BA.5, BA.2.12.1... của biến thể Omicron đã được ghi nhận trong nước; Bộ Y tế đã chỉ đạo tăng cường giám sát sự lưu hành của các biến thể phụ để chủ động có các biện pháp xử lí kịp thời. ","answer":"Tại Hà Nội, thống kê từ đầu năm đến 22/7, Hà Nội có 1.562.760 ca mắc, 480 ca tử vong. Theo Trung tâm Kiểm soát bệnh tật (CDC) Hà Nội từ đầu năm đến nay đã tiến hành giải trình tự gene gần 300 mẫu bệnh phẩm dương tính tại cộng đồng. Trong đó, biến thể Omicron vẫn chiếm ưu thế, được phát hiện tại 30/30 quận huyện; còn lại tỷ lệ nhỏ nhiễm biến thể Delta. Đối với biến thể Omicron, dòng BA.2 chiếm ưu thế với tỉ lệ hơn 56,6%; BA.2.3 chiếm hơn 30%... "},{"question":"অনুগ্রহ করে নিচের অনুচ্ছেদটি পড়ুন এবং প্রশ্নের উত্তর দিন |প্রশ্ন : কত সালে বঙ্গভঙ্গের কথা ঘোষিত হয় ?নতুন প্রদেশটির নামকরণ করা হয় “পূর্ব বঙ্গ ও আসাম” যার রাজধানী হবে ঢাকা এবং অনুষঙ্গী সদর দফতর হবে চট্টগ্রাম। এর আয়তন হবে ১,০৬,৫৪০ বর্গ মাইল এবং জনসংখ্যা হবে ৩১ মিলিয়ন যাদের মধ্যে ১৮ মিলিয়ন মুসলিম ও ১২ মিলিয়ন হিন্দু। এর প্রশাসন একটি আইন পরিষদ ও দুই সদস্যবিশিষ্ট একটি রাজস্ব বোর্ড নিয়ে গঠিত হবে এবং কলকাতা হাইকোর্টের এখতিয়ার বজায় থাকবে। সরকার নির্দেশ দেয় যে পূর্ব বঙ্গ ও আসামের পশ্চিম সীমানা স্পষ্টভাবে নির্দিষ্ট থাকবে সাথেসাথে এর ভৌগোলিক, জাতিক, ভাষিক ও সামাজিক বৈশিষ্টাবলিও নির্দিষ্ট থাকবে। সরকার তাদের চূড়ান্ত সিদ্ধান্ত ঘোষণা করে ১৯শে জুলাই, ১৯০৫ সালে এবং বঙ্গভঙ্গ কার্যকর হয় একই বছরের ১৬ই অক্টোবর।","answer":"১৯শে জুলাই, ১৯০৫ বঙ্গভঙ্গের কথা ঘোষিত হয় |"},{"question":"Dê um exemplo de uma pergunta da categoria Geografia","answer":"Qual foi o primeiro estado a se unir aos Estados Unidos após as treze colônias originais? Delaware"},{"question":" Liste um pintor açorianos notável.","answer":"Entre os pintores notáveis dos Açores, destaca-se César Augusto Pires, conhecido pela sua representação vívida da paisagem açoriana. As suas telas capturam a exuberância das ilhas com cores vibrantes e detalhes cativantes."},{"question":" Inona no fikarohana siantifika nitarika ny fivoaran'ny vaksiny voalohany ary iza no mpahay siansa tao ambadik'io fandrosoana io?","answer":" Edward Jenner no mpahay siansa tao ambadiky ny fikarohana izay nitarika ny fivoaran'ny vaksiny voalohany. Tamin'ny taona 1796 dia nanao andrana izy izay nanosoriny zazalahy kely voan'ny nendra omby (vaccinia) ary avy eo nampiharihary ilay zazalahy tamin'ny nendra olombelona, ​​ka nampiseho ny fahombiazan'ny vaksiny miady amin'ny nendra. Io fahitana io no nametraka ny fototry ny fanaovana vaksiny maoderina."},{"question":"రెండు గోళాల ఘనపరిమాణాల నిష్పత్తి 8:27 అయిన వాటి వక్రతల వైశాల్యాల నిష్పత్తి ఎంత ?","answer":"4:9"},{"question":"ગુજરાતી ભોજન સંસ્કૃતિ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"ગુજરાતી ખોરાક મુખ્યત્વે શાકાહારી છે. સામાન્ય ગુજરાતી થાળીમાં રોટલી/ ભાખરી/ થેપલા/ રોટલો, દાળ, કઢી, ખીચડી, ભાત અને શાકનો સમાવેશ થાય છે. અથાણું(ભારતીય અથાણું) અને છૂંદોનો ઉપયોગ મસાલા તરીકે થાય છે. ગુજરાતના ચાર મુખ્ય પ્રદેશો ગુજરાતી ભોજનમાં પોતપોતાની શૈલીઓ લાવે છે. ઘણી ગુજરાતી વાનગીઓ એક જ સમયે વિશિષ્ટ રીતે મીઠી, ખારી અને મસાલેદાર હોય છે. સૌરાષ્ટ્ર વિસ્તારમાં, છાશ તેમના રોજિંદા ખોરાકમાં આવશ્યક માનવામાં આવે છે."},{"question":"Jan Janszoon","answer":"Janszoon van Haarlem, ti a mọ si Reis Mourad the Younger (c. 1570 – c. 1641), jẹ apaniyan Dutch ti tẹlẹ ti o di corsair Barbary ni Ottoman Algeria ati Republic of Salé. Lẹhin ti o ti gba nipasẹ awọn ẹlẹṣin Algerian kuro ni Lanzarote ni ọdun 1618, o yipada si Islam o si yi orukọ rẹ pada si Mourad. O di ọkan ninu olokiki julọ ti awọn corsairs Barbary orundun 17th. Paapọ pẹlu awọn corsairs miiran, o ṣe iranlọwọ lati fi idi Republic of Salé olominira mulẹ ni ilu orukọ yẹn, o ṣiṣẹ bi Alakoso akọkọ ati Alakoso. O tun ṣiṣẹ bi Gomina Oualidia.Janszoon van Haerlem ni a bi ni Haarlem ni ọdun 1570, eyiti o wa ni Holland, lẹhinna agbegbe kan ti ijọba ijọba Habsburg ṣe ijọba. Ogun Ọdun Mẹjọ laarin awọn ọlọtẹ Dutch ati Ijọba Ara ilu Spanish labẹ King Philip II ti bẹrẹ ni ọdun meje ṣaaju ibimọ rẹ; o pẹ ni gbogbo igbesi aye rẹ. A mọ diẹ nipa igbesi aye akọkọ rẹ. O fẹ Southgen Cave ni ọdun 1595 ati pe o ni awọn ọmọ meji pẹlu rẹ, Edward ati Lysbeth. [ijuwe ti nilo]Ni ọdun 1600, Jan Janszoon bẹrẹ bi ọkọ oju-omi aladani Dutch ti o wa lati ibudo ọkọ oju-ile rẹ ti Haarlem, ti n ṣiṣẹ fun ipinle pẹlu awọn lẹta ti marque lati ṣe ifilọlẹ gbigbe ọkọ oju omi Spanish ni Ogun Ọdun Mẹjọ. Janszoon bò awọn aala ti awọn lẹta rẹ o si wa ọna rẹ si awọn ilu ibudo igbẹkẹle ti Barbary Coast of North Africa, nibiti o le kọlu awọn ọkọ oju omi ti gbogbo ilu ajeji: nigbati o kọlu ọkọ oju omi Spanish kan, o fo asia Dutch; nigbati o kọlu eyikeyi miiran, o di Captain Ottoman o si fo oṣupa oṣupa ati asia irawọ ti awọn Tooki tabi asia eyikeyi ninu ọpọlọpọ awọn ijọba Mẹditarenia miiran. Lakoko yii, o ti kọ idile Dutch rẹ silẹ.A gba Janszoon ni ọdun 1618 ni Lanzarote ( ọkan ninu awọn erekusu Canary ) nipasẹ awọn ẹlẹṣin Algerian ati pe o mu lọ si Algiers bi igbekun. Nibẹ ni o \\"tan Turk\\", tabi Musulumi. Diẹ ninu awọn akoitan ṣalaye pe iyipada naa fi agbara mu. Janszoon funrararẹ, sibẹsibẹ, gbiyanju gidigidi lati yi awọn ara ilu Yuroopu ẹlẹgbẹ rẹ ti o jẹ Kristiẹni lati di Musulumi ati pe o jẹ ihinrere Musulumi ti o ni itara. Awọn Tooki Ilu Ottoman ṣetọju iwọn ipa ti ipa lori dípò ti Sultan wọn nipa iwuri fun awọn Moors ni gbangba lati ṣe ilosiwaju ara wọn nipasẹ ajalelokun lodi si awọn agbara Yuroopu, eyiti o binu si Ottoman Ottoman. Lẹhin iyipada Janszoon si Islam ati awọn ọna ti awọn ti o mu, o wọ ọkọ pẹlu olokiki olokiki Sulayman Rais, ti a tun mọ ni Slemen Reis, ẹniti o jẹ Dutchman kan ti a npè ni De Veenboer, ẹniti Janszoon ti mọ ṣaaju gbigba rẹ ati ẹniti o tun yipada si Islam. Wọn wa pẹlu Simon de Danser. [ijuwe ti nilo] Ṣugbọn, nitori Algiers ti pari alafia pẹlu ọpọlọpọ awọn orilẹ-ede Yuroopu, kii ṣe ibudo ti o yẹ lati eyiti lati ta awọn ọkọ oju omi ti o gba tabi ẹru wọn. Nitorinaa, lẹhin ti o pa Sulayman Rais nipasẹ ibọn kekere kan ni ọdun 1619, Janszoon gbe lọ si ibudo atijọ ti Salé o bẹrẹ iṣẹ lati ọdọ rẹ bi corsair Barbary kan.Ni ọdun 1619, Salé Rovers ṣalaye ibudo naa lati jẹ olominira olominira lati ọdọ Sultan. Wọn ṣeto ijọba kan ti o ni awọn oludari apaniyan 14 ati dibo Janszoon gẹgẹbi Alakoso wọn. Oun yoo tun ṣiṣẹ bi Admiral Grand, ti a mọ ni Murat Reis, ti ọgagun wọn. Awọn ọkọ oju-omi Salé jẹ to awọn ọkọ oju omi mejidilogun, gbogbo wọn kere nitori ẹnu-ọna abo aijinile pupọ.Lẹhin idoti ti ko ni aṣeyọri ti ilu naa, Sultan ti Ilu Morocco jẹwọ iṣẹ-ṣiṣe rẹ. Ni ilodisi igbagbọ olokiki pe Sultan Zidan Abu Maali ti gba ijọba ọba pada lori Salé o si yan Janszoon Gomina ni ọdun 1624, Sultan gba idibo Janszoon gẹgẹbi alaga nipasẹ yiyan ni yiyan bi gomina ayẹyẹ rẹ.Labẹ itọsọna Janszoon, iṣowo ni Salé ṣe rere. Awọn orisun akọkọ ti owo oya ti ijọba olominira yii jẹ apaniyan ati awọn oniwe-nipasẹ-trades, sowo ati awọn olugbagbọ ni ohun-ini ji. Awọn akoitan ti ṣe akiyesi oye ati igboya ti Janszoon, eyiti a fihan ninu agbara olori rẹ. O fi agbara mu lati wa oluranlọwọ lati tọju, eyiti o yorisi igbanisise ti arakunrin ẹlẹgbẹ kan lati Netherlands, Mathys van Bostel Oosterlinck, ẹniti yoo ṣiṣẹ bi Igbakeji-Admiral rẹ.Janszoon ti di ọlọrọ pupọ lati owo oya rẹ bi ẹwa apaniyan, awọn sisanwo fun ìdákọró ati awọn owo abo miiran, ati fifọ awọn ẹru ji. Oju-ọjọ iṣelu ni Salé buru si opin ọdun 1627, nitorinaa Janszoon dakẹ gbe ẹbi rẹ ati gbogbo iṣẹ rẹ pada si Algiers olominira.Àwọn ará Netherlands tí wọ́n kó nígbèkùnLakoko ti o wa ni Ilu Morocco, Janszoon ṣiṣẹ lati ni aabo itusilẹ ti awọn igbekun Dutch lati awọn ajalelokun miiran ati ṣe idiwọ wọn lati ta sinu ifi.Àgbékalẹ̀ Àárín Àwọn Ọmọ ilẹ̀ Faransé àti Morocco ti ọdún 1631Imọ ti awọn ede pupọ, lakoko ti o wa ni Algiers o ṣe alabapin si idasile adehun adehun Franco-Moroccan ti 1631 laarin Faranse King Louis XIII ati Sultan Abu Marwan Abd al-Malik II.LundyNi ọdun 1627, Janszoon gba erekusu Lundy ni ikanni Bristol o si mu u fun ọdun marun, ni lilo rẹ bi ipilẹ fun awọn irin-ajo gigun.Ilẹ̀ IcelandNi ọdun 1627, Janszoon lo Danish kan “ẹrú” ( o ṣee ṣe ki o jẹ ọmọ ẹgbẹ atukọ kan ti o gba ọkọ oju-omi Danish kan ti o gba bi ẹbun apaniyan kan ) lati ṣe awakọ oun ati awọn ọkunrin rẹ si Iceland. Nibẹ ni wọn ja abule ipeja ti Grindavík. Awọn ohun mimu wọn jẹ kekere, diẹ ninu awọn ẹja iyọ ati awọn ibi aabo diẹ, ṣugbọn wọn tun gba Icelanders mejila ati awọn Danes mẹta ti o ṣẹlẹ lati wa ni abule naa. Nigbati wọn nlọ Grindavík, wọn ṣakoso lati tan ati mu ọkọ oju-omi oniṣowo Danish kan ti o kọja nipasẹ ọna fifo asia eke. [ijuwe ti nilo]Awọn ọkọ oju omi wọ ọkọ oju omi lọ si Bessastaðir, ijoko ti gomina Danish ti Iceland, lati ja ṣugbọn ko lagbara lati ṣe ibalẹ – o sọ pe wọn ti kuna nipasẹ ina Kanonu lati awọn odi agbegbe ( Bessastaðaskans ) ati ẹgbẹ ti o ni kiakia ti awọn anfani lati Gusu Peninsula. Wọn pinnu lati ta ọkọ si ile Salé, nibiti wọn ti ta awọn igbekun wọn bi ẹrú.Awọn ọkọ oju omi corsair meji lati Algiers, o ṣee ṣe sopọ si igbogun ti Janszoon, wa si Iceland ni ọjọ 4 Keje ati pe o wa nibẹ. Lẹhinna wọn wọ ọkọ oju omi lọ si Vestmannaeyjar kuro ni etikun gusu ati ja si ibẹ fun ọjọ mẹta. Awọn iṣẹlẹ wọnyẹn ni a mọ ni Iceland gẹgẹ bi Tyrkjaránið ( awọn ifipa ti Ilu Turki ), bi awọn ipinlẹ Barbary ṣe jẹ apakan ti Ottoman Ottoman.Awọn iroyin nipasẹ awọn Icelanders ti o jẹ ẹrú ti o lo akoko lori awọn ọkọ oju omi corsair sọ pe awọn ipo fun awọn obinrin ati awọn ọmọde jẹ deede, ni pe wọn yọọda lati gbe jakejado ọkọ oju omi, ayafi si dekini mẹẹdogun. Awọn ajalelokun naa ni a rii fifun ni afikun ounjẹ si awọn ọmọde lati awọn ikọlu ikọkọ ti ara wọn. Obinrin ti o bi ọkọ oju-omi ni a tọju pẹlu iyi, ni agbara ikọkọ ati aṣọ nipasẹ awọn ajalelokun. Wọn fi awọn ọkunrin naa si idaduro awọn ọkọ oju omi ati pe wọn ti yọ ẹwọn wọn kuro ni kete ti awọn ọkọ oju omi ba to lati ilẹ. Laibikita awọn iṣeduro ti o gbajumọ nipa itọju ti awọn igbekun, awọn iroyin Icelander ko mẹnuba pe awọn ẹrú ni ifipabanilopo lori irin-ajo funrararẹ, sibẹsibẹ, Guðríður Símonardóttir, ọkan ninu awọn igbekun diẹ lati pada si Iceland nigbamii, ni a ta sinu ifi ẹrú ibalopo bi apejọ kan.Àpótí Ìlú Baltimore, ní Ilẹ̀ IrelandLehin ti o wọ ọkọ oju omi fun oṣu meji ati pẹlu diẹ lati ṣafihan fun irin-ajo naa, Janszoon yipada si igbekun ti o ya lori irin-ajo, Roman Katoliki kan ti a npè ni John Hackett, fun alaye lori ibiti igbogun ti ere le ṣee ṣe. Awọn olugbe Alatẹnumọ ti Baltimore, ilu kekere kan ni West Cork, Ireland, ni ilu abinibi ara ilu Roman Katoliki ti ara ilu Irish nitori wọn gbe wọn si awọn ilẹ ti o gba lati idile O'Driscoll. Hackett ṣe itọsọna Janszoon si ilu yii ati kuro lọdọ tirẹ. Janszoon ti gba Baltimore silẹ ni 20 June 1631, ti o gba ohun-ini kekere ṣugbọn mu awọn igbekun 108, ẹniti o ta bi ẹrú ni Ariwa Afirika. A sọ pe Janszoon ti tu Irish silẹ ati pe o mu awọn igbekun Gẹẹsi nikan. Laipẹ lẹhin apo naa, wọn mu Hackett ati gbe mọ fun ilufin rẹ. \\"Eyi kii ṣe Kristiẹni kan ti ko sọkun ati ẹniti ko kun fun ibanujẹ ni oju ọpọlọpọ awọn iranṣẹbinrin oloootitọ ati ọpọlọpọ awọn obinrin ti o dara ti a kọ silẹ si iwa ika ti awọn alaigbede wọnyi ”\\". Meji ninu awọn abule naa nikan pada si ilu wọn.Àwọn Ìjà Ìjà Ní Òkun MẹditaréníàÀtúnṣeMurat Reis pinnu láti rí owó tó pọ̀ gbà nípa lílo àwọn erékùṣù Mẹditaréníà bí àwọn erékún Balearic, Corsica, Sardinia, àti etíkun gúúsù Sicily. Ó sábà máa ń ta ọ̀pọ̀ lára àwọn nǹkan rẹ̀ ní ìlú Tunis, níbi tó ti di ọ̀rẹ́ àwọn Dey. Ó ti ń rìnrìn àjò ní Òkun Jóńsíkò. Ó bá àwọn ará Venice jà nítòsí etíkun Kírétè àti Sípírọ́sì pẹ̀lú ẹgbẹ́ àwọn ọmọ ogun olúgbìn tó ní àwọn ọmọ ilẹ̀ Dutch, Moriscos, Arab, Turkish, àti àwọn ọmọ ogun Janissaries tó jẹ́ olóye.Ni ọdun 1635, nitosi eti okun Tunisia, Murat Reis ti kun ati iyalẹnu nipasẹ ikọlu lojiji. Oun ati ọpọlọpọ awọn ọkunrin rẹ ni o gba nipasẹ awọn Knights ti Malta. O ti wa ni ewon ninu awọn ile nla dudu ti erekusu naa. O ṣe ibi ati ni ijiya, o si jiya ilera aisan nitori akoko rẹ ninu ile-ẹwọn. Ni ọdun 1640, o ko sa asala lẹhin ikọlu Corsair nla kan, eyiti Dey ti Tunis gbero ni pẹkipẹki lati le gba awọn atukọ ẹlẹgbẹ wọn ati Corsairs. O bu ọla fun pupọ o si yìn fun ipadabọ rẹ si Ilu Morocco ati awọn Ipinle Barbary nitosi.Lẹhin Janszoon pada si Ilu Morocco ni 1640, o ti yan gẹgẹ bi Gomina ti odi nla ti Oualidia, nitosi Safi. O ngbe ni Castle ti Maladia. Ni Oṣu Keji ọdun 1640, ọkọ oju omi de pẹlu consul Dutch tuntun kan, ẹniti o mu Lysbeth Janszoon van Haarlem, ọmọbinrin Janszoon nipasẹ iyawo Dutch rẹ, lati ṣabẹwo si baba rẹ. Nigbati Lysbeth de, Janszoon \\"joko ni pomp nla lori capeti, pẹlu awọn aga timutimu, awọn iranṣẹ ni ayika rẹ\\". O rii pe Murat Reis ti di alailagbara, arugbo. Lysbeth duro pẹlu baba rẹ titi di Oṣu Kẹjọ ọdun 1641, nigbati o pada si Holland. Little ni a mọ ti Janszoon lẹhinna; o ṣee ṣe ti fẹyìntì nikẹhin lati igbesi aye gbangba ati ajalelokun. Ọjọ iku rẹ ko jẹ aimọ.Ni ọdun 1596, nipasẹ obinrin Dutch ti a ko mọ, ọmọ akọkọ ti Janszoon ni a bi, Lysbeth Janszoon van Haarlem. [ mimọ ti nilo ]Lẹhin ti o di apaniyan kan, Janszoon pade obinrin ti a ko mọ ni Cartagena, Spain, ẹniti yoo fẹ. Idanimọ ti obinrin yii jẹ ohun ti ko ni itan-akọọlẹ, ṣugbọn ipohunpo ni pe o jẹ ti ipilẹṣẹ ti ọpọlọpọ-ẹya, ti a ka si “Morisco” ni Ilu Sipeeni. Awọn akoitan ti sọ pe ko jẹ nkankan diẹ sii ju apejọ kan, awọn miiran sọ pe o jẹ Musulumi Mudéjar kan ti o ṣiṣẹ fun idile ọlọla Kristiẹni kan, ati awọn iṣeduro miiran ni a ti ṣe pe o jẹ “Ọmọ-binrin ọba.”.\\" Nipasẹ igbeyawo yii, Janszoon ni awọn ọmọ mẹrin: Abraham Janszoon van Salee ( b.1602 ), Philip Janszoon van Salee ( b. 1604 ), Anthony Janszoon van Salee ( b.1607 ), ati Cornelis Janszoon van Salee ( b. 1608 ).O jẹ akiyesi pe Janszoon ṣe igbeyawo fun igba kẹta si ọmọbirin Sultan Moulay Ziden ni ọdun 1624.Ni ọdun 2009, ere kan ti o da lori igbesi aye Janszoon bi apaniyan kan, “Jan Janszoon, de bilondi Arabier”, ti Karim El Guennouni kọ irin-ajo Netherlands. \\"Ọmọ-baba agba: Ballad ti Murad the Captain\\" jẹ ewi awọn ọmọde nipa Janszoon ti a tẹjade ni ọdun 2007.[7]Ni ọdun 2015, Janszoon jẹ alatako bọtini ninu itan aramada Slave si Fortune nipasẹ D.J. Munro.A tun mọ Janszoon bi Murat Reis the Younger. Awọn orukọ Dutch rẹ ni a tun fun ni Jan Jansen ati Jan Jansz; orukọ rẹ ti a gba bi Morat Rais, Murat Rais, Morat; Little John Ward, John Barber, Captain John, ati Caid Morato jẹ diẹ ninu awọn orukọ Pirate rẹ. \\"“Irun irun” jẹ oruko apeso ti Janszoon."},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.තනි කකුලෙන් ඉන්න සුදා     ","answer":"හතු"},{"question":"Geeraar aqoontu caqiido weeye?","answer":"AQOONTU CAQIIDO WEEYE.aqoontu caqiido weeyecaqliga taban toosi weeye.cibaadiyo toobad weeye.cadaabta ka joogso weeyeillaah cabsidiisa weeye ha caasiyin waalid weeye.curyaanka ha dhaafin weeye.ka liitana caawi weeye.cidlada ha ku dhaafin weeyecidaad xukunkooda haysocadaalad ku maamul weeye.ha ciilin mid gaara weeyeha caayin dhigaaga weeyecirdiga ruuxnaba ha liidinha ciirsanan gaalka weeyecalaamad cidgaari leeday.cumaamad ha moodin weeye.canaan intaad xaqleeday.caloosha ka qaado weeye.ciqdigaa ha ku waarin weeye.calaamo adoo arkaaya.si aan cuqubadu u raacincaruurta ha quudin weeye.cirkaa sida loo yagleelay cibaaro ka qaaado weeye.aqoontu car juuqdhe maaha casiis diido gef maaha.dhulkiyo ciidaada hooyocaraabe ka dooro maahacaadayso xumoonta maaha.markuu curcurkaagu buuxo.intaad cantartood ismoodo.midaan ciidi loodinayninciqaabta ku dhaado maaha.haduu carigii holcaayey.hadaba cagihii ku joogohaday cayladii colloowdaycooladihi laga heshiiyay.haduu cilmigina quluubtaceegaago sidii harooyinmaxaa camalkii hor jooga?maxaa maskaxdii cidaaday?maxaa curdiinkii baxaayey?ku ciilay hankuu tabaayey.maxaa curadkii aqoonta.?maxaa cinaabkii culuumta?maxaa camalkii masuulka?maxaa sharaftii cuqaasha?jahliga cidhbihiisa geeyay. "},{"question":"Beqil ma mbind mii:Nangeen fonk julli, di joxe asaka, te di rukkoo ànd ak way-rukkoo ya. [Jullig mbooloo, di julli ci biir jàkka yi].","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Na ngéen fonk julli, di joxe àsaka, te di rukoo ànd ak wayrukoo ya. [Jullig mbooloo, di julli ci biir jàkka yi]."},{"question":"කල්පිටියේ ධීවර හා සංචාරක ප්‍රජාවේ බොහෝ දෙනෙක් බාර් රීෆ් ජාතික වස්තුවක් ලෙස සලකන්නේ ඇයි, එය ආරක්ෂා කිරීමට සහ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය කිරීමට ඔවුන් ගෙන ඇති ක්‍රියාමාර්ග මොනවාද?","answer":"කල්පිටියේ ධීවර හා සංචාරක ප්‍රජාවේ බොහෝ දෙනෙක් බාර් රීෆ් ජාතික නිධානයක් සහ සමුද්‍ර අභයභූමියක් ලෙස සලකති. ඔවුන් විවිධ සංවිධාන, රාජ්‍ය ආයතන සහ ප්‍රජාවගේම සහයෝගය සහ උපදෙස් ඇතිව ගල්පරය ආරක්ෂා කිරීම සහ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණය කිරීම සඳහා ක්‍රියාකාරීව සහභාගී වේ."},{"question":"Inona no fahitana mifandraika amin'ny herinaratra nataon'i Benjamin Franklin?","answer":"Hitan'i Benjamin Franklin fa endriky ny herinaratra ny tselatra rehefa manidina ny papango malaza mandritra ny oram-baratra, manampy amin'ny fahatakarana ny herinaratra."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Jika penuh ia menyelam, jika kosong ia bergantung. Dijumpai di tandas.","answer":"Jawapan: gayung. "},{"question":"ඇතුළත පිදුරු බිස්ස ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න.","answer":"ඉඩකඩ තිබෙන හෝ නිවෙස්වල ගෙයි ඇතුළත (පිදුරු) බිස්සක් දක්නට ලැබේ. එය 'ඇතුළත පිදුරු බිස්ස' නම් වේ. මෙම බිස්ස සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම පිදුරුවලින් තනාගත්තකි. එළිමහන් පිදුරු බිස්සට මෙන් උමං ලී හෝ ආධාරක වැල් අවශ්‍ය නොවේ. අවශ්‍යවන්නේ පිදුරු හා මානව ශ්‍රමය පමණි. නිවසේ ඉඩකඩ තියෙන ස්ථානයක් මේ වෙනුවෙන් තෝරා ගනු ලබයි. බොහෝ විට මෙය ගබඩා කාමරයක් වේ."},{"question":"Create an intricate mystery novel with multiple plot twists and layers of deception.","answer":" एक जटिल रहस्य उपन्यास बनाएं जिसमें कई कथा पलटने और भ्रांतियों की विभिन्न स्तरें हों।"},{"question":"Iyawo olori ileegbimọ aṣofin Ọṣun tẹlẹ, Najeem Salaam, ti ku o","answer":"Olori ileegbimọ aṣofin ipinlẹ Ọṣun tẹlẹ, Ọnarebu Najeem Salam, ti kede iku ọkan lara awọn iyawo rẹ, Adebimpe Adukẹ Salam, eyi to ṣẹlẹ laaarọ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii.Ninu ọrọ to fi sori ayelujara laipẹ yii ni ọkunrin oloṣelu ọmọ bibi ilu Ejigbo naa ti sọ pe oun ko le bi Ọlọrun lẹjọ lori adanu nla naa, ṣugbọn oun ti gba bi akọsilẹ oun ṣe ri.Oṣogbo la gbọ pe obinrin ẹni to ti to aadọta ọdun naa ku si laaarọ oni lẹyin aisan ranpẹ.Oun niyawo keji fun Salam, ileewosan ijọba to wa niluu Ejigbo lo si ti n ṣiṣẹ nitori oṣiṣẹ eleto ilera ni. Irọlẹ ọjọ Aje ọsẹ yii la gbọ pe wọn yoo si sinku rẹ nilana Musulumi nile wọn to wa niluu Ejigbo.Latigba ti ọkọ rẹ ti kede iku ọhun lawọn araalu, paapaa awọn oloṣelu ti n ranṣẹ ibanikẹdun si i.Gomina Oyetọla ṣapejuwe obinrin naa gẹgẹ bii onirẹlẹ to fọwọ ti ọkọ rẹ lẹyin, to si jẹ apẹẹrẹ rere fun awọn obinrin ti ọkọ wọn n ṣoṣelu."},{"question":"Inona ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\" Fampihaingoana\\"?","answer":"Ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Fampihaingoana\\" dia \\"Fandravahana\\"."},{"question":"Sheeg ninkii ugu horeeyey ee Islaam ah oo yeesho ciidan ilaaliya?","answer":"Wuxu ahaa Mucaawiye Binu Abii Sufyaan (RC)."},{"question":"代表作に交響詩「ローマの松」「ローマの噴水」「ローマの祭」の「ローマ3部作」があるイタリアの作曲家は誰でしょう？","answer":"オットリーノ・レスピーギです。"},{"question":"Answer the following question with \\"Yes\\" or \\"No\\" or \\"None\\" if none of the first two answers apply.Question: పామురెల్లి గ్రామానికి పశ్చిమాన ఉన్న జిల్లా ఏది ?Topic: పామురెల్లిArticle: పామురెల్లి, విశాఖపట్నం జిల్లా, పాడేరు మండలానికి చెందిన గ్రామము.[1]ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన పాడేరు నుండి 9 కి. మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన అనకాపల్లి నుండి 83 కి. మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 22 ఇళ్లతో, 71 జనాభాతో 52 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 33, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 38. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 0 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 71. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 584636[2].పిన్ కోడ్: 531077.విద్యా సౌకర్యాలుసమీప బాలబడి పాడేరులోను,ప్రాథమిక పాఠశాల, ప్రాథమికోన్నత పాఠశాల, మాధ్యమిక పాఠశాల‌లు గుత్తులపుట్టులోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప జూనియర్ కళాశాల, ప్రభుత్వ ఆర్ట్స్ / సైన్స్ డిగ్రీ కళాశాల పాడేరులోను, ఇంజనీరింగ్ కళాశాల అనకాపల్లిలోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వైద్య కళాశాల, మేనేజిమెంటు కళాశాల విశాఖపట్నంలోను, పాలీటెక్నిక్ పాడేరులోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వృత్తి విద్యా శిక్షణ పాఠశాల అరకులోయలోను, అనియత విద్యా కేంద్రం అనకాపల్లిలోను, దివ్యాంగుల ప్రత్యేక పాఠశాల విశాఖపట్నం లోనూ ఉన్నాయి. వైద్య సౌకర్యంప్రభుత్వ వైద్య సౌకర్యంఒక సంచార వైద్య శాలలో డాక్టర్లు లేరు. ముగ్గురు పారామెడికల్ సిబ్బంది ఉన్నారు. సమీప ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య ఉప కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 5 కి.మీ. లోపు దూరంలో ఉంది. సమీప సామాజిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉంది. డిస్పెన్సరీ, పశు వైద్యశాల గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం, మాతా శిశు సంరక్షణ కేంద్రం, టి. బి వైద్యశాల గ్రామం నుండి 10 కి.మీ. కంటే ఎక్కువ దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. అలోపతి ఆసుపత్రి, ప్రత్యామ్నాయ ఔషధ ఆసుపత్రి, కుటుంబ సంక్షేమ కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 10 కి.మీ. కంటే ఎక్కువ దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. ప్రైవేటు వైద్య సౌకర్యంతాగు నీరుబావుల నీరు  గ్రామంలో అందుబాటులో ఉంది. తాగునీటి కోసం చేతిపంపులు, బోరుబావులు, కాలువలు, చెరువులు వంటి సౌకర్యాలేమీ లేవు.పారిశుధ్యంగ్రామంలో మురుగునీటి పారుదల వ్యవస్థ లేదు. మురుగునీటిని శుద్ధి ప్లాంట్‌లోకి పంపిస్తున్నారు. గ్రామంలో సంపూర్ణ పారిశుధ్య పథకం అమలవుతోంది. సామాజిక మరుగుదొడ్డి సౌకర్యం లేదు. ఇంటింటికీ తిరిగి వ్యర్థాలను సేకరించే వ్యవస్థ లేదు. సామాజిక బయోగ్యాస్ ఉత్పాదక వ్యవస్థ లేదు. చెత్తను వీధుల పక్కనే పారబోస్తారు. సమాచార, రవాణా సౌకర్యాలుపోస్టాఫీసు సౌకర్యం, సబ్ పోస్టాఫీసు సౌకర్యం, పోస్ట్ అండ్ టెలిగ్రాఫ్ ఆఫీసు గ్రామానికి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ....దూరము. ","answer":"None"},{"question":"பஞ்சாப் கேசரி ” என்றழைக்கப்பட்ட தேசிய தலைவர்","answer":"விடை: லாலா லஜபதிராய்"},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Taïwan?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Taïwan mu ngi tudd Taipei."},{"question":"\\"Өз атын атап жадабай,Жар салат ой-тоо кыяга,Жумурткасын таштап ал,Бир кез келген уяга\\"- табышмактын жандырмагы кандай?","answer":"Табышмактын жандырмагы -(күкүк 🐦)"},{"question":"Sheeg isha ugu muhiimsan ileyska (Iftiinka) ?","answer":"Isha ugu muhiimsan Ileyska (Iftiinka) waa Qoraxda ."},{"question":"කම්පාලා නගරය කිනන් රටක අගනුවරද?","answer":"කම්පාලා නගරය උගන්ඩාව රටෙහි අගනුවර ලෙස සැලකේ."},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত বাক্যাংশটি সম্পূর্ণ করুন :‘বীরাঙ্গনা’ শব্দের আভিধানিক অর্থ হচ্ছে 'বীর নারী'; জাতির জনক বঙ্গবন্ধুই যুদ্ধকালীন সময় লাঞ্ছিত, নির্যাতিত নারীদের \\"বীরাঙ্গনা\\" খেতাব দিয়েছিলেন।","answer":"স্বাধীনতা যুদ্ধে বিজয় লাভের পর যুদ্ধকালীন সময় ধর্ষিত নারীদেরকে ‘ধর্ষিতা রমণী’, ‘অপমানিতা রমণী’, ‘দুঃস্থ মহিলা’, ‘ধর্ষণের শিকার’, ‘সৈন্যদের নিপীড়নের শিকার’, ‘ক্ষতিগ্রস্ত মহিলা’, ‘ভাগ্যবিড়ম্বিতা’ ইত্যাদি অভিধায় অভিহিত করা হতো। ১৯৭২ সালে ১৮ ফেব্রুয়ারি মুক্তিযুদ্ধকালীন নির্যাতিত মহিলাদের জন্য সরকার বাংলাদেশ মহিলা পূনর্বাসন বোর্ড গঠন করে ধর্ষিতা মহিলাদের জন্য গৃহীত পুনর্বাসন কর্মসূচির মাধ্যমে নির্যাতিতাদের মর্যাদা সমুন্নত করার উপায় উদ্ভাবনের প্রচেষ্টা নেয় এবং জাতীয় পর্যায়ে তাদের অবদানকে স্বীকৃতি দেয় বীরাঙ্গনা খেতাব প্রদানের মাধ্যমে।"},{"question":"ලන්ඩනයේ සිටියදී මා නැරඹිය යුතු ආකර්ෂණීය ස්ථාන මොනවාද?","answer":"ලන්ඩනයේ කිරීමට සහ බැලීමට බොහෝ දේ ඇත. විශාල කෞතුකාගාර ගණනාවක් නොමිලේ වන අතර සංචාරය කිරීම වටී. ඔබට ස්වභාවික ඉතිහාස කෞතුකාගාරය, බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය කෞතුකාගාරය, විද්‍යා කෞතුකාගාරය මෙන්ම වික්ටෝරියා සහ ඇල්බට් කෞතුකාගාරය නැරඹිය හැකිය. මීට අමතරව, ඔබට ජාතික ගැලරිය, ටේට් මොඩර්න් සහ ටේට් බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය වැනි කලාගාර ගණනාවකට නොමිලේ නැරඹිය හැකිය. ලන්ඩන් යනු පා ගමනින් ගවේෂණය කිරීමට හොඳ නගරයක් වන අතර ඔබට තේම්ස් නදියේ දකුණු ඉවුර දිගේ ඇවිද යා හැකිය. ලන්ඩන් කුළුණ සහ වෙස්ට්මිනිස්ටර් ඇබේ නැරඹීමට ගඟ දිගේ බෝට්ටුවක් රැගෙන ගඟේ සිට මෙන්ම පයින් යා හැකිය. බකිංහැම් මාලිගය පිටත සිට නැරඹීම සඳහා ශාන්ත ජේම්ස් උද්‍යානය හරහා ඇවිදීම ද වටී. ඔබට ලන්ඩන් අයි, මැඩම් ටුසාඩ්ස්, වෙස්ට්මිනිස්ටර් ඇබේ, ලන්ඩන් ටවර් සහ බකිංහැම් මාලිගය වැනි විවිධ ගෙවුම් ආකර්ෂණ ස්ථාන ද ඇත."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸੰਤ ਕਾ ਨਿੰਦਕੁ ਮਹਾ ਅਤਤਾਈ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕਾ ਨਿੰਦਕੁ ਖਿਨੁ ਟਿਕਨੁ ਨ ਪਾਈ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕਾ ਨਿੰਦਕੁ ਮਹਾ ਹਤਿਆਰਾ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕਾ ਨਿੰਦਕੁ ਪਰਮੇਸੁਰਿ ਮਾਰਾ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕਾ ਨਿੰਦਕੁ ਰਾਜ ਤੇ ਹੀਨੁ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕਾ ਨਿੰਦਕੁ ਦੁਖੀਆ ਅਰੁ ਦੀਨੁ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕੇ ਨਿੰਦਕ ਕਉ ਸਰਬ ਰੋਗ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕੇ ਨਿੰਦਕ ਕਉ ਸਦਾ ਬਿਜੋਗ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕੀ ਨਿੰਦਾ ਦੋਖ ਮਹਿ ਦੋਖੁ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਸੰਤ ਭਾਵੈ ਤਾ ਉਸ ਕਾ ਭੀ ਹੋਇ ਮੋਖੁ ॥੩॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 280 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਸੰਤ ਦੀ ਨਿੰਦਿਆ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਸਦਾ ਅੱਤ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਕ ਪਲਕ ਭਰ ਭੀ (ਅੱਤ ਚੁੱਕਣ ਵਲੋਂ) ਆਰਾਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੈਂਦਾ ।ਸੰਤ ਦਾ ਨਿੰਦਕ ਵੱਡਾ ਜ਼ਾਲਮ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਰੱਬ ਵਲੋਂ ਫਿਟਕਾਰਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਸੰਤ ਦਾ ਨਿੰਦਕ ਰਾਜ (ਭਾਵ, ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੇ ਸੁਖਾਂ) ਤੋਂ ਵਾਂਜਿਆਂ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਸਦਾ) ਦੁਖੀ ਤੇ ਆਤੁਰ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਸੰਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਿੰਦਿਆ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਰੇ ਰੋਗ ਵਿਆਪਦੇ ਹਨ।(ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਉਸ ਨੂੰ (ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦੇ ਸੋਮੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਤੋਂ) ਸਦਾ ਵਿਛੋੜਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਸੰਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਿੰਦਿਆ ਕਰਨੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਮਾੜਾ ਕੰਮ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਜੇ ਸੰਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ (ਨਿੰਦਕ) ਦਾ ਭੀ (ਨਿੰਦਿਆ ਤੋਂ) ਛੁਟਕਾਰਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।\\""},{"question":"පහත ගීතය ගයනා  කරන්නේ කව්ද ?පෙම් රැහැනින් මා වෙලන්නඔබෙ සෙවණේ මට හිඳින්නමම ආසයි ඔබත් සමගමේ දිවි මග එකට යන්නමගෙ ආදර විල් ජලයේනිල් මානෙල් මලක් වෙන්නරේණු සලා මල් මුවරදසිහිල් දියට එක් කරන්නමම රැය නම් ඔබ පුරහඳසිත් අහසේ නැගී එන්නසඳ සිහිලේ තැවුල් නිවාරැයත් සමග ගෙවී යන්න","answer":"අජන්තා නාකන්දල"},{"question":"UMirriam sengathi wayebethelwe kwaDicey. Wake wahlala wathula kungavumi nokubaasukume.'Akusavumi yini ukuba uphume lapha ekhaya?' ebuza ejabhile.'Hhayi sengizosukuma. Uyazi nawe ukuthi akulubala ukushiya indlu osuyihlaleiminyaka ethi ayibe yishumi nesithupha.''Okusho ukuthi kubuhlungu nokubushiya ubugqila uma ukhulele kubo?''Kunjalo Chule uma kunjengoba ngizwa.' Wasukuma ngokuzidela wakhombaamapulasitiki namapotimenjana akhathele. UChule wakweya. Ngokubona kwakheuMirriam kwakufanele ayishiye le mithwalo, aphume ngayekugqokile kuphelaayothenga okusha okungafanelana nezinga lomuzi wakhe.'Bengizothi kushiyele umfana kaNtshangase konke lokhu kokwendlula umbhede ukubaangesabi ukuthi angahle akuphephethe ngezinsila zakho.''Kanti ngeke akwenze lokho.''Ungamphikeli. Ukhala nje, kulukhuni kuyitshe nokuba uphume lapha endlini, awaziwakwenzani.'Imithwalo yaphuma, wabelekelela uHlulintombi bayilayisha emotweni.'Sizomtshela uGenyeza ukuthi wena phixiphixana ubuwelekelela kulayishwaizimpahla.' Esho sengathi akanakile uRose ezedlulela ngendlela.Wema khimilili uHlulintombi enamahlonyana.Waqhubeka nokho ngoba egqugquzelwa uChule ngokuba asale eseqhubeka ukuzeashayelwe isenzo asaziyo.Balayisha koma. Kwasala umbhede, iwodilobhu netafula elalinomsakazwana omncaneuChule athi awushiyele ukududuza uGenyeza. OChule noHlulintombi besaxhawulanangasemotweni, bebongana ngemali, uChule embonga ngosizo ayebe naloekunqotshweni kukaMirriam, uMirriam wasala wathatha ipheshana wabhalelauGenyeza.1. Chaza ukulandelana kwezehlakalo/kwezigameko ezaholela ekushonenikukaMahuzu.","answer":"UMaHadebe wahlela noMahuzu ukuba aye eThekwini ayodlisa uNomvulaumuthi nokubuya nencwadi yocingo. Kwathi uma efika eThekwini uMahuzuwayalela abangane bakhe ukuba badlise uNomvula. Ngenkathibesekamelweni likaNomvula, wakwazi ukulwa nabo wasizwa nanguChule.OMahuzu babaleka ngemoto, endleleni bama bashintsha inombolo puleti,kwaqhamuka iloli yabashayisa, bafa oMahuzu."},{"question":"Ай деген эмне ? ","answer":"Ай, жалчык — Жердин жалгыз табигый жандоочусу, Жерге жакын жайгашкан асман телосу. Асманда жарыгы боюнча Күндөн кийинки экинчи объект. Жер менен Айдын аралыгы 384 467 чарчы."},{"question":"Quelle personne est connue pour avoir publié « L’interprétation des rêves » ?","answer":"La personne connue pour avoir publié « L'interprétation des rêves » est Sigmund Freud. Sigmund Freud était un neurologue autrichien et le fondateur de la psychanalyse, un domaine de la psychologie axé sur la compréhension de l'inconscient et de son influence sur le comportement humain. Selon Freud, les rêves se forment à la suite de deux processus mentaux. Le premier processus implique des forces inconscientes qui construisent un souhait exprimé par le rêve, et le second est le processus de censure qui déforme de force l’expression du souhait. Selon Freud, tous les rêves sont des formes de « réalisation de souhaits »."},{"question":"Amelia Earhart 1932 දී අත්ලාන්තික් සාගරය හරහා වාර්තා තැබූ ගුවන් ගමන සහ එම ගමනේදී ඇය මුහුණ දුන් අභියෝග විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"1932 දී Amelia Earhart අත්ලාන්තික් සාගරය හරහා තනි ගුවන් ගමනක් සම්පූර්ණ කළ අතර, එය කළ පළමු කාන්තාව බවට පත්විය. සැතපුම් 2,026ක නොනවතින ගමනේදී, ඇයට තෙහෙට්ටුව, කාන්දු වන ඉන්ධන ටැංකියක් ඇතුළු අභියෝගවලට මුහුණ දීමට සිදු විය. උතුරු අයර්ලන්තයට ගොඩබෑමට පෙර යානයේ පියාපත් මත අයිස් සෑදී තිබූ අතර, අඩි 3,000 ක් පහළට බැසීමටද සිදු විය."},{"question":"Em Os Três Porquinhos, de que é feita a casa mais forte?","answer":"A casa mais forte em Os Três Porquinhos é feita de tijolos."},{"question":"Ìgbà mélòó ọ̀tọ̀ọ̀tọ̀ ni wọ́n ti yàn Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala gẹ́gẹ́ bi mínísítà fún ètò ọ̀rọ̀ ìṣúná Nàìjíríà?","answer":"ẹ̀ẹ̀mejì"},{"question":"Šios Lietuvoje gyvenančios tautinės mažumos vienas tradicinių kepinių yra šimtalapis. Kokia tai tautinė mažuma?","answer":"Totoriai."},{"question":"Туулган күнгө карата куттуктоо жазып бере аласыңбы  ?","answer":"Мен эч качан бейишке барган эмесмин, бирок бул мага сенин кучагыңа караганда сооронуч бере албастыгын билем. Бирок, сен азыр жана түбөлүккө менин өзгөчө адамымсың! Туулган кунуңуз менен куттуктайм!"},{"question":"Kumuu Ahaa Raysul wasaarihii labaad(2) ee wadanka soomaaliya?","answer":"Muhamad Xaaji Ibraahim Cigaal"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki yang bertemakan permainan berikut: Bulatan yang kecil dan keras dimain oleh budak.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah guli"},{"question":"Суроо: Дүйнөдөгү эң узун дарыя кайсы?","answer":"Жооп: Нил дарыясы дүйнөдөгү эң узун дарыя"},{"question":"Inona no volana aorinan'ny Febroary","answer":"Martsa no volana aorinan'ny Febroary"},{"question":"ග්‍රීක පුරාවෘතයට අනුව වයින් වලට අධිපති දෙවියා කවුද?","answer":"ග්‍රීක පුරාවෘතයට අනුව වයින් වලට අධිපති දෙවියා ඩයොනයිසස් වේ."},{"question":"வினா: ஒற்றை ஒலிம்பிக்கில் அதிக ஒலிம்பிக் பதக்கம் வென்ற நாடு எது?","answer":"விடை: அமெரிக்கா"},{"question":"సరికాని జత ఏది?A) విటమిన్ A – రెటినాల్B) విటమిన్ D – కాల్సిఫెరాల్C) విటమిన్ K – టోకోఫెరాల్D) విటమిన్ C – ఆస్కార్బిక్ ఆమ్లం","answer":"C) విటమిన్ K – టోకోఫెరాల్"},{"question":"Viết tiếp đoạn văn sau: Năm ngoái, lực lượng Nga vẫn cho rằng \\"họ có thể tiếp tục tấn công và giành được nhiều lãnh thổ, thậm chí là toàn bộ Ukraine\\", theo Cancian. \\"Nhưng giờ họ chỉ cố gắng bảo vệ những lãnh thổ đã kiểm soát\\".Tại Zaporizhzhia, nơi Ukraine tiến hành mũi phản công chính, lực lượng Nga không giành thêm được lãnh thổ trong một năm qua. Thay vào đó, họ chủ yếu xây dựng công sự để tạo thành phòng tuyến nhiều lớp.Chiến thuật này cho thấy Nga đang quay lại với tư duy quân sự truyền thống là tập trung cho hoạt động phòng thủ để đối phó với cuộc tấn công của Ukraine.\\"Chuẩn bị tuyến phòng thủ kiểu này là điều mà các chỉ huy Nga đã nghiên cứu sâu từ khi còn là học viên\\", Dara Massicot, nhà phân tích quân sự Nga ở tổ chức RAND Corp ở Mỹ, nói.","answer":"Bài viết trên tạp chí Military Thought của giới tinh hoa quân sự Nga hồi tháng 4 dường như thừa nhận lực lượng Nga đã chịu tổn thất vì tập trung vào tấn công. Dù không đề cập tới Ukraine, bài viết đã vạch ra chiến thuật thực tế về cách bảo vệ các khu vực quan trọng trước một đối thủ \\"vượt trội\\"."},{"question":"Qual a categoria desta pergunta: Qual país tem a maior quantidade de floresta tropical?.","answer":"A categoria desta pergunta é geografia. A maior floresta tropical do mundo (Floresta Amazônica) está localizada na região norte do Brasil, com seus mais de 6 milhões km², integrando o território de nove países da América Latina e sete estados brasileiros."},{"question":"Ayat 1: Wolfbot juga mempunyai keupayaan untuk mengikat webbing untuk menembak mangsanya. Ayat 2: Wolfbot juga mempunyai keupayaan untuk menembak webbing untuk mengikat mangsa-mangsanya. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Tidak"},{"question":"Ñaata at la Yónnent bi ﷺ amoon ?","answer":"63"},{"question":"தண்ணீருக்கு அடியில் மெதுவாக வாழும் விலங்கு எது?","answer":"விடை: கடற்குதிரை"},{"question":"Sheeg magaca Wasiirkii Arrimaha Gudaha Xukuumaddii Daakhiliga 1956kii?","answer":"Waxa uu ahaa Muuse Boqor Cismaan."},{"question":"anadkii la-soo saaray xanjo buufiska","answer":" jawab. waxa la soo saaray 1928-dii."},{"question":"રમેશભાઈ ઓઝા વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"રમેશભાઈ ઓઝા હિંદુ ધર્મનાં જાણીતા ભાગવત કથાકાર છે.તેમનો જન્મ ૩૧ ઓગસ્ટ ૧૯૫૭ નાં રોજ અમરેલી જિલ્લાના રાજુલા તાલુકાનાં દેવકા ગામે, પિતા વ્રજલાલ કે. ઓઝા અને માતા લક્ષ્મીબેનને ત્યાં, થયો હતો. તેઓ જ્ઞાતીએ ઔદિચ્ય બ્રાહ્મણ છે. એમણે અંગ્રેજી માધ્યમમાં વિનયન શાખામાં સ્નાતક સુધીનો અભ્યાસ કર્યો છે. આથી એમની કથાઓમાં શ્રોતાઓને ભાગવતની સાથે સાથે અંગ્રેજી સંવાદો તેમ જ ગહન તત્વજ્ઞાનનો લ્હાવો પણ અસ્ખલીતપણે પહાડી અવાજમાં માણવા મળે છે.રમેશભાઈ ઓઝા પોતના પિતા વ્રજલાલ હેઠળ હમેશા \\"ભાગવદગીતા\\" નો પાઠ કરતા હતાં. રમેશભાઈ ઓઝા ના કાકા જીવરાજભાઈ ઓઝા એક અત્યંત આદરણીય કથાવાચક હતા. દરેક વ્યક્ત્તિ ને રમશભાઈ ઓઝા પોતાના પ્રવચન કુશળતા દ્વારા અને તેમના કુદરતી આકર્ષણ અને મેગ્નેટીઝમ દ્વારા આકર્ષિત કરતા."},{"question":"ජ්‍යාමිතියේ පියා ලෙස අන්වර්ථ නාමයක් ලද ගණිතඥයා කවුද?","answer":"ජ්‍යාමිතියේ පියා ලෙස අන්වර්ථ නාමයක් ලද ගණිතඥයා ​ග්‍රීක ජාතික යුක්ලී​ඩ් (Euclid) වේ. ඔහුගේ \\"මූලද්‍රව්‍ය\\" (Elements) නම් ග්‍රන්ථය සඳහා ඔහු වඩාත් ප්‍රසිද්ධ ව​න අතර එම ග්‍රන්ථය තුළ ඇති ජ්‍යාමිතිය සම්බන්ධ මූලධර්ම අදටත් වැදගත් වේ."},{"question":"ලංකාවේ විශාලතම වනාන්තරය කුමක්ද?","answer":"යුනෙස්කෝ  ලෝක උරුම මධ්යස්ථානයක් වන සිංහරාජ වන රක්ෂිතය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රාථමික පහත්බිම් වැසි වනාන්තරයේ අවසාන විස්තීර්ණ පැල්ලම ආවරණය කරමින්, සිංහරාජ වන රක්ෂිතය ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිරිතදිග පහතරට තෙත් කලාපයේ පිහිටා  ඇත."},{"question":"Toggle the table of contentsඅව තියවක යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"අව තියවක යනු චන්ද්‍ර මාසයක අව පක්‍ෂයේ තෙවන (3) තිථිය වෙයි. එසේම අව තියවක යනු සිංහල මාස ක්‍රමයේ දී අව දියවක තිථියට පසු සහ අව ජලවක තිථියට පෙර යෙදෙන මාසයේ දහ අට වන (18) තිථිය යි."},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 山形大学のグループは、ペルーにある世界遺産の「ナスカの地上絵」について研究しています。グループは2019年6月から2020年2月まで、ペルーの専門家と一緒に、AIやドローンを使ってナスカの町のまわりなどを調べました。その結果、新しい地上絵を168見つけたと発表しました。猫やらくだの仲間や人のような絵などです。大きさが50mぐらいの絵もあります。グループは、紀元前100年ごろからの400年の間に作った絵だと考えています。このグループが見つけた絵は、全部で358になりました。山形大学の坂井正人教授は「今もまだ、どうして地上絵を作ったのかよくわかっていません。これからもAIを使って地上絵をさがして、何のために作ったのか調べたいです」と話していました。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"awak rendah sangkutan tinggi\\"?","answer":"Peribahasa ini bermaksud perbelanjaan lebih besar daripada pendapatan"},{"question":"昔話の主人公で物語の最後に「打ちでのこづち」で体を大きくしてもらったのは誰？","answer":"一寸法師です。"},{"question":"१८ को ०.६ द्वारा विभाजित नतिजा पत्ता लगाउ।","answer":"१८ भाग ०.६ बराबर ३० हो।"},{"question":"ਜੰਮੂ ਦੇ ਪਿੰਡ ਮੜ੍ਹ ਵਿਚ ਸੋਮਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਕੁਲਗਾਮ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਸ਼ਹੀਦ ਹੋਏ ਡੀਐਸਪੀ ਅਮਨ ਠਾਕੁਰ ਦੇ ਅੰਤਮ ਸੰਸਕਾਰ ਮੌਕੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਪਤਨੀ ਸਰਲਾ ਦੇਵੀ ਤੇ ਛੇ ਸਾਲਾਂ ਦਾ ਪੁੱਤਰ ਆਰੀਆ ਵਿਲਕਦੇ ਹੋਏ। ਅਮਨ ਠਾਕੁਰ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਕਿੱਥੇ ਹੋਈ?","answer":"ਡੀਐਸਪੀ ਅਮਨ ਠਾਕੁਰ ਜੰਮੂ ਦੇ ਮੜ੍ਹ ਪਿੰਡ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਕ  ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਸ਼ਹੀਦ ਹੋਏ।"},{"question":"నిర్జీవుల, సజీవుల పెరుగుదలలో భేదాలను ఎలా గుర్తిస్తారు?","answer":"పెరుగుదల సజీవులలో ఒక ముఖ్య లక్షణముగా పేర్కొనవచ్చు. ఈ జీవులలో పెరుగుదల అంతర్గతముగా జరుగును. నిర్జీవులలో పెరుగుదల ఉండదు. కాని కొన్ని నిర్జీవులు బాహ్యముగా పదార్థము సమకూరటం వల్ల పెరుగుదల చూపును."},{"question":"Саламат Садыкова ким?","answer":"Саламат Садыкова даңазалуу кыргыз ырчысы, комузчусу, аткаруучусу. Кыргызстан Республикасынын Эл артисти. Казакстан Республикасынын Эмгек сиңирген артисти."},{"question":" Qual foi o primeiro país a permitir o voto feminino?","answer":"A Nova Zelândia, em setembro de 1893."},{"question":"Mety hisy fiantraikany ratsy eo amin'ny fahasalamana ara-tsaina sy ara-batana ny adin-tsaina. Zava-dehibe ny fampiharana ny paikady handaminana ny adin-tsaina, toy ny fisaintsainana sy ny fandrindrana ny fotoana, mba hitazonana ny fahasalamana any am-piasana.Fintino amin’ny fehezanteny vitsivitsy ny lahatsoratra etsy ambony.","answer":"Ny adin-tsaina amin'ny asa dia mety hisy fiantraikany amin'ny fahasalamana, fa ny fisaintsainana sy ny fandaminana fotoana dia tetika mahomby amin'ny fandrindrana izany."},{"question":"ਮੈਂ ਗਲਾਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਾਣੀ ਪਾਇਆ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਪਾਣੀ ਨਾਲ ਮੇਰੀ ਪਿਆਸ ਬੁੱਝ ਗਈ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਗਲਾਸ ਭਰ ਗਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਗਲਾਸ ਭਰ ਗਿਆ।"},{"question":"a ∈ A ⇒ a ∈ B అయినA) A ⊂ BB) B ⊂ AC) A = BD) A = B = Φ","answer":"A) A ⊂ B"},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Vắng bóng căn hộ 25 triệu đồng/m2 ở quận trung tâm Bộ Xây dựng vừa công bố thông tin nhà ở và thị trường bất động sản quý II/2022. Theo báo cáo, thị trường quý này đã có dấu hiệu hồi phục và phát triển tốt với tổng lượng giao dịch căn hộ chung cư, nhà ở riêng lẻ, đất nền cao hơn cùng kỳ năm 2021. Tỷ lệ hấp thụ sản phẩm ở hầu hết các phân khúc ở mức cao, hầu như không phát sinh lượng bất động sản tồn kho mới. Tỉ lệ trống văn phòng, mặt bằng thương mại cho thuê giảm dần… Thị trường bất động sản đã cân bằng trở lại giữa hoạt động đầu tư, kinh doanh với mua bán để sử dụng.  Các dự án nhà ở thương mại tại khu vực trung tâm của các đô thị hầu như không có căn hộ với mức giá dưới 25 triệu đồng/m2. Trong ảnh: Dự án chung cư tại khu Tây Nam Linh Đàm (Hoàng Liệt, Hoàng Mai, Hà Nội) đang mở bán với giá từ 40-45 triệu đồng/m2. Về giá bán, Bộ Xây dựng cho biết, giá căn hộ chung cư vẫn tăng so với thời điểm cuối năm 2021, mức độ tăng giá các phân khúc tập trung trong quý I/2022 chậm dần và có dấu hiệu chững lại trong các tháng quý II/2022. Theo báo cáo, các dự án nhà ở thương mại tại khu vực trung tâm của các đô thị hầu như không có căn hộ với mức giá dưới 25 triệu đồng/m2. Căn hộ có mức giá này chỉ có tại một số ít các dự án tại khu vực xa trung tâm. Trong khi đó, sản phẩm chủ đạo trên thị trường trong quý II vẫn là các căn hộ phân khúc trung cấp có giá từ 30-50 triệu đồng/m2. Đặc biệt, tại Hà Nội và TP. HCM một số dự án có vị trí đặc biệt, trung tâm có mức giá quảng cáo, chào bán rất cao lên đến 300-325 triệu đồng/m2... Mua gom đất rồi \\"phân lô, tách thửa\\" chào bán tràn lan Cũng theo Bộ Xây dựng, giá nhà ở riêng lẻ, đất nền cho xây dựng nhà ở tại các dự án trong quý II/2022 đang có xu hướng chững lại ở hầu hết các địa phương khi các hoạt động đầu tư, kinh doanh, dịch vụ thuộc các ngành nghề, lĩnh vực khác được phục hồi, bình thường trở lại.  Thị trường xuất hiện tình trạng các nhà đầu tư nhỏ lẻ tự mua gom đất ở, đất nông nghiệp, đất trồng cây lâu năm và lợi dụng các thông tin về quy hoạch, đầu tư hạ tầng để phân lô, tách thửa và chào bán tràn lan. Tại nhiều địa phương (như Đồng Nai, Bình Phước, Lâm Đồng, Vũng Tàu, Đắk Lắk,…) đã xuất hiện tình trạng các nhà đầu tư nhỏ lẻ tự mua gom đất ở, đất nông nghiệp, đất trồng cây lâu năm và lợi dụng các thông tin về quy hoạch, đầu tư hạ tầng để phân lô, tách thửa và chào bán tràn lan gây mất ổn định cho thị trường bất động sản. Trước tình hình đó, cơ quan quản lý tại các địa phương đã phải đưa ra các biện pháp ngăn chặn như siết chặt, dừng việc phân lô bán nền đối với các giao dịch đất đai trên địa bàn. Ngoài ra, để \\"siết\\" lại tình trạng này, Bộ Xây dựng yêu cầu các địa phương có biện pháp quản lý, ngăn chặn việc chia tách, \\"phân lô, bán nền\\" tại các khu vực chưa được phép đầu tư, thiếu hệ thống hạ tầng; tăng cường kiểm soát hoạt động của các sàn giao dịch bất động sản, các tổ chức, cá nhân hành nghề môi giới bất động sản; chấn chỉnh hành vi mua bán trao tay, \\"thổi giá\\" gây nhiễu loạn thông tin thị trường bất động sản. Đồng thời, theo dõi nắm bắt thông tin, tình hình diễn biến của thị trường và thực hiện các biện pháp xử lý kịp thời để bình ổn thị trường, không để xảy ra tình trạng sốt giá và bong bóng bất động sản trên địa bàn; Tăng cường kiểm tra, thanh tra đồng thời xử lý nghiêm với các trường hợp vi phạm về pháp luật về kinh doanh bất động sản, đất đai, xây dựng… Nguồn cung hạn chế Theo Bộ Xây dựng, nguồn cung mới các sản phẩm bất động sản ở tất cả các phân khúc trong nửa đầu năm 2022 đều hạn chế. Nguyên nhân chủ yếu là do việc siết chặt các thủ tục pháp lý của các dự án bất động sản, ngoài ra việc dòng vốn cho thị trường bị thu hẹp từ nhiều phía như kiểm soát chặt nguồn vốn tín dụng, phát hành trái phiếu doanh nghiệp, sự suy giảm của thị trường trái phiếu,… cũng là nguyên nhân khiến nguồn cung hạn chế. Nhà ở, đất nền vẫn là loại hình bất động sản thu hút sự quan tâm nhiều nhất trong nửa đầu năm 2022, đặc biệt là phân khúc nhà ở thương mại trung cấp, bình dân và nhà ở xã hội, tuy nhiên, nguồn cung cho phân khúc này tương đối ít.","answer":"Xuất hiện tình trạng mua gom đất để 'phân lô, tách thửa' chào bán gây loạn thị trường"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. පින්න මලේ සුද ඇන්න ගිහින්වදමුහුණ පුරා පෙම පිරිලාඉන්න එපා නුඹ හැන්දෑකරේ දොරකන්ද කපා හඳ ගෙට එන්නා","answer":"පින්න මලේ සුද ඇන්න ගිහින්වදමුහුණ පුරා පෙම පිරිලාඉන්න එපා නුඹ හැන්දෑකරේ දොරකන්ද කපා හඳ ගෙට එන්නාදුන්න වගේ නැමි බණ්ඩි කුරක්කන්අන්න බලාපන් අත වනතේමන්ද නඟේ නුඹ යන්නෙ ගමෙන් පිටගං ගොඩ වෙල් එළි පාළු වෙතේඉන්නෙ මොකෝ වැට ඉන්න වගේ නුඹඑන්නෙ අළුත් අවුරුදු කාලේගන්න එපා පර දේස සිරිත් නෙකමේක අපේ සිංහල දේසේඑඩ්වඩ් ජයකොඩිඅමරසේන කංකානම්ගේරෝහණ වීරසිංහ"},{"question":"Vraag: Welke Nederlander ging eerder de ruimte is, Wubbo Ockels of Andre Kuipers?","answer":"Antwoord: Wubbo Ockels"},{"question":"క్రింది ప్రశ్నకి ఒక్కమాటలో జవాబునివ్వండి.  పడమటి తీర మైదానంను కేరళలో ఏమంటారు?","answer":"మలబారు తీరం."},{"question":"为以下的原文给译文：（冯）异为人谦退不伐，行与诸将相逢，辄引车避道。进止皆有表识，军中号为整齐。每所止舍，诸将升坐论功，异常独屏树下，军中号曰“大树将军”。及破邯郸，乃更部分诸将，各有配隶，军中皆言愿属大树将军，光武以此多之。","answer":"冯异为人处事谦虚退让，不自夸。出行与别的将军相遇，就把马车驶开避让。军队前进停止都有标明旗帜，在各部队中号称最有纪律。每到一个地方停下宿营，其他将军坐在一起讨论功劳时，冯异经常独自退避到树下，军队中称他为“大树将军”。等到攻破邯郸，要重新安排各将领任务，每人都有被分配隶属，士兵们都说愿意跟随大树将军。光武帝因为这个而赞扬他。"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa saxaabiga qudha ee magiciis Quranka lagu sheegay?","answer":"Waxa weeyaan Zayid binu- Xaarith (RC)."},{"question":"Ano ang tamang sagot sa tanong na ito : Kung ang tao ay may dalawa, ilan naman sa aso?","answer":"Malabo ang konteksto ng pahayag. Maaaring dalawa rin ang sagot kung ang tinutukoy ay kung ilan ang mata, o pwede ring apat kung ang tinutukoy kung ilan ang binti."},{"question":"Paragrafı devam metni yaz:  İklim değişikliği, atmosferdeki sera gazlarının artışı ile doğrudan ilişkilidir. Bu gazlar arasında","answer":"karbondioksit (CO2), metan (CH4) ve azot oksitler (NOx) bulunur. Bu gazlar, güneş ışınlarını yakalar ve Dünya'nın yüzey sıcaklığını artırarak sera etkisi yaratırlar."},{"question":"Kañ lañu ko fal njiitu réewu Senegaal ?","answer":"2019."},{"question":"Aṣofin mẹta tun darapọ mọ APC l’Ogun","answer":"Afikun ti ba iye awọn aṣofin to jẹ ọmọ ẹgbẹ APC nileegbimọ aṣofin ipinlẹ Ogun. Eyi waye lọjọ Iṣẹgun, ọjọ kẹtalelogun, oṣu keji, nigba ti awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu African Democratic Congress(ADC) mẹta to wa nile igbimọ naa, iyẹn Ọnarebu Jẹmili Akingbade, Adegoke Adeyanju ati Wahab Haruna, lawọn ko ṣe ADC mọ, APC lawọn fẹẹ maa ṣe bayii. Eyi tumọ si pe ninu aṣofin mẹrindinlọgbọn (26) to so ile-igbimọ aṣofin Ogun ro, mẹẹẹdọgbọn(25) lo to di ọmọ ẹgbẹ APC bayii, ẹni kan ṣoṣo to ku lo jẹ ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP.Ninu ijokoo ile aṣofin naa to waye lọfiisi wọn l’Oke-Mosan, ni Abẹnugan ile, Ọnarebu Ọlakunle Oluọmọ, ti ka lẹta tawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ mẹta yii kọ lati fi kede pe awọn ti darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu Onigbaalẹ.Oluọmọ sọ pe awọn mẹtẹẹta naa darapọ mọ APC ki wọn le sa ipa wọn fun ilọsiwaju ipinlẹ Ogun. Wọn tun sọ pe ija abẹnu wa ninu ẹgbẹ tawọn ti kuro, awọn si ti ba awọn aṣaaju awọn sọ ọ kawọn too gbe igbesẹ lati darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ Onitẹsiwaju ti i ṣe APC.Lọjọ yii naa ni wọn mẹnu ba ipo to ba ni lọkan jẹ ti papa iṣere Mudal Lawal to wa ni Aṣero, l’Abẹokuta, wa. Awọn aṣofin sọ pe papa iṣere ti wọn fi n ranti Oloogbe Muda Lawal to jẹ ọkan pataki agbabọọlu fun Naijiria ko ṣee ri mọ rara, o si yẹ kijọba Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun ṣe igbedide rẹ kia, nitori akọni ti wọn fi sọri rẹ, ati nitori anfaani to yẹ ko maa ti ibẹ jade.Ṣa, ile fẹnu ko si pe ki ileeṣẹ to n ri si ere idaraya ati ọrọ awọn ọdọ, mu ẹda iwe ilẹ (survey) papa yii wa, ki wọn si pese akọsilẹ orukọ awọn to n ta ọja tabi ni ile okoowo ninu ọgba naa, ki kaluku le ṣe ẹtọ ẹ nipa sisanwo to ba yẹ ki wọn maa san fun ibi ti wọn ti n ṣòwò yii.Wọn ni ki wọn gbe iwe owo to wọle lati papa iṣere naa lati ọdun 2015 titi di asiko yii jade, ki ile le mọ iye to wọle ati iye ti wọn na sita nibẹ."},{"question":"Inona no tsy marina momba ny fambolen-bary eto Madagasikara?1-  Ny vary no foto-tsakafon’i Madagasikara.2- Any amin’ny lemaka sy lohasaha any amin’ny faritra afovoan-tany no tena fambolem-bary.3- Amin’ny fotoana manokana eto Madagasikara ihany no hanina ny vary.","answer":"Ny safidy diso dia - 3. Amin'ny fotoana manokana eto Madagasikara ihany no hanina ny vary."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"adat pulau limburan pasang\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud kehidupan manusia hendaklah bantu-membantu, yang kaya membantu yang miskin dan yang berilmu membantu yang bodoh, yang berkuasa melindungi yang lemah"},{"question":"Misy firy ny lafin' ny folojoro ?","answer":"Misy lafiny sivy ny folojoro ."},{"question":"Podaj trzy ciekawe informacje o rzece Odra.","answer":"Oto trzy informacje o rzece Odra: 1) Jest to rzeka w Europie Środkowej, w zlewisku Morza Bałtyckiego, na terenie Czech, Polski i Niemiec. 2) Pod względem całkowitej długości jest drugą (po Wiśle) rzeką Polski. 3) Biorąc pod uwagę tylko jej część w granicach Polski, jest trzecią rzeką pod względem długości (po jej dopływie Warcie)."},{"question":"クリケットは、１イニング何アウトでチェンジとなるでしょう？","answer":"１０アウト"},{"question":"في أي قارة تقع مقدونيا؟","answer":"تقع مقدونيا في قارة أوروبا."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය රචනා  කළේ  කවුද?ඔබ දෙපා දොවා බැතියෙන් මා පිදූ පැතුම් පියුමන් පෙති තලා දමා, මලසුනේ හෙළා මට තබා ගොසින් කඳුලැල් පුජාසනය අඳුරුයි විමනේ පහන නිවිලා පුජාසනය අඳුරුයි විමනේ පහන නිවිලා මා දෑස දුකඳුරු ගෙයි ඔබගේ නමින් යදිනා ආයාචනය ඔබටයි දෙවිඳේ මසිත දරනා ආයාචනය ඔබටයි දෙවිඳේ මසිත දරනා මේ යාතිකා ගැයූමයි ඔබගේ සරණ පතනා","answer":"චන්ද්‍රලේඛා  පෙරේරා "},{"question":"भारताने २०३० पर्यंत किती टक्क्यांनी कार्बन उत्सर्जन कमी करण्याचे उद्दीष्ट ठेवले आहे असे पंतप्रधानानी जाहीर केले आहे?(A)  ४०(B)  ४४(C)  ४६(D)  ४५","answer":"(D) ४५"},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து பொரி உருண்டை செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:இரண்டு கிண்ணம் அவல் பொரிஅரை கிண்ணம் வெல்லம்கால் கிண்ணம் வறுத்த வேர்க்கடலைஒன்றரை மேஜைக்கரண்டி பொட்டுக்கடலைகால் மேஜைக்கரண்டி சுக்கு தூள்கால் மேஜைக்கரண்டி ஏலக்காய் தூள்எட்டு அல்லது பத்து முந்திரி பருப்புகள்தேவையான அளவு நெய்","answer":"செய்முறை:1. முதலில் அவல் பொரியை ஒரு துணியில் கொட்டி அதை நன்கு சுத்தம் செய்து எடுத்து ஒரு பாத்திரத்தில் வைத்து, பின்பு முந்திரி பருப்புகளை சிறு சிறு துண்டுகளாக நறுக்கி கொள்ளவும்.2. இப்பொழுது ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் முந்திரி பருப்புகளை போட்டு அதை சுமார் ஒரு நிமிடம் வரை வறுத்து எடுத்து ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.3. பின்னர் ஒரு கிண்ணத்தை எடுத்து அதில் அவல் பொரி, வறுத்த வேர்கடலை, பொட்டுக்கடலை, மற்றும் நாம் வறுத்து எடுத்து வைத்திருக்கும் முந்திரியை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விட்டு ஒரு காற்று புகாத மூடி போட்ட பாத்திரத்தில் போட்டு வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.4. அடுத்து ஒரு வாணலியை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் வெல்லத்தை தூள் செய்து போட்டு இரண்டு கிளறு கிளறி பின்பு அதில் கொஞ்சம் கொஞ்சமாக தண்ணீர் சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கரைத்து விடவும்.5. தண்ணீர் சேர்க்கும் போது கவனமாக சேர்க்க வேண்டும் அதிகமாக தண்ணீர் சேர்த்து விடக்கூடாது.6. பின்பு வெல்லம் நன்கு கரைந்ததும், அதை ஒரு வடிகட்டியின் மூலம் வேறொரு பாத்திரத்தில் ஊற்றி அதை நன்கு வடிகட்டி கொள்ளவும்.7. பிறகு வேறொரு வாணலியை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் நாம் வடிகட்டிய வெல்லத்தை ஊற்றி அதை மீண்டும் சுட வைக்கவும்.(அவ்வப்போது அதை ஒரு கரண்டியை கொண்டு கிண்டி விடவும்.)8. வெல்லம் சிறிது சூடானதும் அதில் சுக்குத் தூள் மற்றும் ஏலக்காய் தூளை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.9. பின்னர் அதை ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் எடுத்து கவனமாக ஒரு கம்பி பதத்தை பாகு எட்டி விட்டதா என்பதை பார்க்கவும்.10. வெல்லப்பாகு இரண்டு கம்பி பதத்தை தாண்டியவுடன் ஒரு சிறிய கிண்ணத்தில் சிறிதளவு தண்ணீரை எடுத்து அதில் கொதித்து கொண்டிருக்கும் வெல்ல பாகிலிருந்து ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் இரண்டு துளிகளை எடுத்து விடவும்.11. பின்பு அதை நம் கைகளின் மூலம் உருட்டும் போது அது நன்கு உருட்ட வரவேண்டும். (இது தான் பாகின் சரியான பதம், இந்த பதத்தை பாகு தாண்டிவிட்டால் நம் பொரி உருண்டைகள் நன்கு இறுக்கமாக ஆகிவிடும்.)12. அப்படி உருட்ட வந்தவுடன் அடுப்பை முற்றிலுமாக குறைத்து விட்டு அதில் நாம் கலந்து வைத்திருக்கும் அவல் பொரி கலவையை கொட்டி அதை பக்குவமாக ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் நன்கு கிளறி விடவும்.13. பிறகு அதில் அரை மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு நெய் ஊற்றி அதை நன்கு கலந்து விட்டு அடுப்பை அணைத்து விடவும்.14. இந்த பொரி கலவையை சூடாக இருக்கும் போதே நாம் உருண்டைகளாக பிடித்தால் தான் உண்டு அப்படி இல்லை என்றால் அவை ஆறியவுடன் நம்மால் பிடிக்க முடியாது.15. அதனால் நம் கைகளில் நன்கு நெய்யை தடவி கொண்டு அது சூடாக இருக்கும் போதே அதை பக்குவமாக உருண்டைகளாக பிடித்து அதை சிறிது நேரம் ஆற விட்டு பின்பு பரிமாறவும்.16. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சுவையான மற்றும் மொறு மொறுப்பாக இறுக்கும் பொரி உருண்டை தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து உண்டு மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":"Makinde bẹrẹ iwadii lori ọga ileewe tawọn wolewole lu lalubami n’Ibadan","answer":"Lẹyin ti wọn lu oludasilẹ ileewe aladaani kan, Ọlayemi Sylva, lalubami nigboro Ibadan, ti wọn si tun fọlọpaa gbe e, Gomina ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ẹnjinnia Ṣeyi Makinde, ti bẹrẹ iwadii lori ija naa pẹlu ipinnu lati fiya jẹ ẹni to ba jẹbi ninu wọn.Ninu àkásílẹ̀ ohùn kan ti Abilekọ Ọlayemi fi ranṣẹ sawọn eeyan, eyi to ti gba ori ẹrọ ayelujara kan bayii, lo ti ṣalaye bi awọn oṣiṣẹ eleto imọtoto ayika ipinlẹ Ọyọ ṣe fiya jẹ ẹ to.Gẹgẹ bii awijare oludasilẹ ileewe naa, o ni ọkan ninu awọn akẹkọọ oun lawọn oṣiṣẹ eleto ilera mu fun ẹsun pe o dalẹ̀ soju títì, oun si lọ si olu ileeṣẹ awọn ajọ naa lati gba ọmọ yii silẹ, ṣugbọn awọn oṣiṣẹ ijọba naa sọ ọ dija mọ oun lọwọ, wọn ni oun n di awọn lọwọ lẹnu iṣẹ.O ni nigba ti oun sọ ọrọ naa di ariwo mọ wọn lọwọ ni wọn fi ọlọpaa mu oun lẹyin ti wọn lu oun bii ejo aijẹ tan.Ohun ti obinrin yii fi ranṣẹ, to si tan kaakiri ori ẹrọ ayelujara ni Gomina Makinde gbọ to fi gbe igbimọ oluwadii dide lati tọpinpin ọrọ naa, ki wọn si fi oju aṣebi lori iṣẹlẹ yii han ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ fun iya jẹ. Ninu atẹjade ti Ọgbẹni Taiwo Adisa ti i ṣe akọwe iroyin Gomina Makinde gbe jade lorukọ ọga rẹ lo ti sọ pe ijọba oun ko ni i faaye gba oṣiṣẹ ijọba tabi ajọ to n ṣoju ijọba kan laaye lati fiya jẹ araalu kankan lọna aitọ, bakan naa lo ni awọn ko ni i gba fun ẹnikẹni lati maa huwa to lodi sofin.”"},{"question":"Ortalama hız ihlal tespit sistemi Türkiye'de nerelerde var?","answer":"Afyonkarahisar, Aksaray, Ankara, Bitlis, Çorum, Eskişehir ve Konya illerinde oluşturulan 1.904 km uzunluğundaki Ortalama Hız İhlal Tespit Sistemleri trafik denetimlerinde aktif olarak kullanılıyor."},{"question":"من الذي لقب بأول فرسان العالم ؟","answer":"المقداد بن عمرو"},{"question":"Wybierz prawidłową odpowiedź.W którym roku drużyna Reprezentacja Polski rozegrała swój pierwszy mecz międzypaństwowy?A) 1947B) 1944C) 1921D)  1923","answer":"Poprawna odpowiedź to (C) w 1921."},{"question":"四国で一番面積が広いのは高知県。では九州で一番面積が広いのは何県？","answer":"鹿児島です。"},{"question":"O que significa o ditado popular: \\"Nada como um dia depois do outro\\"?","answer":"Este ditado nos remete à ideia de que, após um dia ruim, sempre vem um bom pela frente. É só deixar o tempo passar.Exemplo: “Aos poucos, a tristeza foi passando. Nada como um dia após o outro…”"},{"question":"Inona no fitambaran'ny loko ampiasaina matetika hanehoana ny maha-vehivavy?a) Manga sy maitsob) Mavokely sy volomparasyd) Mavo sy menae) volomboasary sy mainty","answer":"b) Mavokely sy volomparasy  no fitambaran'ny loko ampiasaina matetika hanehoana ny maha-vehivavy"},{"question":"اكتب خطابًا قصيرًا للطلاب في مدرستك يشجعهم على القراءة ويوضح لهم فوائدها. استخدم أمثلة من الحياة الواقعية وقصص شخصية لإلهام الطلاب. قدم نصائح عملية حول كيفية تنظيم وقت القراءة واختيار الكتب المناسبة. يجب أن يكون الخطاب واضحًا وملهمًا، وأن يتضمن فكرة رئيسية ومقدمة وخاتمة معبرة","answer":"التالي خطاب قصير ممكن تقديمة للطلاب في مدرستك:\\"السلام عليكم ورحمة الله وبركاتهأيها الطلاب الأعزاء،أنا أكتب إليكم اليوم لأحدثكم على أحد أجمل وأنفع الهوايات في الحياة، وهي القراءة. القراءة هي بوابة العلم والثقافة والتنوير. من خلال القراءة، تستطيعون أن تسافروا في عوالم مختلفة وتتعرفوا على شخصيات مختلفة وتتعلموا من تجاربهم وخبراتهم. القراءة تنمي مهاراتكم اللغوية والفكرية والإبداعية ، وتزيد من ثقتكم بأنفسكم وتحسن من مزاجكم وصحتكم النفسية.أنا أعلم أن بعضكم قد يشعر بالملل أو الضجر من القراءة، أو قد يجد صعوبة في اختيار الكتب المناسبة له، أو قد يفتقر إلى الوقت أو المكان المناسب للقراءة. لذلك، أود أن أقدم لكم بعض النصائح العملية التي تساعدكم على تحويل القراءة إلى عادة يومية ممتعة ومفيدة.اولًا: اختاروا الكتب التي تناسب اهتماماتكم وذوقكم. لا تقروا كتابًا فقط لأنه مشهور أو مطلوب، بل ابحثوا عن الكتب التي تثير فضولكم وتجذب انتباهكم. يمكنكم استخدام محركات البحث على الإنترنت أو زيارة المكتبات أو طلب المشورة من المعلمين أو الأصدقاء لإيجاد الكتب المناسبة لكم.ثانيًا: حددوا وقتًا محددًا في كل يوم للقراءة. يفضل أن يكون هذا الوقت في بداية اليوم أو قبل النوم، حيث تكونون أكثر هدوءًا وراحة. حاولوا أن تخصصوا نصف ساعة على الأقل في كل يوم للقراءة، ولا تسمحوا لأي شيء يشغلكم عنها، مثل التلفزيون أو الموبايل أو المهام الجانبية الأخرى.ثالثًا: اختاروا مكانًا هادئًا ومريحًا للقراءة. يجب أن يكون هذا المكان نظيفًا ومضيئًا وجيد التهوية. تجنبوا القراءة في المكان الذي تنامون فيه، حتى لا تشعروا بالنعاس أثناء القراءة. كذلك، تجنبوا القراءة في المكان الذي يحدث فيه ضجيج أو ازدحام، حتى لا تتشتتوا أو تنزعجوا.رابعًا: تفاعلوا مع الكتاب الذي تقرونه. لا تكتفوا بقراءة الكلمات فقط، بل حاولوا أن تفهموا المعنى والرسالة والغرض من الكتاب. اسألوا أنفسكم عن رأيكم في الكتاب وماذا تعلمتم منه وماذا تريدون أن تفعلوا بعد قراءته. كتبوا ملاحظاتكم أو تعليقاتكم على الهامش أو في دفتر خاص. شاركوا آراءكم وانطباعاتكم مع الآخرين، سواء كانوا أصدقاء أو أسرة أو معلمين.خامسًا: استمتعوا بالقراءة ولا تجعلوها عبئًا أو إلزامًا. لا تقروا كتابًا إذا شعرتم بالملل أو الضيق منه، بل انتقلوا إلى كتاب آخر أو غيروا نوعية القراءة. لا تحددوا هدفًا محددًا لعدد الكتب التي تريدون قراءتها في فترة معينة، بل اجعلوا القراءة مسألة جودة وليس كمية. لا تخافوا من تجربة كتب جديدة أو مختلفة عن ما اعتدتم عليه، فقد تجدون فيها متعة وفائدة لم تتوقعوها.أخيرًا، أود أن أخبركم عن قصة شخصية عزيزة علي، وهي قصة والدي الذي كان يحب القراءة منذ صغره. والدي نشأ في قرية بسيطة لم يكن فيها مدرسة أو مكتبة، فكان يذهب إلى المدينة المجاورة ليستعير الكتب من المكتبات هناك. كان يقرأ الكتب بشغف وحب، ويحفظ مافيها من معلومات وحكم. كان يشارك مع أصدقائه وأقاربه مافي الكتب من قصص وأفكار، ويحثهم على القراءة. بفضل القراءة، استطاع والدي أن يحصل على شهادات علمية رفيعة المستوى، الى أن يصبح طبيبًا وأنجحهم على مستوى البلاد . كان دائمًا يقول لي: “القراءة هي الرفيق التي لن تخذلك ابدًا.“شكرًا لكم على اهتمامكم \\""},{"question":"প্রাকৃতিক সম্পদে সমৃদ্ধ দক্ষিণ এশিয়ার একটি দেশ বাংলাদেশ। ঘনবসতিপূর্ণ দেশ হওয়ায় এদেশের জনগণ নিরাপদ পানি ও খাদ্য সমস্যা জর্জরিত। এই সমস্যার সমাধান ও অর্থনৈতিক উন্নয়নের জন্য প্রয়োজন পানি সম্পদ ব্যবস্থাপনা ও প্রাকৃতিক সম্পদের যথাযথ ব্যবহার।উদ্দীপকের আলোকে বাংলাদেশের অর্থনীতিতে প্রাকৃতিক সম্পদের গুরুত্ব ব্যাখ্যা করো।","answer":"বাংলাদেশের অর্থনীতিতে প্রাকৃতিক সম্পদের গুরুত্ব অপরিসীম।প্রকৃতি থেকে প্রাপ্ত সম্পদকেই প্রাকৃতিক সম্পদ বলা হয়। মাটি, পানি, বনভূমি, সৌরসম্পদ, মৎস্য, খনিজ প্রভৃতি হলো প্রাকৃতিক সম্পদ। যেকোনো দেশের অর্থনৈতিক উন্নয়নে প্রাকৃতিক সম্পদ খুবই গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ভূমিকা রাখে। বাংলাদেশ দক্ষিণ এশিয়ার একটি দেশ। এদেশ বিভিন্ন প্রাকৃতিক সম্পদে ভরপুর। এদেশের মাটি খুবই উর্বর। এদেশের জলবায়ু ও কৃষিজ উৎপাদনের জন্য অত্যন্ত উপযোগী। এজন্য এদেশে ধান, গম, পাট, আলু, ভুট্টা, সরিষাসহ বিভিন্ন কৃষিজ পণ্য প্রচুর পরিমাণে উৎপাদিত হয়। যা আমাদের খাদ্যের চাহিদা পূরণের মাধ্যমে অর্থনীতিতে অবদান রাখছে। এদেশ উষ্ণ ও আর্দ্র জলবায়ু অঞ্চলে অবস্থিত হওয়ায় এদেশে বিভিন্ন বনাঞ্চল গড়ে উঠেছে যা আমাদের গুরুত্বপূর্ণ প্রাকৃতিক সম্পদ। বন থেকে আমরা বাড়িঘর ও আসবাবপত্র নির্মাণের কাঠ, জ্বালানি, মধু, মোমসহ বিভিন্ন বনজ সম্পদ পাই। আবার অনেক শিল্পের কাঁচামালও বন থেকে আসে। এজন্য বনজ সম্পদ এদেশের অর্থনীতির জন্য অত্যন্ত গুরুত্বপূর্ণ । আবার এদেশের অসংখ্য নদ-নদী, বিল, হাওড়, বাওড়, পুকুর থাকায় দেশটি মৎস্য সম্পদে সমৃদ্ধ। বঙ্গোপসাগরেও মাছের ভাণ্ডার রয়েছে। এই মৎস্য সম্পদ দেশের আমিষের চাহিদা পূরণের পাশাপাশি রপ্তানির মাধ্যমে প্রচুর বৈদেশিক মুদ্রা অর্জন করা সম্ভব হবে। বাংলাদেশে গ্যাস, কয়লা, তেল, চুনাপাথরসহ নানা ধরনের খনিজ সম্পদ পাওয়া গেছে। এসব সম্পদ আহরণের মাধ্যমে দেশে বিভিন্ন শিল্পের বিকাশ ঘটানো হচ্ছে যা অর্থনীতির উন্নতির জন্য অত্যন্ত গুরুত্বপূর্ণ। এছাড়া সৌরশক্তিও এদেশের মূল্যবান প্রাকৃতিক সম্পদ। কেননা, ভৌগোলিক অবস্থানগত কারণে আমরা সহজে প্রচুর সৌরশক্তি লাভ করি। আধুনিক প্রযুক্তি ব্যবহারের মাধ্যমে এ সম্পদ দিয়ে আমরা বিদ্যুতের চাহিদা পূরণ করতে পারি। পাশাপাশি খাদ্য, চিকিৎসা, বাসস্থানসহ সবক্ষেত্রেই সৌরশক্তিকে ব্যবহার করে এদেশের আরও উন্নতি লাভের সম্ভাবনা রয়েছে।উপরের আলোচনা থেকে বলা যায়, মাটি, পানি, জলবায়ু, বনজ, মৎস্য, খনিজ ও সৌরসম্পদ প্রভৃতি প্রাকৃতিক সম্পদ দেশের অর্থনীতিতে বিরাট ভূমিকা রাখছে। এজন্য এদেশের অর্থনীতিতে প্রাকৃতিক সম্পদের গুরুত্ব অনস্বীকার্য।"},{"question":"Los de volgende vergelijking op: y = 7x + 2 waar x = 2","answer":"Natuurlijk, we kunnen deze vergelijking stap voor stap oplossen: 1. y = 7(2) + 2 2. y = 14 + 2 3. y = 16 Het uiteindelijke antwoord is 16."},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"சாதி இருக்கக் கூடாது"},{"question":"Kọmiṣanna Ambode fi ẹgbẹ APC silẹ, o loun naa fẹẹ di gomina Eko","answer":"Ọkan lara awọn komiṣanna to ba gomina ipinlẹ Eko tẹlẹ, Akinwunnmi Ambọde ṣiṣe, Ọnarebu Abdul-Lateef Abdul-Hakeem ti kuro ninu ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC bayii.Ohun to mu ọkunrin oloṣelu yii kuro ni bo ti ṣe fi ifẹ han lati dije dupo gomina lọdun 2023, eyi to sọ pe ko dun mọ awọn agbaagba kan ninu ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC. O ni, iyẹn gan-an lo mu oun yẹra bayii, ki igbesẹ oun yii ma da wahala silẹ ninu ẹgbẹ.Nigba ti Ọnarebu Lateef n ṣe ifilọlẹ Iyẹpẹ 2023 lo sọrọ yii fawọn oniroyin. Bakan naa lo sọ pe, bi oun ti ṣe kuro ninu ẹgbẹ, oun rọ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC lati faaye gba awọn eeyan oun ti wọn ṣi wa pẹlu wọn, ki wọn ma ṣe tori wi pe oun ko si pẹlu wọn mọ fara ni wọn ninu ẹgbẹ.Ninu ọrọ ẹ naa lo tun ti sọ pe ọmọ ipinlẹ Eko loun, ati pe oun letọ daadaa labẹ ofin lati ko eeyan jọ lori erongba oun lati dupo oṣelu, pẹlu ojuṣe agbekalẹ eto ati ilana to tọ fun wọn nipa ijọba dẹmokiresi, eyi to le mu aye rọrun fun tẹru-tọmọ.Ọnarebu Yẹpẹ gẹgẹ bi awọn eeyan ṣe maa n pe e, ti figba kan jẹ ọmọ ile igbimọ aṣofin Eko nigba kan ri, bẹẹ lo tun jẹ olubadamọran fun olori ile igbimọ aṣofin Eko, Mudashiru Ọbasa.Ọkunrin oloṣelu yii ti waa dupẹ lọwọ Aṣiwaju Bọla Tinubu, Ọladele Ajọmale, Tunde Balogun atawọn ẹlomi-in ninu ẹgbẹ. O ni, ipa nla ni Tinubu ko nipa bi oun naa ṣe fẹsẹ rinlẹ daadaa ninu oṣelu loni-in."},{"question":"Foley trabajó con Gurf Morlix, con Townes Van Zandt, con Guy Schwartz, con Billy Block y Calvin Russell, entre otros. Pregunta: ¿Foley trabajó con, entre otros, Calvin Russell, Townes Van Zandt, Gurf Morlix, Billy Block y Guy Schwartz?Verdadero o falso.","answer":"Verdadero.La afirmación \\"Foley trabajó con Gurf Morlix, con Townes Van Zandt, con Guy Schwartz, con Billy Block y Calvin Russell, entre otros\\" se puede reorganizar como \\"Foley trabajó con, entre otros, Calvin Russell, Townes Van Zandt, Gurf Morlix, Billy Block y Guy Schwartz\\", lo que hace que sea verdadera la declaración. Esto indica que Foley colaboró con estos músicos, así como con otros que no se mencionan específicamente en la lista."},{"question":"Complete o seguinte trecho:  Grzegorz Krejner  (nascido em em Żyrardów) é um ciclista polaco. Especialista do ciclismo de pista, foi ganhador da medalha de bronze da categoria no","answer":"campeonato mundial de 2001."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa qiimaha caafimaad ee miraha haylka iyo Saliidiisa Iyo cudurrada lagula dagaallamo?","answer":"Haylku waa midho inta badan cunnada lagu darsado si loogu carfiyo, dhadhanna loogu yeelo. Waxaa kale oo haylka iyo saliidiisa loo isticmaalaa dawo ahaan.Asal ahaan waxa uu ka soo  jeedaa Dalka Hindiya balse caalamka oo dhan ayaa laga isticmaalaa. Wadanka ugu badan ee haylka soo saara waa dalka Guatemala. Waxaa jira labo nooc oo hayl ah mid mid cagaaran iyo mid madow.Haylku ma ahan oo keliya inuu cunnada udgooneeyo ama macaaneeyo balse waxaa kale oo xambaarsan yahay maadooyin waxtar ballaadhan u leh caafimaadka.Haddaba Casharkaan waxa uu Daryeel Maagaziin ku iftiiminayaa qiimaha caafimaad ee midhaha haylka.1. Caafimaadka afka:Haylku wuxuu la dagaallamaa bakteeriyada loo yaqaanno “Streptococcus mutans” oo afka bini-aadamka ku badan taas oo keenta ilko bololka iyo caabuqa dhuunta iyo cirridka . Sida oo kale, waxaa uu badiyaa calyada taas oo caawisa sifeynta huurada iyo ka hortagga tarmidda bakteeriyada, sidaas awgeed waxa uu ka takhalusaa af-urka.2. Jeermis dile:Haylka wuxuu Alle ku abuuray maado lagu magacaabo “eugenol” oo leh awood jeermis dile. Maadadani waa tan masuulka ka ah carafta haylka. Cilmi baadhisyo la sameeyay waxaa lagu arkay in saliidda ku jirta haylka ay disho noocyo  bakteeriyada ka mid ah. Waxaa la arkay  inuu haylku uu shaqo ka qabto bakteeriyada “E.coli”, bakteeriyada “Staphylococcus” oo keenta sumowga cunnada iyo bakteeriyada “Campylobacter” oo ka qayb qaadata hurka caloosha.3. Kolestaroolka:Haylku waxa uu yareeyaa heerka dufanka dhiigga ee loo yaqaanno kolestaroolka kaas oo halis ku ah wadnaha iyo xididada dhiigga4. Niyad Jabka:Haddii aad qabto xanuunka niyad jabka, cab shaaha haylka leh maalin kasta. Tani waxa ay yareysaa astaamaha niyad jabka.5. Caafimaadka maqaarka:Haylku waxa uu hodan ku yahay faytamiin C oo ah sunsaare awood leh. Waxaa kaloo ku jira maadada “phytonutrients” oo kobcisa wareegga dhiigga ee maqaarka, islamarkaana la dagaallanta duuduubka iyo calaamadaha kale ee gabowga.Hayl budo ah iyo malab la isku qasay oo si joogto ah wajiga loo marsado waxay iftiimisaa midabka maqaarka, waxayna baabi’isaa raadadka finanka iyo nabraha.6. Caafimaadka caloosha:Haylka waxaa lagu yaqaanna inuu ka shaqeysiiyo habka dheefsiga cunnada ee jidhku uu kaga faaidaysano nafaqada iyo inuu kordhiyo soo saarista dheecaanka bayl oo wanaajiya cunno shiidista kana hortaga laab jeexa iyo cilladaha caloosha. Cilmi baadhis ayaa iftiimisay in haylku uu ka hortago bakteeriyada “helicobacter Pylori” taas oo keenta gaastriigga iyo boogaha caloosha iyo mindhicirada"},{"question":"Raha jerena ireto fehezanteny roa ireto:Fehezanteny A: \\"Ny dia mankany amin'ny fahalalana ny matematika sarotra dia sarotra, saingy azoko ihany tamin'ny farany.\\"Fehezanteny B: \\"Na eo aza ny fahasarotana dia nahavita nahafantatra ireo foto-kevitra matematika intricate aho.\\"Mitovy ve ny dikany?","answer":"Tsia, tsy mitovy ny dikan'ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"徳川家康が亡くなった城は駿府城ですが、豊臣秀吉が亡くなった城は何城でしょう？","answer":"伏見城です。"},{"question":"පහත පද පෙරළි වලට කෙලිනම් විසඳුම දෙන්න. එවර නුළිය ","answer":"නුවර එළිය"},{"question":"冷やす目的やテレビの演出でよく使われる、二酸化炭素を冷やして凍らせたものを何と言うでしょう？","answer":"ドライアイスです。"},{"question":"问题：铅笔刀可以手动操作吗？","answer":"答案：大多数铅笔刀是手动操作的，需要用户通过旋转刀片来削铅笔。"},{"question":"من هم أهل البيت الذين خصهم الله في القرآن الكريم؟.","answer":"الجواب أهل البيت هم أسرة الرسول محمد صلى الله عليه وسلم"},{"question":"सामाजिक समस्या, सांस्कृतिक अभ्यास र वातावरणीय सरोकारहरूमा प्रकाश पार्ने नेपाली डकुमेन्ट्री फिल्महरूको योगदानबारे चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"नेपाली डकुमेन्ट्री फिल्महरूले सामाजिक समस्या, सांस्कृतिक प्रचलन र वातावरणीय सरोकारहरूमा प्रकाश पारेर महत्त्वपूर्ण योगदान पुर्‍याएका छन्। \\"द ब्ल्याक हेन\\" र \\"हिमालयन मेलोडिज\\" जस्ता वृत्तचित्रहरूले काल्पनिक क्षेत्रहरू भन्दा बाहिरको प्रामाणिक कथा कथनको लागि प्लेटफर्म प्रदान गर्दछ।"},{"question":"ඩාවෝස් ආර්ථික සමුළුව පවත්වන රට කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ඩාවෝස් ආර්ථික සමුළුව, වඩාත් විධිමත් ලෙස ලෝක ආර්ථික සංසදය (WEF) වාර්ෂික රැස්වීම ලෙස හැඳින්වේ,. ස්විට්සර්ලන්තයේ නගරයක් වන ඩාවෝස් මෙම සමුළුවේ   සත්කාරකත්වය දරයි. ගෝලීය ආර්ථික ප්‍රශ්න සාකච්ඡා  කිරීම සඳහා  දේශපාලන නායකයින්, ව්‍යාපාරික විධායකයින්, ආර්ථික විද්‍යාඥයින් සහ අනෙකුත් බලගතු පුද්ගලයින් මෙම සමුළුවට සහභාගී වේ. "},{"question":"மெய் எழுத்துக்களில் எவ்வளவு எழுத்துக்கள் உள்ளன?","answer":"மெய் எழுத்துக்களில் 18 எழுத்துக்கள் உள்ளன. இவை தமிழ் எழுத்துப் பொருள்களின் மெய் எழுத்துக்கள். இவை உயிர் எழுத்துக்களுடன் சேர்க்கப்பட்டு, தமிழில் அர்த்தமான வார்த்தைகளை உருவாக்குகின்றன.க் ங் ச் ஞ் ட் ண் த் ந் ப் ம் ய் ர் ல் வ் ழ் ள் ற் ன், மெய் எழுத்துகள் மொத்தம் 18(பதினெட்டு )"},{"question":"లేపాక్షి ఉత్సవాల గురించి మీ సొంతమాటలలో వ్రాయండి.","answer":"ఆంధ్రప్రదేశ్ లోని అనంతపురం జిల్లాలో లేపాక్షి ఉంది. ప్రతి సంవత్సరం ఫిబ్రవరి నెలలో రెండు రోజులు ఉత్సవాలు జరుగుతాయి. వీటిలో అనేక సాంస్కృతిక కార్యక్రమాలు ప్రదర్శిస్తారు. యక్షగానాలు, హరికథలు కూడా ఉంటాయి. నృత్య, గాన, సంగీత ప్రదర్శనలు ఆకట్టుకొంటాయి. ఆలయాలనలంకరిస్తారు."},{"question":"Jinsi ya kupika loshoro ","answer":"Napeta makande naweka kwenye chungu na maji naweka jikoni yanachemka yakiiva name ya ndizi nachanganya na makande yakiiva napanda yanalainika vizuri naweka maziwa ya mtindi tayari Kwa ku!a"},{"question":"Quantos anos tem o diretor de Homem-Aranha: De Volta ao Lar?","answer":"40 anos"},{"question":"මම දුම්කොළ හෝ නිකොටින් වාෂ්ප කළහොත් COVID-19 සංකූලතා ඇතිවීමේ අවදානම මට තිබේද?","answer":"විද්‍යුත් සිගරට් භාවිතය මගින් පෙනහළු විෂ රසායනික ද්‍රව්‍යවලට නිරාවරණය කළ හැකි නමුත් එම නිරාවරණයන් COVID-19 අවදානම වැඩි කරයිද නැතහොත් COVID-19 ප්‍රතිඵලවල බරපතලකම නොදනී. කෙසේ වෙතත්, බොහෝ විද්‍යුත් සිගරට් භාවිතා කරන්නන් වත්මන් හෝ කලින් දුම් පානය කරන්නන් වන අතර සිගරට් දුම්පානය නියුමෝනියාව ඇතුළු ශ්වසන ආසාදන අවදානම වැඩි කරයි."},{"question":"فردای دوشنبه چند شنبه است؟","answer":"روز بعد از دوشنبه در هفته، سه‌شنبه است که چهارمین روز در هفته است."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa macnaha magaca Jibriil?","answer":"Macnaha Jibriil waa Adoon, sida uu ku fasiray Ibnu Cabaas."},{"question":"Tẹjuoṣo ki i ṣe ọba, a si ti yọ ọ nipo baalẹ ta a fi jẹ pẹlu- Igbimọ Baalẹ Kemta","answer":"‘Kemta Traditional Council of Chiefs’ iyẹn igbimọ to n ri si ọrọ oye jijẹ ni Kemta, nipinlẹ Ogun, ti yọ Oloye Adetokunbọ Tẹjuoṣo ti wọn fi jẹ Baalẹ Adabọnyin lorile Kemta kuro nipo baalẹ.Wọn ni baalẹ ni, ki i ṣe ọba, awọn si ti yọ ọ nipo baalẹ ọhun paapaa.Ọjọruu, ọjọ kẹtadinlọgbọn, oṣu kẹrin, ni igbimọ naa gbe igbesẹ yii, iyẹn lẹyin ipade wọn ti wọn ṣe ni Ile Ogboni Kemta, to wa l’Ojule ogun, Opopona Mọṣalaaṣi Jimọh, Kemta Agelende, l’Abẹokuta.Atẹjade ti wọn fi sita lẹyin ipade naa, eyi ti Oloye Yọmi  Rotimi; Oluwo Kemta, Oloye Oluwatosin Fadare ati Oloye Bọla Taiwo, fọwọ si, ṣalaye pe o jọ awọn loju gidi bi wọn ṣe mu Tẹjuoṣo lọ sagọọ ọlọpaa, ti wọn si tun ti i mọle nibẹ, wọn lohun to ti ni loju jọjọ ni. Fun idi eyi, wọn ni igbimọ awọn yọ ọ nipo baalẹ, awọn si tun ni lati ṣalaye daadaa pe ọkunrin naa ki i ṣe ọba gẹgẹ bawọn akọroyin ṣe n pe e.Atẹjade naa sọ pe ‘‘A yan Adetokunbọ Tẹjuoṣo gẹgẹ bii Baalẹ Adabọnyin lorile Kemta, nijọba ibilẹ Ọdẹda, nipinlẹ Ogun.‘’Ijọba ipinlẹ Ogun ana to kogba sile lo yan an lọba lai jẹ pe awa igbimọ oloye Kemta fa a kalẹ fun wọn, bẹẹ ni Alake ilẹ Ẹgba, Ọba Adedọtun Arẹmu Gbadebọ, Okukẹnu kẹrin ko fọwọ si i.‘‘Ijọba to wa lode yii yẹ ọna ti awọn ọba marundinlọgọrin naa gba jẹ ọba, wọn ri i pe ko tọna, wọn si paṣẹ pe kawọn ọba naa pada sipo baalẹ ti wọn wa, ki wọn ma ara wọn lọba mọ.‘’Awọn ọba naa gba kootu lọ, ile-ẹjọ si paṣẹ pe ki wọn pada sipo baalẹ na, gẹgẹ bijọba ṣe sọ. Ṣugbọn niṣe ni Adabọnyin ṣi n pe ara ẹ lọba ni tiẹ, awọn aṣoju ijọba ko si da a lẹkun ẹ, bẹẹ lawọn agbofinro naa ko mu un si.‘’Ṣugbọn ni bayii, igbimọ oloye Kemta ti yọ Ọgbẹni Adetokunbọ Tẹjuoṣo nipo baalẹ Adabọnyin, nitori ẹsun jibiti ibasun atawọn mi-in tawọn eeyan kan fi kan an, ti ẹri si wa fun un.‘’A waa rọ awọn akọroyin ati gbogbon eeyan patapata lati ma ṣe pe Ọgbẹni Adetokunbọ Tẹjuoṣo ni Baalẹ Abule Adabọnyin tabi Olu Kemta mọ, nitori ọrọ naa ṣi wa nile-ẹjọ.’’Tẹ o ba gbagbe, Tẹjuoṣo Adetokunbọ lawọn ọlọpaa mu lọsẹ diẹ sẹyin, ti wọn ti i mọle pe o gba ẹgbẹlẹgbẹ miliọnu lọwọ awọn obinrin kan, to loun yoo fẹ wọn, ti ko si pada fẹ wọn, to jẹ wọn ni Tẹjuoṣo lu awọn ni jibiti owo ati tara ni.Tẹjuoṣo sọrọ lasiko naa, o ni iyawo oun, Olori Halima Tẹjuoṣo, lo wa nidii ibajẹ oun. O fi kun un pe awọn kan ni wọn n lo obinrin naa lati ba toun jẹ, nitori oun ṣi n polongo idasilẹ ilẹ Olominira Yoruba ni.Ṣugbọn bo ṣe sọrọ ohun tan lawọn ọlọpaa tun gbe e lọ s’Abuja, ti wọn ni ẹsun ti wọn fi kan an ti kọja ipinlẹ Ogun, o ti di ti fẹdira, l’Abuja.Ohun to ṣaa foju han bayii ni pe awọn igbimọ Oloye Kemta ti lawọn ko mọ Tẹjuoṣo Adetokunbọ ri mọ, ki i ṣe baalẹ, bẹẹ ni ki i ṣe Olu Orile Kemta."},{"question":"विश्वव्यापी भूराजनीतिको सन्दर्भमा ऊर्जाको भूमिकाबारे चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"ऊर्जा स्रोतहरू, विशेष गरी जीवाश्म ईन्धनहरू, भू-राजनीतिक गतिशीलताको केन्द्रबिन्दु भएका छन्। ऊर्जा स्रोतहरूमा नियन्त्रणले अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय सम्बन्ध, व्यापार र द्वन्द्वलाई असर गर्न सक्छ।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"belum tahu dimasin garam\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud masih belum mempunyai pengalaman."},{"question":"மூன்று நிகழ்கலை கலைஞர்களை நேர்முகம் கண்டு அவர்களது கருத்துகளையும் அவர்களது மறுவாழ்விற்கான வழிமுறைகளாக நீங்கள் கருதுவனவற்றையும் குறிப்பிட்டு எழுதுக.","answer":"அறிமுகம்:நிகழ்கலை கலைஞர்களில் கரகாட்டம், மயிலாட்டம், பொய்க்கால் குதிரையாட்டம் ஆகியவற்றை நிகழ்த்திக்காட்டும் கலைஞர்களை நேரில் கண்டு, அவர்களின் வாழ்வியல் சூழல்களையும், கலை நிலையையும் குறித்துக் கேட்டறிந்தேன்.கலைகள்:நாட்டார் வழக்காறுகளை ஆழமாக ஆய்வு செய்த நா.வானமாமலை கூற்றுப்படி, தமிழ்நாட்டில் ஏறக்குறைய 1,026 கலைகள் இருந்ததாகத் தெரிகிறது. ஆனால் அவை இன்றைக்கு ஒவ்வொன்றாக மறைந்து வருவதோடு, எளிதில் எண்ணிவிடக் கூடிய அளவில் குறைந்துவிட்டதையும் அறிய முடிகிறது.பெரியசவால்:நிகழ்கலை கலைஞர்கள் சிறுசிறு குழுக்களாக ஒருங்கிணைக்கப்படாமல் எல்லா மாவட்டங்களிலும் இருக்கிறார்கள் என்பதையும், எப்போதாவது கிடைக்கின்ற வாய்ப்பினைப் பயன்படுத்தி நிகழ்கலைகளை நிகழ்த்தினாலும், அதனால் வாழ்வை நடத்துவதற்குப் போதுமான வருமானம் கிட்டுவதில்லை. இதனால் வறுமையில் சிக்கியுள்ள பெரும்பாலான கலைஞர்களை வேறுபணிகளை நாடிச் செல்லும் நிலை ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது. தொலைக்காட்சி மற்றும் நவீன மின்னணு ஊடகங்கள் கோலோச்சுகின்ற இக்காலக்கட்டத்தில் நாட்டுப்புறக்கலைகளும், அவற்றை நிகழ்த்துகின்ற கலைஞர்களும் பெரிய சவால்களை எதிர்காக்கும் அவலநிலைக்குத் தள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளனர்.காப்பாற்றுதல்:நிகழ்கலைகளை நிகழ்த்துவதற்கான ஆடை, ஆபரணங்கள் செலவும் அதிகமாக உள்ளது. அரசும் மக்களும் தங்கள் கலைகளை ஊக்குவித்து, வாய்ப்பளித்து, வாழ்வாதாரத்திற்கு உத்தரவாதமாய் உதவினால் மட்டுமே கலைகளையும், கலைஞர்களையும் காப்பாற்ற முடியும் என்பது அம்மூன்று கலைஞர்களின் ஒருமித்த குரலில் வெளிப்பட்டது.அரசின் உதவி:தமிழகமெங்கும் உள்ள கலைஞர்களை ஒவ்வொரு கலையின் அடிப்படையிலும் ஆவணப்படுத்தி அவர்களுக்கு முறையான அங்கீகாரம் வழங்குவது மிகவும் தேவையான ஒன்றாகும். நிகழ்கலைகளை மீட்டுருவாக்கம் செய்கின்ற வகையில், கிராமம் கிராமமாகத் தேடிச் சென்று கலைகள் பற்றிய தகவல்களைச் சேகரித்து ஆவணப்படுத்த வேண்டும். கலைக்குழுக்களை அரசுத்துறையில் முறையாகப் பதிவு செய்யப்பட வேண்டும். எல்லாக் கலைஞர்களுக்கம் அடையாள அட்டை வழங்கி ஊக்குவிப்பு ஊதியம் வழங்கப்பட வேண்டும்.செய்ய வேண்டுவது:நிகழ்கலைகளை ஆவணப்படுத்துவதற்கும், கலைகள் குறித்த வகுப்புகள், கருத்தரங்குகள், விவாதங்கள், உரையாடல் நடத்தவும் நிகழ்கலைகளுக்கான தனிப்பல்கலைக்கழகம் அமைக்கப்பட்டு, நிகழ்கலைகளுக்கான கலைஞர்கள் உருவாக்கப்பட வேண்டும்.அரசின் சார்பில் நிகழ்கலைகளுக்கென்று தனிவிழாக்கள் நடத்தப்பட வேண்டும். பள்ளி, கல்லூ ரிகளிலும் நிகழ்கலைகளை நடத்திட வேண்டும்.நிறைவு:தமிழரின் பண்பாட்டு அடையாளங்களாக விளங்கும் நிகழ்கலைகளையும், கலைஞர்களையும் ஆதரித்துக் காக்க வேண்டிய பொறுப்பு ஒவ்வொரு தமிழனுக்கும் உரியது என்பது திண்ணம்."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਰਾਗੁ ਗਉੜੀ ਚੇਤੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਨਾਮਦੇਉ ਜੀਉ ਕੀੴ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ॥ਦੇਵਾ ਪਾਹਨ ਤਾਰੀਅਲੇ ॥ਰਾਮ ਕਹਤ ਜਨ ਕਸ ਨ ਤਰੇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਤਾਰੀਲੇ ਗਨਿਕਾ ਬਿਨੁ ਰੂਪ ਕੁਬਿਜਾ ਬਿਆਧਿ ਅਜਾਮਲੁ ਤਾਰੀਅਲੇ ॥ਚਰਨ ਬਧਿਕ ਜਨ ਤੇਊ ਮੁਕਤਿ ਭਏ ॥ਹਉ ਬਲਿ ਬਲਿ ਜਿਨ ਰਾਮ ਕਹੇ ॥੧॥ਦਾਸੀ ਸੁਤ ਜਨੁ ਬਿਦਰੁ ਸੁਦਾਮਾ ਉਗ੍ਰਸੈਨ ਕਉ ਰਾਜ ਦੀਏ ॥ਜਪ ਹੀਨ ਤਪ ਹੀਨ ਕੁਲ ਹੀਨ ਕ੍ਰਮ ਹੀਨ ਨਾਮੇ ਕੇ ਸੁਆਮੀ ਤੇਊ ਤਰੇ ॥੨॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 345 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਤੁਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਭਗਤ ਨਾਮ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! (ਉਹ) ਪੱਥਰ (ਭੀ ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਉੱਤੇ) ਤੂੰ ਤਰਾ ਦਿੱਤੇ (ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਤੇਰਾ ‘ਰਾਮ’ ਨਾਮ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ; ਭਲਾ) ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ) ਕਿਉਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਤਰਨਗੇ, ਜੋ ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦੇ ਹਨ? ।ਰਹਾਉ।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਤੂੰ (ਮੰਦ-ਕਰਮਣ) ਵੇਸਵਾ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਤੋਂ) ਬਚਾ ਲਈ, ਤੂੰ ਕੁਰੂਪ ਕੁਬਿਜਾ ਦਾ ਕੋਝ ਦੂਰ ਕੀਤਾ, ਤੂੰ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਗਲੇ ਹੋਏ ਅਜਾਮਲ ਨੂੰ ਤਾਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ,  (ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨ ਜੀ ਦੇ) ਪੈਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਨਿਸ਼ਾਨਾ ਮਾਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਸ਼ਿਕਾਰੀ (ਅਤੇ) ਅਜਿਹੇ ਕਈ (ਵਿਕਾਰੀ) ਬੰਦੇ (ਤੇਰੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ) ਮੁਕਤ ਹੋ ਗਏ ਮੈਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਹਾਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆ ।੧।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਗੋੱਲੀ ਦਾ ਪੁੱਤਰ ਬਿਦਰ ਤੇਰਾ ਭਗਤ (ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਹੋਇਆ); ਸੁਦਾਮਾ (ਇਸ ਦਾ ਤੂੰ ਦਲਿੱਦਰ ਕੱਟਿਆ), ਉਗਰਸੈਨ ਨੂੰ ਤੂੰ ਰਾਜ ਦਿੱਤਾ । ਹੇ ਨਾਮਦੇਵ ਦੇ ਸੁਆਮੀ! ਤੇਰੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਉਹ ਉਹ ਤਰ ਗਏ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕੋਈ ਜਪ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੇ, ਕੋਈ ਤਪ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਾਧੇ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਉੱਚੀ ਕੁਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ, ਕੋਈ ਚੰਗੇ ਅਮਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਨ ।੨।੧।\\""},{"question":"Fenoy ity ohabolana ity: “Ny aina Ramangatahiana,_”","answer":" “Ny aina Ramangatahiana, ny vola Ramangakatsahina”"},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp nội dung cho đoạn văn sau: \\"Cơ quan Mật vụ Mỹ (USSS) dự tính sẽ tắt tính năng gửi tin nhắn qua iMessage trên các iPhone nội bộ của nhân viên. Đây được xem là nỗ lực của chính quyền Mỹ sau những tranh cãi liên quan đến các tin nhắn bị xóa trước vụ tấn công Điện Capitol hôm 6/1/2021. \\"Chúng tôi đang cân nhắc kỹ lưỡng về biện pháp này. Giám đốc Cơ quan Mật vụ James Murray đã yêu cầu nghiêm túc nghiên cứu xem liệu có thể tắt iMessage mà không gây ra ảnh hưởng gì đến hệ thống vận hành của thiết bị hay không\\", Anthony Guglielmi, đại diện của cơ quan, này chia sẻ. Guglielmi còn cho biết ông Murray yêu cầu kết quả phải có ngay trong tuần. Theo Politico, Mật vụ Mỹ đã làm theo cách Bộ An ninh Nội địa quản lý các tin nhắn trên iMessage. Nhưng hiện cơ quan này vẫn chưa tắt tính năng iMessage trên điện thoại nhân viên của mình. Trong khi đó, Nhà Trắng đã thực hiện biện pháp này từ trước, Chris Krebs, cựu Giám đốc Cơ quan An ninh Mạng và Cơ sở hạ tầng, cho biết. Cơ quan này lo ngại việc tắt tính năng iMessage buộc họ phải phụ thuộc vào tin nhắn thông thường, làm ảnh hưởng đến việc trao đổi những thông tin khẩn cấp với các bộ, ngành khác. \\"Chúng tôi muốn đảm bảo rằng mọi thay đổi trong chính sách của mình sẽ không ảnh hưởng đến nhiệm vụ bảo vệ tổng thống hay điều tra của mình\\", đại diện Guglielmi chia sẻ. Ông cho biết Mật Mỹ sẽ tìm thêm những biện pháp khác để khắc phục sơ sót này. Theo Politico, những tin nhắn bị xóa được đánh giá là rất quan trọng đối với cuộc điều tra của Hạ Viện và Bộ Tư Pháp, nhằm xác định xem liệu cựu tổng thống Donald Trump có khuyến khích cuộc tấn công vào Điện Capitol hay không. Cụ thể, hôm 14/7, Văn phòng Tổng thanh tra Bộ An ninh Nội địa Mỹ đã gửi một bức thư tới Ủy ban An ninh Nội địa thuộc Hạ viện và Thượng viện, trong đó tuyên bố các tin nhắn trao đổi giữa nhân viên mật vụ Mỹ trong hai ngày 5-6/1/2021 đã bị xóa sau khi bị yêu cầu công bố. Lời tố giác này đã buộc Hạ viện nhúng tay vào cuộc điều tra. \\"Nếu có cách khôi phục tin nhắn, chúng tôi sẽ làm điều đó\\", Hạ nghị sĩ Bennie Thompson, Chủ tịch Ủy ban của Hạ viện phụ trách điều tra vụ bạo loạn ở Điện Capitol và là chủ tịch Ủy ban An ninh Nội địa Hạ viện, khẳng định. Các quan chức khác cũng cho rằng việc Cơ quan Mật vụ làm mất tin nhắn quan trọng đã vi phạm luật lưu trữ dữ liệu của Liên bang.\\"","answer":"Về phần mình, Mật vụ Mỹ phủ nhận họ cố ý xóa các tin nhắn, nhưng tuyên bố một số dữ liệu đã bị mất khi được di chuyển. Theo Politico, vào thời điểm đó, Cơ quan Mật vụ Mỹ cho biết họ phải xóa toàn bộ dữ liệu trên điện thoại để chuyển sang nền tảng quản lý thiết bị di động mới. Công nghệ này sẽ giúp cấp trên quản lý bao quát và lưu trữ toàn bộ email, hình ảnh và những thông tin khác trên điện thoại cấp dưới của mình. Trong đó, những tin nhắn trên iMessage không thể lưu lại vì đã được mã hóa và nằm trên iPhone, khác với những tin nhắn thông thường. Vì thế, Mật vụ Mỹ không thể lưu trữ iMessages trong bộ dữ liệu trung tâm như email hay các thông tin khác, làm ảnh hưởng đến số tin nhắn liên quan đến bạo động tại Điện Capitol. Một số nghị sĩ không cảm thấy cách giải thích này thuyết phục. \\"Tôi nghi ngờ có sự gian trá ở đây\\", nghị sĩ Jamie Raskin nói. \\"Việc các tin nhắn biến mất vào đúng hai ngày xảy ra vụ bạo loạn dữ dội nhất chống lại liên bang trong lịch sử, kể từ nội chiến, là sự trùng hợp rất kỳ lạ\\", ông Raskin bình luận. Theo Politico, các chuyên gia an ninh mạng cũng tỏ ra ngỡ ngàng khi Mật vụ Mỹ, một cơ quan vốn có nhiệm vụ bảo vệ tổng thống và thực hiện nhiều cuộc điều tra liên quan đến tội phạm mạng, lại có thể làm mất những dữ liệu số quan trọng này. Họ cho rằng ngay cả các tổ chức có quy mô nhỏ cũng có thể di chuyển dữ liệu một cách trơn tru. Đồng thời, rất đáng ngờ khi những thiết bị này đã bị xóa dữ liệu đúng vào lúc cơ quan giám sát yêu cầu nộp lên trong quá trình điều tra vụ bạo loạn ở Điện Capitol. Nếu Mật vụ Mỹ muốn, họ có thể dễ dàng bảo vệ những tin nhắn của nhân viên mình bởi sao lưu và xuất dữ liệu là chức năng cơ bản của tất cả dịch vụ tin nhắn. Mới đây, ngày 21/7, một vụ xóa dữ liệu khác cũng diễn ra. Toàn bộ tin nhắn giữa Chad Wolf, Quyền Bộ trưởng An ninh Nội địa Mỹ (DHS) dưới thời ông Donald Trump, và Quyền Thứ trưởng Ken Cuccinelli trong khoảng thời gian quan trọng dẫn đến vụ tấn công Điện Capitol ngày 6/1 cũng bị mất."},{"question":"İkinci Dünya Savaşı'nda hangi ülkeye ve şehirlere atom bombası atılmıştır?","answer":"İkinci Dünya Savaşı sırasında Amerika Birleşik Devletleri, Japonya'ya atom bombası atmıştır. Atılan şehirler Hiroşima ve Nagazaki'dir. Hiroşima'ya 6 Ağustos 1945'te, Nagazaki'ye ise 9 Ağustos 1945'te atom bombaları atılmıştır. Bu olaylar, savaşın sona ermesine büyük ölçüde etki etmiş ve Japonya'nın teslim olmasına yol açmıştır."},{"question":"Que mês é conhecido no Brasil como mês do orgulho?","answer":"Junho."},{"question":"Welk van de volgende dieren is een vissoort? Zeedraak, ezel","answer":"Dit is simpel, een zeedraak is een vissoort."},{"question":"ලොව විශාලතම වෘක්ෂ වර්ගය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ලොව විශාලතම වෘක්ෂ වර්ගය රෙඩ්වුඩ් ගස්ය. ලොව විශාලතම ස්වාධින ජිවියා කැලිපොනියානු රෙඩ්වුඩ් ශාකයයි. මෙය රතු දුඹුරු පැහැති කඳකින් හෙබි තේජාන්විත සදාහරිත වෘක්ෂයක්ය. වටක් ප්රනමානයෙන් මීටර 24 ක් හා උසින් මීටර 120ක් දක්වා වු ශාක පිලිබඳව වර්ථා වී ඇත. උතුරු ඇමරිකාවේ වයඹ වෙරග තීරයට (Redwood Cree Vally) ආසන්නයේ මෙම ශාක බහුලවම හමු වේයි. රෙඩ්වුඩ් ශාකයට වසර 2400-4000ක් පමණ ආයු කාලයක් ඇතැයි විශ්වාස කෙරේ. ඇස්තමෙන්තු කර ඇත් පරිදි මෙම ශාකයක බර ටොන් 2000ක්ය. මේ ශාකයේ කඳ නම් ගින්නටවත්, කෘමීන්ටවත් විනාෂ කරන්න පහසු නැහැ."},{"question":"\\"Адамды акылынан ...\\"  деген макал-лакапты улантып берчи?","answer":"Сиз суранган макал-лакап мындай болушу мүмкүн: \\"Адамды акылынан, даракты жалбырагынан байка.\\""},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga: \\"__ dia fombamalagasy nentim-paharazana izay mitantara tantara amin'ny alalan'ny hetsika.\\"","answer":"Valiny: Ny Hiragasy dia fomba malagasy nentim-paharazana izay mitantara tantara amin'ny alalan'ny hetsika."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\"Malaelo aho milaza aminao fa _ ahy ny aty\\"","answer":"Malaelo aho milaza aminao fa mafinaritra ahy ny aty."},{"question":"Daj mi przykład zagadki z tej kategorii: gry wideo.","answer":"Oto zagadka z kategorii gry wideo:\\"Która firma tworzyła oryginalną grę Doom? ID Software\\"."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Xem video (theo VTVCab) Đội hình ra sân Hà Nội: Tấn Trường; Duy Mạnh, Thành Chung, Văn Hậu, Văn Toàn, Hùng Dũng, Văn Quyết, Văn Kiên, Tuấn Hải, Xuân Tú, Siladij. SLNA: Văn Hoàng, Bá Sang, Thế Nhật, Ngọc Hải, Xuân Tiến, Sỹ Hoàng, Xuân Mạnh, Đình Hoàng, Văn Đức, Oseni, Michael Olaha. Bàn thắng: Siladij 53' (pen), Thành Chung 76' - Olaha 4' Thẻ đỏ: Olaha 49'","answer":"Video bàn thắng Hà Nội 2-1 SLNA: Thành Chung tỏa sáng"},{"question":"નીચેના શબ્દસમૂહ માટે એક શબ્દ આપો:જીવાત્મા - પરમાત્મા એક જ છે એવો વાદ ","answer":"અદ્વૈતવાદ "},{"question":"ప్రత్యక్ష ప్రజాస్వామ్యం గురించి నీకు తెలిసింది రాయండి.","answer":"ప్రత్యక్ష ప్రజాస్వామ్యం: ఈ పద్ధతిలో ప్రజలు ప్రభుత్వ పాలన వ్యవహారాలలో ప్రత్యక్షంగా పాల్గొంటారు. శాసన సంబంధమైన అధికారాలన్నీ వారు చెలాయిస్తారు. ప్రజలే చట్ట సభలలో పాల్గొని చట్టాలను రూపొందిస్తారు. రాజ్య వ్యవహారాలలో ప్రజలు ప్రత్యక్షంగా భాగస్వామ్యం వహిస్తారు.ప్రత్యక్ష ప్రజాస్వామ్య విధానం ప్రస్తుతం స్విట్జర్లాండ్లో కొన్ని కాంటన్ల లోనూ, అమెరికా సంయుక్త రాష్ట్రాలలోని కొన్ని ప్రాంతాలలోనూ నెలకొని ఉంది."},{"question":"Tại sao các ngọn núi cao nhất thế giới lại nằm gần xích đạo ? Kể tên  những ngọn núi cao nằm ở gần xích đạo ?","answer":"Ba yếu tố điều khiển việc tăng trưởng chiều cao của các dãy núi là: sức mạnh nằm dưới lớp vỏ Trái Đất, độ lớn của sự kiến tạo địa chất và độ lớn của sự xói mòn. Tất cả các dãy núi cao nhất Thế giới có có sức mạnh dưới lớp vỏ Trái Đất lớn, nhưng cho tới bây giờ vẫn còn chưa rõ ràng về việc đỉnh núi cao nhất thế giới là chủ yếu do sự nâng lên mạnh hay do sự xói mòn ít nhất. Các ngọn núi cao gần xích đạo có thể kể đến như sau:1. Núi Everest: Nằm trên dãy Himalaya, giữa biên giới Nepal và Trung Quốc.2. Núi Kilimanjaro: Nằm ở Tanzania, là ngọn núi cao nhất châu Phi.3. Núi Aconcagua: Nằm ở Argentina, là ngọn núi cao nhất châu Mỹ.4. Núi Denali: Nằm ở Alaska, Hoa Kỳ, là ngọn núi cao nhất Bắc Mỹ.5. Núi Elbrus: Nằm ở Nga, là ngọn núi cao nhất châu Âu.Tuy nhiên, cũng cần lưu ý rằng không tất cả các ngọn núi cao nhất thế giới đều nằm gần xích đạo. Vị trí của các ngọn núi phụ thuộc vào sự tương tác phức tạp giữa các mảng kiến tạo địa chất trên toàn cầu."},{"question":"Íchafụ","answer":"Olundi - akịsị"},{"question":"Àsìkò wo ni a máa ń se eré ìdárayá?","answer":"Léyìn isé òòjó"},{"question":"A wace kasa ce Bashir Ahmed Qureshi ya rasu?","answer":"A Pakistan ne."},{"question":"வினா : இந்திய சிவில் விமானப் போக்குவரத்தின் தந்தை?","answer":"விடை : டாட்டா"},{"question":"Promote කියන වචනයට ගැළපෙන ලස්සන  සිංහල  වචනයක් දෙන්න.මෙහෙවර ප්‍රාශියකට.","answer":"ප්‍රවර්ධනය , අභිවර්ධනය වගෙ හොඳයි නේද මෙහෙවර ප්‍රකාශයකට"},{"question":"Scrivi una continuazione: Prodotto dei Miami Redhawks si dichiara eleggibile dopo quattro anni di college ","answer":"per il Draft NBA 2012, ma non viene scelto."},{"question":"Quando o Vasco da Gama foi fundado?","answer":"O Vasco da Gama foi fundado em 21 de agosto de 1898."},{"question":"Buatlah dua paragraf cerita pendek berdasarkan judul atau topik yang disediakan, dengan melanjutkan penggalan teks di bawah ini.Judul: Kisah Dua Sahabat dan Beruang.Toni dan Leo merupakan dua orang yang telah bersahabat sejak lama. Karena hari libur, mereka berdua berencana untuk ...","answer":"berjalan-jalan menyusuri keindahan alam yang ada di hutan. Saking senangnya ketika di hutan, mereka tidak menyadari bahwa mereka telah berjalan jauh ke dalam hutan. Hingga mereka melewati batas yang telah ditentukan untuk dilalui. Karena terlalu masuk ke dalam hutan, mereka berdua tidak sengaja bertemu dengan seekor beruang lapar yang sedari tadi mengincar mereka. Karena takut, Toni pun langsung naik ke atas pohon dan meninggalkan Leo di bawah begitu saja. Leo yang mengetahui hal tersebut berusaha keras mencari ide. Leo tidak memanjat karena ia tidak bisa memanjat pohon. Setelah berpikir keras, Leo akhirnya ingat ia pernah mendengar bahwa hewan akan meninggalkan dan tidak menyukai orang yang telah mati. Akhirnya Leo berbaring di tanah dan menahan napas dalam-dalam.Melihat hal tersebut si beruang pun langsung menghampiri Leo yang terbaring di tanah seraya mengenduskan hidungnya. Tak lama kemudian beruang pergi meninggalkan Leo yang tengah berbaring. Toni dari atas pohon melihat hal tersebut merasa penasaran, akhirnya setelah beruang pergi, ia pun langsung turun menghampiri Leo dan bertanya dengan penasaran. \\"Apa yang dibisikkan beruang kepadamu? Mengapa ia langsung pergi?\\" tanya Toni. \\"Katanya aku disuruh menjauhi teman yang mementingkan diri sendiri sepertimu\\", jawab Leo. Merasa bersalah, Toni meminta maaf pada Leo."},{"question":"Content:  ਸਥਾਨਕ ਪਸ਼ੂ ਪਾਲਣ ਤੇ ਡੇਅਰੀ ਵਿਭਾਗ ਦੀ ਟੀਮ ਨੇ ਘਟਨਾ ਵਾਲੀ ਥਾਂ ਦਾ ਦੌਰਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਪਾਣੀ ਤੇ ਚਾਰੇ ਦੇ ਸੈਂਪਲ ਲਏ ਹਨ।ਪਸ਼ੂ ਪਾਲਣ ਵਿਭਾਗ ਦੇ ਡਿਪਟੀ ਡਾਇਰੈਕਟ ਅਨਿਲ ਕੁਮਾਰ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ, \\"ਜਦੋਂ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਟੈਸਟ ਰਿਪੋਰਟ ਮਿਲੇਗੀ ਅਸੀਂ ਉਦੋਂ ਹੀ ਕੁਝ ਕਹਿ ਪਾਵਾਂਗੇ। ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਜਾਂਚ 'ਚ ਇਹ ਫੂਡ ਪੁਆਈਜ਼ਨਿੰਗ ਦਾ ਮਾਮਲਾ ਜਾਪ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਦੋ ਸ਼ੈੱਡਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਗਾਵਾਂ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਬੀਮਾਰ:ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਨਾਲ ਫੋਨ 'ਤੇ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਮਾਤਾ ਮਨਸਾ ਦੇਵੀ ਗੋਧਾਮ ਦੇ ਜਨਰਲ ਸਕੱਤਰ ਨਰੇਸ਼ ਮਿੱਤਲ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ 70 ਗਾਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਹੁਣ ਤੱਕ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੱਸਿਆ, \\"ਗੋਧਾਮ 'ਚ ਕੁੱਲ 7 ਸ਼ੈੱਡ ਹਨ। ਦੂਜੇ ਅਤੇ ਤੀਜੇ ਸ਼ੈੱਡ ਦੀਆਂ 400 ਗਾਵਾਂ 'ਚੋਂ 100 ਬੀਮਾਰ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਸਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਚੋਂ 70 ਗਾਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ। ਕੁੱਲ 1350 ਗਾਵਾਂ ਗੋਧਾਮ 'ਚ ਹਨ।\\"ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਅੱਗੇ ਕਿਹਾ, \\"ਪੂਰੇ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਖਦਸ਼ਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕੋਈ ਨਵਰਾਤਰਿਆਂ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਪੂਰੀ-ਹਲਵਾ ਜਾਂ ਕੱਟੂ ਆਟਾ ਦੀ ਰੋਟੀ ਸ਼ਾਇਦ ਗਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਖੁਆ ਗਿਆ, ਜਿਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਹ ਬੀਮਾਰ ਪੈ ਗਈਆਂ।\\"ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਬਿਠਾਈ ਜਾਂਚ: ਘਟਨਾਸਥਾਨ ਦਾ ਦੌਰਾ ਕਰਨ ਆਏ ਸਥਾਨਕ ਵਿਧਾਇਕ ਅਤੇ ਹਰਿਆਣਾ ਵਿਧਾਨ ਸਭਾ ਦੇ ਸਪੀਕਰ ਗਿਆਨਚੰਦ ਗੁਪਤਾ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਜਾਂਚ ਬਿਠਾ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਗਈ ਹੈ। ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਪੱਧਰ 'ਤੇ ਹੋਈ ਲਾਪਰਵਾਹੀ ਨੂੰ ਬਰਦਾਸ਼ਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾਵੇਗਾ।\\"ਗਿਆਨ ਚੰਦ ਗੁਪਤਾ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਸ਼ਨ ਨੂੰ ਨਵੀਆਂ ਗਾਇਡਲਾਇਨਜ਼ ਤੈਅ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਵੀ ਕਿਹਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਜੋ ਅੱਗੇ ਤੋਂ ਅਜਿਹੀ ਘਟਨਾ ਨਾ ਵਾਪਰੇ।ਇਸੇ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਸਥਾਨਕ ਬਜਰੰਗ ਦਲ ਦੇ ਸਥਾਨਕ ਆਗੂਆਂ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਘਟਨਾ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਗਹਿਰੀ ਸਾਜ਼ਿਸ ਹੋਣ ਦਾ ਖਦਸਾ ਵੀ ਪ੍ਰਗਟਾਇਆ। ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਦੀ ਗਹਿਰਾਈ ਨਾਲ ਜਾਂਚ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਮੰਗ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ 7 ਸੈਂਡਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੋ ਸੈਂਡਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਗਾਵਾਂ ਹੀ ਮਰੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਜੋ ਮਿਊਸਪਲ ਕੌਂਸਲ ਨੇ ਅਵਾਰਾ ਫੜ ਕੇ ਦਿੱਤੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਜੋ ਦੁੱਧ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੰਦੀਆਂ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਜੇਕਰ ਫ਼ੂਡ ਪੁਆਇੰਸਨਿੰਗ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਚਾਰਾ ਤਾਂ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਸ਼ੈੱਡਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਗਾਵਾਂ ਨੇ ਖਾਧਾ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ। ਪਰ ਅਨਿਲ ਮਿੱਤਲ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਜਾਂਚ ਪੂਰੀ ਹੋਣ ਤੱਕ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਨਤੀਜੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਪਹੁੰਚਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ।","answer":"ਪੰਚਕੂਲਾ 'ਚ ਬੁੱਧਵਾਰ ਸਵੇਰੇ ਮਨਸਾ ਦੇਵੀ ਗਉਸ਼ਾਲਾ 'ਚ ਕਰੀਬ 70 ਗਾਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਅਤੇ 30 ਦੇ ਕਰੀਬ ਗਾਵਾਂ ਬੀਮਾਰ ਦੱਸੀਆਂ ਜਾ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ।"},{"question":"Lan moo waral turu Senegaal ?","answer":"Turu Senegaal moo ngi juuge ci Sunu gaal."},{"question":"வினா: நாம் ஏன் மரபினைப் பின்பற்ற வேண்டும். அவ்வாறுபின்பற்றவில்லையெனில் மொழியின் நிலை என்னவாகும்? வகுப்பறையில் கலந்துரையாடுக.","answer":"விடை: ஒரு மாணவன்: வணக்கம்! நம் முன்னோர்கள் நெடுங்காலமாக எப்பொருளை எச்சொல்லால் எப்படிச் சொன்னார்களோ, அச்சொல்லை அப்படியே சொல்வது மரபாகும். நாய் கத்தியது எனக் கூறுவது வழக்கம். அவ்வாறு கூறுதல் கூடாது. நாய் குரைத்தது என்பதே உரிய மரபுத் தொடர்ச் சொல் ஆகும்.மற்றொரு மாணவன்: ஆம் சரியாக கூறினாய். இம்மரபுச் சொற்களைப் பின்பற்றவில்லையெனில் மொழியின் அமைப்பு சிதைந்து விடும்.மற்றொரு மாணவன்: ஆம் சரியாக கூறினாய். இம்மரபுச் சொற்களைப் பற்றி தொல்காப்பியர் தனது நூற்பாவில் 'பார்ப்பும் பறழும் குட்டியும் குருளையும்கன்றும் பிள்ளையும் மகவும் மறியும் என்றுஒன்பதும் குழவியொடு இளமைப் பெயரே.\\"\\"ஏறும் ஏற்றையும் ஒருத்தலும் களிறும்சேவும் சேவலும் இரலையும் கலையும்மோத்தையும் தகரும் உதளும் அப்பரும்போத்தும் கண்டியும் கடுவனும் பிறவும்யாத்த ஆண்பாற் பெயர் என மொழிப.\\" \\"பேடையும் பெடையும் பெட்டையும் பெண்ணும்மூடும் நாகும் கடமையும் அளகும்மந்தியும் பாட்டியும் பிணையும் பிணவும்அந்தம் சான்ற பிடியொடு பெண்ணே.\\" என்று குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளார்."},{"question":"ફિલોજેનેટિક્સ એટલે શું?","answer":"ફિલોજેનેટિક્સ એ ઉત્ક્રાંતિ ઇતિહાસ અને સજીવના જૂથો વચ્ચે અથવા અંદરના સંબંધોનો અભ્યાસ છે.આ સંબંધો ફાયલોજેનેટિક અનુમાન પદ્ધતિઓ દ્વારા નક્કી કરવામાં આવે છે જે ડીએનએ સિક્વન્સ, પ્રોટીન એમિનો એસિડ સિક્વન્સ અથવા મોર્ફોલોજી જેવા અવલોકન વારસાગત લક્ષણો પર ધ્યાન કેન્દ્રિત કરે છે.આવા વિશ્લેષણનું પરિણામ એ એક ફાયલોજેનેટિક વૃક્ષ છે - એક આકૃતિ જેમાં સંબંધોની પૂર્વધારણા છે જે સજીવના જૂથના ઉત્ક્રાંતિ ઇતિહાસને પ્રતિબિંબિત કરે છે."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Một người tử vong tại quán cà phê võng ở Bình Tân, TP HCM","answer":"Ngày 31-7, Công an TP HCM cho biết các phòng nghiệp vụ đang phối hợp với Công an quận Bình Tân (TP HCM) và các cơ quan chức năng làm rõ vụ người đàn ông tử vong tại quán cà phê võng. Theo thông tin ban đầu, tối 30-7, nhiều người đá bóng tại một sân bóng ở đường số 6 (phường Bình Hưng Hòa B, quận Bình Tân) phát hiện người đàn ông trên 50 tuổi nằm bất động trên võng ở quán cà phê sân bóng. Một số người đến kiểm tra thì phát hiện người đàn ông đã tử vong nên báo công an. Nhận được tin báo, các cơ quan chức năng đã nhanh chóng khám nghiệm hiện trường, trích xuất camera và làm rõ vụ việc."},{"question":"What are the only two mammals that lay eggs?","answer":"Echidna and platypus"},{"question":"යින් සහ යැං යන්නෙහි තේරුම කුමක්ද?","answer":"යින් යැං සංකල්පය (බොහෝ විට “යින් සහ යැං” ලෙස හැඳින්වේ) යනු ප්‍රතිවිරුද්ධ බලවේග එකිනෙක සම්බන්ධ වී එකිනෙකා මත රඳා පවතින ආකාරය පැහැදිලි කිරීමට භාවිතා කරන චීන දාර්ශනික අදහසකි. වෙනත් වචන වලින් කිවහොත්, කළු පාටට සුදු නොමැතිව, ආලෝකය නොමැතිව අඳුරු, තාපය නොමැතිව සීතල, යනාදී ලෙස පැවතිය නොහැක. යින් යැං සංකල්පය සම්භාව්‍ය චීන විද්‍යාව සහ දර්ශනය, සාම්ප්‍රදායික චීන වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාව සහ විවිධ චීන සටන් කලාවන්හි බොහෝ ශාඛා වල පදනම වේ, තායි චි ඇතුළු ව්‍යායාම."},{"question":"Oro","answer":"Orò wà nínú àwọn àjọ̀dún ńlà tí àwọn Yorùbá ma ǹ ṣe ní ọdọọdún. Ọdún Orò jẹ́ ọọ̀kan pàtàkì nínú ọdún tí àwọn ẹ̀yà Yorùbá ma ń ṣe.Oro si je osa kekere kan ti a mo si olorun ogun. Ara igi agbon lati gbe Oro jade. Osa nla gidi gan ni Oro je, won a si ma boo ni odoodun. Oro je osa kan to sepe omo okunrin nikan lo le foju ri to si le boo paapaa julo lodo awon ti ajodun yii ba tan mo. A ki wo ni Oro fun eni ti ko ba n se omo oloro pelu fun obinrin lapaapo. Gbogbo obinrin pelu eni ti ko ba tan mo oloro ni lati wa ni asemo lasiko ti odun Oro ba waye. Ewe, obinrin o gbodo fi oju kan osa yi ti a n pe ni Oro. Bi obinrin ba foju kan Oro, Oro a gbe. Orisirisi ona ara, asa ati ise ni awon oloro ma n gba se odun yii. Osi yato lati ipinle si ipinle ati ilu si ilu. Ni awon akoko miran, Oro a ma jade, tabi ki won gbe oro fun eni pataki bii oba to ba je olori awon to n boo orisa yii (Oro). Bi Oro se bereNi aye atijo, osa merin kan wa ton n gbe ni Erekusu. Awon osa won yi so di mimo pe: Ta'aroa, Iyemoja (god of the sea), Tane, Oluigbo (god of the forest), Tu, (Jagunmolu atijo) ati Ro'o, (olorun nkan ogbin pelu bi oju ojo tinri). Awon onimose ti won tedo si agbegbe Polynesian tan esin won kakiri gbogbo igberiko Erekusu. Omu itesiwaju ba gbogbo agbaye àti idagbasoke si agbegbe ti ó je ti won gangan. Eleyi mu iyato ba nkan gbigbe awon ileto Polynesia. Ni agbegbe Ralatea, adari orisa Ta,aroa tin se ti olorun odo je ohun pataki erekusu odo fun orisa yi ti o wa lati da aye sile. Ohun ti a le salaye ninu e nipe, Arikiti je adari ijoye ati awon eniyan nlanlan ti Ralatea. Won tan ipinlese DE Taaroa. Lafikun, atun ripe awon alawo Oro ni ówò, bi omo Taaroa, Hina tu a uta, sibi marae, Taputapute nile Ralatea la fi lele. Gene bi isedale, Taputapute je idakeji ilu abinibi Oro."},{"question":"নিচের অনুচ্ছেদের বিষয় কি ?উয়েফা ইউরো ২০২০-এর গ্রুপ সি-এর সকল ম্যাচ ২০২১ সালের ১৩ হতে ২১শে জুন তারিখ পর্যন্ত নেদারল্যান্ডসের আমস্টারডামের ইয়োহান ক্রুইফ এরিনা এবং রোমানিয়ার বুখারেস্টের এরিনা নাৎসিয়োনালায় অনুষ্ঠিত হয়েছে। এই গ্রুপে নেদারল্যান্ডস, ইউক্রেন, অস্ট্রিয়া এবং উত্তর মেসিডোনিয়া একে অপরের মুখোমুখি হয়েছে।","answer":"উয়েফা ইউরো ২০২০ |"},{"question":"شكون هو اللي رسلو الرسول صلى وسلم باش يهدم صنم دوس؟","answer":" الجواب هو جرير بن عبد الله البجلي."},{"question":"Funda ngomlando nangokusetshenziswa kwesihlahla somganu bese wenza umsebenzi ekhasinielilandelayo.Amaqiniso Ngesihlahla SomganuUmlando wesihlahla somganu uhlehla ufike eminyakeni engaphezu kweyizinkulungwane. Lesisihlahla siyatholakala nakwezinye izindawo kodwa e-Afrika siyigugu elikhulu. Saziwa kakhulungesithelo saso esibizwa ngokuthi iganu. Lesi sihlahla sibaluleke kakhulu ngoba yonke ingxenyeyaso inosizo olukhulu kusukela kuwo amagxolo esihlahla, kube amaqabunga aso, isithelo, kanyenenhlamvu ephuma esithelweni.Abantu abaningi basazi lesi sihlahla ngesithelo saso esiwela phansi emhlabathini bese sidliwayizindlovu zize zidakwe. ENingizimu Afrika sitholakala kakhulu eziqiwini zezilwane nasezindawenizazemaphandleni ikakhulukazi ezifundazweni zaseLimpopo, KwaZulu Natali, eNtshonalanga KapanaseMpumalanga.Kunezinto ezintathu esingaziqaphela ngesihlahla somganu. Okokuqala ngukuthi sinamaqabungaamaningi. La maqabunga asiza ukuthi sithele izithelo eziningi. Isihlahla ngasinye singathela izitheloezingama-kg angama-500 ngonyaka. Okwesibili ukuthi lesi sihlahla singakhula sibe phakathikwamamitha ayi-9 kuya kwayi-18 ubude futhi siyakwazi ukumelana nesomiso. Okokugcina ukuthisinobulili obubili. Lokhu kusho ukuthi kukhona isihlala sesilisa nesesifazane. Isihlahla sesifazaneyiso esithela izithelo, bese kuthi esesilisa sona siba nezimbali.Ezindaweni eziningi zase-Afrika, lesi sihlahla siyavikelwa kakhulu. Imihlangano eminingi ibanjelwangaphansi kwaso ngoba sikhula sifane nesambulela. Lokhu kwenza ukuthi sinikeze umthunziomuhle abantu abangahlala ngaphansi kwawo ukuze bangashiswa yilanga. Phela ezindawenilapho sitholakala khona lesi sihlahla uthola ukuthi kusemaphandleni ngakho intuthuko iza kancaneokwenza ukuthi izidingongqangi ezifana namahholo zingabi khona. Ngakho-ke, imihlanganoyemiphakathi ibanjelwa phandle. Kanti okunye futhi ngukuthi isimo sezulu sivamise ukushisakakhulu.Okunye okwenza ukuba sibaluleke e-Afrika ngukuthi siyasiza ngokwempilo. Sifana nekhemisi laphoabantu bethola usizo uma begula noma belimele. Amagxolo alesi sihlahla yiwo asetshenziswakakhulu ukwelapha labo abagulayo nabalimele kwesinye isikhathi. Okunye okuphawulekayongamagxolo esihlahla somganu ukuthi asetshenziselwa ukwenza ipulangwe noma ukhuniolusetshenziswa ukwakha izigubhu, izitulo, izitsha kanye nokunye. Lesi sihlahla siwusizo laphokukhona okhishwa yisisu, onesifo samathambo, olunywe yizinambuzane ezifane nomiyanenezinyosi, kanye nokunye okuningi. Kunoketshezi oluphuma emaqabungeni alesi sihlahla. Loluketshezi lusebenza lapho kukhona oshile noma olunywe yisicabucabu. Yingakho-ke sihlonishwafuthi sivikelwa njengezikhali zamaNtungwa.Iganu, okuyisithelo salesi sihlahla, lisetshenziswa emikhiqizweni eminingi futhi ethandwa kakhulungabantu. Abezempilo bathi iganu linamavithamini aphindwe kasishiyagalombili kunalawoatholakala ewolintshini. Bathi futhi iganu liphinde libe ngesinye sezithelo ezibaluleke kakhuluekuvikeleni izifo ezingosomathuba ezifana nomdlavuza kanye nesifo senhliziyo. Lesi sitheloasigcini nje ngokusiza ngokwezempilo siphinde sisetshenziswe kakhulu emikhiqizweni edliwayonephuzwayo. Abantu abaningi bayasazi futhi basikhonzile isiphuzo esidakanayo esibizwange-Amarula. Lesi sithelo sisetshenziswa nalapho kwenziwa izinto ezifana nojamu kanye nokunyeukudla.Ngaphakathi kwesithelo somganu kunenhlamvu. Le nhlamvu uma uyiqhekeza uthola ikinati elinukakamnandi. Leli kinati lidliwa ngabantu nayizilwane. Amafutha atholakala kuleli kinati asetshenziselwaukupheka, kanye nokwenza imikhiqizo yesikhumba nezinwele. Nawo lawa makinati anomsoco futhiasiza kakhulu ekwakheni izicubu zomzimba.1. Yini okwenza abantu base-Afrika basivikele lesi sihlahla","answer":"• imihlangano ibanjelwa ngaphansi kwaso ngoba sinomthunzi• siyasiza ngokwempilo / sifana nekhemisi "},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. W zdaniu: Moja mama lubi apaszki, słowo \\"moja\\" stanowi jaką część mowy?","answer":"W tym zdaniu \\"moja\\" to przydawka."},{"question":"Perasaan Encik Lee ______ apabila anaknya hanya lulus dua mata pelajaran dalam peperiksaan UPSR.","answer":"Seperti kaca terhempas ke batu"},{"question":"Arọ ","answer":"Olundi - afọ "},{"question":"Ọpẹlọpẹ awọn ṣọja, ọọdunrun ọmọleewe lawọn agbebọn tun fẹẹ ko lọ ni Kaduna","answer":"Ko jọ pe wahala awọn janduku agbebọn to n ji awọn ọmọleewe gbe lagbegbe Oke-Ọya yoo rọlẹ bọrọ tori kaka kewe agbọn dẹ, niṣe lo n le koko si i lọrọ naa da. Awọn agbebọn yii tun ti lọọ ji awọn ọọdunrun o le meje ọmọleewe (307) gbe laaarọ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde yii, ọpẹlọpẹ awọn ṣọja ni o jẹ ki wọn ko wọn wọ’gbo, wọn ri awọn ọmọ naa gba pada.Ileewe ijọba Government Science Secondary School, to wa ni lagbegbe Ikara, nipinlẹ Kaduna, niṣẹlẹ naa ti waye, ibẹ lawọn agbebọn ya bo ni nnkan bii aago marun-un idaji ọjọ Aiku yii, wọn si ti ko awọn akẹkọọ ogo-wẹẹrẹ naa, ṣugbọn wọn lawọn kan lara awọn akẹkọọ naa ti dọgbọn tẹ aago idagiri tijọba ti ṣe sileewe wọn, gbara ti wọn ti ri ohun to n ṣẹlẹ. Aago yii tawọn agbofinro gbọ ni wọn lo jẹ kawọn ọlọpaa atawọn ṣọja sare dihamọra lọ sibi iṣẹlẹ naa, ti wọn si ṣe kongẹ bi awọn ọdaju ẹda yii ṣe fẹẹ ko awọn ọmọ naa lọ, ni wọn ba fija pẹẹta pẹlu wọn.Kọmiṣanna fun eto aabo abẹle ati ọrọ ile nipinlẹ Kaduna, Ọgbẹni Samuel Aruwan, lo sọrọ yii di mimọ lọjọ Aiku, o ni: “A dupẹ pe wọn ṣaṣeyọri o, ọpẹlọpẹ awọn ṣọja ileeṣẹ ologun ilẹ wa ti wọn tete gbe igbesẹ akin gbara ti olobo ti ta wọn lori iṣẹlẹ naa. Aijẹ bẹẹ, ọọdunrun o le meje (307) lawọn ọmọ wa tawọn agbebọn naa ti ji gbe, wọn tun fẹẹ ko wọn wọgbo lọ.“Awọn agbebọn naa ti sa lọ, nigba ti wọn ri awọn agbofinro. Ṣugbọn awọn ọlọpaa atawọn ṣọja ṣi n tọpasẹ wọn lọ lati mu wọn,” gẹgẹ bi Samuel ṣe sọ.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, awọn akẹkọọ bii mẹtadinlogoji ti wọn lawọn agbebọn naa ji gbe wọ’gbo lọ lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, to kọja yii, ṣi wa lakata wọn, wọn o ti i tu wọn silẹ. Ileewe Federal College of Forestry Mechanisation ni wọn ti ji wọn ko.Iya gidi ni wọn si fi n jẹ awọn akẹkọọ yii ninu igbo ti wọn gbe wọn lọ ninu fidio kan to jade nipa wọn. Bẹẹ lawọn ọmọ yii n bẹbẹ pe ki ijọba jọwọ, waa tu awọn silẹ ni igbekun awọn ajinigbe yii. Bọlọ ni awọn to jẹ obinrin ninu awọn akẹkọọ yii n sunkun, aṣọ nikan ni wọn si ro mọya ninu fidio to ṣafihan wọn naa, ọpọ ninu wọn ko wẹwu rara.Wọn lawọn agbebọn naa ni miliọnu lọna ẹẹdẹgbẹta (500m) lawọn maa gba ki wọn too da awọn akẹkọọ naa nide lakata wọn."},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Tanindrazan'ilay jamba , ka _\\"","answer":"\\"Tanindrazan'ilay jamba , ka izay diavin'ny tongotra tanindrazana avokoa\\""},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਗੋਬਿੰਦੁ ਗੁਣੀ ਨਿਧਾਨੁ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਜਾਣੀਐ ॥ਹੋਇ ਕ੍ਰਿਪਾਲੁ ਦਇਆਲੁ ਹਰਿ ਰੰਗੁ ਮਾਣੀਐ ॥੧॥ਆਵਹੁ ਸੰਤ ਮਿਲਾਹ ਹਰਿ ਕਥਾ ਕਹਾਣੀਆ ॥ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਸਿਮਰਹ ਨਾਮੁ ਤਜਿ ਲਾਜ ਲੋਕਾਣੀਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਜਪਿ ਜਪਿ ਜੀਵਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਹੋਵੈ ਅਨਦੁ ਘਣਾ ॥ਮਿਥਿਆ ਮੋਹੁ ਸੰਸਾਰੁ ਝੂਠਾ ਵਿਣਸਣਾ ॥੨॥ਚਰਣ ਕਮਲ ਸੰਗਿ ਨੇਹੁ ਕਿਨੈ ਵਿਰਲੈ ਲਾਇਆ ॥ਧੰਨੁ ਸੁਹਾਵਾ ਮੁਖੁ ਜਿਨਿ ਹਰਿ ਧਿਆਇਆ ॥੩॥ਜਨਮ ਮਰਣ ਦੁਖ ਕਾਲ ਸਿਮਰਤ ਮਿਟਿ ਜਾਵਈ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਕੈ ਸੁਖੁ ਸੋਇ ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਭਾਵਈ ॥੪॥੧੧॥੧੧੩॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 399 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨੋ!) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਸਾਰੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾਈ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈਜੇ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਇਆਵਾਨ ਹੋਵੇ ਤ੍ਰੁੱਠ ਪਏ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ (-ਆਨੰਦ) ਮਾਣਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਹੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨੋ! ਆਓ, ਅਸੀਂ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਬੈਠੀਏ ਤੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਕਰੀਏ, ਲੋਕ-ਲਾਜ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦੇ ਰਹੀਏ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨੋ!) ਮੈਂ ਤਾਂ ਜਿਉਂ ਜਿਉਂ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ) ਨਾਮ ਜਪਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੰੁਦਾ ਹੈ ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਬੜਾ ਆਨੰਦ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਵੇਲੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਤੱਖ ਅਨੁਭਵ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਸੰਸਾਰ (ਦਾ ਮੋਹ) ਵਿਅਰਥ ਮੋਹ ਹੈ, ਸੰਸਾਰ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਹੀਂ, ਸੰਸਾਰ ਤਾਂ ਨਾਸ ਹੋ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ (ਇਸ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਸੁਖ-ਆਨੰਦ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਮਿਲੇ?) ।੨।(ਪਰ, ਹੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨੋ!) ਕਿਸੇ ਵਿਰਲੇ (ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲੇ) ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਕੋਮਲ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਪਾਇਆ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੇ (ਇਹ ਪਿਆਰ ਪਾਇਆ ਹੈ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮੂੰਹ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮੂੰਹ ਸੋਹਣਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨੋ!) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆਂ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ (ਦੇ ਗੇੜ) ਦਾ ਦੁੱਖ ਮਿਟ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਹੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨੋ!) ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਚੰਗਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ (ਉਹੀ ਚੰਗਾ ਹੈ ਇਹ ਨਿਸ਼ਚਾ ਜੋ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ) ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਆਨੰਦ (ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰੀ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ) ।੪।੧੧।੧੧੩।\\""},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Aza mitaitay toy ny fitia  .................................... \\"  ","answer":"\\"  Aza mitaitay toy ny fitia tsy ho ela. \\"  "},{"question":"கேள்வி: காமராசர் பற்றி எழுதுக.","answer":"பதில்:காமராசர் தொடக்கக்கால வாழ்க்கை:காமராசர் விருதுநகரில் 1903 ஆம் ஆண்டு சூலை 15ஆம் தேதி பிறந்தார். இவர்தம் பெற்றோர் குமாரசாமி நாடார் மற்றும் சிவகாமி அம்மாள் ஆவர். முதலில் இவருக்குக் குலத் தெய்வமான காமாட்சியின் பெயரையே முதலில் சூட்டினார்கள். தாயார் சிவகாமி அம்மாள் மட்டும், அவரை \\"ராசா\\" என்றே அழைத்து வந்தார். நாளடைவில் காமாட்சி என்ற பெயர் மாறி, ‘காமராசு’ என்று ஆனது. தனது பள்ளிப் படிப்பைச் சத்ரிய வித்யா சாலா பள்ளியில் தொடங்கினார். படிக்கும் போதே மிகவும் பொறுமையுடனும் விட்டுக் கொடுக்கும் மனத்துடனும் விளங்கினார். சிவகாமி அம்மாளுக்கு இரண்டு சகோதரர்கள். ஒருவர் கருப்பையா நாடார். இவர் துணிக்கடை வைத்திருந்தார். மற்றொருவர் பெயர் காசிநாராயண நாடார். இவர் திருவனந்தபுரத்திலே மரக்கடை வைத்து நடத்தி வந்தார்.சிறை வாழ்க்கையும் படிப்பும்பள்ளிப்படிப்பைத் தொடரமுடியாத நிலை ஏற்பட்டதும் காமராசர் தன் மாமாவின் துணிக்கடையில் வேலையில் அமர்ந்தார். அங்கிருக்கும்போது பெ. வரதராசுலு நாயுடு போன்ற தேசத் தலைவர்களின் பேச்சுகளில் கவரப்பட்டு அரசியலிலும் சுதந்திரப் போராட்டங்களிலும் ஆர்வம் காட்டினார். தன்னுடைய 16ஆம் வயதில் காங்கிரசின் உறுப்பினராக ஆனார்.ராசாசியின் தலைமையில் 1930 மார்ச்சு மாதம், வேதாரண்யத்தில் உப்பு சத்தியாக்கிரகம் நடைபெற்றபோது அதில் கலந்து கொண்டார். அதற்காகக் காமராசர் கைது செய்யப்பட்டு கல்கத்தா அலிப்பூர் சிறைக்கு அனுப்பப்பட்டார். அடுத்த ஆண்டு காந்தி - இர்வின் ஒப்பந்தத்தின் அடிப்படையில் விடுதலை ஆனார். விருதுநகர் வெடிகுண்டு வழக்கில் கைதாகி, சேலம் டாக்டர் பெ. வரதராசுலு நாயுடுவின் வழக்காடும் திறமையால் குற்றச்சாட்டு நிறுவப்படாததால் விடுதலை ஆனார். 1940 இல் மீண்டும் கைதாகி வேலூர் சிறையில் அடைக்கப்பட்டார். அங்கிருக்கும் போதே விருதுநகர் நகராட்சித் தலைவராகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார். ஒன்பது மாதங்களுக்குப் பின் விடுதலை ஆனதும் நேராகச் சென்று தன் பதவி விலகினார். பதவிக்கு நேர்மையாக முழுமையாகக் கடமையாற்ற முடியாத நிலையில் அதில் ஒட்டிக் கொண்டிருப்பது தவறு என்பது அவருடைய கொள்கையாக இருந்தது. மீண்டும் 1942-இல் ஆகத்து புரட்சி நடவடிக்கைகளுக்காகக் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார். இந்த முறை மூன்று ஆண்டுகள் தண்டனையாகப் பெற்றார்.1933 ஜூன் 23-ம் தேதி விருது நகர் நகராட்சித் தேர்தலில் போட்டி யிட்ட காமராஜர், நீதிக்கட்சியின் செல்வாக்கு மிகுந்தவர்களால் கடத்தப்பட்டார். முத்துராமலிங்கத் தேவர் அவர்களால் மீட்கப்பட்டார். விருதுநகர் நகராட்சிக்கு தேர்தல் வந்தது. வரி செலுத்துவோர் மட்டுமே தேர்தலில் நிற்க முடியும் என்ற விதி இருந்தது. ஓர் ஆட்டுக் குட்டியை விலைக்கு வாங்கிய தேவர், காமராஜர் பெயரில் வரி கட்டி ரசீதைப் பெற்றார். காமராஜரை தேர்தலில் நிறுத்தி வெற்றிபெறச் செய்தார். அவரை நகரசபைத் தலைவராக்கி பெருமை சேர்த்தார். அரசியல் குருகாமராசர், சிறந்த பேச்சாளரும் நாடாளுமன்றவாதியும் ஆன சத்தியமூர்த்தியைத் தன் அரசியல் குருவாக ஏற்றுக் கொண்டிருந்தார். 1936-இல் சத்தியமூர்த்தி பிரதேச காங்கிரசின் தலைவரானபோது காமராசரைச் செயலாளராக ஆக்கினார். இருவரின் முயற்சியில் காங்கிரசு கட்சி நல்ல வளர்ச்சி கண்டு தேர்தல்களில் பெருவெற்றி பெற்றது. இந்தியா சுதந்திரம் அடைந்த செய்தி கேட்டு காமராசர் முதலில் சத்தியமூர்த்தியின் வீட்டுக்குச் சென்று அங்குதான் தேசியக் கொடியை ஏற்றினார். காமராசரை அனைவரும் கிங் மேக்கர் என்று அழைக்கின்றனர். அரசியல் தந்திரங்களை நன்கு அறிந்தவர். இவரை இந்திய அரசியலின் குரு என்றும் அழைக்கின்றனர்.தமிழக ஆட்சிப் பொறுப்பு1953-இக்குப் பிறகு சக்ரவர்த்தி ராசாசிக்கு அவர் கொண்டு வந்த குலக்கல்வித் திட்டத்தால் அதிக அளவில் எதிர்ப்புகள் கிளம்பி இருந்த நேரம். காமராசர் ஆட்சித் தலைமைப் பொறுப்புக்கு வரத் தயங்கியதற்கு அவருக்கிருந்த மொழிவளம் குறித்த தாழ்வுணர்ச்சி ஒரு முக்கிய காரணம். (அப்போது தமிழகம் சென்னை ராச்சியமாக ஆந்திராவின் பெரும்பகுதி, கர்நாடகாவின் சில பகுதிகள் ஆகியவற்றைத் தன்னகத்தே கொண்டிருந்தது)குலக்கல்வித் திட்டத்தால் ராசாசியின் செல்வாக்கு வேகமாகக் கீழிறங்கிக் கொண்டிருக்க, மொழிவாரி மாநிலங்கள் அமைப்பின் காரணமாக (அக்டோபர் 1, 1953-இல் ஆந்திரா பிறந்து விட்டது) தமிழ்நாடும் சுருங்கிப் போக, காங்கிரசின் உள்ளேயே ராசாசிக்குப் பெரும் எதிர்ப்பு கிளம்பி விட்டது. நிலைமை அறிந்த கட்சி மேலிடம், தமிழக அளவில் தீர்மானித்துக் கொள்ள அனுமதி வழங்கி விட்டது. ராசாசி தான் அவமானப்படுவதைத் தவிர்க்க, ‘எனக்கு எதிராகக் கட்சியில் யாரும் தீர்மானம் கொண்டு வர வேண்டாம். நானே விலகிக் கொள்கிறேன்’ என்று அறிவித்து விட்டாலும் தன் இடத்திற்குத் தன்னுடைய முக்கிய ஆதரவாளரான சி.சுப்பிரமணியத்தை முன்னிறுத்த பின் வேலை செய்தார். அவருடைய இன்னொரு முக்கிய ஆதரவாளரான எம். பக்தவத்சலம் அதனை முன்மொழிந்தார்.ஆனால் கட்சி சட்டமன்ற உறுப்பினர்களின் கூட்டத்தில் காமராசர் பெருவாரியான வாக்குகள் முன்னணியில் வெற்றி பெற்றார். இதுதான், காமராசர் தமிழக முதல்வராக 1953 தமிழ்ப்புத்தாண்டு அன்று பதவியேற்றதன் பின்னணியாகும்.அமைச்சரவைகாமராசர் அமைச்சரவை அமைத்த விதத்தில் சில நுட்பமான விஷயங்கள் இருந்தன:மிகக் குறைந்த எண்ணிக்கையிலேயே (8 பேர்) அமைச்சர்கள் இருந்தனர்.தன்னை எதிர்த்துப் போட்டியிட்ட சி.சுப்பிரமணியம், அவரை முன்மொழிந்த எம். பக்தவத்சலம் இருவரையுமே அமைச்சரவையில் சேர்த்திருந்தார்.அவருடைய அமைச்சரவையில் இடம் பெற்றிருந்த இன்னும் முக்கிய இருவர், ராமசாமி படையாச்சி, மாணிக்கவேலு நாயக்கர் ஆகியோர். இவர்கள் இருவரும் காங்கிரசை எதிர்த்துப் போட்டியிட்டு தி.மு.க ஆதரவோடு வென்றவர்கள். (1952 தேர்தலில் தி.மு.க. போட்டியிடவில்லை என்றாலும் அது சில வேட்பாளர்களை வெளிப்படையாக ஆதரித்தது. \\"தி.மு.க.வின் திராவிட நாடு கொள்கையை ஆதரிக்கிறேன்; சட்டமன்றத்தில் திமுக-வின் கொள்கைகளை எதிரொலிப்பேன்; தி.மு.க வெளியிடும் திட்டங்களுக்கு ஆதரவு பெருக்கும் வகையில் சட்ட மன்றத்தில் பணியாற்றுவேன்\\" என்கிற நிபந்தனைகளுக்கு எழுத்துபூர்வமாகக் கையெழுத்திட்டுத் தருபவர்களுக்கு ஆதரவு அளித்தது திமுக. அப்படிக் கையெழுத்துப் போட்டுக் கொடுத்துக் காங்கிரசை எதிர்த்து வெற்றி பெற்று அமைச்சர் ஆனவர்கள் இந்த இருவரும்அமைச்சரவையின் இன்னொரு குறிப்பிடத்தக்க அம்சம், பி. பரமேசுவரன் என்கிற அமைச்சர். அவருக்குத் தரப்பட்டிருந்த பொறுப்பு, தாழ்த்தப்பட்டோர் நலம் மற்றும் அறநிலையத் துறை.முதலமைச்சராக ஆற்றிய பணிகள்ராசாசி கொண்டு வந்திருந்த குலக்கல்வித் திட்டத்தினைக் கைவிட்டார். அவரது ஆட்சிக் காலத்தில் தமிழகத்தில் பள்ளிகளின் எண்ணிக்கை 27,000 ஆனது. 1920 இல் நீதிக்கட்சி அரசு ஆதரவுடன் சென்னை மாநகராட்சியில் மதிய உணவுத் திட்டம் கொண்டுவரப்பட்டது. முதலில் ஆயிரம் விளக்குப் பகுதியில் இருந்த ஒரு மாநகராட்சிப் பள்ளியில் காலை உணவுத் திட்டமாக அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டது. பின் மேலும் நான்கு பள்ளிகளுக்கு விரிவுபடுத்தப்பட்டது. இத்திட்டமே 1960 களில் காமராசரால் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டு எம். ஜி. ராமச்சந்திரனால் 1980 களில் விரிவுபடுத்தப்பட்ட சத்துணவுத் திட்டத்தின் முன்னோடியாகும். அவரது மதிய உணவுத் திட்டம் இன்று உலக அளவில் பாராட்டப்படும் திட்டமாகும். அதன் பலனாகப் பள்ளிகளில் படிப்போரின் எண்ணிக்கை 37 விழுக்காடாக உயர்ந்தது. (பிரித்தானியர் காலத்தில் இது 7 விழுக்காடாக இருந்தது). பள்ளிகளில் வேலைநாட்கள் 180 இல் இருந்து 200 ஆக உயர்த்தப்பட்டது. சென்னை இந்தியத் தொழில்நுட்ப நிறுவனம் தொடங்கப்பட்டது.காமராசர் முதலமைச்சராகப் பதவி வகித்த காலங்களில் நாட்டு முன்னேற்றம், நாட்டு மக்களின் வாழ்க்கை முன்னேற்றம், கல்வி, தொழில் வளத்துக்கு முன்னுரிமையளித்து பல திட்டங்களை நிறைவேற்றினார். அவரது ஆட்சியின் கீழ் 10 முக்கிய நீர்பாசனத்திட்டங்கள் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டன. அவை பவானித்திட்டம், மேட்டூர் கால்வாய்த்திட்டம், காவேரி டெல்டா வடிகால் அபிவிருத்தி திட்டம், மணிமுத்தாறு, அமராவதி, வைகை, பரம்பிக்குளம் ஆழியாறு பாசன திட்டம், சாத்தனூர், கிருசுணகிரி, ஆரணியாறு ஆகியவையாகும். கன்னியாகுமரி மாவட்டத்தில் மலை கிராமங்களுக்குக் குடிநீர் பிரச்சனையை தீர்ப்பதற்காகக் காமராசரால் கட்டப்பட்ட மாத்தூர் தொட்டிப் பாலம் ஆசியாவின் மிகப்பெரிய தொட்டிப்பாலமாக இன்றளவும் உள்ளது.அவர் காலத்தில் தமிழகத்தில் தொடங்கப்பட்ட முக்கிய பொதுத் துறை நிறுவனங்களும் பெருந்தொழிற்சாலைகளும்:பாரத மிகு மின் நிறுவனம்நெய்வேலி பழுப்பு நிலக்கரி நிறுவனம்மணலி சென்னை சுத்திகரிப்பு நிலையம் இரயில்பெட்டி இணைப்புத் தொழிற்சாலை நீலகிரி புகைப்படச் சுருள் தொழிற்சாலைகிண்டி மருத்துவ சோதனைக் கருவிகள் தொழிற்சாலை,மேட்டூர் காகிதத் தொழிற்சாலைகுந்தா மின் திட்டமும், நெய்வேலி மற்றும் ஊட்டி ஆகிய இடங்களின் வெப்ப மின் திட்டங்களும் காமராசரால் ஏற்படுத்தப்பட்டவை.காமராசர் முதல் அமைச்சரான முதல் ஆண்டிலேயே அனைத்துத் தொடக்கப்பள்ளி ஆசிரியர்களுக்கும் ஓய்வு ஊதியம் வழங்க ஆணையிட்டார். பின்னர் உயர்நிலைப் பள்ளி ஆசிரியர்களுக்கும் அதன்பின்னர் தனியார் கல்லூரி ஆசிரியர்களுக்கும் ஓய்வு ஊதியம் வழங்கும்படி ஓய்வு ஊதியத் திட்டத்தை நீட்டித்தார். 1967 ஆம் ஆண்டுத் தேர்தல் தோல்வி1967 ஆம் ஆண்டு நடைபெற்ற தமிழக சட்டமன்றப் பொதுத் தேர்தலில் தமது சொந்த ஊரான விருதுநகர் தொகுதியில் பெ. சீனிவாசன் என்பவரால் 1,285 வாக்குகள் வேறுபாட்டில் தோற்கடிக்கப்பட்டார். நாகர்கோயில் மக்களவைத் தொகுதியில் 1969 இல் நடைபெற்ற இடைத்தேர்தலில் வெற்றி பெற்றார்.அகில இந்திய காங்கிரசு தலைமைதிருமங்கலம் பி.கே.என். ஆண்கள் மேல்நிலைப் பள்ளியில் அமைந்துள்ள காமராசரின் சிலைமூன்று முறை (1954–57, 1957–62, 1962–63) முதலமைச்சராகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டிருந்த காமராசர், பதவியைவிடத் தேசப்பணியும் கட்சிப்பணியுமே முக்கியம் என்பதை மக்களுக்கும் குறிப்பாகக் கட்சித் தொண்டர்களுக்கும் காட்ட விரும்பிக் கொண்டு வந்த திட்டம் தான்காமராசர் திட்டம்'  எனப்படும் '.அதன்படி கட்சியின் மூத்த தலைவர்கள் பதவிகளை இளையவர்களிடம் ஒப்படைத்து விட்டுக் கட்சிப்பணியாற்றச் செல்ல வேண்டும் என்று இவர் நேருவிடம் சொன்னதை அப்படியே ஏற்றுக் கொண்டார் நேரு. இந்தத் திட்டத்தை முன்மொழிந்த கையோடு தன் முதலமைச்சர் பதவியைப் பதவி விலகல் செய்து (2. அக்டோபர் 1963) பொறுப்பினை பக்தவத்சலத்திடம் ஒப்படைத்து விட்டு டெல்லி சென்றார் காமராசர். அக்டோபர் 9 அன்று அகில இந்தியக் காங்கிரசின் தலைவர் ஆனார். லால் பகதூர் சாசுதிரி, மொரார்சி தேசாய், எசு. கே. பாட்டீல், செகசீவன்ராம் போன்றோர் அவ்வாறு பதவி துறந்தவர்களில் முக்கியமானவர்கள்.அகில இந்திய அளவில் காமராசரின் செல்வாக்கு கட்சியினரின் மரியாதைக்குரியதாக இருந்தது. அதனாலேயே 1964 இல் சவகர்லால் நேரு இறந்தவுடன் இந்தியாவின் தலைமை அமைச்சராக லால் பகதூர் சாசுதிரியை முன்மொழிந்து காமராசர் சொன்ன கருத்தினை அனைவரும் ஏற்றனர். 1966-இல் லால் பகதூர் சாசுதிரியின் திடீர் மரணத்தின்போது ஏற்பட்ட அசாதாரண அரசியல் சூழ்நிலையின்போது இந்திரா காந்தியை தலைமை அமைச்சராக வரச் செய்ததில் காமராசருக்குக் கணிசமான பங்கு இருந்தது.இறுதிக் காலம்காமராசருக்கு இந்திராகாந்தியுடன் ஏற்பட்ட பிணக்கின் காரணமாகக் காங்கிரசு கட்சி இரண்டாக உடையும் நிலை ஏற்பட்டது. காமராசரின் தலைமையிலான சிண்டிகேட் காங்கிரசு தமிழக அளவில் செல்வாக்குடன் திகழ்ந்தது. ஆனாலும் திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழகத்தின் மாபெரும் வளர்ச்சியால் அதன் பலம் குன்றிப் போகக் காமராசர் தன்னுடைய அரசியல் பயணத்தைத் தமிழக அளவில் சுருக்கிக் கொண்டார். தமிழக ஆட்சியாளர்களின் தவறுகளைச் சுட்டிக் காட்டி வந்தார். இந்திரா காந்தி நெருக்கடி நிலையினை அமல் செய்தபோது அதனைக் கடுமையாக எதிர்த்தவர்களில் காமராசரும் ஒருவர். இந்தியாவின் அரசியல் போக்குகுறித்து மிகுந்த குறையும் கவலையும் கொண்டிருந்த நிலையில் காமராசர் இருந்தார், இந்தியாவின் விடுதலைக்குப் பாடுபட்ட ஜெயப்பிரகாஷ் நாராயணன், மொரார்ஜி தேசாய் மற்றும் பல தலைவர்கள் இக்காலகட்டத்தில் இந்திரா காந்தி அரசால் கைது செய்யப்பட்டிருந்தனர். அக்டோபர் இரண்டு காந்தியடிகள் பிறந்த நாளன்று அவர்கள் விடுதலை செய்யப்படுவார்கள் என்று எதிர்பார்த்திருந்தார் காமராசர். ஆனால், அன்று ஆச்சார்ய கிருபளானியும் கைது செய்யப்பட்டார் என்ற செய்தியைக் கேட்ட அன்றே உயிர் துறந்தார். 1975 அக்டோபர் திங்கள் இரண்டாம் நாள் (காந்தியின் பிறந்தநாள்) மதிய உறக்கத்திற்குப் பின்னர் அவரின் உயிர் பிரிந்தது[8]. அவர் இறந்தபோது பையில் இருந்த சிறிதளவு பணத்தைத் தவிர வேறு வங்கிக் கணக்கோ, சொந்த வீடோ, வேறு எந்த வித சொத்தோ இல்லை. தன் வாழ்நாள் இறுதி வரை வாடகை வீட்டிலேயே வசித்தார்.நினைவுச் சின்னங்கள்காமராசர் நினைவிடம், கிண்டிதமிழ்நாடு அரசு, காமராசர் நினைவைப் போற்றும் வகையில் சென்னை கிண்டியில் நினைவிடம் ஒன்றை அமைத்துள்ளது. இங்குக் காமராசரின் மார்பளவு சிலை அமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. கன்னியாகுமரியில் காமராசர் மணிமண்டபம் ஒன்றையும் அமைத்துள்ளது. இங்குக் காமராசரின் மார்பளவு சிலையும் நூலகமும் அமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. அவரின் வாழ்க்கை வரலாறு தொடர்பான புகைப்படங்கள் பொதுமக்கள் பார்வைக்குக் கண்காட்சியாக வைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. "},{"question":"ناوی چەند شاعیرێکی گەورەی کورد بنووسە. ","answer":"نالی ،مەحوی، ناری، ئەحمەد موختار جاف، گۆران، بابە تاهیری هەمەدانی "},{"question":"Kedụ ebe mbụ a chọpụtara mmanụ crude n’ala Naijiria?","answer":"Ọ bụ na Oloibiri"},{"question":"Ovatko tutkijat ilmastonmuutoksesta eri mieltä?","answer":"Tiedeyhteisö on jo pidempään ollut hyvin yksimielinen siitä, että ilmastonmuutos on tosiasia.Ilmastonmuutosta tutkitaan hyvin monilla eri tieteenaloilla, eri aikaskaaloissa ja erilaisin menetelmin. Osa näkemyseroista saattaa johtua siitä, että tilastollinen lähestymistapa ja fysikaalisiin ilmiöihin perustuva mallittaminen eivät kohtaa toisiaan. Ilmastonmuutoksen riski näyttäytyy myös erilaisena, jos tarkastellaan vuosimiljoonia, jolloin ihmistä ei vielä ollut tai jos tarkastellaan riskiä nyky-yhteiskunnalle."},{"question":"Which tree is traditionally associated with cemeteries?","answer":"Yew trees. Jennifer Chandler suggests that yew trees were planted in graveyards because they thrived on corpses and Robert Turner, writing in 1644, suggested that yew trees absorbed the vapours produced by putrefaction."},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 滋賀県大津市で3日、新しい年になって初めて弓道をする会がありました。子どもから80歳ぐらいまでの52人が参加しました。会ではまず、代表の人が28m前にある的に向かって、今年初めての矢をうつ式をしました。そのあと、参加した人たちが並んで、弓道が上手になるように祈りながら、2本ずつ矢をうちました。正月のこの日は、ピンクや薄い青のきれいな色の着物で参加する女性もいました。20歳の大学生は「勉強も弓道もしっかり頑張って、いい1年にしたいです」と話しました。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。"},{"question":"Малың тоонун чымчыгы, үйүң талдын чырпыгы.- дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Малыңа мактанба, себеби малды берген Кудай, алып коюшу дагы тез. Үйдү берген Кудай, бир селде алып коюшу же бир кырсыкты алып коюшу мүмкүн."},{"question":" Dhig Sumadda haladkore? ","answer":" Sumadda haladkore (') "},{"question":"بیلنس ادائیگیوں کے فوائد اور نقصانات ایکسچینج ریٹ کے تعین کا نظریہ ","answer":"(I) خوبیاں:میں. یہ غیر ملکی کرنسی مارکیٹ میں کسی کرنسی کی طلب اور رسد کے نظام الاوقات کے تعین کی وضاحت فراہم کرتا ہے۔ اس وجہ سے، یہ ان نظریات سے بہتر ہے جو اس وضاحت کو نظر انداز کرتے ہیں.ii نظریہ \\"اس لحاظ سے زیادہ حقیقت پسندانہ ہے کہ غیر ملکی کرنسی کی مقامی قیمت کو بہت سے اہم متغیرات کے کام کے طور پر دیکھا جاتا ہے، نہ صرف اس کی قوت خرید کو عام قیمت کی سطحوں کا اظہار کرنے کے لیے۔\\"iii نظریہ کو اس حقیقت کو شامل کرنے کے لیے بڑھایا جا سکتا ہے کہ کسی ملک کی ادائیگیوں کا توازن کئی عوامل سے متاثر ہوتا ہے، اور اسے مختلف پالیسی اقدامات کے ذریعے بھی ایڈجسٹ کیا جا سکتا ہے۔iv نظریہ یکطرفہ سرمائے کی نقل و حرکت کو ان کی نوعیت، مدت اور وسعت سے قطع نظر ایڈجسٹ کرنے کے قابل ہے۔اس طرح، یہ واضح طور پر اس حقیقت کو تسلیم کرتا ہے کہ شرح تبادلہ متنوع دباؤ کے تابع ہے، بشمول مثال کے طور پر، جنگ کی تلافی، بقایا غیر ملکی قرضوں کی ادائیگی، سرمائے کی قیاس آرائی پر مبنی پروازیں وغیرہ۔(II) نقصانات:میں. یہ نظریہ بذات خود، قوتوں کے پورے شعبے کی وضاحت نہیں کرتا ہے جو ممالک میں ادائیگیوں کے بہاؤ کا تعین کرتے ہیں اور اس طرح، شرح مبادلہ کو متاثر کرتے ہیں۔ii ایسا لگتا ہے کہ یہ موقف اختیار کرتا ہے کہ ادائیگیوں کے توازن اور شرح مبادلہ کے درمیان یک طرفہ وجہ اثر تعلق ہے۔یہ کہتا ہے کہ کسی ملک کی ادائیگی کے توازن کی پوزیشن زر مبادلہ کی توازن کی شرح کے نفیس تصور کی وضاحت کرتی ہے۔یہ اس حقیقت کو نظر انداز کرتا ہے کہ شرح مبادلہ اور ادائیگیوں کا توازن ایک دوسرے پر منحصر ہے اور یہ کہ ان کا اثر و رسوخ کا تعلق شرح مبادلہ کے تغیرات سے لے کر ادائیگیوں کے توازن تک بھی ہو سکتا ہے۔ایک رائے کے مطابق، \\"کسی ملک کے بیرونی لین دین میں توازن یا عدم توازن، یک طرفہ طور پر شرح مبادلہ کا تعین کرنے سے کہیں زیادہ، شرح مبادلہ اور متعلقہ قیمت کی سطح کے درمیان تعلق کا نتیجہ ہے۔\\"iii شرح مبادلہ کے تعین کے نظریہ کے طور پر، یہ ترجیحی بنیادوں پر زر مبادلہ کی توازن کی شرح پر کام کرنے میں ہماری مدد نہیں کرتا ہے۔دوسری طرف، کسی ملک کو ادائیگیوں کے توازن میں عارضی اور چکراتی اتار چڑھاؤ کا سامنا کرنا پڑ سکتا ہے جو کہ شرح مبادلہ میں تبدیلی کے بجائے اس کے سونے اور زرمبادلہ کے ذخائر میں تبدیلی کے ذریعے جذب کیا جا سکتا ہے۔\\"یہ نظریہ مبہم طور پر زر مبادلہ کے توازن کی شرح کو مبہم طور پر بیان کرتا ہے جسے اگر کم از کم کئی سالوں کے لیے مقرر کیا جائے\\"، تو کسی ملک کے توازن میں دائمی سرپلس یا خسارے کا سبب نہیں بنے گا۔\\"لیکن یہ ہمیں یہ نہیں بتاتا کہ ریٹ کا اندازہ کیسے لگایا جائے، اور نہ ہی اس کا تعین کرنے والے عمومی اصولوں کو بھی بیان کیا جائے۔\\""},{"question":"Calculate the area of a kite with diagonals of length 10 meters and 16 meters, using the formula A = (1/2) * d₁ * d₂, where 'd₁' and 'd₂' are the lengths of the diagonals.","answer":"The area of the kite is A = (1/2) * 10 meters * 16 meters = 80 square meters."},{"question":"பள்ளித் திடலில் கிடந்த பணப்பையை உரியவரிடம் ஒப்படைத்ததையும், அதற்குப் பாராட்டுப் பெற்றதையும் பற்றி வெளியூரில் இருக்கும் உறவினர் ஒருவருக்குக் கடிதம் எழுதுக.","answer":"திருச்சி,18.03.2020அன்புள்ள சித்தப்பாவிற்கு இரகு எழுதுவது,நலம். நலம் அறிய ஆவல்.நான் இன்று மிக்க மகிழ்ச்சியில் இருக்கிறேன். ஏன் தெரியுமா? நேற்று வகுப்பு முடிந்து வெளியே வந்து கொண்டிருந்தேன். அப்போது பள்ளித்திடலில் ஒரு பணப்பை கிடந்தது. அதில் அதிகமான பணம் இருந்தது. ஒரு நிமிடம் பயம்! ஐயோ! இவ்வளவு பணம் இருக்கிறதே. பையை எடுத்துக் கொண்டு தலைமை ஆசிரியரிடம் சென்றேன். அவர் அலுவலக ஊழியர் கட்டணம் வசூலித்த பணம் இருசக்கர வாகனத்தில் எடுத்துச் செல்லும்போது தவற விட்டுவிட்டார் என்றார்.தலைமை ஆசிரியர் மிகவும் மகிழ்ந்தார். என் நேர்மையையும், கண்ணியமான செயலையும் பாராட்டினார்.‘பிறர் பொருளுக்கு ஆசைப்படாத உன்னைப் பாராட்டியே தீர வேண்டும் என்று, மறுநாளே காலை இறைவணக்கக் கூட்டத்தில் மாணவர்கள் மத்தியில் என் நேர்மையைப் பாராட்டி, சன்மானத் தொகையைப் பரிசாகவும் வழங்கினார்.அது மட்டுமில்லாமல் என்னைப் பள்ளி மாணவர் தலைவராக்கினார். நேர்மைக்கு எப்போதும் உயர்வு உண்டு என்று கூறி, அதற்கு இரகுவே’ சான்று என்று என்னைப் பாராட்டினார்.இந்நிகழ்வின் மகிழ்ச்சியை உங்களுடனும், சித்தி, தங்கையுடனும் இக்கடிதம் மூலம் பகிர்ந்து கொள்வதற்கு மகிழ்கிறேன்.இப்படிக்கு,தங்கள் அன்புள்ள,இரகு."},{"question":"Koks sausumos gyvūnas yra didžiausias gyvas gyvūnas žemėje?","answer":"Afrikinis savaninis dramblys – straublinių būrio, dramblinių šeimos, afrikinių dramblių genties labai stambi žinduolių rūšis, paplitusi Afrikos savanose. Jis užauga iki 4 m aukščio ir sveria iki 7,5 t. Turi didžiules ausis ir durklus, kurie patinams užauga iki 3,5 m."},{"question":"Awọn ajinigbe ji ondupo alaga kansu gbe ni Ilọrin, miliọnu marun-un ni wọn n beere","answer":"Awọn ajinigbe ji Iyemọja gbe ni Ilọrin, wọn n beere fun miliọnu marun-un owo itusilẹHon. Ọlamilekan Yusuf ti ọpọ eeyan mọ si Iyemọja lawon ajinigbe ti gbe lọ nile rẹ to wa ni Mandi, lagbegbe Okoolowo, niluu Ilọrin, nipinlẹ Kwara.ALAROYE gbọ lẹnu iyawo arakunrin ọhun, Arabinrin Nafisat, ni ni nnkan bii aago mẹsan-an aabọ alẹ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii, ti ọkọ oun n wọle bọ lati igboro, bo ṣe si geeti tan, njẹ ko gbe ọkọ wọle ni awọn ajinigbe naa ṣe akọlu si i. Iyaale ile yii ni wọn lu ọkọ oun lalubami, wọn si n rọjo ibọn ki wọn too ri ọkọ ohun gbe lọ.Ni bayii, awọn ajinigbe naa to n sọ ede Hausa ti n beere fun miliọnu marun-un naira, owo itusilẹ.Obinrin naa ni Nafisat awọn ti fi ọrọ naa to awọn ọlọpaa leti, wọn si ṣeleri pe awọn yoo gbiyanju agbara awọn lati doola ẹmi arakunrin ọhun"},{"question":"Completa la siguiente frase :  Ganó una medalla de oro en el.... ","answer":"Campeonato Mundial de Ciclismo en Pista de 2015 y cinco medallas en el Campeonato Europeo de Ciclismo en Pista entre los años 2014 y 2012."},{"question":"కింది పరిచిత గద్యాలను చదివి, ఇచ్చిన ప్రశ్నలకు సమాధానాలు రాయండి.గుశ్వం నాటిక హాస్యంతో కూడినది. ఎందుకంటే శిష్యులు పదాలు సరిగా పలకలేక పోవడం గుఱ్ఱం బదులు : | గుల్లం అనడం నవ్వు తెప్పిస్తుంది. గుర్రంలో ‘గు’, అశ్వంలో ‘శ్వం’ కలిపి ‘గుశ్వం’ అనే పదం వారు తయారు చెయ్యడం హాస్యానికి కారణం. గుర్రానికి గుడ్డు ఉండదని కూడా తెలియని వాళ్ళ అమాయకత్వం, ఆ అయోమయాన్ని గురువు గారికి కూడా తగిలించి వాళ్ళు గుర్రం గుడ్డు తెస్తామనగానే ఆయన తలూపి పది వరహాలివ్వడం నవ్వు పుట్టిస్తుంది. బూడిద గుమ్మడికాయను గుడ్డు అని చెప్పగానే నమ్మేయడం గుమ్మడికాయ పగిలిపోతే ఆ శబ్దానికి బెదిరి కుందేలు పరుగెత్తడం చూసి ఆ కాయలోంచే కుందేలు వచ్చి ఉంటుందని వారు భావించి దానివెంట పరుగెత్తడం మరీ విడ్డూరం. ఇలా ఈ కథలో ప్రతి సన్నివేశమూ నవ్వు పుట్టిస్తుంది ఈ నాటికలో. –ప్రశ్నలు :1. శిష్యుల అమాయకత్వం ఎలాంటిది?2. పరమానందయ్య శిష్యులు ఎలాంటివారు?3. ‘గుశ్వం’ నాటిక దేనితో కూడినది ?4. శిష్యులు దేనిని గుర్రం గుడ్డుగా భావించారు?","answer":"1. శిష్యుల అమాయకత్వం ఎలాంటిది?జవాబు:గుర్రానికి గుడ్డు ఉండదని తెలియకపోవడం శిష్యుల అమాయకత్వం.2. పరమానందయ్య శిష్యులు ఎలాంటివారు?జవాబు:పరమానందయ్య శిష్యులు అమాయకులు.3. ‘గుశ్వం’ నాటిక దేనితో కూడినది ?జవాబు:‘గుశ్వం’ అనే నాటిక హాస్యంతో కూడినది.4. శిష్యులు దేనిని గుర్రం గుడ్డుగా భావించారు?జవాబు:శిష్యులు బూడిద గుమ్మడికాయను గుర్రం గుడ్డుగా భావించారు."},{"question":"Буддизмдин эң байыркы жана бүгүнкү күнгө чейин сакталып келген мектебинин мүчөлөрү кимдер?","answer":"Виная - бул молдолор менен кечилдердин адеп-ахлактык нормалары. Ал Патимокханы, Тхеравадинин рецензиясындагы кечилдер үчүн 227 эрежелердин топтомун камтыйт. Винаяпитаканын (Винаядагы ыйык жазмалардын) так мазмуну ар кандай мектептерге жараша бир аз айырмаланат, ал эми ар кандай мектептер же субмектептер Винаяга кармануунун деңгээли боюнча ар кандай стандарттарды белгилешет. Монахтардын негизги осуяттары болгон он осуятты монахтар өздөрү колдонушат."},{"question":"Quem foi o vencedor do Big Brother Brasil 20?","answer":"A médica Thelma Assis."},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Magaca Wadankii Ugu Danbeeyey Ee Xurnimo Qaata Qaarada Asia?","answer":"Jawab Waa Wadanka Loo-Yaqaano East Timor, Wuxuuna Ka Go’ay Wadanka Indonesia."},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Coreia do Norte?","answer":"Pionguiangue."},{"question":"س278- أين تقع مدينة سوسة ؟","answer":"ج278- تقع في ليبيا وفي تونس"},{"question":"Khwenya and khwenyela.","answer":"Draw up the body(of a horse),draw in a tail(of a dog)."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న :  ప్రస్తుత కాలంలో పంటలు పండించే విధానాలు మహాజనపదాల కాలంలో విధానాలతో ఏ విధంగా సరిపోతాయి?","answer":"ప్రస్తుతం, మహాజనపదాల కాలంలో ఇనప నాగలి వినియోగించడం జరిగింది.ప్రస్తుతం, మహాజనపదాల కాలంలో వరి నారు పోసే పద్దతి. ఒకే విధంగా ఉంది.ప్రస్తుతం, మహాజనపదాల కాలంలో సాగునీటి సౌకర్యాల కల్పన ఒకేలా ఉంది.ప్రస్తుతం, మహాజనపదాల కాలంలో పాలకులు వ్యవసాయాభివృద్ధికి కావాల్సిన సౌకర్యాలు కల్పించడం జరుగుతుంది."},{"question":"Beantwoord deze ingewikkelde vraag: Op welk eiland heeft het schip dat oorspronkelijk La Gallega heette, Christoffel Columbus geholpen kolonies te vestigen?","answer":"Het antwoord is La Santa María,"},{"question":"Sọ fúnmi nípa ìlu Bauchi.","answer":"Bauchi jẹ́ olú-ìlú Ìpínlẹ̀ Bauchi ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà."},{"question":"सर्वप्रथम चन्द्र धरातलमा पुग्ने अन्तरिक्ष यान कुन हो?","answer":"सर्वप्रथम चन्द्र धरातलमा पुग्ने अन्तरिक्ष यान लुना–२ हो|"},{"question":"Qual o nome do quadro de René Magritte em que se lê a inscrição \\"ceci n'est pas une pipe\\"?a) O Jóquei Perdidob) A Procura do Absolutoc) O Espelho Falsod) Reprodução Proibidae) A Traição das Imagens","answer":"Resposta correta: e) A Traição das Imagens.A obra A Traição das Imagens (La trahison des images, em francês) foi pintada em 1929 pelo artista belga René Magritte. Nela, lê-se a frase que indica que o que o espectador vê não é um cachimbo (\\"ceci n'est pas une pipe\\", \\"isto não é um cachimbo\\" em português), mas uma imagem, uma representação de um cachimbo."},{"question":"Adajọ ti ni ki wọn yẹgi fun Abiọdun ati Sunday to ja ileepo lole n’Ikọle-Ekiti","answer":"Ọkunrin ẹni ọgbọn ọdun kan, Olowoṣọla Femi Abiọdun, ati Olowoṣọla Sunday toun jẹ ẹni ọdun marundinlogoji, nile-ẹjọ giga ilu Ado-Ekiti ti ni ki wọn lọọ yẹgi fun titi ti ẹmi yoo fi bọ lara wọn.Awọn eeyan naa ni wọn sọ pe wọn ja ileepo kan lole niluu Ikọle-Ekiti lọjọ kọkandinlọgbọn, oṣu kejila, ọdun 2017.Amofin Julius Ajibare to ṣoju ijọba fẹsun kan wọn pe wọn gbe ibọn lọọ ka Awoyọmi Temitọpẹ mọ ileepo to ti n ṣiṣẹ, wọn si gba miliọnu kan ati ẹgbẹrun lọna ọọdunrun naira (N1.3m) pẹlu foonu Tecno L8 meji ati Nokia kan.O ni ẹsun mẹta lawọn olujẹjọ naa jẹbi wọn, iyẹn igbimọ-pọ ṣiṣẹ ibi, idigunjale ati nini ibọn nikaawọ lọna aitọ.Temitọpẹ ti wọn ja lole sọ fun kootu naa pe oun ni manija ileepo ọhun, bi awọn adigunjale naa si ṣe de ni wọn fi ibọn gba oun lori, ki wọn too gba owo ati foonu lọ.Amofin Ajibare pe awọn ẹlẹrii mẹta lati fidi awọn ẹsun rẹ mulẹ, bẹẹ lo lo akọsilẹ awọn olujẹjọ, ibọn meji, ọta mẹta atawọn foonu mẹtẹẹta ti wọn ji gẹgẹ bii ẹri.Amofin Yinka Ọpaleke lo ṣoju awọn olujẹjọ, ṣugbọn ko pe ẹlẹrii kankan.Nigba to n gbe idajọ kalẹ, Onidaajọ Adekunle Adelẹyẹ sọ pe awọn nnkan ti wọn ba lọwọ awọn eeyan naa ati ẹri to wa nilẹ ta ko wọn ni gbogbo ọna, o si fi han pe wọn digun jale loootọ.O waa ni ki wọn lọọ yẹgi fun wọn lori ẹsun kin-in-ni ati ekeji, ki wọn si lọọ ṣẹwọn ọdun mẹwaa lori ẹsun kẹta."},{"question":"Hint: కొనగలూరు, ఆంధ్ర ప్రదేశ్ రాష్ట్రములోని శ్రీ పొట్టి శ్రీరాములు నెల్లూరు జిల్లా, పొదలకూరు మండలానికి, దుగ్గుంట పంచాయతికి చెందిన గ్రామము.[1]. ఇక్కడి నుంచి నెల్లూరు 42 కీ.మీ, సైదాపురం 38 కీ.మీ, రాపురు 23 కీ.మీ, కలువాయి 50 కీ.మీ. సంగం నుంచి 35 కి.మి, పొస్టల్ పిన్ కోడ్ నం. 524 409, ఎస్.టి.డి.కోడ్- 08621.దేవాలయాలు, ప౦డుగలుకొనగలూరు గ్రామ౦లొ మస్తాన్ స్వామి దర్గా- జెండా పండుగ, వినాయక చవితి మరియు శ్రీరామ నవమి పండుగలు సంబర౦గా జరుపుకుంటారు.శ్రీ వినాయక స్వామివారి దేవాలయం:-ఈ గ్రామంలొ పూజలందుకొనే దేవాలయాలు 21వ శతాబ్దం వరకు లేవు అంటే ఆశ్చర్యపొనవసరము లేదు. ఈ గ్రామంలొ నందిబీళ్ళు ప్రాంతంలొ పురాతన కాలం నాటి శివుడు పార్వతి, వినాయకుడు మరియు నంది రాతి విగ్రహాలు బయటపడ్డవి. అప్పటి గ్రామ పెద్దలు శ్రీరాములవారి దేవాలయ నిర్మాణానికి ఉపక్రమించారు, ఊరిలొ వాందరి సహకారం అందకపొవడంతొ వారి ప్రయత్నాన్ని విరమించుకున్నారు.చాలా కాలం తరువాత ఈ గ్రామానికి ఉపాద్యయుడుగా వచ్చినటువంటి కీ.శే. శ్రీ ప్రకాశం పంతులు గారు స్వతహగ బ్రాహ్మణుడు అగుటచేత గ్రామ పెద్దలైన శ్రీ చిరుమావిళ్ళ సత్యనారాయణ గారు, కీ.శే. శ్రీ పేట చంచయ్య గార్లను శ్రీ వినాయక స్వామివారి దేవాలయం నిర్మించమని కొరారు అందుకు అంగీకరించిన వారు పాఠశాల సమీపంలొని ప్రాంతంలొ నిర్మించతలపెట్టారు, వారు తలపెట్టినా కొన్ని కారణాల మూలంగా నిర్మాణానికి ఆటంకాలు ఎదురైనవి, ఈ సమయంలొనె శ్రీ పేట చంచయ్య గారు, శ్రీ ప్రకాశం పంతులు గారు కాలం చెశారు. తదుపరి గ్రామస్థులు నిర్మణపనులు వేగవంతం చేయడంతొ 2009 సంవత్సరములొ ఆలయంలో శ్రీ ప్రకాశం పంతులు గారు ప్రతిష్టించాలనుకున్న విగ్రహాన్ని ప్రతిష్టించి పూజలు, హొమాలు నిర్వహంచారు.ఈ దేవాలయంలో వినాయక చవితి రోజు ఈ దేవాలయాన్ని పూవ్వులు, పండ్లుతొ అలంకరించి, పూజలు నిర్వహించి తీర్థప్రసాదాలు భక్తులకు ఇస్తారు, స్వామివారి సన్నిథిలొ ఉట్టి మహొత్సవం నిర్వహించి తదుపరి స్వామివారి విగ్రహాన్ని ఊరంతా ఊరేగించి ఊరు ప్రక్కనే ప్రవహించే కండలేరు ఏరులొ (నది) నిమఘ్నం చెస్తారు.శ్రీ మస్తాన్ వలి దర్గా:- జెండా పండుగ, గంధమహొత్సవముజెండా పండుగ, గంధమహొత్సవము మే నుండి జూలై మాసంలొ కసుమూరు దర్గా గంధమహొత్సవము తరువాత జరుగును. పేద, థనిక, కుల, మత తారతమ్యాలు లేకుండా మస్తాన్ స్వామి జెండా ఉత్సవాన్ని గ్రామ ప్రజలందరు భక్తిశ్రద్డలతొ జరుపుకుంటారు. కొరిన కొర్కెలు తీర్చె దేవునిగా కొలుస్తారు, కాలగమణంలొ మస్తాన్ స్వామి మహబూబ్ స్వామిగా,...","answer":"కొనగలూరు "},{"question":"Tính và so sánh kết quả cho các phép tinh sau:a) (– 4) . 7 và 7 . (– 4); b) [(– 3). 4] . (– 5) và (– 3) . [4. (– 5)];c) (– 4) . 1 và – 4; d) (– 4) . (7 + 3) và (– 4) . 7 + (– 4) . 3.","answer":"Lời giải:a) (– 4) . 7 = – (4 . 7) = – 287 . (– 4) = – (7 . 4) = – 28Vậy (– 4) . 7 = 7 . (– 4).b) [(– 3) . 4] . (– 5) = [– (3 . 4)] . (– 5) = (– 12) . (– 5) = 60(– 3) . [4 . (– 5)] = (– 3) . [– (4 . 5)] = (– 3) . (– 20) = 60Do đó: [(– 3) . 4] . (– 5) = (– 3) . [4 . (– 5)].c) (– 4) . 1 = – (4 . 1) = – 4Vậy (– 4) . 1 = – 4.d) (– 4) . (7 + 3) = (– 4) . 10 = – (4 . 10) = – 40(– 4) . 7 + (– 4) . 3 = [– (4 . 7)] + [– (4 . 3)] = (– 28) + (– 12) = – (28 + 12) = – 40Vậy (– 4) . (7 + 3) = (– 4) . 7 + (– 4) . 3. "},{"question":"Inona ny planeta mafana indrindra ? ","answer":"Ny planeta Venus no mafana indrindra amin'ireo planeta ao amin'ny rafi-masoandrontsika. "},{"question":"Kış stajı kaç ay?","answer":"Yönetmelik gereği öğrencilerimizin en az 30-45 gün staj yapmaları gerekmektedir. Bu 30-45 gün için “iş kazası ve meslek hastalıkları sigorta prim” Siirt Üniversitesi Rektörlüğü tarafından ödenecektir. Dileyen öğrenciler en 30 iş günü tamamlamak kaydıyla daha uzun süre de staj yapabilirler."},{"question":"Бирөө тентип Алтайга,Бирөө тентип Каңгайга,Бирөө тентип Эреңге,Бирөө түшүп кетти тереңге.Бул ыр саптары кайсы эпоско таандык ","answer":"\\"Манас\\" эпосунан алынган"},{"question":"次の段落は何について話しているのか？ マイナンバーカードは、日本に住む人に1人ずつ決まっている番号や、名前などが書いてあるカードです。カードには、国などから出るお金をもらうための銀行などの口座を登録することができます。国によると、今までに登録された口座約5400万の中に、子どもの家族など、違う人の口座が約13万あることがわかりました。家族でもない別の人の口座が登録された間違いも748ありました。国は、違う人の口座を登録できないようにシステムを直すと言っていますが、時間がかかりそうです。違う人の口座の場合、お金をもらうことができない可能性があります。デジタル庁の大臣は「申し訳ありません。違う人の口座になっている場合はすぐに変えてください」と言っています。","answer":"マイナンバーカード　家族などの口座が約13万登録されていた"},{"question":"සාපේක්ෂ කියන වචනයෙ අරුත පහදන්න.","answer":"සාපේක්ෂ සංස්කෘත තත්සම පදයකි.सापेक्ष adj. requiring or pre-supposing anythingसापेक्ष adj. having regard or respect toसापेक्ष adj. dependent onවර්තමාන භාවිතයේදී සන්සන්දනාත්මක යන අර්ථය දෙයි."},{"question":"ما هو الجهاز الذي يُستخدم لقياس الضغط الجوي؟","answer":"الباروميتر."},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp đoạn văn sau: Trong khi mưa xối xả và lũ quét tiếp tục diễn ra ở tỉnh Balochistan, dòng nước lũ đã tràn vào quận Qambar-Shahdadkot tại tỉnh Sindh liền kề và vùng đồi núi Kachho ở huyện Dadu, gây ra nhiều thiệt hại ở các khu vực khác nhau, kênh tin tức của Pakistan ARY News đưa tin. \\"30 ngôi làng khác ở Kachho và các tuyến đường kết nối lưu thông đã chìm trong nước, nâng tổng số ngôi làng bị ngập nước ở vùng đồi núi lên tới 50\\", theo các nguồn tin. ARY News thông tin, các nguồn tin địa phương cho biết, người dân ở các khu vực bị ảnh hưởng buộc phải trú ẩn trên các ngọn đồi và đê bảo vệ để tránh dòng nước lũ: \\"Một cụ bà 70 tuổi ở một ngôi làng bị lũ lụt đã tử vong khi tình trạng sức khỏe nguy cấp mà không được cấp cứu kịp thời\\". Tỉnh Balochistan nói riêng đã chứng kiến những trận mưa lớn bất thường trong mùa gió mùa năm nay. Các nhà chức trách quản lý thảm họa của Pakistan hôm 30/7 cho biết, mưa lớn và lũ lụt đã khiến thêm 19 người tử vong và hàng trăm người khác mắc kẹt ở các tỉnh Balochistan và Khyber Pakhtunkhwa. Trong 24 giờ qua, 9 người trong một gia đình, trong đó có 7 trẻ em và một phụ nữ, đã chết đuối sau khi họ bị lũ cuốn ở tỉnh Balochistan, một phương tiện","answer":"truyền thông địa phương dẫn nguồn PDMA. Tại tỉnh Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, ít nhất 10 người thiệt mạng và 17 người bị thương do lũ lụt và sập mái nhà, theo báo cáo của PDMA. Trong 36 giờ qua, gần 100 ngôi nhà bị thiệt hại hoàn toàn trong trận lũ, khiến người dân bị mất nhà cửa, mắc kẹt trong vùng nước ngập ngang thắt lưng. Dữ liệu do PDMA cung cấp cho biết, Peshawar, Swabi, Charsadda, Shangla, Khyber, Dera Ismail Khan và Bajaur là những khu vực bị ảnh hưởng nặng nề nhất. Chánh văn phòng tỉnh Balochistan Abdul Aziz Uqaili xác nhận, kể từ ngày 1/6, mưa lớn đã cướp đi sinh mạng của 124 người và làm hư hại 10.000 ngôi nhà trên địa bàn tỉnh. Lũ lụt đã làm hư hại khoảng 565 km đường và 197.930 mẫu đất nông nghiệp, trong khi 712 con gia súc đã chết, ông Uqaili nói thêm. Những trận mưa gió mùa thảm khốc đã khiến hai con đập Jara và Tabina trên dãy núi Toba Kakar ở tỉnh Balochistan bị vỡ. Một số con đập khác trong khu vực cũng trong tình trạng tương tự. Sau khi các con đập bị sập, nước lũ đã tràn vào quét sạch gia súc, hoa màu và đất canh tác ở những khu vực bị ảnh hưởng. Kết nối đất liền với Toba Achakzai (một nhánh của dãy núi Toba Kakar) với các vùng khác của đất nước đã bị ngắt trong 4 ngày. Trong khi đó, tuyến đường bộ giữa tỉnh Balochistan và tỉnh Sindh đã bị cắt đứt hoàn toàn sau khi một cây cầu và một con đường nối hai tỉnh lần lượt bị hư hỏng ở Lasbela và Khuzdar. Giao thông trên đường cao tốc Quetta - Karachi vẫn bị đình chỉ do sập các cây cầu chính và nhiều đoạn đường cao tốc bị nước lũ cuốn trôi. "},{"question":"総合的科学データブック『理科年表』の編集元である、文部科学省の付属機関はどこでしょう？","answer":"国立天文台"},{"question":"भारतात नोट बंदी केव्हा झाली?","answer":"भारतात नोट बंदी 8 नोव्हेंबर 2016 झाली."},{"question":"මනෝ විශ්ලේෂණවාදයේ වැදගත්කම ගැන කියන්න.","answer":"බොහෝ කරුණු හේතුවෙන් මනෝවිද්‍යාවේ විවිධ ගුරුකුල අතරින් මනෝවිශ්ලේෂණවාදය‍ට හිමි වන්නේ සුවිශේෂ හා වැදගත් ස්ථානයකි.ප්‍රථමයෙන්, අනෙක් සෑම මනෝවිද්‍යා ගුරුකුලයකටම වඩා වෙනස්ව මනෝවිශ්ලේෂණවාදය‍ මනෝවිද්‍යා විෂයයෙන්ම ප්‍රභවය වූයේ නැත. විශේෂයෙන් එහි නිර්මාතෘ සිග්මන්ඩ් ප්‍රොයිඩ් තම න්‍යායය ගොඩ නැගීමට ආධාර කරගත්තේ විශ්ව විද්‍යාල පර්යේෂණාගාර නොව තමාගේ චිකිත්සාගාරයයි. මේ කාලයේ පැවති මනෝවිද්‍යා ගුරුකුලවල පොදු එකගතාවයක් වූයේ පර්යේෂණාගාර, පුස්තකාල සහ දේශනාගාර ආශ්‍රිතව මූලික සංකල්ප බිහි කිරීමයි. එනිසාම ඔවුනගේ අධ්‍යයන කටයුතු සංජානනය, සංවේදනය, මතකය සහ ඉගෙනුම යන පොදු සංකල්පයන්ගෙන් බැහැරට යොමු වූයේ නැත. එසේම ඔවුන් ස්වාභාවික විද්‍යාවන්ට සමාන්තරව මනෝවිද්‍යා ඥානය ගොඩනැගීමේ ප්‍රයත්නයක නියුක්ත වූහ. එහෙත් ප්‍රොයිඩ්ගේ න්‍යාය මානසික රෝගීන් ආශ්‍රිතව ගොඩ නැගුණු අතර එහි මූලධර්ම පෞරුෂය, චිත්තවේග, ප්‍රේරණ, මනස සහ මානසික ප්‍රතිකාර වැනි නව මංපෙත් කරා යොමු විය. ප්‍රොයිඩ්ගෙන් පසු ඔහුගේ සෑම අනුගාමිකයෙක්ම අද දක්වාම අනුගමනය කරන්නේ මෙම සම්ප්‍රදායයි. එබැවින් මනෝවිශ්ලේෂණවාදය‍ මගින් නව සම්ප්‍රදාය, නව සංකල්ප, නව විධික්‍රම මනෝවිද්‍යාව‍ට හඳුන්වා දුන් ගුරුකුලයක් වශයෙන් කැපී පෙනේ.දෙවනුව මනෝවිශ්ලේෂණවාදය මනෝවිද්‍යාවේ පටු සීමාවන් ඉක්මවා තවත් විෂය ක්‍ෂේත්‍ර රාශියකට බලපෑම් කළේය. ඒ අතරින් භාෂා අධ්‍යයනය, දර්ශනය, දේශපාලන විද්‍යාව, ආචාර ධර්ම විද්‍යාව, සමාජ විද්‍යාව, මානව විද්‍යාව, ආගම් අධ්‍යයනය සහ සෑම කලා ක්‍ෂේත්‍රයකම කැපී පෙනෙයි. මනෝවිශ්ලේෂණවාදය මුල් කරගෙන රමණීය කවි, කථා, ගීත, කාව්‍ය, චිත්‍රපට විශාල සංඛ්‍යාවක් බිහි වී ඇත. මේ නිසාම මනෝවිශ්ලේෂණවාදය නියම මනෝවිද්‍යා ගුරුකුලයක් වශයෙන් පිළිගැනීමට එකල මනෝවිද්‍යාඥයෝ අකමැති වූහ. එහෙත් මනෝවිශ්ලේෂණවාදට මනෝවිද්‍යාවේ පමණක් නොව සමස්ත මානව ඥානයේම නොසෙල්විය හැකි තැනක් ලැබී ඇත. එනිසාම මනෝ විශ්ලේෂණවාදය ස්වාධීන ජාත්‍යන්තර සංවිධානයක් වශයෙන්ද ගොඩනැගී ඇත.තෙවනුව මනෝවිශ්ලේෂණවාදයේ මෙම විස්තීර්ණ බව හේතුවෙන්ම එය පොදු ජනතාව අතර ඉතාම ජනප්‍රියතම ගුරුකුලය බවට පත්ව ඇත. සමහර පුද්ගලයන් එය ඉතා ආදරයෙන් වැළඳගත් අතර සමහර පුද්රගලයින් එය‍ට වෛර කිරීමට පෙළඹුනාහ. සාම්ප්‍රදායික සූර්යකේන්‍ද්‍රවාදය ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරමින් ගැලීලියෝ පෘථිවිකේන්‍ද්‍රවාදය ඉදිරිපත් කළ අවස්ථාවේ ලෝකයා කැළඹුණු ආකාරයටම ප්‍රොයිඩ් විසින් විඥානයේ යථා ස්වභාවය හෙළිදරව් කළ විට ලෝකයා යළිත් කැළඹුනහ.සිව්වනුව මනෝවිශ්ලේෂණවාදය අන්සෑම ගුරුකුලයකටම වෙනස්ව තනි පුද්ගලයෙකුගේ එනම් පෞරුෂය කේන්ද්‍ර කරගෙන ගොඩනැගී ඇත. මනෝවිශ්ලේෂණවාදයේ න්‍යාය සහ මූලධර්ම අති බහුතරය ප්‍රොයිඩ් විසින්ම ගොඩ නගන ලදී. ඔහුගේ අනුගාමිකයන්ගේ කාර්යය වූයේ මෙම න්‍යායය සහ මූලධර්ම පෝෂණය කිරීම, වෙනස් කිරීම සහ අර්ථකතකය කිරීමයි. මෙම සියළු කරුණු හේතුවෙන් මනෝවිද්‍යාවේ විවිධ ගුරුකුල අතරින් මනෝවිශ්ලේෂණවාදය‍ට හිමි වන්නේ සුවිශේෂී හා වැදගත් ස්ථානයකි."},{"question":"Nyatakan jenis peribahasa bagi peribahasa berikut:\\"Seperti pungguk rindukan bulan\\"","answer":"Jawapannya ialah peribahasa jenis perumpamaan"},{"question":"السؤال: متى قبتل حيي بن الأخطب؟","answer":"الإجابة: في غزوة بني قريظة"},{"question":"Apakah maksud dengan peribahasa \\"bagai menatang minyak yang penuh\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud memelihara anak dengan penuh kasih sayang."},{"question":"Kedụ mgbe amụrụ òtíégwú a na-akpọ Bright Chimezie?","answer":"Amuru ya na afọ 1 Oktoba 1960"},{"question":"what is the capital of KSA?","answer":"Riyadh formerly known as Hajr al-Yamamah."},{"question":"Escribe una adivinanza sobre animales:","answer":"Adivinanza sobre animales :En la selva o en la sabana me verás,Con manchas oscuras en mi piel andar.Fierro y elegante, sin rival en mi hogar,Un cazador sigiloso, ¿quién soy, adivinaras?. "},{"question":"Дүйнө элдери арасындагы шайлоо тууралуу кызыктуу фактыларды жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Африка өлкөлөрүндө чындап эле шайлоонун да “кара” жактары бар. Маселен, шайлоо алдындагы компаниялар ондогон ритуалдык өлүмдөрдү чакырышат.  Мисалы, кандидаттар атайын бүбү-бакшыларды жалдашып, алар шайлоодо тигилер жеңишке жетиши үчүн адамдын өмүрүн курмандыкка чалышат."},{"question":"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks Bahasa Jawa yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke teks dalam Bahasa Indonesia.\\"Kayane nyenengke!\\", kandhane kabeh kewan. Singa dolanan, dheweke seneng banget.Terjemahan:","answer":"\\"Wah! Kelihatannya seru!\\", kata teman-teman hewan yang lain melihat si singa. Singa pun akhirnya bermain bersama mereka dan merasa sangat gembira."},{"question":"泰勒斯認為萬物之源是？","answer":"泰勒斯在多個領域有所建樹，在哲學方面，泰勒斯拒絕倚賴玄異或超自然因素來解釋自然現象，試圖藉助經驗觀察和理性思維來解釋世界。他提出了水本原說，即“萬物源於水”，是古希臘第一個提出“什麼是萬物本原”這個哲學問題的人。"},{"question":"Ity misy lahatsoratra:Ny fahadiovana dia sady fahafinaretana no antoky ny fahasalamana.Tokony handro isan'andro raha azo atao, mba hadio foana ny tena manontolo. Fitafiana mandio no anaovana; fandriana, ondana ary kidoro sy lamba firakotra madio no atoriana.Tokony hadio koa ny trano onenana, indrindra moa fa ny lakozia anomanana sakafo, mba tsy hisy loto hanintona ny lalitra.Hatramin'ny manodidina ny trano no tokony hovoara-maso tsara, ka diovina tsara ny lava-piringa. Tsy hadinoina ny manao lava-pako; kapaina ny lobolobo; totofana ny rano miandrona izay mahabe moka. Fadina indrindra ny manarinary fako sy poti-kanina eny rehetra eny fa mamelona voalavo ireny.Raha io lahatsoratra io, inona no tokony hatao mba tsy hampisy ny moka ao amin'ny trano fonenana?","answer":"Raha io lahatsoratra io, mba tsy hampisy ny moka ao amin'ny trano fonenana dia tokony hokapaina ny lobolobo."},{"question":"கேள்வி: தமிழ் இலக்கியம் குறித்து எழுதுக.","answer":"பதில் :முன்னுரை :தமிழ் இலக்கியம் இரண்டாயிரம் ஆண்டுகளுக்கு மேலாக தொடர்ச்சி கொண்டு இவ்வுலகின் சிறந்த இலக்கியங்களில் ஒன்று. வாழ்வின் பல்வேறு கூறுகளைத் தமிழ் இலக்கியங்கள் இயம்புகின்றன. தமிழ் இலக்கியத்தில் வெண்பா, குறள், புதுக்கவிதை, கட்டுரை, பழமொழி, தொண்ணூற்றாறு வகை சிற்றிலக்கியங்கள் எனப் பல வடிவங்கள் உள்ளன. தமிழில் வாய்மொழி இலக்கியங்களும் முக்கிய இடம் வகிக்கின்றன.வரலாறுமு. வரதராசனின் தமிழ் இலக்கியம் என்னும் நூலில் தரப்பட்டிருக்கும் தமிழ் இலக்கிய கால வகைப்பாட்டை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்ட வகைப்பாடு பின்வருமாறு:பழங்காலம்சங்க இலக்கியம் (பொ.ஊ.மு. 500 – பொ.ஊ. 300)நீதி இலக்கியம் (பொ.ஊ. 300 – பொ.ஊ. 500)இடைக்காலம்பக்தி இலக்கியம் (பொ.ஊ. 700 – பொ.ஊ. 900)காப்பிய இலக்கியம் (பொ.ஊ. 900 – பொ.ஊ. 1200)உரைநூல்கள் (பொ.ஊ. 1200 – பொ.ஊ. 1500)புராண இலக்கியம் (பொ.ஊ. 1500 – பொ.ஊ. 1800)புராணங்கள், தலபுராணங்கள்இஸ்லாமிய தமிழ் இலக்கியம்இக்காலம்பத்தொன்பதாம் நூற்றாண்டுகிறிஸ்தவ தமிழ் இலக்கியம்புதினம்இருபதாம் நூற்றாண்டுகட்டுரை, சிறுகதை, புதுக்கவிதை, ஆராய்ச்சிக் கட்டுரைஇருபத்தோராம் நூற்றாண்டுஅறிவியல் தமிழ், கணினித் தமிழ்முதற்சங்கம், இடைச்சங்கம்தொல்பழங்காலத்தில், அக்காலப் பாண்டிய அரசர்களின் ஆதரவில், ஒன்றுக்குப்பின் ஒன்றாக மூன்று தமிழ்ச் சங்கங்கள் தோன்றித் தமிழாராய்ந்ததாகவும், அக்காலத்தில் தமிழிலக்கியங்கள் பல இயற்றப்பட்டதாகவும் நம்பப்படுகிறது. முதற்சங்கம், இடைச்சங்கம், கடைச்சங்கம் என அழைக்கப்படும் இச்சங்கங்கள் சார்ந்த இலக்கியங்களில் கடைச்சங்க நூல்கள் மட்டுமே தற்போது கிடைப்பதாகச் சொல்லப்படுகிறது. முன்னிரண்டு சங்கங்களையும் சேர்ந்த நூல்கள், அக்காலங்களில் ஏற்பட்ட கடல்கோள்களின்போது, நாட்டின் பெரும்பகுதியுடன் சேர்ந்து அழிந்துபோனதாகக் கருதப்படுகிறது. எனினும், முதலிரு சங்கங்கள் இருந்தது பற்றியோ அக்காலத்தில் இலக்கியங்கள் இருந்தது பற்றியோ உறுதியான ஆதாரங்கள் இல்லை.சங்க இலக்கியம்சங்க இலக்கியம் எனப்படுவது தமிழில் பொது ஆண்டுக்கு முற்பட்ட காலப்பகுதியில் எழுதப்பட்ட செவ்வியல் இலக்கியங்கள் ஆகும்.சங்க இலக்கியம் 473 புலவர்களால் எழுதப்பட்ட 2,381 பாடல்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது. இப்புலவர்களுள் பலதரப்பட்ட தொழில் புரிந்தோரும், பெண்களும் அடங்குவர். அக்காலகட்டத்தில் வாழ்ந்த தமிழர்களின் அன்றாட வாழ்க்கை நிலைமைகளைப் படம்பிடித்துக் காட்டுவதாய்ச் சங்க இலக்கியங்கள் உள்ளன. பண்டைத் தமிழரது காதல்,போர், வீரம், ஆட்சியமைப்பு, வணிகம் போன்ற நடப்புகளைச் சங்க இலக்கியப் பாடல்கள் நமக்கு அறியத் தருகின்றன.பதினெண்மேற்கணக்கு நூல்கள் என்று வழங்கப்படும் எட்டுத்தொகை, பத்துப்பாட்டு என்ற தொகுப்புகளே சங்க இலக்கிய நூல்கள் ஆகும். இவை மதுரையில் அமைந்த கடைச்சங்கத்தில் தொகுக்கப்பட்டவையாகக் கருதப்படுகின்றன.சங்கம் மருவிய காலம் / நீதி நூற்காலம்சங்க காலத்திற்கு அடுத்து வந்த காலப்பகுதியில் அறவழி கூறும் நூல்கள் மிகுதியாக வெளிவந்தன. எனவே இக்காலம் நீதிநூற்காலம் எனப்படுகிறது. இந்நூல்களுள் போதிக்கப்படும் நீதி, பெரும்பாலும் சமயச் சார்பற்றவையாகக் கருதப்படுகிறது.[1] நாலடியார் முதற்கொண்டு இன்னிலை / கைந்நிலை ஈறாக உள்ள பதினெட்டு நூல்கள், பதினெண்கீழ்க்கணக்கு நூல்கள் என்று வழங்கப்படுகிறது. இவையே நீதி நூல்கள் என்றும் வகைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளன. உலகப் பொதுமறை என்று போற்றப்படும் திருக்குறள் இத்தொகுப்பினுள் அடக்கம்.சிலப்பதிகாரம், மணிமேகலை என்னும் இரட்டைக் காப்பியங்கள் இயற்றப்பட்டதும் இக்காலத்தில்தான்.தற்கால இலக்கியம்பொ.ஊ. 18-ஆம், 19-ஆம் நூற்றாண்டுக் காலப்பகுதியில் தமிழ்நாட்டில் அரசியல், மதம், கல்வி போன்ற தளங்களில் பல விதமான மாற்றங்கள் இடம்பெற்றன. குன்றக்குடி, திருவாவடுதுறை, திருப்பனந்தாள் போன்ற சைவ மடங்களின் ஆதரவாலும், சில புலவர் பரம்பரையினரின் முயற்சியாலும் தமிழ் இலக்கியச் செல்வங்கள், விழுமியங்கள் அழிவுறுவது காலத்தால் தடுக்கப்பட்டது. பல்வேறு பேரரசுகளின் ஆட்சியாலும், ஆங்கில மொழியின் வரவாலும் ஒரு தேக்கம் ஏற்பட்டது தமிழ் இலக்கியத்தில். பின்னர் நிலையான ஆங்கிலேயர் ஆட்சியும், ஐரோப்பிய மிஷனரிகளின் தமிழ் மொழி ஈர்ப்பும், அவர்கள் கொண்டுவந்த அச்சியந்திரங்களும், பின் ஏற்பட்ட சுதந்திர இந்திய ஆட்சியும் மதச்சுதந்திரமும், கல்வி முறையில் ஏற்பட்ட தோற்ற வளர்ச்சி, நவீன சிந்தனைகளின் உருவாக்கமும் போன்ற காரணிகளால் தமிழ் மொழியும், இலக்கியமும் இக்காலகட்டத்தில் பெரிதும் வளர்ச்சியுற்றன. இக்காலகட்டத்தில் இடம்பெற்ற முக்கிய மாற்றமாகக் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க விடயங்களாவன:சங்க இலக்கியங்கள் மீளக் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டதும் அச்சேற்றியதும்.உரைநடையில் எழுதுவது அறிமுகமானது. (19-ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் கடைப்பகுதி)புதுக்கவிதை எனும் புதுப்பாணி தோற்றம் பெற்றது. (20-ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் முற்பகுதி)மணிப்பிரவாள நடை ஒழிந்தது. (20-ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் பிற்பகுதி)அச்சியந்திரங்களின் வருகையால் ஏடுகளில் மட்டும் இருந்த தமிழ் இலக்கியங்கள் உ. வே. சாமிநாதையர், ஆறுமுக நாவலர், சி. வை. தாமோதரம்பிள்ளை போன்றோரின் மீள் கண்டுபிடிப்பாலும், அயராத உழைப்பாலும் அச்சாக வெளிவந்தது."},{"question":"Se Ana é neta de Luís, então é correto afirmar que...","answer":"Luís é avô de Ana."},{"question":"இந்திய ராணுவத்தின் மிக உயர்ந்த பதவி எது?","answer":"இந்தியத் தரைப்படை இந்தியப் படைத்துறையின் மிகப்பெரிய பிரிவாகும். இது இந்தியாவின் எல்லை கண்காணிப்பு, உள்நாட்டு பாதுகாப்பு, அமைதி நிலைநாட்டல், பயங்கரவாத எதிர்ப்புப் பணிகளில் பெரும் பங்கு வகிக்கிறது. இயற்கைச் சீற்றங்களின்போது மீட்புப்பணி, நலப் பணிகளிலும் ஈடுபடுகின்றது. இந்திய தரைப்படை இந்தியப் பாதுகாப்பு அமைச்சகத்தின் நேரடி கட்டுப்பாட்டின் கீழ் இயங்குகிறது.ஏறத்தாழ 11,30,000 படையினர் இப்படைப்பிரிவில் செயலார்ந்த தீவிரப் பணியாற்றுகின்றனர் மேலும், ஏறத்தாழ 18,00,000 படையினர் இருப்புப் படையாக தயார் நிலையில் உள்ளனர். இந்திய தரைப்படை உலகின் இரண்டாவது மிகப்பெரிய தரைப்படையாகும். வீரர்கள் தன்னார்வத்தின் மூலமே படையில் சேர்க்கப்படுகின்றனர். இருப்பினும் இந்திய அரசியலமைப்பில் அவசர காலத்தில் கட்டாயத்தின் பேரிலும் வீரர்களை படையில் சேர்க்க வழிவகை உண்டு. அது ஒருபோதும் நடைமுறை படுத்தப்படவில்லை.இந்தியத் தரைப்படை எண்ணிக்கையில் உலகில் மூன்றாவது இடத்தில் இருக்கிறது.இந்தியா விடுதலை அடைந்த 1947 ஆம் ஆண்டில் இந்திய தரைப்படை உருவாக்கப்பட்டு, ஆங்கிலேய இந்தியாவின் தரைப்படை, இந்திய தரைப்படையுடன் இணைக்கப்பட்டது. இந்திய தரைப்படை உலகின் பல சச்சரவுப் பகுதிகளில் ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் அவையின் அமைதி காக்கும் படையாக பணியாற்றியுள்ளது. இப்படை தற்பொழுது முதன்மை தரைப்படை தலைவர் பிக்ரம் சிங் தலைமையில் செயல்படுகிறது. தரைப்படையின் தலைமைப் பதவி பீல்டு மார்சல். இது இந்திய குடியரசுத் தலைவரால் வழங்கப்படுகிறது. இந்நாள் வரை இரண்டு தரைப்படை பட்டாளர்கள் மட்டுமே இந்த உயர் பதவியை அடைந்திருக்கின்றனர். அவ்விருவர்: பீல்டு மார்சல் மானக்சா 1973, ஓய்வு பெற்ற பின் 30 அண்டுகள் கழித்து 1986 இல் பீல்டு மார்சல் கரியப்பா."},{"question":"فسر النكتة دي: ازاي تهدي طفل رائد فضاء لما يعيط؟  هزه!","answer":"أكيد. النكتة دي ترجمة حرفية لنكتة انجليزية بتعتمد على اللعب بالكلام. فى النسخة الأصلية بتوقف عياط الطفل عن طريق هزه شوية لحد ما يسكت. الكلمة دي بالنجليزى هي \\"روك إت\\" و اللى بتشابه فى نطقها كلمة \\"روكيت\\" و اللى بتعنى صاروخ. و من هنا يظهر اللعب فى الكلام و اللى بيضيع تماما فى الترجمة العربية، رائد الفضاء بيتعامل مع الصواريخ ، فطريقة تسكيت ابنه من العياط هى \\"روك إت\\" أو هزه يعنى.اتمنى أكون ساعدتك. فى حاجة تانى أقدر أساعدك بيها؟"},{"question":"ප්‍රශ්වාස වාතයේ කාබන්ඩයාක්සයිඞ්‌ ප්‍රතිශතය කීයද?","answer":"පිට කරන වාතයේ ඇති කාබන්ඩයොක්සයිඩ් ප්‍රතිශතය (CO₂) ආශ්වාස කරන වාතයට වඩා සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස වැඩිය. පිට කරන වාතයේ දී, CO₂ සාන්ද්‍රණය සාමාන්‍යයෙන් 4% සිට 5% දක්වා වේ. මෙම වැඩිවීම ශරීරයේ පරිවෘත්තීය ක්රියාවලීන් නිසාය. සෛල බලශක්ති නිෂ්පාදනය සඳහා ඔක්සිජන් භාවිතා කරන විට, ඒවා අපද්‍රව්‍ය නිෂ්පාදනයක් ලෙස CO₂ නිපදවන අතර එය රුධිරය හරහා පෙනහළු වෙත ප්‍රවාහනය කර හුස්ම ගැනීම හරහා බැහැර කරයි. මෙය පෘථිවි වායුගෝලයේ ඇති පරිදි 0.04% පමණ වන ආශ්වාස කරන වාතයේ CO₂ සාන්ද්‍රණයට ප්‍රතිවිරුද්ධ වේ."},{"question":"स्वयम्भूनाथ स्तुपा क्षेत्र वरपर हेर्न को लागी अन्य स्मारकहरु के छन्?","answer":"स्वयम्हुनाथ स्तूप क्षेत्रमा हेर्नका लागि केही महत्त्वपूर्ण स्मारकहरू:१. स्तुपाको पूर्वपट्टि राखिएको विशाल सुनले ढाकिएको वज्र ‘थन्डरबोल्ट’२. स्वयम्भूको पश्चिम तर्फ बुद्ध मुर्ति।३. सुत्ने बुद्ध४.  देवा धर्म मठ, बुद्ध र परम्परागत तिब्बती चित्रहरूको कांस्य प्रतिमा"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੧ ॥ਰੇ ਮਨ ਐਸੀ ਹਰਿ ਸਿਉ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਕਰਿ ਜੈਸੀ ਜਲ ਕਮਲੇਹਿ ॥ਲਹਰੀ ਨਾਲਿ ਪਛਾੜੀਐ ਭੀ ਵਿਗਸੈ ਅਸਨੇਹਿ ॥ਜਲ ਮਹਿ ਜੀਅ ਉਪਾਇ ਕੈ ਬਿਨੁ ਜਲ ਮਰਣੁ ਤਿਨੇਹਿ ॥੧॥ਮਨ ਰੇ ਕਿਉ ਛੂਟਹਿ ਬਿਨੁ ਪਿਆਰ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਅੰਤਰਿ ਰਵਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਬਖਸੇ ਭਗਤਿ ਭੰਡਾਰ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਰੇ ਮਨ ਐਸੀ ਹਰਿ ਸਿਉ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਕਰਿ ਜੈਸੀ ਮਛੁਲੀ ਨੀਰ ॥ਜਿਉ ਅਧਿਕਉ ਤਿਉ ਸੁਖੁ ਘਣੋ ਮਨਿ ਤਨਿ ਸਾਂਤਿ ਸਰੀਰ ॥ਬਿਨੁ ਜਲ ਘੜੀ ਨ ਜੀਵਈ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਜਾਣੈ ਅਭ ਪੀਰ ॥੨॥ਰੇ ਮਨ ਐਸੀ ਹਰਿ ਸਿਉ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਕਰਿ ਜੈਸੀ ਚਾਤ੍ਰਿਕ ਮੇਹ ॥ਸਰ ਭਰਿ ਥਲ ਹਰੀਆਵਲੇ ਇਕ ਬੂੰਦ ਨ ਪਵਈ ਕੇਹ ॥ਕਰਮਿ ਮਿਲੈ ਸੋ ਪਾਈਐ ਕਿਰਤੁ ਪਇਆ ਸਿਰਿ ਦੇਹ ॥੩॥ਰੇ ਮਨ ਐਸੀ ਹਰਿ ਸਿਉ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਕਰਿ ਜੈਸੀ ਜਲ ਦੁਧ ਹੋਇ ॥ਆਵਟਣੁ ਆਪੇ ਖਵੈ ਦੁਧ ਕਉ ਖਪਣਿ ਨ ਦੇਇ ॥ਆਪੇ ਮੇਲਿ ਵਿਛੁੰਨਿਆ ਸਚਿ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਦੇਇ ॥੪॥ਰੇ ਮਨ ਐਸੀ ਹਰਿ ਸਿਉ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਕਰਿ ਜੈਸੀ ਚਕਵੀ ਸੂਰ ॥ਖਿਨੁ ਪਲੁ ਨੀਦ ਨ ਸੋਵਈ ਜਾਣੈ ਦੂਰਿ ਹਜੂਰਿ ॥ਮਨਮੁਖਿ ਸੋਝੀ ਨਾ ਪਵੈ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸਦਾ ਹਜੂਰਿ ॥੫॥ਮਨਮੁਖਿ ਗਣਤ ਗਣਾਵਣੀ ਕਰਤਾ ਕਰੇ ਸੁ ਹੋਇ ॥ਤਾ ਕੀ ਕੀਮਤਿ ਨਾ ਪਵੈ ਜੇ ਲੋਚੈ ਸਭੁ ਕੋਇ ॥ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਹੋਇ ਤ ਪਾਈਐ ਸਚਿ ਮਿਲੈ ਸੁਖੁ ਹੋਇ ॥੬॥ਸਚਾ ਨੇਹੁ ਨ ਤੁਟਈ ਜੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਭੇਟੈ ਸੋਇ ॥ਗਿਆਨ ਪਦਾਰਥੁ ਪਾਈਐ ਤ੍ਰਿਭਵਣ ਸੋਝੀ ਹੋਇ ॥ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਨ ਵੀਸਰੈ ਜੇ ਗੁਣ ਕਾ ਗਾਹਕੁ ਹੋਇ ॥੭॥ਖੇਲਿ ਗਏ ਸੇ ਪੰਖਣੂੰ ਜੋ ਚੁਗਦੇ ਸਰ ਤਲਿ ॥ਘੜੀ ਕਿ ਮੁਹਤਿ ਕਿ ਚਲਣਾ ਖੇਲਣੁ ਅਜੁ ਕਿ ਕਲਿ ॥ਜਿਸੁ ਤੂੰ ਮੇਲਹਿ ਸੋ ਮਿਲੈ ਜਾਇ ਸਚਾ ਪਿੜੁ ਮਲਿ ॥੮॥ਬਿਨੁ ਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰੀਤਿ ਨ ਊਪਜੈ ਹਉਮੈ ਮੈਲੁ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥ਸੋਹੰ ਆਪੁ ਪਛਾਣੀਐ ਸਬਦਿ ਭੇਦਿ ਪਤੀਆਇ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਆਪੁ ਪਛਾਣੀਐ ਅਵਰ ਕਿ ਕਰੇ ਕਰਾਇ ॥੯॥ਮਿਲਿਆ ਕਾ ਕਿਆ ਮੇਲੀਐ ਸਬਦਿ ਮਿਲੇ ਪਤੀਆਇ ॥ਮਨਮੁਖਿ ਸੋਝੀ ਨਾ ਪਵੈ ਵੀਛੁੜਿ ਚੋਟਾ ਖਾਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਦਰੁ ਘਰੁ ਏਕੁ ਹੈ ਅਵਰੁ ਨ ਦੂਜੀ ਜਾਇ ॥੧੦॥੧੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 59 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਮਨ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰ, ਜਿਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਪਾਣੀ ਦਾ ਕੌਲ ਫੁੱਲ ਵਿਚ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਕੌਲ ਫੁੱਲ ਦਾ ਪਾਣੀ ਵਿਚ) ਕੌਲ ਫੁੱਲ ਪਾਣੀ ਦੀਆਂ ਲਹਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਧੱਕੇ ਖਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਫਿਰ ਭੀ (ਪਰਸਪਰ) ਪਿਆਰ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੌਲ ਫੁੱਲ ਖਿੜਦਾ (ਹੀ) ਹੈ (ਧੱਕਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਗੁੱਸੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ) ਪਾਣੀ ਵਿਚ (ਕੌਲ ਫੁੱਲਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ) ਜਿੰਦਾਂ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਐਸੀ ਖੇਡ ਖੇਡਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਪਾਣੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਉਹਨਾਂ (ਕੌਲ ਫੁੱਲਾਂ) ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ।੧। ਹੇ ਮਨ ! (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨਾਲ) ਪਿਆਰ ਪਾਉਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਤੂੰ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਹੱਲਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ) ਬਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ (ਪਰ ਇਹ ਪਿਆਰ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਐਸੀ ਪਿਆਰ-ਸਾਂਝ ਬਣਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਦੇ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਹੀ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। ਹੇ ਮਨ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਕਰ, ਜਿਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਮੱਛੀ ਦਾ ਪਾਣੀ ਨਾਲ ਹੈ  ਪਾਣੀ ਜਿਤਨਾ ਹੀ ਵਧੀਕ ਹੈ, ਮੱਛੀ ਨੂੰ ਉਤਨਾ ਹੀ ਵਧੀਕ ਸੁਖ-ਆਨੰਦ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਤਨ ਵਿਚ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਚ ਠੰਡ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਪਾਣੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਇਕ ਘੜੀ ਭੀ ਜੀਊ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੀ । ਮੱਛੀ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਵੇਦਨਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਆਪ) ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧। ਹੇ ਮਨ ! ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨਾਲ ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹੀ ਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਕਰ, ਜਿਹੋ ਜਿਹੀ ਪਪੀਹੇ ਦੀ ਮੀਂਹ ਨਾਲ ਹੈ (ਪਾਣੀ ਨਾਲ) ਸਰੋਵਰ ਭਰੇ ਹੋਏ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਧਰਤੀ (ਪਾਣੀ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਹਰਿਆਵਲੀ ਹੋਈ ਪਈ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਜੇ (ਸ੍ਵਾਂਤੀ ਨਛੱਤ੍ਰ ਵਿਚ ਪਏ ਮੀਂਹ ਦੀ) ਇਕ ਬੂੰਦ (ਪਪੀਹੇ ਦੇ ਮੂੰਹ ਵਿਚ) ਨਾਹ ਪਏ, ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਾਣੀ ਨਾਲ ਕੋਈ ਭਾਗ ਨਹੀਂ (ਪਰ ਹੇ ਮਨ ! ਤੇਰੇ ਭੀ ਕੀਹ ਵੱਸ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ) ਆਪਣੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਮਿਲੇ ਤਾਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਨਹੀਂ ਤਾਂ) ਪੂਰਬਲਾ ਕਮਾਇਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਸਿਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਉੱਤੇ ਝੱਲਣਾ ਹੀ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩। ਹੇ ਮਨ ! ਹਰੀ ਨਾਲ ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਬਣਾ, ਜਿਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਪਾਣੀ ਤੇ ਦੁੱਧ ਦਾ ਹੈ (ਪਾਣੀ ਦੁੱਧ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਦੁੱਧ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਦੁੱਧ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਰੂਪ ਬਣਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜਦੋਂ ਉਸ ਪਾਣੀ-ਰਲੇ ਦੁੱਧ ਨੂੰ ਅੱਗ ਉੱਤੇ ਰੱਖੀਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ) ਉਬਾਲਾ (ਪਾਣੀ) ਆਪ ਹੀ ਸਹਾਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਦੁੱਧ ਨੂੰ ਸੜਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇਂਦਾ (ਇਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਜੇ ਜੀਵ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਕਰਨ, ਤਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ) ਵਿੱਛੁੜੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਮੇਲ ਕੇ (ਲੋਕ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ) ਇੱਜ਼ਤ-ਮਾਣ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।ਹੇ ਮਨ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰ, ਜਿਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਚਕਵੀ ਦਾ (ਪਿਆਰ) ਸੂਰਜ ਨਾਲ ਹੈ (ਜਦੋਂ ਸੂਰਜ ਡੁੱਬ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਚਕਵੀ ਦੀ ਨਜ਼ਰੋਂ ਉਹਲੇ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਚਕਵੀ) ਇਕ ਖਿਨ ਭਰ ਇਕ ਪਲ ਭਰ ਨੀਂਦ (ਦੇ ਵੱਸ ਆ ਕੇ) ਨਹੀਂ ਸੌਂਦੀ, ਦੂਰ (-ਲੁਕੇ ਸੂਰਜ) ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਗ-ਸੰਗ ਸਮਝਦੀ ਹੈ ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁੱਖ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਗ-ਸੰਗ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਸਮਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦੀ ।੫। ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਹੀ ਵਡਿਆਈਆਂ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਪਰ ਜੀਵ ਦੇ ਭੀ ਕੀਹ ਵੱਸ ?) ਉਹੀ ਕੁਝ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਕਰਤਾਰ (ਆਪ) ਕਰਦਾ (ਕਰਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ) (ਕਰਤਾਰ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ) ਜੇ ਕੋਈ ਜੀਵ (ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਵਡਿਆਈਆਂ ਛੱਡਣ ਦਾ ਜਤਨ ਭੀ ਕਰੇ, ਤੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਦਰ ਪਛਾਣਨ ਦਾ ਉੱਦਮ ਕਰੇ, ਤਾਂ ਭੀ) ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਦਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈ ਸਕਦੀ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਦਰ) ਤਦੋਂ ਹੀ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਜਦੋਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੋਵੇ । (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਮਿਲਿਆਂ ਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ ।੬।(ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੋੜਨ ਵਾਲਾ) ਜੇ ਉਹ ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲ ਪਏ, ਤਾਂ (ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮਿਹਰ ਦਾ ਸਦਕਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂੁ ਨਾਲ ਅਜੇਹਾ) ਪੱਕਾ ਪਿਆਰ (ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਕਦੇ) ਟੁੱਟਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ  (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ-ਪਦਾਰਥ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਸਮਝ ਭੀ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਤਿੰਨਾਂ ਭਵਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੈ ਜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਦਾ ਸਦਕਾ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ (ਦੇ ਸੌਦੇ) ਦਾ ਖ਼ਰੀਦਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਏ, ਤਾਂ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਨਾਮ (ਫਿਰ ਕਦੇ) ਨਹੀਂ ਭੁੱਲਦਾ ।੭। (ਹੇ ਮਨ ! ਵੇਖ) ਜੇਹੜੇ ਜੀਵ-ਪੰਛੀ ਇਸ (ਸੰਸਾਰ-) ਸਰੋਵਰ ਉੱਤੇ (ਚੋਗ) ਚੁਗਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਹ (ਆਪੋ ਆਪਣੀ ਜੀਵਨ-) ਖੇਡ ਖੇਡ ਕੇ ਚਲੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਹਰੇਕ ਜੀਵ-ਪੰਛੀ ਨੇ ਘੜੀ ਪਲ ਦੀ ਖੇਡ ਖੇਡ ਕੇ ਇਥੋਂ ਤੁਰਦੇ ਜਾਣਾ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਖੇਡ ਇਕ ਦੋ ਦਿਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ (ਛੇਤੀ ਹੀ) ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ  (ਹੇ ਮਨ ! ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਸਦਾ ਅਰਦਾਸ ਕਰ ਤੇ ਆਖ—ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਮਿਲਾਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ, ਉਹੀ ਤੇਰੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਇਥੋਂ ਸੱਚੀ ਜੀਵਨ‑ਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਜਿੱਤ ਕੇ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੮।ਗੁਰੂ (ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਣ) ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਪੈਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਉੱਦਮ ਨਾਲ ਮਨ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਹਉਮੈ ਦੀ ਮੈਲ ਦੂਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ਜਦੌਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਵਿੱਝ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਪਤੀਜ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤਦੋਂ ਇਹ ਪਛਾਣ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮੇਰਾ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸੁਭਾਉ ਰਲਿਆ ਹੈ ਜਾਂ ਨਹੀਂਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅਸਲੇ ਨੂੰ) ਪਛਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ) ਜੀਵ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਉੱਦਮ ਕਰ ਕਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ ।੯। ਜੇਹੜੇ ਜੀਵ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਪਤੀਜ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਕੋਈ ਐਸਾ ਵਿਛੋੜਾ ਰਹਿ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਦੂਰ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮੁੜ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨਾਲ ਜੋੜਿਆ ਜਾਏ  ਪਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਸਮਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦੀ, ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਵਿੱਛੁੜ ਕੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦੀਆਂ) ਚੋਟਾਂ ਖਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਹੀ ਇਕ ਆਸਰਾ ਪਰਨਾ (ਦਿੱਸਦਾ) ਹੈ । ਪ੍ਰਭੂੁ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਸਹਾਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ (ਦਿੱਸਦਾ) ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਥਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਸਦੀ ।੧੦।੧੧।\\""},{"question":"Berikan jawapan kepada teka-teki yang susah ini: Dalam banyak-banyak ikan, ikan apa yang masuk syurga?","answer":"Jawapan: Ikan patin bakar sebab dia maknyah."},{"question":"అశోకుని గొప్పతనాన్ని సంక్షిప్తంగా వివరించండి.","answer":"భారతీయ చక్రవర్తులలోనే గాక ప్రపంచ చక్రవర్తులలో కూడా ప్రత్యేక స్థానాన్ని సంపాదించుకున్నవాడు అశోకుడు. అశోకుని కాలంలో మౌర్య సామ్రాజ్యం ఆసేతు హిమాచల పర్యంతం విస్తరించింది.తొలి జీవితం: అశోకుడు బిందుసారుని కుమారుడు. తండ్రి మరణానంతరం క్రీ.పూ. 273లో మౌర్య సింహాసనాన్ని అధిష్టించాడు. అయితే అశోకుడికి, అతని సోదరులకు మధ్య సింహాసనం కోసం పోరాటం జరగటం వల్ల అశోకుడు తన పట్టాభిషేకాన్ని క్రీ.పూ. 269లో జరుపుకున్నాడు. సింహళ చరిత్ర గ్రంథాలు అశోకుని స్వభావం క్రూరమైనదని, తండ్రి మరణానంతరం తన 99 మంది సోదరులను వధించి సింహాసనాన్ని ఆక్రమించాడని వివరిస్తున్నాయి. అయితే అశోకుడు ఒక శిలాశాసనంలో తన సోదరుల, బంధువుల సంక్షేమానికి తీసుకున్న శ్రద్ధను ప్రస్తావించాడు. కాబట్టి అశోకుని వ్యక్తిత్వాన్ని మార్చటంలో బౌద్ధమతం యొక్క గొప్పదనాన్ని నొక్కిచెప్పటం కోసం ఈ ఐతిహ్యాన్ని సృష్టించారని, అది వాస్తవం కాదని కొందరు చరిత్రకారుల అభిప్రాయం.అశోకుని చరిత్రకు ఆధారాలు: అశోకుని ఉదాత్త లక్ష్యాలు, ఆదర్శాలు, పరిపాలనా కాలంలోని ముఖ్య సంఘటనలను తెలుసుకోవడానికి అతడు దేశంలో వివిధ ప్రాంతాల్లో వేయించిన శిలాస్తంభ శాసనాలు ఎంతో ఉపకరిస్తాయి. ఈ శాసనాలు బ్రాహ్మీలిపిలో వున్నాయి. బౌద్ధమత గ్రంథాలైన “మహావంశ”, “దివ్యావదాన” కూడా అశోకుని చరిత్రకు సంబంధించిన అంశాలను వివరిస్తాయి. అశోకుడు తన శాసనాలలో తనను ‘దేవానాంప్రియ’ (దేవతలకు ప్రియమైనవాడు), ‘ప్రియదర్శి’ (చక్కని రూపం కలవాడు) అని చెప్పుకున్నాడు.కళింగ యుద్ధం: అశోకుడు మౌర్య సింహాసనాన్ని అధిష్టించక పూర్వం ఉజ్జయిని పాలకుడుగా పనిచేసి పరిపాలనానుభవాన్ని గడించాడు. పట్టాభిషేకం జరుపుకున్న 9 సంవత్సరాలకు (క్రీ.పూ. 261) సామ్రాజ్య విస్తరణకాంక్షతో కళింగపై దండెత్తాడు. అందుకు కారణం మగధ సామ్రాజ్యంలో భాగంగా వున్న కళింగ, నందరాజుల పతనంతో స్వతంత్రించింది. పైగా దక్షిణ భారతదేశానికి వున్న, భూ, జల మార్గాలు కళింగ ద్వారా వుండటం వల్ల దానిని స్వాధీనం చేసుకోదలిచాడు. క్రీ.పూ. 261లో జరిగిన కళింగ యుద్ధంలో లక్షమంది హతులైనట్లు, లక్షన్నర మంది ఖైదీలుగా పట్టుబడినట్లు అశోకుడు తన 13వ శిలాశాసనంలో పేర్కొన్నాడు. ఈ విజయంతో కళింగ మౌర్య సామ్రాజ్యంలో అంతర్భాగమైంది. కళింగ యుద్ధం అశోకునిలో వినూత్నమైన హృదయ పరివర్తనను తెచ్చింది. చండాశోకుడు ధర్మాశోకుడుగా మారాడు. ఇకముందు యుద్ధాలు చేయకూడదని, ధర్మప్రచారం, ప్రజాసంక్షేమం కోసం పాటుపడాలని నిశ్చయించుకొన్నాడు. ఉపగుప్తుడనే బౌద్ధమతాచార్యుని వద్ద బౌద్ధమత దీక్ష తీసుకున్నాడు. రెండు సంవత్సరాల తరువాత బౌద్ధ భిక్షువుగా మారి బుద్ధగయ, లుంబిని, కపిలవస్తు, శ్రావస్తి, కుశ నగరాలను సందర్శించాడు. బౌద్ధభిక్షువుగానే రాజ్యభారాన్ని నిర్వహించాడు.సామ్రాజ్య విస్తీర్ణం: అశోకుని సామ్రాజ్యం సువిశాలమైనది. తమిళనాడు, అస్సాం ప్రాంతాలు మినహా మిగిలిన భారతదేశమంతా అశోకుని సామ్రాజ్యంలో భాగంగా వుంది. భారతదేశం వెలుపలి ప్రాంతాలైన కాబూల్, కాందహార్, హీరత్, బెలూచిస్థాన్లు ఇతని సామ్రాజ్యంలో చేరివున్నాయి.బౌద్ధమత వ్యాప్తి: బౌద్ధమతాన్ని స్వీకరించిన తరువాత అశోకుడు స్వదేశంలోను, విదేశాల్లోను బౌద్ధధర్మ ప్రచారం కోసం సంఘాలను ఏర్పాటు చేశాడు. బౌద్ధ ధర్మసూత్రాలను శిలలు, స్తంభాలపై చెక్కించి జనసమ్మర్ధ ప్రదేశాలలో, యాత్రాస్థలాల్లో వాటిని నెలకొల్పాడు. అహింసా సిద్ధాంతానికి అనుగుణంగా జంతు బలులు, వేటలు, మాంసాహార వంటకాలను నిషేధించాడు. పాటలీపుత్రంలో మూడవ బౌద్ధ సమావేశాన్ని ఏర్పాటు చేశాడు. ధర్మబోధన చేయటానికి ధర్మ మహామాత్రులనే ప్రత్యేక అధికారులను నియమించాడు. మత ప్రచారకులను ఈజిప్టు, మాసిడోనియా, సైప్రస్, ఎపిరస్ మొదలైన దేశాలకు పంపాడు.అశోకుని ధర్మం: తన సామ్రాజ్య పటిష్టత కోసం అశోకుడు ఒక ధర్మాన్ని ప్రవచించాడు. అశోకుని ఆదర్శాలు, ఆలోచనలు అశోకుని ధర్మంలో కనిపిస్తాయి. అన్ని మతాల మహోన్నత ఆదర్శాలకు ఈ ధర్మం అద్దంపడుతుంది. ఈ ధర్మసూత్రాల్లో ప్రధానమైనవి: జీవహింస చేయరాదు. ఇతరుల విశ్వాసాలు, భావాలపట్ల సహనాన్ని చూపాలి. సర్వప్రాణులపట్ల కరుణ, జాలి చూపాలి. బానిసలు, సేవకుల పట్ల దయతో మెలగాలి. గృహస్థులను, బ్రాహ్మణులను, సన్యాసులను దయతో సత్కరించాలి. వారికి ధనసహాయాన్ని చెయ్యాలి. మాటలను అదుపులో పెట్టుకొని ఇతరుల మతాన్ని గౌరవించటం ద్వారానే తమ మతాన్ని, మత పలుకుబడిని పెంచుకోవాలి. ఈ సార్వజనీనమైన సూత్రాలను ఆచరించినట్లయితే మానవుడు సత్ప్రవర్తన, నైతికతలను సాధించి మోక్షాన్ని పొందుతాడు.అశోకుని పరిపాలన: అశోకుడు తన సామ్రాజ్యంలో రాష్ట్రస్థాయిలో పరిపాలనా వికేంద్రీకరణను ప్రవేశపెట్టాడు. పరిపాలనలో అతనికి యువరాజు, రాజకుమారుడు, కుమార, ఆర్యపుత్ర మొదలైనవారు సహాయపడేవారు. తక్షశిల, ఉజ్జయిని, వైశాలిలను రాష్ట్రాలకు కేంద్రాలుగా చేసి వాటికి కుమారులను రాష్ట్రపాలకులుగా నియమించాడు. రాజ్య వ్యవహారాల్లో రాజుదే తుదినిర్ణయం. న్యాయవిచారణలో అశోకుడు న్యాయమూర్తుల జాగు, అసహనాలను తొలగించి ప్రశంసనీయమైన మార్పులను ప్రవేశపెట్టాడు."},{"question":"Bu metin hangi önemli olayla ilgilidir: Kamu Yatırım Fonu yıllık olarak Riyad'daki Suudi Arabistan'ın 2030 Vizyonu kapsamında bir yatırım forumu, Gelecek Yatırım Girişimi veya “Çölde Davos” düzenlemektedir. Bununla birlikte Suudi Arabistan'ın, Cemal Kaşıkçı cinayetine karışması nedeniyle artan tartışma ve artan gerilimlerin ortasında, birçok üst düzey şirketin CEO’su konferanstan vazgeçti. Google Cloud, KKR &amp; Co. L.P., Ford Motor, JPMorgan Chase, BlackRock, Uber ve The Blackstone Group, 23 Ekim 2018'de yapılacak olan zirveden CEO / Başkan isimlerini geri çekti. CNN, Bloomberg, CNBC, \\"The New York Times\\", Fox Business Network, \\"Financial Times\\", \\"Los Angeles Times\\" ve \\"Huffington Post\\" gibi büyük medya kuruluşları da ortak olarak geri çekildi.","answer":"cinayetine"},{"question":"Afaka mandrefy ny fihetseham-po ara-tsiansa ve isika?","answer":"Eny, mampiasa fomba isan-karazany ny mpahay siansa, toy ny fanontana fanontaniana, fandinihana ny ati-doha, ary fandrefesana ara-batana, mba hanombanana sy handrefesana ny fihetseham-po."},{"question":"Iwọde SARS l’Ekoo: Awọn ṣọja binu si Sanwo-Olu patapata!","answer":"Bi Gomina ipinlẹ Eko, Babajide Sanwo-Olu, ba mọ pe bi ọrọ igbimọ ti oun gbe dide yoo ti pada ja si niyi, boya ni yoo gbe igbimọ kankan dide lori iwọde SARS to ṣẹlẹ loṣu to kọja, niṣe ni iba dakẹ jẹẹjẹ bii omi adagun. Ṣugbọn nitori ko jọ pe ọrọ naa ye gomina yii lati ibẹrẹ, o si ti ro pe ohun ti wọn le fi eto ati ọgbọn ijọba bo gbogbo ohun to ṣẹlẹ mọlẹ ni, o gbe igbimọ kan dide lati wadii ohun to fa rogbodiyan iwọde SARS, ohun ti awọn ọdọ n fẹ ati ohun ti awọn le ṣe. Igbimọ yii ti waa di nnkan mi-in si i lọrun bayii ṣaa o, nitori awọn aṣiri to n tu niwaju igbimọ naa lojoojumọ ti sọ Sanwo-Olu ati awọn ṣọja di ọta ara wọn, boya ni ajọṣẹ gidi kan yoo ti aarin wọn jade mọ, nitori bi awọn ṣọja ṣe n binu si ọkunrin gomina yii, bẹẹ ni gomina naa n binu si wọn. Ṣugbọn apa gomina ko ka ṣọja, nitori ko si ohun ti oromọdiẹ yoo fi ẹyẹ aṣa ṣe.Awọn ṣọja n binu, wọn ni Sanwo-Olu purọ mọ awọn ni gbangba, o doju ti awọn pe oun ko mọ bi awọn ṣe de too-geeti ni Lẹkki, bẹẹ oun lo ranṣẹ pe awọn. Sanwo-Olu naa n binu pe ọrọ yii, ọrọ awo ni, ki i ṣe ohun to yẹ ko lu jade rara, bawo lawọn olori ologun yoo ṣe waa maa tu aṣiri ohun ti awo ṣe. Ṣugbọn awọn ologun ti wọn jade mọ ohun ti wọn n ṣe, wọn mọ pe bi ọrọ naa ti ri yii, bi awọn ko ba jade sọrọ soke, to ba di lọjọ iwaju, ti awọn ile-ẹjọ agbaye ba ko iwe aṣiṣe tawọn ṣe kalẹ fawọn, ati Buhari ati awọn olori ṣọja pata, gbogbo wọn le fara gba a, ti wọn yoo dero ẹwọn, iyẹn bi ile-ẹjọ agbaye yii ko ba ni ki wọn yẹgi fun wọn, nitori pe wọn mọ bi awọn ṣọja kan ti yinbọn pa awọn eeyan ti wọn ṣewọde, awọn ti wọn ko mu ohun ija dani, ti wọn ko si fajangbọn, to jẹ nibi ti wọn jokoo si jẹẹjẹ lawọn ṣọja ti lọọ bawọn.Ọrọ ti burẹkẹ bayii ṣaa o, awọn ṣọja ti jade wa siwaju igbimọ, wọn ti ṣalaye ọrọ, kaluku si ti mọ ohun ti wọn jọ se ti ile fi jona. Ṣugbọn awọn aṣiri kan ṣi wa ti ko ti i tu sita tan. Bo tilẹ jẹ awọn ṣọja yii gba pe awọn wa nibẹ, awọn lọ si too-geeti ni Lẹkki lati tu awọn ọdọ ti wọn n ṣe iwọde naa ka, sibẹ lojoojumọ lawọn ṣọja yii n ta ku pe awọn kọ lawọn yinbọn nibi iṣẹlẹ naa, ati pe ẹnikẹni ko ku nibẹ. Bẹẹ gomina Sanwo-Olu funra ẹ ti gba pe oun ri oku meji, oun si de ọsibitu funra oun lati ri ọpọlọpọ awọn ti ibọn ba nibi oju ija yii, o si sọ fawọn oniroyin pe gẹgẹ bii fidio ti oun ri, awọn ṣọja lo yinbọn. Yatọ si eyi, girangiran ni awọn ọta ibọn kun ibi ti wọn ti da gbogbo ẹ ru ni too-geeti yii, awọn onimọ si ti ni ọta ibọn naa ki i ṣe tawọn ọdaran, o jọ tawọn ologun Naijiria daadaa. Ta lo waa yinbọn o, eeyan meloo lo si ku? Ta lo pa wọn? Lara awọn iṣoro to wa niwaju igbimọ yii niyẹn.Yoo ṣoro ki ọrọ yii too niyanju pata o. Ohun to mu ki ọrọ naa yanju de ibi to de yii ni pe ki i ṣe lẹyin ti wọn fa wahala ni Lẹkki ni ijọba ipinlẹ Eko gbe igbimọ dide. Nigba togun naa ti n le, ti awọn ọdọ yii ni awọn ko gba rara mọ, ti wọn n gbegi dina ni marosẹ, ti wọn tẹdo si Lẹkki ati Sẹkiteeria ni Alausa, ti wọn ko si jẹ ki awọn onimọto lọ, nigba naa ni ijọba ipinlẹ Eko ti sare gbe igbimọ yii dide, ọjọ kọkandinlogun, oṣu kẹwaa, ni wọn si ṣe ifilọlẹ igbimọ naa, ti ijọba ni ki wọn tete bẹrẹ iṣẹ wọn. Adajọ Doris Okuwobi ni wọn fi ṣe olori igbimọ naa, wọn si ko awọn meje mi-in ti i, wọn ni ki wọn fi oṣu mẹfa ṣe iṣẹ wọn. Ijọba ni oun fẹẹ mọ ohun to n bi awọn ọdọ yii ninu lori ọrọ SARS, oun fẹ ki awọn ọdọ mu amọran wa lori ohun ti ijọba yoo ṣe ti iru iwọde bayii ko fi ni i waye mọ, oun si fẹ ki kaluku jade wa ki wọn waa sọ ohun ti awọn ọlọpaa SARS yii ṣe fawọn gan-an.Afi bii ẹni pe ọrọ naa daru mọ ijọba Sanwo-Olu funra ẹ loju, nitori lọjọ keji to gbe igbimọ yii dide, ọjọ naa jẹ ogunjọ, oṣu kẹwaa, niṣe nijọba kede lojiji pe awọn yoo bẹrẹ ofin konilegbele jake-jado ipinlẹ Eko, ati pe ofin naa yoo bẹrẹ ni deede aago mẹrin irọlẹ ọjọ naa, ki kaluku tete gba ile ẹ lọ. Ọrọ naa ba awọn eeyan lojiji, nitori wọn ko ro o ti rara, awọn ti wọn si ti wa ọna kan tabi omi-in de ibi iṣẹ wọn ko mọ bi wọn yoo ṣe sare pada wa sile koo to di aago mẹrin irọlẹ ti ijọba da, nitori ni bii aago kan ọṣan ni wọn ṣe ikede naa. N lọrọ ba di girigiri, kaluku n wa ọna bi yoo ti ṣe dele. Nirọlẹ ọjọ naa, ni bii aago mẹfa aabọ si meje lalẹ ni awọn ṣọja de si Lẹkki. Bi wọn si ti debẹ ni iro ibọn bẹrẹ si i ṣẹlẹ, ni ọrọ ba di bo o lọ o ya, oku bẹrẹ si i sun kaakiri.Lẹyin ti wọn ti da wahala silẹ ni ọjọ yii, ọrọ naa fẹju si i lọjọ keji, awọn ọdọ kan binu, wọn dana sun awọn ile ati ileeṣẹ awọn eeyan ti wọn ro pe wọn lọwọ si idaamu awọn, ati awọn oloṣelu kọọkan, nigba naa ni awọn janduku si yi wọ aarin wọn, ti wọn gba ọrọ naa kanri, awọn si lo iṣẹlẹ naa lati fi da wahala silẹ ati lati fi jale kaakiri. Nigba ti wọn yoo fi pana ọrọ naa, nnkan ti bajẹ kọja kekere. Eyi mu ki iṣẹ igbimọ ti Sanwo-Olu gbe dide yii ya kiakia, nitori wọn ko duro mọ, wọn bẹrẹ iṣẹ lẹsẹkẹsẹ ni. Ohun to si fa eyi ko ju pe ijọba fẹẹ fi han gbogbo aye pe awọn ti mura si ọrọ naa, awọn si ti fẹẹ wadii ohun to ṣẹlẹ, pe ki kaluku fọkanbalẹ, awọn yoo ridii okodoro.Ni bii ọjọ kẹrin iṣẹlẹ yii ni igbimọ naa ti jokoo, ti wọn ti ni ki awọn eeyan maa mu ẹri wọn wa, nitori iṣẹ ti bẹrẹ loju mejeeji niyẹn.Ko too digba yii, Sanwo-Olu ti jade to ni oun kọ loun ran awọn ṣọja niṣẹ, oun ko tilẹ mọ kinni kan nipa ẹ, awọn to lagbara ju oun lọ lo wa nidii ọrọ naa o. Ileeeṣẹ ologun paapaa sare jade, awọn naa ni awọn ko mọ kinni kan nipa ẹ o, awọn ko tilẹ debẹ rara, iṣẹ awọn lawọn n ṣe ni baraaki awọn, ko sẹni to mọ ohun to ṣẹlẹ ni Lẹkki. Ṣugbọn nigba ti ọmọbinrin oṣere kan, Obianuju Udeh (DJ Switch) jade pẹlu fidio tirẹ, to fi awọn ṣọja han nibi iṣẹlẹ naa ni gbogbo igba ti ibọn n ro, to fawọn ṣọja han nibi ti wọn ti n sare kiri ati nibi ti awọn eeyan ti n gbe oku to ku, to si ṣalaye pe oun ri awọn ṣọja ti wọn n ko awọn oku sinu mọto wọn, ti ileeṣẹ ajafẹtọọ-ọmọniyan agbaye, Amnesty International, si tu aṣiri bi awọn ṣọja ṣe rin lati Bonny Camp l’Ekoo de too-geeti Lẹkki, awọn ologun naa ri i pe aṣiri ti tu patapata.Ohun to jẹ ki awọn jẹwọ niyẹn o, ki i ṣe pe wọn fẹẹ jẹwọ tẹlẹ. Nigba ti fidio ọmọbinrin yii jade, wọn wa a titi ki wọn mu un, wọn le e kirakira, ṣugbọn wọn ko ri i, nitori ọmọbinrin ohun ti ra mọ wọn loju ki wọn too mọ ijamba to ṣe fun wọn. Ibinu ọrọ yii, ati alaye ti Sanwo-Olu funra ẹ ṣe pe awọn ṣọja lo yinbọn ninu fidio, oun foju ara oun ri oku meji, lo jẹ ki awọn ṣọja jade, ti wọn fi jẹwọ pe loootọ lawọn lọ sibi iṣẹlẹ Lẹkki, ṣugbọn Gomina Sanwo-Olu funra ẹ lo ranṣẹ pe awọn, ṣugbọn awọn ko yinbọn pa ẹnikẹni ni tawọn o. Bawo ni ṣọja yoo ṣe lọ sibi kan ti ko ni i yinbọn, awọn oku ti wọn si ku yii nkọ? Ta lo pa wọn, ati pe nibo lawọn oku naa wa gan-an, nitori nigba ti ilẹ ọjọ keji yoo fi mọ, ko sẹni to ri oku nibi kan, bẹẹ fidio yii ṣafihan awọn oku to ku, ọmọbinrin to ya fidio naa si ṣalaye pe oun ri awọn ṣọja ti wọn n fi ọkọ gbọọrọ wọn ko awọn oku lọ. Nibi ni iṣẹ igbimọ yii ti bẹrẹ.Nitori pe ẹri to wa niwaju wọn fi han pe ogunlọgọ awọn eeyan lo ku, ohun ti wọn kọ fẹẹ wadii ni ibi ti awọn oku naa wa, ki wọn si le mọ ibi ti wọn yoo ti ri wọn ati iru awọn eeyan ti wọn jẹ gan-an. Nibi yii ni igbimọ naa ti kọkọ ni iṣoro pẹlu awọn ṣọja, nitori ọrọ naa di wahala diẹ ki wọn too wọle si ọsibitu awọn ologun yii l’Ekoo. Ko too digba naa, awọn igbimọ yii ti kọwe si awọn ṣọja pe ki wọn waa ṣalaye niwaju igbimọ bi ọrọ ti ri, nigba to jẹ awọn naa ti jẹwọ bayii pe awọn wa ni Lẹkki, nibi ti ina ibọn ti n dahun lori awọn ọdọ ti wọn n sẹwọde. Wọn ni nibi ti ọrọ de duro naa, afi ki awọn ṣọja yii jade wa lati sọ tẹnu wọn, ki wọn waa ṣalaye bo ti jẹ ijọba ipinlẹ Eko lo pe wọn, ki wọn si sọ ohun ti wọn ṣe gan-an. N lawọn ṣọja ba yari, wọn ni awọn ko ni i jẹ iru ipe bẹẹ, pe awọn ko ni i yọju sigbimọ kan.Alaye ti Niyi Ọṣọba, Alukoro fun ileeṣẹ awọn ologun ọwọ kọkanlelọgorin (81 Division) ti ọrọ yii kan ṣe ni pe awọn ko ni kinni kan ti awọn fẹẹ ṣe niwaju igbimọ, nitori ki i ṣe igbimọ lo ran awọn niṣẹ. Wọn ni ijọba Eko lo ran awọn, awọn ni wọn pe awọn ki awọn waa ba wọn le awọn ọdọ to n da ilu laamu naa kuro nibi ti wọn wa, bo ba si waa di pe ọrọ ti dewaju igbimọ, ijọba Eko to ran awọn niṣẹ naa ni yoo pada waa pe awọn pe ki awọn yọju sibẹ, lẹta ni wọn si gbọdo kọ. O jọ pe lẹyin tawọn ṣọja sọrọ yii, lẹta jade sọwọ awọn ọga wọn loootọ lati ọdọ ịjọba, n lawọn ṣọja yii ba gba lati yọju siwaju igbimọ, wọn lawọn n bọ waa sọ tẹnu awọn naa, ko too di pe wọn parọ ti ki i ṣe tawọn mọ awọn. Nigba to si di ọjọ keje, oṣu kọkanla, ti a wa yii, awọn ọga ṣọja lati 81 Division yii yọju siwaju igbimọ to n wadii iṣẹlẹ SARS.Awọn mẹrin ni wọn yọju lọjọ naa, awọn ti 65 Batallion lo wa sibẹ, nitori awọn gan-an ni wọn ni wọn lọ sibi iṣẹlẹ naa. Awọn naa kọwe tiwọn dani, ẹni to si ṣaaju wọn, Musa Etsu-Ndagi, sọ pe Gomina Sanwo-Olu gan-an lo pe oun ni bii aago meje aabọ alẹ ọjọ naa, to ni awọn ṣọja n yinbọn ni Lẹkki. O ni gomina kan sọ foun pe ọga ṣọja kan ti wọn pe ni Bello lati 65 Batallion ni Bonny Camp lo wa nidii ọrọ yii o,  oun lo ṣaaju awọn to n yinbọn. Etsu-Ndagi ni lẹsẹkẹsẹ loun ti pe Bello, ti oun si beere pe ki lo de to n yinbọn ni too-geeti. O ni niṣe ni Bello kọ ‘haa’, to ni awọn ko ma yinbọn lu ẹnikẹni o, ofurufu lawọn n yinbọn awọn si. Niwaju igbimọ yii naa, wọn pe Bello funra ẹ ko waa sọrọ, n loun naa ba sọ pe ki wọn ma da awọn ti wọn n gbe rumọọsi (ahesọ) kiri lohun, o ni loootọ lawọn wa ni Lẹkki yii, ṣugbọn awọn ko yinbọn lu ẹnikẹni.Nigba ti Bello yoo kuku tilẹ fa ọrọ naa ya, o ni inu awọn ọdọ ti wọn n ṣe iwọde naa dun gan-an nigba ti wọn ri awọn ṣọja ti wọn debẹ. “Ẹ wo o, nigba ti a debẹ, niṣe ni inu awọn ọdọ ti wọn n ṣewọde naa n dun ṣinkin, emi funra mi ni mo si n fun wọn ni piọwọta ti wọn n mu. Mo n bẹ wọn ni, pe ki gbogbo wọn waa maa lọ sile nitori kọfiu ti ijọba ti ṣe, gbogbo wọn si gba si mi lẹnu, wọn n lọ sile wọn wọọrọ. Afi bi awọn janduku kan ṣe bẹ de, ti wọn da wahala bolẹ, ti wọn fẹẹ maa ṣe awọn eeyan leṣe. Nibi ti a ti mura lati gba awọn eeyan naa silẹ ree. Bi ọrọ naa si ti le to, awa ko yinbọn kankan lu ẹni kan o, gbogbo ibọn ti a n yin, oke ni a n yin in si, ka fi le le awọn janduku naa lọ ni! Ko si ootọ ninu awọn ti wọn n gbe ọrọ kiri pe awọn ri oku, tabi pe awa n fi mọto wa ko awọn oku. Wọn n fiyẹn ba wa jẹ lasan ni!”Bayii ni awọn yii rojọ lọjọ naa ti wọn si ba tiwọn lọ. Ṣugbọn ẹjọ naa ri bakan loju awọn ti wọn n gbọ o, nitori ọrọ ti wọn sọ yatọ pata si ohun ti awọn eeyan ti ri lori fidio, ati bi wọn ti ri awọn ṣọja nibẹ ti wọn n le awọn eeyan kiri, ti iro ibọn si n dun lakọlakọ. Nitori ẹ lawọn igbimọ naa ṣe ni awọn ṣi n reti awọn ọga ṣọja mi-in si i, nitori ọrọ naa ko ti i debi ti awọn ti le ri gbogbo okodoro ti awọn n wa kiri. Eyi lo si ṣẹlẹ lọjọ Satide to lọ yii, nigba ti awọn ọga ṣọja wa lati 81 Division, lọjọ naa ni gbẹgẹdẹ gbina taara, aṣiri ọrọ si jade ju ti tẹlẹ lọ. Birigedia Ahmed Taiwo lo ṣaaju wọn wa, oun naa si ba awọn ọmọ igbimọ naa ti wọn duro sẹpẹsẹpẹ. Ko pẹ ti wọn de ti wọn fi bẹrẹ si i tu kẹkẹ ọrọ, bo si tilẹ jẹ pe ọrọ rẹ naa ko fi bẹẹ yatọ si ti awọn ti wọn sọrọ tẹlẹ, to si ko ijọba Eko siyọnu, agaga Gomina Sanwo-Olu.Ọgagun Taiwo ni ki oun sọ tootọ fun gbogbo awọn ti wọn jokoo, inu awọn olori ṣọja ko dun rara si Gomina Sanwo-Olu. O ni ohun to si n bi awọn ọga yii ninu ni pe Sanwo-Olu purọ mọ awọn ni gbangba, o si sẹ awọn loju gbogbo aye. Taiwo ni ko sohun ti i ba kan awọn ninu ọrọ yii bi ko ba jẹ gomina naa ko ranṣẹ pe awọn ni. O ni ki gbogbo awọn ti wọn jokoo gbọ, ko si ohun to buru ninu ki nnkan ṣẹlẹ ki gomina ranṣẹ pe awọn alaabo to ba mọ pe wọn le yanju ọrọ naa kiakia, nitori bẹẹ, ohun to yẹ ki Sanwo-Olu ṣe naa lo ṣe yẹn. Ṣugbọn lati waa maa purọ ni gbangba pe ko sẹni to ran awọn ṣọja niṣẹ, oun ko mọ bi wọn ti debẹ, oga awọn ṣọja naa ni ọrọ naa fa ibinu yọ fawọn gan-an ni. N lo ba bẹrẹ si i ṣalaye bi ọrọ naa ti jẹ nikọọkan, ati bi kinni naa ṣe kan awọn ṣọja to wa nibẹ, iyẹn ni Bonny Camp.O ni nigba ti wahala ọrọ yii bẹrẹ si i fẹju, ẹni ti Sanwo-Olu gbiyanju lati ri ba sọrọ ni Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari, ṣugbọn ko tete ri i ba sọrọ nigba naa, nigba ti ipa rẹ lori igbiyanju naa si pin lo lọọ ba olori awọn oṣiṣẹ nileeṣẹ Aarẹ sọrọ, to sọ ohun to n lọ l’Ekoo fun un. Iyẹn ni ko ni suuru foun, oun yoo fun un lesi laipẹ, ṣugbọn ko jọ pe o ri esi gidi mu wa lasiko, ohun to jẹ ki Sanwo-Olu funra ẹ pe ọga awọn ṣọja pata niyẹn, iyẹn Burutai. Taiwo loun mọ daadaa pe Sanwo-Olu ti pe Buratai ko too di pe o tilẹ ba awọn sọrọ rara. O ni nigba ti awọn gba ipe gomina yii, ti awọn si mura lati ba a ṣe ohun to bẹ awọn, ko si awọn ṣọja ti awọn yoo lo nilẹ, funra olori awọn ologun yii, iyẹn Buratai, lo faṣẹ si i pe ki awọn lọọ ko awọn ọmọọṣe ologun kan ti wọn wa ni ileewe ẹkọṣẹ ologun, pe ki wọn lọọ yanju ọrọ naa.Lorọ kan, gẹgẹ bii Ọgagun Taiwo yii ti wi, ki i ṣe awọn ṣọja ti wọn ti n ṣiṣẹ tẹlẹ ni wọn ko lọ sibẹ, awọn ọmọ ẹkọṣe ologun ni. O ni iyẹn lo fa a ti awọn ko fi ko ọta sinu ibọn wọn, ti awọn kan sọ fun wọn pe ki wọn maa yinbọn soke lasan, ki wọn le fi le awọn eeyan naa lọ nibẹ ni. Taiwo ni ohun to dun awọn ju ni pe Sanwo-Olu tun ni oun ri awọn eeyan to ku, bẹẹ awọn meji to ku yii, ẹni kan ti wọn ri ni ọna Admiralty Way, ni bii maili mẹta si too-geti ni Lẹkki ni, bẹẹ ki i ṣe ọta ibọn lo pa iyẹn, wahala ni wọn lo pa a. Ẹni keji to tun ni oun ri lọsibitu to ku, ki i ṣe Lẹkki ni wọn ti gbe e wa, Yaba ni wọn ti gbe oun wa. O ni ko si ẹni to ri oku nibi kan, nitori awọn ṣọja tawọn ko yinbọn paayan, ko si si oku rẹpẹtẹ to sun ni Lẹkki. Taiwo ni ki ọrọ naa le ye gbogbo eeyan loun ṣe jade, ki wọn si mọ pe inu n bi awọn si gomina to purọ mọ awọn.Ohun to ṣẹlẹ bayii ni pe kaka ki ọrọ naa niyanju, o tubọ n fọ loju si i ni. Gbogbo eeyan agbaye lo ri i pe oku sun ni Lẹkki; nitori awọn fidio ti wọn ri ati awọn ti kinni naa ṣẹlẹ loju wọn; awọn ṣọja ti wọn ni awọn ko debẹ tẹlẹ ti gba pe awọn debẹ bayii, ṣugbọn awọn ko yinbọn; Gomina Sanwo-Olu to sọ pe oun ko ran ṣọja niṣẹ ko sọrọ mọ lati ọjọ ti awọn yẹn ti tu aṣiri pe oun lo ran awọn; ni bayii, awọn ṣọja ti binu si gomina patapata, wọn lo purọ mọ awọn. Ta ni yoo waa ba wọn yanju ẹ? Nibo lọrọ naa yoo yọri si? Wọn wa lẹnu ẹ o!"},{"question":"意大利是用什麼貨幣？","answer":"使用歐元。"},{"question":"请用简洁的语言回答以下问题：问题：人类学研究对解决现实问题有什么帮助？","answer":"答案：人类学研究可以提供实地数据和深入理解，帮助解决诸如社会冲突、文化保护、发展项目等现实问题。"},{"question":"Wanene gwamnan soja na farko a jihar Kano?","answer":"Audu Bako"},{"question":"Hacettepe Üniversitesi Erasmus hangi ülkeler?","answer":"İspanya, Fransa, İsveç, Hollanda, Portekiz, Slovakya, Macaristan, Romanya, Norveç, Almanya, Polonya, Yunanistan, Malta, Belçika, Avusturya, Letonya, Danimarka, Çek Cumhuriyeti, Bulgaristan, İzlanda, İrlanda, Hollanda, Portekiz, Slovakya, İngiltere, İtalya."},{"question":"Ụmị anụ","answer":"Olundị - utoro"},{"question":"Bawọn gomina Guusu ṣe sọ pe ọdọ awọn ni aarẹ yoo ti wa ni 2023 lodi sofin Naijiria-Awọn gomina ilẹ Hausa","answer":"Ipade ti awọn gomina mọkandinlogun lati ilẹ Hausa ṣe lọjọ Mọnde ọsẹ yii ki i ṣe lasan, niṣe ni wọn fi i koro oju si awọn gomina ẹkun Guusu ti wọn ni apa ọdọ awọn ni aarẹ yoo ti wa ni 2023. Bẹẹ ni wọn si binu si ipinnu awọn gomina Guusu to fẹẹ maa gba owo-ori ọja ta a mọ si VAT, wọn ni ipinnu ti ko lẹsẹ nilẹ ni.Bi ipade wọn naa ṣe jẹ pajawiri to, to jẹ ojiji ni wọn sare ṣa ara wọn jọ, sibẹ, awọn gomina Oke-Ọya mọkandinlogun naa fẹnu ko, pẹlu Sultan Sokoto, Muhammadu Abubakar kẹta to wa nikalẹ, wọn lawọn ko fara mọ aba awọn gomina Guusu, pe apa ọdọ wọn ni ki aarẹ ti wa ni 2023.Awọn gomina ilẹ Hausa yii ṣalaye pe bawọn gomina Guusu ṣe sọ pe ọdọ awọn ni aarẹ yoo ti wa ni 2023, lodi si ofin ilẹ Naijiria.Wọn ni ohun ti ofin sọ ni pe ẹni to ba ni ibo to pọ ju ni yoo di aarẹ, ibi to ti wa ko ni nnkan kan i ṣe, iye ibo to ba ni lo ṣe pataki. Fun idi eyi, wọn ni ipade ẹẹmeji tawọn gomina mẹtadinlogun ẹkun Guusu ṣe lori eyi ko wulo lọdọ tawọn, awọn ko fara mọ ọn.Ni ti owo-ori ọja (VAT) to ti n ja ran-in-ran-in nilẹ lati ọsẹ meloo kan sẹyin, awọn gomina ilẹ Hausa yii sọ pe aba ti awọn ti Guusu n da, pe awọn lawọn yoo maa gba owo naa ko daa.Wọn ni ojuṣe ijọba apapọ ni owo-ori ọja, to ba di pe ipinlẹ n gba a, awọn to n ra ọja ni iya rẹ yoo jẹ.Wọn ni fun apẹẹrẹ, owo-ori ọja yii yatọ sawọn  owo ori yooku.Wọn ni nigba to jẹ awọn onraja lo n san owo yii mọ ọja ti wọn ba ra, to ba lọọ ṣe bẹẹ bọ sọwọ ijọba ipinlẹ, niṣe lawọn ọja yoo wọn buruku, ti inira yoo si ba awọn eeyan to n ra ọja, nitori owo-ori ọja ti wọn ni lati san fun ipinlẹ wọn nikan ṣoṣo yii yoo pọ ju, yatọ si ijọba apapọ to jẹ pe o ni agbara lati gba awọn onraja kalẹ lọwọ inira.Nipa pe ilu Eko nikan lo n pese ida aadọta (50%) ninu owo-ori ọja ti ijọba apapọ n pin fawọn ilu yooku, awọn gomina yii sọ pe ko sohun to fa a ju pe Eko ni awọn olu ileeṣẹ nla-nla pọ si lọ.Wọn ni awọn ileeṣẹ ẹlẹrọ ibaraẹnisọrọ, awọn banki, awọn ileeṣẹ to n pese nnkan eelo ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ to pọ l’Ekoo lo fa a, Eko si n gba owo ti ko yẹ ki wọn maa gba lọwọ wọn ni.Ṣa, awọn gomina ati ọba ilẹ Hausa yii sọ pe ni tawọn, afi bi ile-ẹjọ to ga ju lọ ba yanju ọrọ ti VAT yii,  nitori ọrọ naa ṣi wa nile ẹjọ, awọn ko ni i tẹle aba awọn ti Guusu, ka ma ri i."},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε το κείμενο - Ο πρίγκιπας Ζυλ ντε Πολινιάκ, 3ος Δούκας του Πολινιάκ (Auguste Jules Armand Mari de Polignac Γαλλική προφορά: ​[ʒyl.də.pɔ.li.ɲak], 14 Μαΐου 1780 - 2 Μαρτίου 1847 ), ήταν Γάλλος πολιτικός. Ήταν ένας εξαιρετικά βασιλόφρων πολιτικός μετά την Επανάσταση και πρωθυπουργός υπό από τον Κάρολο Ι΄ λίγο πριν την Ιουλιανή Επανάσταση","answer":"του 1830 που ανέτρεψε τη δυναστεία των Βουρβόνων."},{"question":"Табышмак деген эмне ?","answer":"Табышмак — дүйнөдөгү бардык эле элдердин оозеки чыгармачылыгында кеңири учураган жанрлардын бири. Табышмактар деп кандайдыр бир затты, көрүнүштү же башка абстракттуу түшүнүктөрдү өз аты менен атабай, алардын негизги белгилерин айтып, ошол түшүнүктүн аталышын башка бирөөлөрдун табуусун талап кылган чакан тапшырмалар. Мисалы: «Асты таш, үстү таш, ортосунда бышкан аш» деген табышмактын жообу «данек» болууга тийиш. Анткени анда данектин негизги белгилери көрсөтүлүп жатат. Кыргыз фольклорунда мазмуну, композициялык курулушу, түзүлүшү боюнча табышмактар төмөнкүдөй формаларда, көрүнүштөрдө айтылып келген: 1) Ритмдүү жорго сөз түрүндөгү табышмактар; 2) Ыр түрүндөгү табышмактар; 3) Учкул сөздөн турган, прозалык формадагы табышмактар; 4) Суроолуу табышмактар; 5) Айтыш табышмактары; 6) Жомок түрүндөгү табышмактар; 7) Эсеп табышмактары. Жаштарды байкагычтыкка, акылмандуулукка, изденүүчүлүккө тарбиялоодо табышмактардыи мааниси өтө чоң."},{"question":"சூழலுக்கேற்ற உணர்வைத் தெரிவு செய்க.(சிரிப்பு, மகிழ்ச்சி, வருத்தம், வியப்பு, அச்சம்)பாட்டி புத்தாடை வாங்கித் தரும்போது ஏற்படுவது ________","answer":"விடை : மகிழ்ச்சி"},{"question":"Frase 1: Tres hijos jugaron fútbol americano universitario, Chip en la Universidad Northwestern, Holcomb en la Universidad Purdue y Bryan en la Universidad Estatal de Arizona y la Universidad Estatal de Florida. Frase 2: Los tres hijos de Doug jugaron fútbol americano universitario, Chip en la Universidad Northwestern, Holcomb en la Universidad Purdue y Bryan en la Universidad Estatal de Arizona y la Universidad Estatal de Florida. Pregunta: ¿Expresan la frase 1 y la frase 2 el mismo significado?","answer":"Sí, la frase 1 y la frase 2 expresan el mismo significado. Ambas frases describen que los tres hijos de Doug jugaron fútbol americano universitario, mencionando las mismas universidades en las que jugaron: Chip en la Universidad Northwestern, Holcomb en la Universidad Purdue y Bryan en la Universidad Estatal de Arizona y la Universidad Estatal de Florida."},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 日本とベトナムが交流を始めてから、今年で50年になります。お祝いに、日本とベトナムが一緒にオペラを作ることになりました。オペラは、400年ぐらい前にあったことから作りました。貿易の仕事をしていた荒木宗太郎という人が日本の長崎からベトナムに行って、アニオー姫と結婚した話です。先月、ハノイであったイベントでは、アニオー姫の役の人が、結婚して長崎に来たアニオー姫が遠いベトナムのことを思う歌を歌いました。オペラは、今年9月にハノイで行います。その前に、オペラに出る人たちは長崎に来て、長崎の人たちと交流する予定です。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。"},{"question":"ರಾಣಿ ಅಬ್ಬಕ್ಕ ಬಗ್ಗೆ ಕೆಲವು ಅಂಶಗಳನ್ನ ಬರೆಯಿಯಿರಿ ","answer":"ಅಬ್ಬಕ್ಕ ರಾಣಿ ಅಥವಾ ಅಬ್ಬಕ್ಕ ಮಹಾದೇವಿ ತುಳುನಾಡಿನ ರಾಣಿಯಾಗಿದ್ದಳು. ಇವಳು ೧೬ನೇ ಶತಮಾನದ ದ್ವಿತೀಯಾರ್ಧದಲ್ಲಿ ಪೋರ್ಚುಗೀಸರೊಡನೆ ಹೋರಾಡಿದಳು. ರಾಣಿಯು ದೇವಾಲಯಗಳ ನಗರಿ ಮೂಡುಬಿದಿರೆಯ ಪ್ರದೇಶ ವನ್ನಾಳಿದ ಚೌಟ ವಂಶಕ್ಕೆ ಸೇರಿದವಳು. ಬಂದರು ನಗರಿ ಉಳ್ಳಾಲವು ಈಕೆಯ ರಾಜಧಾನಿಯಾಗಿದ್ದಿತು. ಆಯಕಟ್ಟಿನ ಪ್ರದೇಶವಾದ ಉಳ್ಳಾಲವನ್ನು ವಶಪಡಿಸಿಕೊಳ್ಳಲು ಪೋರ್ಚುಗೀಸರು ಅನೇಕ ಯತ್ನಗಳನ್ನು ನೆಡೆಸಿದರು. ಆದರೆ ರಾಣಿಯು ಅವರ ಪ್ರಯತ್ನವನ್ನು ನಾಲ್ಕು ದಶಕಗಳ ಕಾಲ ಹಿಮ್ಮೆಟ್ಟಿಸಿದಳು. ಅವಳ ಧೈರ್ಯದಿಂದಾಗಿ ಅಭಯ ರಾಣಿ ಎಂದು ಹೆಸರಾಗಿದ್ದಳು.ಈಕೆ ವಸಾಹತುಶಾಹಿಗಳ ವಿರುದ್ಧ ಹೋರಾಡಿದ ಮೊದಲ ಭಾರತೀಯರಲ್ಲಿ ಒಬ್ಬಳು ಮತ್ತು ಮೊದಲ ಮಹಿಳಾ ಸ್ವಾತಂತ್ರ್ಯ ಹೋರಾಟಗಾರ್ತಿ ಆಗಿದ್ದಳು."},{"question":"Мотивация (түрткү) бере турган сөздөр менен бөлүш !","answer":"Жашоо - футбол аянтчасы сыяктуу. Сиз ал жерде судья эмес оюнчу болуңуз. Себеби оюнчу гол киргизүү үчүн жол издейт. Калыс - ката."},{"question":"  Sheeg qofkii ugu hor rumeeyey Rasuulka (N.N.K.H) oo haweeyney ah?","answer":"Waxay aheed hooyo Khadiija Bintu Khuweylad."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ഇന്ത്യയുടെ ദേശീയ മൃഗം ഏതാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ബംഗാൾ കടുവ"},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 高知県いの町では今、とうもろこしがたくさんとれています。枝川地区では毎年今の季節、とうもろこしを売る店が道に並んで「きび街道」と呼ばれています。畑からとったばかりのとうもろこしや、塩を入れてゆでたり、焼いたりしたとうもろこしを売っていて、人気があります。店の人は、1つ1つの粒の味がして、おいしいとうもろこしができていると話しています。4日の日曜日は、朝から100人以上の人がとうもろこしを買いに来ました。ほかの県から来た女性は「朝早く家を出ました。全部で13本買いました。食べるのが楽しみです」と話していました。とうもろこしを売る店は、6月の終わりまで並ぶ予定です。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。- とうもろこし: 1）畑に作る作物。夏、じくの周りにびっしり並んだ黄色い実をたくさんつける。食用や家畜のえさにする。とうきび。コーン。- とれ: 1）はなれて落ちる。2）つかれなどが、なくなる。3）その状態になる。4）取ることができる。5）そう考えられる。6）作物などが得られる。- 畑: 1）野菜や穀物などを作る土地。2）専門とする分野。- ゆで: 1）熱い湯で煮る。うでる。- 人気: 1）世の中の人たちのよい評判。- 粒: 1）小さくて丸いもの。2）集まっているものの、一つ一つの質や大きさ。3）小さくて丸いものを数える言葉。"},{"question":"కార్మికుల, కర్షకుల సౌభాగ్యం అంటే ఏమిటి ? మాట్లాడండి.","answer":"కార్మికులు వారి శ్రమకు తగినట్టుగా ప్రతిఫలాన్ని పొందలేక బాధపడుతున్నారు. కర్షకులు కూడా ఎంతో శ్రమతో, చమటోడ్చి పండించిన పంటలకు తగిన గిట్టుబాటు ధరలు లేక అప్పులపాలవుతున్నాడు.వీరికి ‘సౌభాగ్యం’ అంటే వారికి చేతినిండా పని ఉండి వారు, వారి భార్యాబిడ్డలతో సుఖంగా జీవించగలగడం. పారిశ్రామిక కార్మికులకు యజమానులు శ్రమకు తగిన జీతాలు ఇవ్వడం, కార్మికుల పిల్లలకు విద్యాసదుపాయాలు కలుగజేయడం, కార్మికులకు వైద్యసదుపాయాలు కలుగజేయడం వంటి వాటిని వారి సౌభాగ్యంగా భావించాలి.ఇక వ్యవసాయ కార్మికులకు సంవత్సరమంతటా పని ఉండదు. ఆ పని లేని రోజుల్లో కూడా వారి జీవితం సుఖంగా నడిచే ఏర్పాట్లు అనగా ‘పనికి ఆహార పథకం, రోజ్ గార్ పథకం’ వంటివి ఏర్పాటు చేయడం జరగాలి."},{"question":"\\"අයස්කාන්ත\\" වචනයේ තේරුම පැහැදිලි කරන්න","answer":"වචන තේරුම යකඩවලට ඇදීයන යන්නයි. අයස් කියන්නෙ යකඩ.කාන්ත කියන්නෙ ඇදගන්නා  සුළු.ඒ අනුව අයස්කාන්ත කියන්නේ  යකඩ ඇදගන්නා  චුම්භකයක් හා  මෙන් ඇදගන්නා  සුළු යන්නයි."},{"question":"中國四大菜系中，以醬油和糖的甜味為主的是哪一個菜系？","answer":"以醬油和糖的甜味為主的是閩菜。閩菜是中國四大菜系之一，以其獨特的甜味和糖醬的使用而聞名，口味偏甜且多樣豐富。"},{"question":"\\"لطيف ولكن الغرف الفندقية تحتاج صيانة كادر الخدمة يجب ان يكون بالمستوى المطلوب\\" اعط تقييم من 5 للمراجعة السابقة؟","answer":"كلمة لطيف هى كلمة إيجابية لكن لا تتمتع بقوة المشاعر، و هى فى معظم الأقاويل تمثل صورة منمقة لعبارة \\"لا بأس\\". أيضاً هناك كلمة \\"لكن\\" متبوعة ببعض الملحوظات مما يؤكد العبارة السابقة.يمكننا أن نقول أن أقرب تقييم تمثله المراجعة السابقة هو 3 من 5."},{"question":"Como é que José Saramago explorou a memória e a história nas suas obras?","answer":"José Saramago mergulhou na memória coletiva e história especialmente na obra \\"Memorial do Convento\\". Com uma narrativa que mistura realidade e ficção, ele recria a construção do Convento de Mafra, oferecendo um olhar profundo sobre o passado e a sociedade."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最古老的城市墓地是哪個？","answer":"答案：埃及的金字塔墓地"},{"question":"Ijọba, ẹgbẹ oṣiṣe fọwọ si owo oṣu tuntun l’Ekiti","answer":"Ijọba ipinlẹ Ekiti ati agbarijọpọ ẹgbẹ awọn oṣiṣẹ ti fẹnu ko lori owo oṣu tuntun fun ipele keje si ikẹtala gẹgẹ bi ijororo to ti n lọ tẹlẹ.Lalẹ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee ana, ni wọn tọwọ bọ iwe adehun naa, eyi to wa fun awọn oṣiṣẹ nileeṣẹ ijọba gbogbo, kansu ijọba ibilẹ, awọn oṣiṣẹ eto idajọ ati ti eto ilera.Ninu adehun naa ni wọn ti sọ pe awọn oṣiṣẹ onipele keje si ikẹtala yoo bẹrẹ si i gba afikun owo oṣu tijọba fọwọ si tẹlẹ loṣu yii, gẹgẹ bi wọn ṣe bẹrẹ si i san an fun ipele kin-in-ni si ikẹfa lọdun to kọja. Bakan naa ni wọn fẹnu ko pe ipele kẹtala si ikẹtadinlogun yoo jẹ anfaani ọhun lẹyin ti igbimọ to jẹ akojọpọ awọn aṣoju ẹgbẹ oṣiṣẹ ati tijọba ba ṣeto to yẹ.Ijokoo naa tun pinnu pe ijọba ko gbọdọ fiya jẹ oṣiṣẹ kankan to lọwọ si akitiyan lati ṣe afikun owo oṣu ọhun nitori ipa ti wọn ko, bẹẹ ni wọn ko gbọdọ yọ ẹnikẹni niṣẹ nitori ọrọ naa.Olori oṣiṣẹ, Abilekọ Peju Babafẹmi, pẹlu amugbalẹgbẹẹ gomina lori ọrọ oṣiṣẹ, Comrade Oluyẹmi Ẹsan ati olori ẹka idasilẹ iṣẹ, Ọgbẹni Bayọ Ọpẹyẹmi ni wọn fọwọ si iwe adehun naa lorukọ ijọba, nigba ti alaga igbimọ asọyepọ naa, Comrade Kọlapọ Fatomiluyi pẹlu awọn alaga ati akọwe ẹgbẹ NLC ati TUC fọwọ si i lorukọ awọn oṣiṣẹ.Ninu ọrọ ẹ, Anilekọ Babafẹmi fidi ẹ mulẹ pe ipinlẹ Ekiti ni awọn oṣiṣẹ to kunju oṣuwọn ti wọn si n ṣiṣẹ takuntakun, nigba ti Comrade Fatomiluyi ni awọn nigbagbọ pe Gomina Kayọde Fayẹmi yoo ṣe awọn nnkan tawọn fọwọ si."},{"question":"Fingqa isihloko:  Kumdlali ongakafaki amagoli njalo ezingeni lekilabhu, uNicklas Bendtner ngokuqinisekile akadingi isimemo sokuthi ukuphi ngemuva kwenetha ngenkathi egqoke ihembe laseDenmark. Umgadli wangaphambili weArsenal waba yisehluleki eGunners futhi manje ulwela isikhathi somdlalo eWolfsburg. Kodwa i-hat-trick ngokumelene neUSA ngoLwesithathu ikhombisa ukuthi lo mdlali akanayo inkinga ezingeni lamazwe omhlaba. Lapha iSportsmail ibheka irekhodi lomdlali waseDenmark lokushaya amagoli kanye namanye amahotshots ayisishiyagalolunye ahlulekile ukuphindaphinda ifomu eliboniswe izwe labo emakilabhini abo. UAli Daei (Usebenze amazwe angu149, wafaka amagoli angu-109) U-Ali Daei usesigabeni sakhe. Njengomshayi wamagoli wamazwe omhlaba omkhulu kunabo bonke, nguyena kuphela umdlali onqobe amahlandla angaphezu kwe-100 ezweni lakhe. U-Ali Daei ugubha ukushaya kwakhe igoli neBayern Munich bebhekene neHamburg ngesikhathi sakhe esifushane namaqhawe aseJalimane. UDaei wayedlala kakhulu e-Iran futhi wabonakala kwiNdebe yoMhlaba ka-1998 lapho ayedlala khona ne-USA (ngenhla) Kodwa lo mdlali wasesiswini wathola ukuthi ukushaya amagoli e-Iran kwakulula kakhulu kunokukwenza masonto onke eJalimane. UBayer Munich wamthatha ngo-1998 kodwa kungakapheli nonyaka wayeseHertha Berlin, eyamthumela eDubai ngo-2002 ngemuva kwemigomo eyisithupha kuphela yeligi. UStern John (Trinidad & Tobago - Imidlalo engu-115 yamazwe omhlaba, amagoli angu-70) Ngezinga lakhe lokushaya eliphakeme kunelakaLuis Suarez, uZlatan Ibrahimovic noRobin van Persie, unethemba lokuthi umdlali okhiqiza njengaye emhlabeni wonke okungenani uzokwenza umxhwele kuPremier League. UStern John waseBirmingham (kwesokudla) wehla ngaphansi kwengcindezi evela kuJay-Jay Okocha waseBolton ngo-2002. Umdlali waseNgilandi uJohn Terry uphonsa ibhola phambi kukaJohn noRio Ferdinand ngesikhathi iThree Lions iwina ngo 2-0 iTrinidad & Tobago emidlalweni yamaqembu eNdebe yoMhlaba ka-2006. Kodwa uStern John akazange avelele phakathi neminyaka yakhe emibili eBirmingham phakathi kuka-2002 no-2004, kuyilapho iSunderland nayo yakhetha ukungamniki ithuba elikhulu eqenjini eliphezulu. Ngokuqinisekile akubonisi kahle ukuthi izimbangi zezizwe iTrinidad neTobago kumelwe ukuba zazinjani...","answer":"UNicklas Bendtner ufake i-hat-trick yeDenmark ekunqobeni iUSA ngo3-2. UTreble ugcizelele isimo esihle somgadli wangaphambili we-Arsenal ezingeni lamazwe omhlaba. I-Sportsmail ibheka abadlali abayishumi abadlala kangcono izwe kuneklabhu."},{"question":"பொருள் வேற்றுமையணியைச் சான்று தந்து விளக்குக.","answer":"அணி இலக்கணம் :செய்யுளில் கவிஞர் இருவேறு பொருள்களுக்கிடையே ஒற்றுமையை முதலில் கூறியப்பின் ஒன்றிலிருந்து ஒன்றை வேறுபடுத்திக் காட்டுவது பொருள் வேற்றுமை அணி எனப்படும். இது வேற்றுமை அணியின் ஒரு பிரிவாகும்.சான்று :ஓங்கலிடை வந்து உயர்ந்தோர் தொழ விளங்கிஏங்கொலிநீர் ஞாலத்(து) இருளகற்றும் – ஆங்கவற்றுள்மின்னேர் தனியாழி வெங்கதிரொன்(று) ஏனையதுதன்னேர் இலாத தமிழ்.அணிப்பொருத்தம் :கதிரவனும், தமிழ்மொழியும் மலையில் தோன்றுகின்றன என ஒப்புமையைக்கூறி, அவற்றுள் தமிழ்மொழிக்கு நிகராக வேறெந்த மொழியும் இவ்வுலகில் இல்லை என்று வேறுபடுத்திக் காட்டியதால் இப்பாடல் பொருள் வேற்றுமையணி ஆகும்கதிரவன் புற இருளை அகற்றும்;தமிழ்மொழி அக இருளை அகற்றும்.விளக்கம் :கதிரவன்எப்போதும் ஒலித்துக் கொண்டிருக்கும் கடலால் சூழப்பட்ட உலகத்தின் புற இருளை அகற்றும் : கதிரவன் உயர்ந்த மலைகளுக்கு இடையே தோன்றும்.தமிழ்:குளிர்ச்சிப் பொருந்திய பொதிய மலையில் தோன்றிய தமிழ்மொழி மக்களின் அறியாமை என்னும் அக இருளை அகற்றும் அத்தமிழ்மொழிக்கு நிகராக வேறெந்த மொழியும் இல்லை."},{"question":"Frank en Susan hebben zes kinderen: Donald, Rebecca, Mieke, Fabian, Solina en Lara. Susan is zwanger van haar zevende kind, een meisje. Frank en Susan hebben voor haar een naam uitgezocht die bij de andere namen past. Wat zal de naam zijn van het zevende kind: Jessica, Karin, Abby of Silke?","answer":"Het zevende kind zal Silke genoemd worden. Het patroon in de kindernamen is \\"do re mi fa sol la si\\": Donald, Rebecca, Mieke, Fabian, Solina, Lara, Silke. "},{"question":"Ọwọ ba Fulani mẹta nibi ti wọn ti n da awọn eeyan lọna niluu Tede","answer":"Ọwọ awọn ẹṣọ fijilante ti ba awọn afurasi ọdaran Fulani mẹta kan, Yakubu Mohammed, ẹni ogun ọdun, Saleh Magu, ọmọ ọdun mẹtadinlogun ati Ibrahim Legi, ẹni ọdun mẹtalelogun. Ọna to lọ lati ilu Tede si Ọjẹ-Owode, nijọba ibilẹ Atisbo, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, ni wọn ti mu wọn.Gẹgẹ ba a ṣe gbọ, wọn ni niṣe lawọn afurasi mẹtẹẹta yii n fibọn ati ada halẹ mọ awọn arinrin-ajo atawọn agbẹ to n gba ọna naa kọja lọ soko wọn, wọn si n ja wọn lole dukia wọn.L’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii, tọwọ palaba wọn segi, itosi abule Ayefẹlẹ ni wọn lawọn janduku naa duro si, ti wọn si n ba iṣẹ laabi wọn lọ.Ọgbẹni Ademọla Ọlaworẹ, to jẹ ọga agba awọn fijilante agbegbe naa ṣalaye fakọroyin wa pe o ti to ọsẹ mẹta sẹyin tawọn ti gbọ oriṣiiriṣii iroyin buruku nipa iwa ọdaran tawọn amookunṣika ẹda naa n hu lagbegbe ọhun, ṣugbọn bawọn ṣe n dọdẹ wọn ni wọn sa kiri lati ibikan si omi-in.Ọlawọọre ni oju ọna kan to lọ si adugbo Ayefẹlẹ lawọn Fulani ọdaran yii fẹẹ fi ṣe ibuba wọn, wọn ti n mura lati kọ Gaa kan sibẹ kọwọ too tẹ wọn.O ni igba kẹta ree tawọn n gba adugbo naa kọja, tawọn n wa wọn kiri, laimọ pe ori igi ni wọn sa pamọ si.Lọjọ ti wọn mu wọn yii, Ọlawọọre ni awọn ko gba ọna ti gbogbo eeyan maa n gba, ki wọn ma baa fura, lojiji si lawọn yọ si wọn, bi wọn ṣe ri awọn ni wọn bẹrẹ si i yinbọn, bo tilẹ jẹ pe ibọn naa ko le jiṣẹ ti wọn ran an.Ẹyin naa ni wọn gba awọn ohun ija oloro ti wọn gbe dani, lara rẹ ni ibọn, ida oloju meji, ada, ati ọpọ oogun abẹnugọngọ. Wọn lawọn Fulani yii jẹwọ pe ipinlẹ Katsina lawọn ti wa, ati pe loootọ lawọn n da awọn eeyan lọna lagbegbe naa.Ọlawọre ni gbara tawọn ba ti pari iwadii lawọn yoo fa wọn le awọn ọlọpaa teṣan Tede lọwọ, awọn si nigbagbọ p’awọn ọlọpaa yoo fẹsẹ ofin to ọrọ naa bo ṣe yẹ.Ọlawọọre waa gba awọn araalu nimọran lati yẹra fun irin alẹ ati aajin lasiko yii, nitori awọn apamọlẹkun-jaye wọnyi."},{"question":"1857 च्या राष्ट्रीय उठावाचे नेतृत्व कोणी केले ?","answer":" 1857 च्या राष्ट्रीय उठावाचे नेतृत्व बहादूर शहा जफरने केले."},{"question":"Tuliskan cerita fiksyen berdasarkan tajuk berikut; Tajuk: Pencipta Lampu","answer":"Tajuk: Pencipta LampuPada suatu petang, Tok Ketua Harjo menziarahi Saparwi.“Hai, Pawi. Sejak bekerja sebagai jaga sekolah, kau dah jarang melepak bersama Tok.”“Ala, Tok. Aku sibuk. Baru aku tahu kerja jaga ini bukan boleh buat main-main. Besar tanggungjawabnya, Tok.”“Amboi, makin bijak kau Pawi. Syukur dapat jadi cerdik sedikit,” Tok Ketua ketawa mengekeh. “Boleh Tok tanya soalan?” Dia menyoal pula. Saparwi menatap wajah Tok Ketua. Sangsi. “Soalan atau mahu menguji?”“Alah, samalah tu. Bolehlah, ya?” Tok Ketua memujuk. “Satu soalan sahaja. Please, Pawi.”Saparwi berfikir sejenak. “Baik. Satu sahaja.”Tok Ketua tersengih dan mula menyoal. “Baik. Kalau kau betul-betul jadi cerdik sekarang ni, Tok mahu tahu siapa yang mencipta lampu?”Lama Saparwi membisu. Tok Ketua tertawa kecil. “Ha, tadi macam cerdik sangat. Soalan senang pun tak tahu.”“Kalau begitu, apa jawapan Tok?”“Thomas Edison lah….”“Kalau begitu jawapan Tok kurang tepat.”“Aik, pulak? Habis tu siapa?”“Lampu itu cahaya kan?” Saparwi tanya. Tok Ketua mengiyakan. “Kenapa kita perlu cahaya?” Saparwi tanya lagi.“Sebab gelaplah, Pawi.”“Jadi, cahaya dicipta sebab kita tidak suka gelap. Kegelapan adalah pencipta cahaya. Cahaya itu lampu!”Tok Ketua menggeleng.“Kau bukannya cerdik, tetapi pintar memutar belit!”Saparwi tersengih. “Kalau aku pemutar belit, Tok mangsa yang tidak pernah serik.”Saparwi ketawa terbahak-bahak. Tok Ketua terperangkap dalam soalan yang dia timbulkan. Tok Ketua berjanji tidak mahu menguji lagi, untuk hari itu."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Tập đoàn quân tham chiến lần đầu tiên trong","answer":"Chiến tranh Mùa đông 1939–40 chống lại quân đội Phần Lan. Vào tháng 11 năm 1939, ngay trước cuộc tấn công đầu tiên của Liên Xô, tập đoàn quân bao gồm Quân đoàn súng trường 19 (Bao gồm các Sư đoàn súng trường 24, 43, 70, 123), Quân đoàn súng trường 50 (Bao gồm các Sư đoàn súng trường 49, 90, 142), Quân đoàn xe tăng 10, Sư đoàn súng trường 138 và một lữ đoàn xe tăng độc lập."},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 働く時間が長いと疲れが残る　うつの心配も高くなる","answer":"厚生労働省は、働く時間と疲れや精神との関係を調べて、結果を発表しました。会社などで働く約9800人に聞きました。「朝になっても前の日の疲れが残っている」と答えた人は、働く時間が長い人のほうが多いことがわかりました。1週間の働く時間が20時間以上40時間より短い人は53%でした。40時間以上60時間より短い人は60%、60時間以上の人は69%でした。「疲れが次の日にいつも残っている」と答えた人の82％は、うつなど心の病気になっている心配がありました。疲れが次の日に残っていることが多いと、精神に悪いことがわかりました。厚生労働省は「仕事が終わったあと、次の日に仕事を始めるまでの間、しっかり休むことが大切です。会社が働き方を変える必要があります」と話しています。"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe joro ary inona no atao mandritra ny joro?","answer":"Ny joro dia fomba Malagasy iray avy any amin'ny faritra avaratry ny nosy. Amin'ny finoana Malagasy, ny joro dia fipetrahan'ny fanahin'ny mpanjaka iray efa maty, anaty vatan'olombelona mba hahafahany mandray anjara amin'ny asa-piarahamonina. Mandritra io dia misy ny famonoana omby ho fangataham-pitahiana amin'ny razana, na ho sorona amin'ny zanahary. Izay no atao mandritra ny joro."},{"question":"A que categoría corresponde la siguiente pregunta : ¿Quién ha anotado la mayor cantidad de touchdowns a la carrera en la historia de la NFL?","answer":"La categoría corresponde a deportes. "},{"question":"வினா: பின்வரும் மரபுத்தொடர்களைத் தொடரில் அமைத்து எழுதுக.                                                                         1. வாழையடி வாழையாக ","answer":"விடை: நாங்கள் வாழையடி வாழையாக  உழவுத்தொழில் செய்து வருகிறோம். "},{"question":"السؤال: من هي أول امرأة تقود طائرة مقاتلة؟","answer":"الإجابة: ماري مارفينغت من فرنسا "},{"question":"O que caracteriza o signo de Capricórnio?","answer":"O signo de Capricórnio é representado pela cabra montanhesa, que sobe a montanha fincando os pés no chão duro rumo ao topo. Ela é o símbolo da estabilidade e da perseverança. Entretanto, esse animal tem um detalhe mágico, que é uma cauda de peixe que oculta por trás de uma personalidade aparentemente seca – um instinto e uma sensibilidade que quase nunca são citados nas interpretações que lemos por aí.Seu elemento solar é a Terra, o solo onde as raízes se firmam, universo das certezas, da estabilidade e da segurança. Entre as datas dos signos do Zodíaco, a data do signo de Capricórnio é aproximadamente de 22 de dezembro a 20 de janeiro, mas isso pode mudar dependendo do seu ano de nascimento.Você é uma pessoa que tende a pensar e a medir todas as suas atitudes e tem uma preocupação constante com a solidez e a estabilidade. Para você, é importante ser coerente consigo mesmo(a) e com seus objetivos de vida, evitando correr maiores riscos que possam prejudicar o sucesso da escalada.Seus esforços para superar as próprias limitações são invejáveis e, como as cabras que dedicadamente sobem as montanhas, é essencial se manter firme no seu propósito… Sem pressa, com prudência e calculando cada passo para evitar os imprevistos que podem surgir no seu caminho."},{"question":"Quelles couleurs sont sur le drapeau canadien?a) vertb) bleuc) rouged) orangee) blanc","answer":"Le drapeau canadien utilise le rouge (c) et le blanc (e). Il se compose d'une feuille d'érable rouge sur fond blanc avec deux bandes rouges de chaque côté"},{"question":"Inona no fanalavana ny SMOTIG?","answer":"Ny fanalavana ny SMOTIG dia Service de la Main d'Oeuvre pour les Traveaux d'Interêt Général"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ചോദ്യം: ആഫ്രിക്കയിൽ ആനയെ കൊല്ലുന്നതിന്റെ പ്രശ്നം എന്താണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ആനയെ കൊല്ലുന്നത് അഥവാ വേട്ടയാടൽ, ആനക്കൊമ്പുകൾക്കായി ആനകളെ നിയമവിരുദ്ധമായി വേട്ടയാടുന്നതും കൊല്ലുന്നതും ആണ്. ആനകളുടെ നിലനിൽപ്പിനെ ഭീഷണിപ്പെടുത്തുകയും ആവാസവ്യവസ്ഥയെ തകർക്കുകയും ചെയ്യുന്നതിനാൽ ഈ പ്രശ്നം ഒരു പ്രധാന ആശങ്കയായി മാറിയിരിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"विजेवर चालणारी पहिली ट्रेन भारतात कोणत्या वर्षी सुरु झाली होती?","answer":"उत्तर: विजेवर चालणारी पहिली ट्रेन भारतात १९२५ मध्ये, हि ट्रेन मुंबई सीएसटी ते कुर्ला या दोन स्टेशन दरम्यात धावली होती."},{"question":"معي مثل ، ماقدرت افهمه . لو سمحت اشرحه: علم البلا ما يختفيش!","answer":"يختفيش: يختفي، والشيء للدلالة على ضمير الغائب .. والمعنى أن خبر الشر سرعان ما ينتشر ويشيع بين الناس."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en está categoría : películas. ","answer":"¿Quién es el más viejo de los hermanos Baldwin?. "},{"question":"NAFDAC ṣekilọ: Ẹ sọra fun ayederu epo pupa o!","answer":"Ajọ to n ri si ọrọ ounjẹ ati oogun nilẹ yii (NAFDAC), ti rọ gbogbo ọmọ Naijiria lati maa ṣọra pẹlu awọn ounjẹ tabi oogun ti wọn yoo maa lo lasiko yii, nitori o lewu fun ilera, paapaa ju lọ epo pupa, nitori ayederu epo pupa ti gbode.Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọṣẹ yii, ni ọga agba fun ajọ naa nilẹ yii, Ọjọgbọn Mojisola Adeyẹye, ṣe ikilọ yii niluu Ilọrin, ti i ṣe olu ilu ipinlẹ Kwara, lasiko ilanilọyẹ ti wọn ṣe fun ẹkun Aarin Gbungbun Ariwa orile-ede yii to waye niluu Ilọrin, nigba to gbe ilanilọyẹ naa lọ si awọn ọja nla kan niluu Ilọrin, o ni ero ajọ naa ni lati daabo bo ọmọ Naijiria lori bi awọn ayederu ohun eelo ipese ounjẹ ṣe gba igboro. O tẹsiwaju pe ọpọ awọn onisowo to n ta ọja lawọn ọja gbogbo ni ko naani ilera araalu, bi wọn yoo ṣe jere rẹpẹtẹ lo jẹ wọn logun, eyi lo mu ki wọn maa po aro papọ mọ epo pupa ko le pọ daadaa.O fi kun un pe ọpọ lo maa n fi majele (sniper) sinu ẹwa, ẹja ati ẹran ko le pa kokoro to wa lara ounjẹ wọn yii, ti iru ounjẹ bẹẹ si lewu fun ẹni to ba jẹ ẹ lọjọ iwaju. Bakan naa lo tun gba awọn iyalọja nimọran lati maa ṣamulo gbogbo eroja to yẹ lati dena arun Korona lawọn ọja wọn gbogbo."},{"question":"පහත නාම පදයට අදාළ පුරුෂ ලිංග නාම පාදක කුමක්ද? මහත්මිය ","answer":"මහත්මා"},{"question":"অনুগ্রহ করে এই অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন :এপ্রিলের প্রথম দিকে, অপারেশন সার্চলাইট","answer":"কে সাহায্য করার জন্য পাকিস্তানি নৌবাহিনী পূর্ব পাকিস্তানে নৌ-অপারেশন শুরু করে। রিয়ার এডমিরাল মোহাম্মদ শরীফ এসব মিশনের সমন্ব্য় করতেন। ২৬ এপ্রিল পাকিস্তান নৌবাহিনী সফল ভাবে অপারেশন বরিশাল সম্পূর্ণ করে কিন্তু তা ছিল ক্ষণস্থায়ী ।"},{"question":"तलको लेख \\"८० दिनमा विश्वो भ्रमण\\" कथा बाट झिकिएको हो । यो लेख पढि सोधिएको प्रश्नको उत्तर दिनुहोस् । “यदि म असी दिनभित्र आउन सकिन भने मेरो ब्याङ्कमा रहेको २० हजार पौन्ड (करिब २० लाख नेपाली रुपियाँ) तिमीहरूको हुने छ ।” फिलियसले भन्यो । यसपछि त उसका साथीहरू अझै अच्चम्ममा परे । यति अचम्म कि उनीहरू छक्क परेर फिलियसलाई हेर्नुबाहेक केही बोल्नै सकेनन् ।अन्त्यमा फिलियस र उसका पाँच जना साथीहरूले बाजी थापे । बाजीका सर्त निश्चित गरियो : यदि फिलियसले ८० दिन अथवा ८० दिनभन्दा कम समयमा विश्व परिक्रमा गरेमा फिलियस फगलाई उसका साथीहरूले २० हजार पौन्ड दिने तर उसको भ्रमण ८० दिनभन्दा लामो भएमा फिलियसले उसका प्रत्येक साथीलाई चार हजारका दरले जम्मा २० हजार पौन्ड दिने ।फिलियसले फेरि थप्यो, “आज २ अक्टोबर हो र अहिले ८ः४५ बजेको छ । म तिमीहरूलाई २१ डिसेम्बरमा यही कोठामा यही समयमा भेट्ने छु ।”उसले समाइराखेको तास राख्यो र तुरुन्तै क्लबबाट बाहिरियो । ऊ फटाफट घरतिर लाग्यो । उसको घरमा पासपारटु शान्तपूर्वक आफ्नै तालमा काम गरिरहेको थियो । “पासपारटु !” फिलियसले भन्यो, “एउटा झोलामा मेरो र अर्को झोलामा तिम्रो सामान राखेर छिटो तयार होऊ ।”“हामी कतै जाँदै छौँ ?” पासपारटुले सोध्यो ।“हो, हामी जाँदैछौ । हामी विश्वको परिक्रमा गर्न जाँदै छौँ ।” फिलियस फगले भन्यो ।पासपारटु हाँस्न त खोज्यो तर कुन्नि किन हो हाँस्न सकेन । प्रश्न :-कथा अनुसार १ हजार पौन्ड नेपाली रुपियाँमा कती हुने बताइएको छ ?  ","answer":"उत्तर :-कथा अनुसार २० हजार पौन्ड करिब २० लाख नेपाली रुपियाँ हुने बताइएको छ । त्यसैले १ हजार पौन्ड नेपाली रुपियाँमा करिब १ लाख हुन्छ । "},{"question":"ලෝක මාධ්‍ය දිනය කවදාද?","answer":"ලෝක මාධ්‍ය දිනය ජූලි 01 දාය."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bulan kesiangan'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud berwajah pucat. Contoh ayat: Mukanya seperti bulan kesiangan apabila dia tidak bersolek."},{"question":"O ma ṣe o, eeyan mẹsan-an ku ninu ijamba ọkọ l’Ekiti","answer":"Beeyan ba jẹ ori ahun, poro-poro lomije yoo maa da loju rẹ bo ba debi ijamba mọto kan to ṣẹlẹ ni ilu Ijan-Ekiti, ni kututu aaro ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii. Niṣe ni wọn to oku awọn eeyan naa silẹ bẹẹrẹbẹ, ti agbara ẹjẹ si n ṣan bii omi, ninu ijamba mọto to ṣẹlẹ loju ọna to lọ lati ilu Ado-Ekiti si Ijan/Ilumọba-Ekiti.Boosi akero alawọ funfun kan to ko ero mejidinlogun, ti  nọmba idanimọ rẹ jẹ ONDO KER 44 XA, to gbera lati ilu Ado-Ekiti  to n lọ si Ikarẹ, nipinlẹ Ondo. O ri afara nla kan to kọja ilu Ijan-Ekiti, ko too de Ilumọba-Ekiti lo wa to fi fẹẹ ya ọkọ ajagbe nla  kan silẹ, lasiko to fẹẹ ṣe eleyii lo sadeede la ori mọ ọkọ akero miiran ti nọmba idanima tiẹ jẹ  LAGOS  APP 207, to oun naa n bọ lati ilu Ikare, to n lọ si ilu Ado-Ekiti.Awọn ara ilu Ijan-Ekiti to wa nibi iṣẹlẹ naa to ba ALAROYE sọrọ sọ pe lojiji ni ọkọ akero yii fẹẹ ya ọkọ ajagbe yii silẹ ni kete to kọja ori afara yii, lojiji ni ọkọ miiran sare yọ loju popo naa, eleyii to fa a ti ọkọ akero yii fi fa ori pada sinu, ṣugbọn aṣọ ko ba Ọmọye mọ, bo ṣe fẹẹ fa ori pada sinu lo la ori mọ ọkọ akero bọọsi miiran to n bọ lati ilu Ikare.Eleyii lo fa a ti mẹsan-an lara awon ero to wa ninu ọkọ naa ṣe jẹ Ọlọrun ni ipe lojiji, nigba ti awọn mejilelogun miiran fi ara pa yanna-yanna.Ni akoko ti a fi n ko iroyin yii jọ awọn ọlọpaa ati awọn ẹsọ ojupopo ti wa ni ibi ti iṣẹlẹ naa ti ṣẹlẹ, ti akitiyan si n lọ lọwọ lati ko awọn oku ati awọn to fara pa nibi iṣẹlẹ naa lọ si ileewosan.Nigba to n sọrọ lori iṣẹlẹ naa, Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ekiti, Ọgbẹni Sunday Abutu, sọ pe oun wa nibi ti iṣẹlẹ  naa ti ṣẹlẹ lakooko toun fi n ba ALAROYE sọrọ, o juwe iṣẹlẹ naa gẹgẹ bii ohun to buru gbaa, o rọ gbogbo awakọ ki wọn maa ni suuru loju popo nigbakigba ti wọn ba n wa ọkọ."},{"question":"Misy boky firy ao amin’ny Baiboky protestanta ?1-662-733-39","answer":"1-66 no isan’ny boky mandrakitra ny Baiboly protestanta izay mizara ho roa : ny 39 ny testamenta taloha ary 27 ny testamenta vaovao."},{"question":"Zer da linguistika, eta nola aztertzen du hizkuntzen jatorria eta garapena?","answer":"Linguistika da hizkuntzen ikerketa zientifikoa. Hizkuntzen jatorria eta garapena aztertzeko, linguistikak erakusten du nola hizkuntzak aldatu diren denboran zehar eta nola hizkuntzak elkarrekin lotuta dauden."},{"question":"हाल नेपालमा तराईका जिल्ला कतिवटा छन् ?","answer":"नेपालमा हाल २१ वटा तराई जिल्ला रहेका छन् ।"},{"question":"Me ake nufi da \\"orange\\" da Hausa? \\t\\t\\t\\t\\t","answer":"Tana nufin \\"lemu\\""},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Jarochowski, som var domare i Posen, publicerade \\"Teka Gabryela J. Podoskiego\\" (sex band, 1856–62): viktiga aktstycken rörande Polens historia vid tiden för föreningen med Sachsen, varjämte han författade kung August II:s historia (1856–74) samt åtskilliga smärre historiska skrifter, utkomna under titeln \\"Opowiadania historyczne\\" (sex band, 1860–86),","answer":"ävensom några särskilt utgivna avhandlingar, däribland \\"Wielkopolska w czasie pierwszej wojny szwedzkiej w r. 1655–57\\" (Storpolen under det första svenska kriget 1655–57, 1864) och \\"Car Piotr i carewicz Aleksy\\" (1862)."},{"question":"Wahala ẹgbẹ PDP l’Ekiti: Ija ṣẹṣẹ bẹrẹ ni – Olujimi","answer":"Sẹnetọ to n ṣoju ẹkun idibo Guusu Ekiti, Biọdun Olujimi, ti sọ pe ko si ọna abayọ kankan ju ki gomina Ekiti tẹlẹ, Ayọdele Fayoṣe, gba awọn ti ipo tọ si laaye lati ṣiṣẹ fun idagbasoke ẹgbẹ People’s Democratic Party (PDP), paapaa nipinlẹ naa ati nilẹ Yoruba lapapọ.Eyi ni ọrọ ti Olujimi n tẹnumọ lopin ọsẹ to kọja nigba to n sọrọ nipa aawọ to wa laarin oun ati Fayoṣe.Sẹneto to ṣe oludamọran pataki fun Fayoṣe ni saa akọkọ fun ọkunrin oloṣelu naa tun ṣe igbakeji gomina fun un, eyi to tumọ si pe wọn ti jọ n bọ tipẹ, ajọṣepọ wọn si ti kọja ọdun mẹẹẹdogun.Ọjọ keje, oṣu kẹta, ọdun yii, ni eto ibo PDP fawọn oloye wọọdu waye, ibẹ gan-an si ni ipinya manigbagbe ti waye laarin awọn mejeeji.Lọjọ kẹrindinlọgbọn, oṣu to kọja, ni igun mejeeji tun ṣe ibo ọtọọtọ fawọn oloye nijọba ibilẹ mẹridinlogun to wa nipinlẹ Ekiti, nigba to si di ọjọ kọkandinlọgbọn, oṣu to kọja, ni wọn tun yan awọn oloye ipinlẹ ọtọọtọ. Ọnarebu Bisi Kọlawọle di alaga igun Fayoṣe, nigba Ọnarebu Kẹhinde Ọdẹbunmi di alaga igun Olujimi.Ọjọbọ, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ to kọja, nija naa tun gba ọna mi-in yọ nigba ti Fayọse sọrọ si Gomina Ṣeyi Makinde tipinlẹ Ọyọ nibi ipade kan to waye niluu Abẹokuta pe ko ma wa si Ekiti nitori oun yoo doju ija kọ ọ.Lọjọ Ẹti, ọsẹ to kọja, ni lẹta kan to ni orukọ olu-ile ẹgbẹ naa l’Abuja jade, ninu eyi ti wọn ti fontẹ lu iyansipo Ọnarebu Bisi Kọlawọle, ṣugbọn igun Olujimi ni ayederu ni, awọn tawọn n ba ja lo tun n gbọna ẹburu yọ.Lori rogbodiyan yii ati bi nnkan ṣe n lọ, eyi lawọn nnkan ti Olujimi sọ fun akọroyin wa:Ajọṣepọ lati ibẹrẹGbogbo awọn ti Fayoṣe ti ṣanfaani fun, mo ba wọn yọ, mo ba ara mi naa yọ, nitori mo wa lara wọn. Ṣugbọn ẹni to ba ṣoore fun ẹ to ba loṣoo ti i, o sọ ara ẹ di Ọlọrun niyẹn. Teeyan ba ṣoore fun ẹ to ro pe oun aa maa fohun silẹ fun ẹ ni gbogbo igba to ro pe o fẹẹ ṣe nnkan daadaa, Ọlọrun aa da ẹjọ. Igba ti o fi iwa yẹn han ni wahala too bẹrẹ.Nnkan to fa rogbodiyanKo sija ta a ba Fayoṣe ja ju pe ko jẹ kawa naa ṣakoso tiwa. Ọlọrun ti fun un ni tiẹ, o ti se e, awa naa t’Ọlọrun fi sibẹ lasiko yii, ko gbaruku ti wa, iyẹn lo da wahala silẹ.Ko sẹni to n ba Fayoṣe ja, oun lo n ba ara ẹ jẹ. Idi ni pe teeyan ba ti wa nipo kan to ba ti ṣe tiẹ, ko gbọdọ di ibẹ mọ awọn mi-in, Ọlọrun nikan lo n jẹ ‘afemi’. Ti eeyan kan ba ti sọ pe oun loun ni ẹgbẹ, ti ki i ṣe pe o fa wa ni tẹ̀ẹ̀tẹ́ wọ ọ ni, gbogbo wa la jọ wọ ọ, ko le maa fọwọ lalẹ fun wa.Teeyan kan ba sọ pe gbogbo awa ta a wa ni igun yii, a ko jẹ eeyan, koun naa lọọ yẹ ara ẹ wo.Ọrọ igun meji to wa l’EkitiỌnarebu Kẹhinde Ọdẹbunmi atawọn oloye to ku la yan nilana ofin, wọn si ti n ba eto lọ lati gbe PDP goke agba. A nigbagbọ pe awa la maa leke nigbẹyin, Ọlọrun a dẹ fun wa ṣe.Ija Fayoṣe ati MakindeMo dupẹ lọwọ awọn adari wa tuntun l’Ekiti fun bi wọn ṣe fọwọ si Ẹnjinnia Ṣeyi Makinde gẹgẹ bii adari wa nilẹ Yoruba, eyi daa pupọ.Ọrọ Ṣeyi Makinde ko le rara. Oun nikan ni gomina to jẹ ọmọ ẹgbẹ wa nilẹ Yoruba, o si ni imọ, oye ati ifẹ eeyan lọkan, bẹẹ lo gbọn gidi. Oun lo yẹ ko jẹ aṣoju wa patapata.Iru igbesẹ yii naa la gbe nigba ti gomina tẹlẹ l’Ekiti, Ayọdele Fayoṣe, wa lori aleefa, nitori oun nikan ni gomina ẹgbẹ PDP nilẹ Yoruba nigba yẹn, a dẹ gbaruku ti i.Mo ranti pe nigba yẹn, ipinlẹ Ọyọ ni iru wahala ta a ni l’Ekiti yii, Fayoṣe dẹ gbiyanju lati yan igbimọ alakooso le wọn lori. Iru ẹ naa tun waye lọpọ igba ni Eko ati Oṣun. O waa jẹ iyalẹnu pe ọrọ adari ẹgbẹ nilẹ Yoruba di ariyanjiyan bayii.Ẹni to ba wa nibẹ lo n ṣe ibẹ. Ayọ Fayoṣe jẹ ọkan lara awọn adari PDP l’Ekiti, ṣugbọn ko le sọ pe oun n du ipo adari ilẹ Yoruba.Bi Fayoṣe ṣe ko awọn kan lọọ ṣepade ni Abẹokuta gan-an ko tọna nitori Ọlọrun ti fi olurọpo sẹyin gbogbo ẹda, asiko ti Gomina Makinde lo kan.Ko si nnkan ti Makinde ṣe ju pe o ni ẹni kan ko le gba Ekiti la, o ni ki n duro digba ti ọrọ yii maa niyanju, ti gbogbo wa maa pada jẹ ọkan, nnkan to sọ to fi jẹbi niyẹn o.Gbogbo ẹnu la fi sọ ọ pe ki Makinde maa bọ l’Ekiti, a maa ṣajọyọ ẹ, ihalẹ lasan ni pe ko ma wa.Igbesẹ awọn adari ẹgbẹ patapataGbogbo eleyii to n waye yii n tẹsiwaju nitori awọn adari ẹgbẹ lapapọ n ṣatilẹyin fun Fayoṣe. Asiko ti to fun wọn lati kede atilẹyin wọn fun gomina tẹlẹ, iyẹn Fayoṣe, tabi adari ilẹ Yoruba to jẹ gomina to wa lori alaeefa lọwọlọwọ.Ti wọn ko ba rọra le maaluu to ja wọ ìsọ̀ àwo yii, a maa ran onisọ lọwọ lati le e jade. Ki gbogbo eeyan yaa mọ pe a mọ nnkan ta a n ṣe, ti ẹgbẹ yii ko ba si ṣatilẹyin fun ida ọgọrin to wa lọdọ tiwa, a maa jọ wọn loju. O to gẹẹ.Fayoṣe ko le gba awọn nnkan to n ṣe yii laelae. Ki lo de tawọn adari n gba a laaye lati jẹ gaba lori ẹgbẹ wa? Abi nnkan kan wa ti a ko mọ nipa ọrọ yii ni? Ṣe wọn fẹẹ tọju ẹgbẹ ni, abi wọn fẹẹ tọju eeyan kan?Igbesẹ alaafia lori ọrọ yiiFayoṣe ni ko jẹ ki igbimọ to fẹẹ ṣiṣẹ yẹn l’Ekiti ṣiṣẹ nitori igba meji pere ni wọn ṣepade, o si fagidi mu wọn lati ṣe nnkan to fẹ.To ba jẹ pe awọn adari wa ko gbọ ẹjọ ẹni kan da ni, wọn ti maa pe gbogbo wa, a ti maa jokoo, a ti maa ri ọna abayọ.Ọna abayọẸ jẹ ko wa ninu akọsilẹ pe a ko ni i gba ọkunrin to ṣakoba nla fun wa lasiko ta a fi omi ati ẹjẹ ara wa jiya laaye lati jẹ ka tun fidi-rẹmi.Yẹyẹ ara wa ta a n ṣe nigboro jẹ kawọn eeyan ro pe oun lo ni ẹgbẹ. Ẹgbẹ gbọdọ gbe igbesẹ bayii tabi ki wọn kabaamọ.A finu-findọ wọ inu ẹgbẹ yii ni, ko sẹni to mu wa wọle, ko si sẹni to maa halẹ mọ wa lati le wa lọ nitori a maa fi ẹjẹ wa silẹ.Ti wọn ko ba gba wa laaye lati ṣeto ẹgbẹ yii lọna to ba ofin mu ta a fẹẹ tọ, ija ṣẹṣẹ bẹrẹ ni."},{"question":"Jereo ity fanambarana ity :« Vesatra ho an’ny fiarahamonina ianao. »Misarona fankahalana ve izany fanambarana izany ?","answer":"Eny, mankahala izany. Ataonao fa tsy mendrika hiaina eo amin’ny fiarahamonina ny olona iray miainga amin’ny fijerinao azy manokana."},{"question":"Cad iad na bronntanais lá Valentine maithe do fhear céile? ","answer":"An maith leis seacláidí, bláthanna, jewelry, turas eachtraíochta, nó rud éigin eile? Má fuaimeann turas éachtraíochta fionnuar, tá pacáiste turas Grand Canyon agus pacáistí Yellowstone nó Niagara Falls ann."},{"question":"Ile Arugbo: Ile-ẹjọ ti ni ijọba Kwara le kọle sori ilẹ awọn Saraki o","answer":"L’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, oni yii, ni ile-ẹjọ giga kan ni ipinlẹ Kwara ti fun ijọba laṣẹ lati kọ ile sori ilẹ ti ẹbi awọn Saraki kọ Ile-Arugbo si. Adajọ Abiọdun Adebara tun paṣẹ fawọn lati san ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọrun-un naira fawọn ti wọn pe lẹjọ, iyẹn Gomina Kwara, Adajọ agba, ile-igbimọ aṣofin ati ileeṣẹ ijọba to n mojuto ọrọ ilẹ, fun fifi akoko wọn ṣofo, ati bi agbẹjọro wọn, Akin Onigbinde, ṣe kọ lati yọju sile-ẹjọ.Bakan naa, Ile-ẹjọ ni wọn yoo tun san ẹgbẹrun lọ́nà aadọta naira fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa, nitori bi wọn ṣe n fa ẹjọ naa nilẹ, nipa bi wọn ṣe kọ lati wa sile-ẹjọ fun ọpọlọpọ igba tẹjọ naa ti n waye.Onigbinde kọ lẹta ranṣẹ sile-ẹjọ pe ara oun ko ya, o si fi akọsilẹ awọn dokita ti i lẹyin. O ni wọn ni oun gbọdọ fun ara nisinmi, ki oun si wa lori ibusun nileewosan lati ọjọ kẹta si ikẹwaa, oṣu yii. Ṣaaju nile-ẹjọ ti n sun ẹjọ naa siwaju fun ọpọlọpọ igba. Nibi ijokoo to waye lọjọ kẹjọ, oṣu keje, Onigbinde funra rẹ rọ ile-ẹjọ lati sun un si ọjọ kejilelogun, oṣu keje, ọdun yii, ṣugbọn nigba to maa di ọjọ naa, o tun gbe awawi mi-in kalẹ. Eyi lo mu ki wọn sun ijokoo mi-in si oni, Ọjọbọ, ọjọ kẹfa, oṣu kẹjọ, sibẹ wọn ko tun ri i.Olootu ati kọmiṣanna fun eto idajọ, Salman Jawondo, to ṣoju ijọba, ni olupẹjọ naa kan n mọ-ọn-mọ fi akoko ile-ẹjọ ṣofo lasan ni, o rọ ile-ẹjọ lati da ẹjọ naa nu. Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa to jẹ olujẹjọ karun-un ti wọn pe lẹjọ naa gba aba Jawondo wọle, wọn ni ki adajọ fagi le ẹjọ naa, nitori o ti fi han pe awọn olupẹjọ ko ni nnkan i ṣe. Adajọ waa sun ẹjọ ọhun si ọjọ kẹtalelogun, ati kẹrinlelogun, oṣu kẹsan-an, ọdun yii, lati gba agbẹjọro olupẹjọ laaye lati tẹsiwaju ninu ẹjọ naa.Ileeṣẹ Asa Investment Limited, to jẹ ti Oloogbe Abubakar Oluṣọla Saraki lo wọ ijọba Kwara lọ sile-ẹjọ lori bi wọn ṣe wo Ile-Arugbo, loṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun yii."},{"question":"நவீன வேதியியலின் தந்தைஎன அழைக்கப்படுபவர் யார்?","answer":" ஆண்டைன் லவாய்சியர் நவீன வேதியியலின் தந்தை என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறா."},{"question":"به این چیستان پاسخ بده.آن کیست که در ابتدا چهار پا دارد سپس دو پا و در نهایت سه پا؟","answer":"پاسخ: انسان؛ در کودکی چهار دست و پا راه می رود، در جوانی با دوپا و در پیری با عصا راه می رود."},{"question":"கேள்வி: நிலையான விவசாயத்தின் முக்கிய கொள்கைகள் என்ன, உணவு உற்பத்தியின் எதிர்காலத்திற்கு அவை ஏன் அவசியம்?","answer":"பதில்: நிலையான விவசாயம்:“இயற்கையில் உள்ள வளங்களை ஒருங்கிணைத்து, மண் வளத்தையும், சுற்றுச் சூழலையும் பாதுகாத்து மகசூலை அதிகப்படுத்தும் முறை நிலையான வேளாண்மை என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. இந்த முறை மூலம் இயற்கை வளம் மேம்படுத்தப்படுகிறது ” என்கிறார் திருநாவலூர் வேளாண்மை உதவி இயக்குநர் கே.ரவீந்திரன்.நிலையான வேளாண்மைக்கு கீழ்க்கண்ட தொழில்நுட்பங்கள் உதவி புரிகின்றனதொழு உரம் மற்றும் பண்ணைக் கழிவு இடுதல்: சாணம், எரு போன்ற விலங்குகளின் கழிவுகள் தொழு உரம் எனப்படுகிறது. இவற்றை குழிகளில் இட்டு மக்கச் செய்து பயிருக்கு இடுவதால், மகசூல் கூடுவதுடன், மண் வளம் காக்கப்படுகிறது.கால்நடை இல்லாதவர்கள் பண்ணைக் கழிவு தொழு உரத்தை பயன்படுத்தலாம். இலைகள், அழுகிய காய்கறிகள், சோளத்தட்டு, ராகித்தட்டு, கடலை ஓடு போன்றவைகளை குழிகளில் இட்டு மக்கச் செய்து, நிலத்தில் இடுவதன் மூலம் மண்ணின் நீர்பிடிப்புத் தன்மை, மண்வளம், நுண்ணுயிர் செயல்பாடு அதிகரித்து மகசூல் கூடுகிறது.ஊட்டமேற்றிய தொழு உரம் இடுதல்: ஒரு ஏக்கருக்கு தேவையான 350 கிலோ தொழு உரம், தேவையான சூப்பர் பாஸ்பேட், தேவையான பொட்டாஷ் போன்றவற்றை 5 சம பாகங்களாக பிரித்து, 5 மீட்டர் நீளம், 3 மீட்டர் அகலமுள்ள மேடான இடத்தில் ஒவ்வொரு பாகமாக சமமாக பரப்பி, முடிவில் களிமண் அல்லது செம்மண் கொண்டு காற்று புகாமல் மூடி பூச வேண்டும். ஒருமாதம் கழித்து கடைசி உழவுக்கு முன்பு சீராக இட வேண்டும். இப்படி இடும்போது பயிருக்கு தேவையான அனைத்து சத்துக்களும் சீராக கிடைக்கின்றன.பயிர் சுழற்சி முறைகளை கடைப்பிடித்தல்: ஒரே பயிரை திரும்ப திரும்ப பயிரிடாமல் மாற்றுப் பயிர்களை பயிரிடுவதன் மூலம் நிலத்துக்கு பயிர் சுழற்சி கொடுப்பதோடு, மண் வளம் பாதுகாக்கப்படுகிறது. அதோடு மட்டுமல்லாமல் பூச்சி, நோய் தாக்குதல் குறைகிறது. பயிர் சுழற்சி செய்யும் போது, ஆண்டுக்கு ஒரு முறை பயறு வகைப் பயிர்களான உளுந்து, பாசிப்பயறு, காராமணி, கொள்ளு போன்றவற்றை தனிப் பயிராகவோ அல்லது கலப்புப் பயிராகவோ பயிரிடுதல் நல்லது.மண் பரிசோதனைப்படி உரம் இடுதல்: மண்ணில் உள்ள சத்துக்களின் விவரங்களைத் தெரிந்து கொள்வதற்கும், பயிருக்கு அளிக்க வேண்டிய சத்துக்களை அறிந்து கொள்வதற்கும், மண் பரிசோதனை செய்வது மிகவும் அவசியமாகிறது. மண் பரிசோதனை முடிவின்படி செயல்படும்போது உரச் செலவு குறைவதுடன், மகசூலை அதிகப்படுத்த முடியும்.ஒருங்கிணைந்த பண்ணைய முறை: வேளாண்மையுடன் கால்நடை வளர்ப்பு, கோழிப் பண்ணை, மீன் பண்ணை, காளான் வளர்ப்பு, பட்டுப்புழு, தேனீ வளர்ப்பு, வேளாண் காடுகள், வீட்டு காய்கறித் தோட்டம், பழ மரங்கள், தீவன மரங்கள், தீவனப் பயிர் போன்றவற்றை ஒருங்கிணைத்து செய்யப்படும் பண்ணையம் ஒருங்கிணைந்த பண்ணைய முறை எனப்படுகிறது. இந்த முறை மூலம் கூடுதல் வருவாய் பெறுவதுடன், பண்ணை கழிவுகளை முறைப்படி உபயோகிக்க முடிகிறது.பயிருக்கு மூடாக்கு இடுதல்: மூடாக்கு என்பது மண்ணை மூடி பாதுகாப்பது. மூடாக்கு இடுவதன் மூலம் நிலத்தின் ஈரம் காக்கப்படுகிறது. மண் அரிப்பு தடுக்கப்படுகிறது. மண் புழுக்கள் காக்கப்படுகின்றன."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：美国的方言有哪些？","answer":"答案：美国有许多方言，由于地理和历史原因，各地区的口音和词汇会有所差异。常见的方言包括南方口音、波士顿口音和西部方言等。"},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk Peranan Unit Bimbingan dan Kaunseling di Sekolah..","answer":"Setiap institusi pendidikan di dalam negara mempunyai unit bimbingan dan kaunseling. Pada hemah saya, unit ini adalah penting untuk diwujudkan di setiap sektor kerana kita memerlukan bimbingan dan kaunseling tanpa mengira usia. Apatah lagi di institusi pendidikan seperti sekolah yang menjadi alma mater kepada ahli masyarakat yang muda-mudi. Dengan peningkatan masalah sosial dalam kalangan pelajar pada masa ini, unit bimbingan dan kaunseling di setiap sekolah mempunyai obligasi yang ulung agar generasi muda dapat dibentuk dengan keperibadian yang baik. Saya menegaskan kita perlu memegang kepada peribahasa Melayu, ingat antara belum kena, hemat antara belum habis. Oleh itu, wajar untuk kita mengetahui tanggungjawab unit bimbingan dan kaunseling di sekolah supaya memberi faedah kepada semua.Fungsi utama unit bimbingan dan kaunseling di sekolah adalah untuk menyediakan khidmat nasihat kepada pelajar. Guru-guru merupakan golongan yang lebih tua berbanding kumpulan pelajar dan sudah lama makan garam. Oleh itu, pelajar memerlukan nasihat yang bermanfaat daripada guru yang mempunyai pengalaman hidup lebih lama berbanding pelajar mereka. Tetapi ia tidak membawa maksud bahawa setiap nasihat guru adalah betul dan perlu diikuti oleh pelajar. Mereka hanya perlu membimbing dan memberikan contoh atau senario yang bakal berlaku sekiranya pelajar membuat pilihan untuk melakukan sesuatu. Pelajar pula perlu mempunyai minda yang terbuka dalam menerima nasihat guru dengan membuang yang keruh dan mengambil yang jernih. Misalnya pelajar mempunyai masalah untuk memakai pakaian sekolah dengan kemas, guru hendaklah menasihati mereka bahawa pakaian seragam perlu dibiasakan sejak sekolah kerana kelak apabila bekerja kita sudah biasa kelihatan kemas dan selesa dengan pemakaian tersebut. Intihannya, penjelasan dan kata-kata hikmah daripada guru dapat membantu murid.Selain itu, fungsi unit bimbingan dan kaunseling di sekolah adalah untuk membantu murid meningkatkan nilai dalam diri masing-masing. Pelajar yang berumur setahun jagung mungkin tidak mengetahui potensi diri mereka. Maka guru-guru dan ibu bapa seharusnya memainkan peranan dalam mencungkil setiap potensi dalam setiap pelajar supaya mereka dapat bersedia demi masa hadapan mereka. Nilai-nilai murni pula boleh dipupuk oleh unit bimbingan dan kaunseling sekolah dengan menganjurkan kem motivasi atau program-program yang berkaitan. Perkara ini dapat membantu membina disiplin dan jati diri pelajar supaya cekal dan kekal berusaha untuk mencapai kejayaan dalam apa bidang sekali pun. Situasi ini perlu dikaitkan dengan pelajar yang tidak gemar dalam bidang akademik kerana mereka menganggap diri mereka gagal. Sebaliknya, pelbagai perkara yang mereka boleh ceburi seperti bidang sukan untuk berjaya dan mendapat kerjaya yang stabil pada masa hadapan. Persis kata peribahasa belakang parang pun kalau diasah akan tajam juga.Fungsi lain unit bimbingan dan kaunseling di sekolah ialah untuk membantu menyelesaikan masalah yang dihadapi oleh murid di sekolah. Antara situasi yang sering berlaku adalah tidak dapat fokus ketika belajar atau tidak selesa bergaul dengan rakan sekelas. Justeru, guru yang berkhidmat di bahagian bimbingan dan kaunseling hendaklah mudah didekati oleh pelajar supaya mereka dapat meluahkan masalah yang dihadapi. Setelah menerima aduan pelajar, maka guru boleh menyiasat dan melaksanakan tindakan yang terbaik bagi setiap pihak tanpa berlaku pergaduhan antara anak murid dan juga melibatkan pihak pentadbiran sekolah. Selain itu, terdapat pelajar yang mempunyai masalah keluarga sehingga menjejaskan prestasi di sekolah. Tetapi dengan bimbingan dan kaunseling yang bersesuaian oleh guru, pelajar tersebut mampu untuk mencapai kecemerlangan di sekolah walaupun tanpa sokongan keluarga. Masalah peribadi murid mungkin membebankan sesetengah guru dan di sinilah unit bimbingan dan kaunseling di sekolah perlu memainkan peranan yang penting.Akhir sekali, unit bimbingan dan kaunseling di sekolah mempunyai obligasi dalam memberikan bimbingan kerjaya kepada murid-murid. Dalam menghadapi zaman yang penuh daya saing ini, ramai pelajar yang mempunyai tekanan serta bingung dengan laluan kerjaya yang bakal mereka ambil. Dengan masalah ekonomi dan pandemik yang melanda dunia, mereka seolah-olah layang-layang yang terputus talinya. Guru kaunseling boleh membimbing pelajar dengan menyesuaikan minat pelajar dengan peluang kerjaya yang ada pada masa kini. Pelajar juga harus diingatkan bahawa tiada jalan mudah untuk mencapai kejayaan seperti yang dimomok-momokan di media arus perdana atau media sosial. Bak kata peribahasa Melayu, berakit-rakit ke hulu, berenang-renang ke tepian; bersakit-sakit dahulu, bersenang-senang kemudian. Dengan bimbingan yang betul, pelajar dapat memastikan mereka fokus kepada bidang pengajian yang akan digunakan kelak dalam kerjaya mereka.Sebagai kesimpulan, unit bimbingan dan kaunseling di sekolah memainkan peranan yang penting bukan sahaja dari aspek pelajar di sekolah malah dalam membentuk anggota masyarakat. Kita seharusnya menghormati dan meraikan para guru yang banyak berkorban dan melayan kita seperti anak-anak mereka sendiri. Ibarat kata-kata cendiakawan, guru merupakan lilin kepada murid-murid yang menyuluhkan cahaya kepada jalan yang bakal dilalui oleh pelajar. Pihak berkuasa seharusnya memantapkan lagi unit bimbingan dan kaunseling bukan sahaja pada sektor pendidikan tetapi kepada semua sektor di dalam negara supaya kita dapat membantu individu yang memerlukan motivasi dalam menghadapi dugaan atau cabaran yang menguji kehidupan masing-masing. Sekiranya setiap di antara kita dibekalkan dengan motivasi dan iltizam yang tinggi, pastinya masyarakat berminda kelas pertama dapat dihasilkan seterusnya membawa negara ke arah kemajuan sejagat."},{"question":"2013年の夏に開かれたご当地キャラ総選挙で優勝し、ロックバンド「ジ・アルフィー」にゲスト出演するなどメディアにも多く登場した船橋市非公認キャラクターは？","answer":"ふなっしーです。"},{"question":"Ułóż zdanie przeciwne do podanego: Nad morzem woda jest zimna.","answer":"Oto zdanie przeciwne do podanego: Nad morzem woda jest ciepła."},{"question":"இந்தியாவில் இரயில் பெட்டிகள் தயாரிக்கப்படும் இடம் \\t1. டில்லி2. சித்தரஞ்சன் ( மேற்கு வங்கம்)3. ஆவடி4. பெரம்பூர்","answer":"4. பெரம்பூர்"},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Tối 31/7, tại khu đô thị Vịnh Xuân Đài, Ủy ban nhân dân thị xã Sông Cầu (tỉnh Phú Yên) tổ chức bế mạc Lễ hội tôm hùm Sông Cầu lần thứ nhất - năm 2022; đón nhận kỷ lục Guiness Việt Nam 100 món ăn từ tôm hùm và vinh danh người nuôi tôm hùm tiêu biểu. Khám phá vườn hồng lập kỷ lục Guiness lớn nhất Việt Nam Vườn hoa hồng ở Ba Vì, Hà Nội đã được Tổ chức Guiness Việt Nam công nhận là vườn hồng lớn nhất Việt Nam. (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({}); Chương trình được tường thuật trực tiếp trên sóng Đài Phát thanh và Truyền hình Phú Yên (PTP) đồng thời tiếp sóng tại 28 tỉnh, thành phố có biển nhằm giới thiệu quảng bá nghề nuôi tôm hùm ở tỉnh Phú Yên, nơi được xem là \\"thủ phủ tôm hùm\\" của Việt Nam. Lễ hội tôm hùm Sông Cầu gồm chuỗi các hoạt động thu hút","answer":"du khách trong dịp du lịch mùa hè như: Lễ hội Nghinh Ông cầu mưa thuận gió hòa, tàu thuyền đầy ắp cá tôm; hội thi thả diều nghệ thuật; hội thảo ứng dụng công nghệ 4.0 trong lĩnh vực nuôi tôm hùm và ký kết giao thương giữa các địa phương, doanh nghiệp... Tổ chức kỷ lục Guiness Việt Nam trao bằng xác lập kỷ lục 100 món ăn từ tôm hùm cho Đảng bộ và chính quyền thị xã Sông Cầu. Ảnh: Xuân Triệu - TTXVN Đáng chú ý, lần đầu tiên tại thị xã Sông Cầu, tỉnh Phú Yên diễn ra chương trình Hội thi trình diễn ẩm thực \\"100 món ăn từ tôm hùm - Tinh hoa của biển\\" do 28 hội đầu bếp, nhà hàng chuyên nghiệp trên mọi miền đất nước kết hợp cùng địa phương tổ chức thực hiện. Các món ăn chế biến từ tôm hùm này cũng được xác lập kỷ lục Guiness Việt Nam. Ông Phan Trần Vạn Huy - Chủ tịch Ủy ban nhân dân thị xã Sông Cầu cho biết: Lễ hội tôm hùm được tổ chức với mục đích nhằm khơi dậy niềm tự hào quê hương, đất nước và nghề nuôi trồng thủy sản đã và đang phát triển hơn 30 năm qua. Thị xã Sông Cầu hướng đến mục tiêu xây dựng \\"thủ phủ tôm hùm\\" lớn mạnh, bền vững, đáp ứng những nhu cầu mới của thị trường sau dịch COVID-19. Đây cũng sẽ là sản phẩm du lịch đặc trưng tại địa phương khi được luân phiên tổ chức 3 năm/lần. (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({}); Tỉnh Phú Yên là \\"thủ phủ tôm hùm\\" của cả nước với khoảng 88.926 lồng nuôi thủy sản, trong đó nhiều nhất tại thị xã Sông Cầu có 58.695 lồng nuôi tôm hùm thương phẩm với sản lượng năm 2021 đạt 1.050 tấn. Số hộ tham gia nuôi tôm hùm trên địa bàn thị xã Sông Cầu là 4.852 hộ. Tại lễ bế mạc Lễ hội tôm hùm Sông Cầu lần thứ nhất - năm 2022, Ủy ban nhân dân thị xã Sông Cầu đã vinh danh 1 tập thể và 5 cá nhân nuôi tôm hùm tiêu biểu. TTXVN"},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?ඇතුළත ","answer":"පිටත"},{"question":"السؤال: كم عدد النقاط التي تستحقها الرمية الحرة؟","answer":"الإجابة: نقطة واحدة"},{"question":" Abdullah Iltire & Muscab Mohamed & Hamda Kayf 16 ","answer":" Sagaaradu waa habar dugaaga kamid ah ugaarta duurjoogta ah "},{"question":"Me dê um exemplo de trivia desta categoria: geografia","answer":"Qual é o rio mais longo no Arizona? Colorado River"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਸਾਧਸੰਗਿ ਤਾ ਕੀ ਸਰਨੀ ਪਰਹੁ ॥ਮਨੁ ਤਨੁ ਅਪਨਾ ਆਗੈ ਧਰਹੁ ॥੧॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਨਾਮੁ ਪੀਵਹੁ ਮੇਰੇ ਭਾਈ ॥ਸਿਮਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਿ ਸਭ ਤਪਤਿ ਬੁਝਾਈ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਤਜਿ ਅਭਿਮਾਨੁ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਣੁ ਨਿਵਾਰਹੁ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੇ ਦਾਸ ਕੇ ਚਰਣ ਨਮਸਕਾਰਹੁ ॥੨॥ਸਾਸਿ ਸਾਸਿ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਮਨਹਿ ਸਮਾਲੇ ॥ਸੋ ਧਨੁ ਸੰਚਹੁ ਜੋ ਚਾਲੈ ਨਾਲੇ ॥੩॥ਤਿਸਹਿ ਪਰਾਪਤਿ ਜਿਸੁ ਮਸਤਕਿ ਭਾਗੁ ॥ਕਹੁ ਨਾਨਕ ਤਾ ਕੀ ਚਰਣੀ ਲਾਗੁ ॥੪॥੫੭॥੧੨੬॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 191 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਵੀਰ !) ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਲੈ । ਆਪਣਾ ਮਨ ਆਪਣਾ ਤਨ (ਭਾਵ, ਆਪਣਾ ਹਰੇਕ ਗਿਆਨ-ਇੰਦ੍ਰਾ) ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਹਵਾਲੇ ਕਰ ਦੇਹ ।੧। ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਵੀਰ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ-ਜਲ ਪੀ (ਸੁਆਸ ਸੁਆਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰ । ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆ ਹੈ) ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਿਮਰ ਸਿਮਰ ਕੇ (ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ) ਸਾਰੀ ਸੜਨ ਬੁਝਾ ਲਈ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦਾ ਗੇੜ ਮੁਕਾ ਲੈ ।੨। (ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਵੀਰ !) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਉਤੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਸਿਰ ਰੱਖ ਦੇ (ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਹਰੇਕ ਸਾਹ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਸਾਂਭ ਰੱਖ । ਉਹ (ਨਾਮ-) ਧਨ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰ ਜੇਹੜਾ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਥ ਕਰੇ ।੩। (ਪਰ ਇਹ ਨਾਮ-ਧਨ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰਨਾ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਵੱਸ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਨਹੀਂ । ਇਹ ਨਾਮ-ਧਨ) ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਮੱਥੇ ਉਤੇ ਭਾਗ ਜਾਗੇ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਆਖ—(ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਤੂੰ ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਚਰਨੀਂ ਲੱਗ (ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਨਾਮ-ਧਨ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਹੈ) ।੪।੫੭।੧੨੬।\\""},{"question":"Một hình chữ nhật có chiều dài là 6 cm, chiều rộng là 5 cm. Biểu thức nào sau đây dùng để biểu thị chu vi của hình chữ nhật đó?a) 2 . 6 + 5 (cm).b) 2 . (6 + 5) (cm).","answer":"Lời giải:Biểu thức biểu thị chu vi của hình chữ nhật có chiều dài là 6 cm, chiều rộng là 5 cm là2 . (6 + 5) (cm)."},{"question":" உலக கால்பந்து கூட்டமைப்பு (FIFA) எந்த நாட்டின் கால்பந்து அமைப்பை இடைநீக்கம் செய்துள்ளது?","answer":"குவைத் மற்றும் இந்தோனேஷியாவை 2015ல் ஃபிஃபா தடை செய்தது. குவைத் நிர்வாகம் என்பதை ஃபிஃபா கண்டறிந்ததை அடுத்து இந்த நடவடிக்கை எடுக்கப்பட்டது."},{"question":"અહીં નરસિંહ મહેતા રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"વૈષ્ણવજન તો તેને રે કહીયે\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"વૈષ્ણવજન તો તેને રે કહીયે, જે પીડ પરાઈ જાણે રે.પરદુઃખે ઉપકાર કરે તોયે, મન અભિમાન ન આણે રે. — વૈષ્ણવ \\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"વૈષ્ણવજન તો તેને રે કહીયે, જે પીડ પરાઈ જાણે રે.પરદુઃખે ઉપકાર કરે તોયે, મન અભિમાન ન આણે રે. — વૈષ્ણવ સકળ લોકમાં સહુને વંદે, નિંદા ન કરે કેની રે.વાચ કાછ મન નિશ્ચલ રાખે, ધન ધન જનની તેની રે. — વૈષ્ણવ સમદ્રષ્ટિને તૃષ્ણા ત્યાગી, પરસ્ત્રી જેને માત રે.જિહ્વા થકી અસત્ય ન બોલે, પરધન નવ ઝાલે હાથ રે.— વૈષ્ણવમોહ માયા વ્યાપે નહિ જેને, દ્રઢ વૈરાગ્ય જેના મનમાં રે.રામ નામ શું તાળી રે વાગી, સકળ તિરથ તેના તનમાં રે. — વૈષ્ણવ વણલોભી ને કપટ રહિત છે, કામ ક્રોધ નિવાર્યા રે.ભણે નરસૈયો તેનું દર્શન કરતા, કુળ ઈકોતેર તાર્યા રે. — વૈષ્ણવ "},{"question":"Ε: Πώς αποκαλείς έναν γέρο χιονάνθρωπο; Α:Νερό! Ποιο νομίζεις ότι είναι το σενάριο του παραπάνω αστείου;","answer":"Εξήγηση: Οι χιονάνθρωποι δεν διαρκούν πολύ επειδή τελικά λιώνουν. Όταν ένας χιονάνθρωπος λιώνει, γίνεται νερό. Αυτό είναι αστείο γιατί ο ακροατής περιμένει ως απάντηση ένα όνομα και όχι νερό. Μπορείτε να δείτε το κινούμενο σχέδιο του Φρόστι ο Χιονάνθρωπος εδώ."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe kolontsaina malagasy ? ","answer":"Ny kolontsaina malagasy dia kolontsain' ny vahoaka malagasy izay isan-karazany noho ny fisian' ny foko samihafa ao aminy sady ahitana taratra ny andiam-pifindrà-monina nifanesy avy any ivelany nankaty Madagasikara, indrindra ny avy any Azia Atsimo-Atsinanana sy Afrika Atsinanana."},{"question":"Na mitologia Romana quem é Mercúrio?","answer":"Mercúrio, na mitologia romana, associado ao deus grego Hermes, é um mensageiro e deus da venda, lucro e comércio, o filho de Maia, uma Plêiade, e Júpiter.  Em suas formas mais antigas, ele aparenta ter sido relacionado ao deus etrusco Turms, mas a maior parte de suas características e mitologia são emprestadas do deus grego, Hermes.Mercúrio é o deus romano encarregado de levar as mensagens de Júpiter, nasceu em Cilene, monte de Arcádia. Os seus atributos incluem uma bolsa, umas sandálias e um capacete com asas, uma varinha de condão e o caduceu. É o deus da eloquência, do comércio e dos viajantes, a personificação da inteligência."},{"question":" طرزالعمل څه ته ویل کیږي؟","answer":"ځواب: د قانون توضیح سره د مثالونو ته طرزالعمل ویل کیږي."},{"question":"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਜਾਵੇਦ ਅਖਤਰ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸੋ।","answer":"ਜਾਵੇਦ ਜਾਨ ਨਿਸਾਰ ਅਖਤਰ (ਜਨਮ 17 ਜਨਵਰੀ 1945) ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਕਵੀ, ਹਿੰਦੀ/ਉਰਦੂ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਗੀਤਕਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਪਟਕਥਾ ਲੇਖਕ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਸਮਾਜਕ ਕਾਰਕੁਨ ਵਜੋਂ ਵੀ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਹਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਕੁਝ ਕਾਮਯਾਬ ਰਚਨਾਵਾਂ 1970ਵਿਆਂ ਅਤੇ 1980ਵਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਲੀਮ ਖਾਨ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਂਝੇ ਤੌਰ ਤੇ ਸਲੀਮ -ਜਾਵੇਦ ਜੋੜੀ ਦੇ ਨਾਂ ਹੇਠ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਈਆਂ। ਅਖ਼ਤਰ ਦਾ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ ਸੰਗਰਾਮੀਆ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ 1857 ਦੇ ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ ਸੰਗਰਾਮ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜੇ ਉਘੇ ਨਾਮ, ਅਲਾਮਾ ਫ਼ਜ਼ਲ-ਏ-ਹੱਕ ਖੈਰਬਾਦੀ (ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ 1861 ਵਿੱਚ ਕਾਲਾ ਪਾਣੀ ਜੇਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਫਾਂਸੀ ਲਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ) ਦੇ ਪੋਤਰੇ ਹਨ।== ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਜੀਵਨ ==ਜਾਵੇਦ ਅਖਤਰ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ 17 ਜਨਵਰੀ 1945 ਨੂੰ ਗਵਾਲੀਅਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਹੋਸ਼ ਲਖਨਊ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੰਭਾਲੀ, ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ ਹੋਸ਼ ਖੋਇਆ ਅਲੀਗੜ ਵਿੱਚ, ਫਿਰ ਭੋਪਾਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਹਿਕੇ ਕੁੱਝ ਹੋਸ਼ਿਆਰ ਹੋਇਆ। ਲੇਕਿਨ ਬੰਬਈ ਆਕੇ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਦਿਨਾਂ ਤੱਕ ਹੋਸ਼ ਠਿਕਾਣੇ ਰਹੇ। ਉਹ ਇੱਕ ਅਜਿਹੇ ਪਰਵਾਰ ਦੇ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਹਨ ਜਿਸਦੇ ਜਿਕਰ ਦੇ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਉਰਦੁ ਸਾਹਿਤ ਦਾ ਇਤਹਾਸ ਅਧੁਰਾ ਰਹਿ ਜਾਏਗਾ। ਸ਼ਾਇਰੀ ਤਾਂ ਪੀੜ੍ਹੀਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਖੂਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੌੜ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਜਾਨ ਨਿਸਾਰ ਅਖਤਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਪ੍ਰਗਤੀਸ਼ੀਲ ਕਵੀ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਤਾ ਸਫਿਆ ਅਖਤਰ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਉਰਦੂ ਲੇਖਿਕਾ ਅਤੇ ਅਧਿਆਪਿਕਾ ਸਨ। ਜਾਵੇਦ ਪ੍ਰਗਤੀਸ਼ੀਲ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਅਤੇ ਸਿਤਾਰੇ ਹਰਮਨ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਕਵੀ ਮਜਾਜ ਦੇ ਭਾਣਜੇ ਵੀ ਹਨ। ਆਪਣੇ ਦੌਰ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਸ਼ਾਇਰ ਮੁਜਤਰ ਖੈਰਾਬਾਦੀ ਜਾਵੇਦ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਦਾਦੇ ਸਨ। ਪਰ ਇੰਨਾ ਸਭ ਹੋਣ ਦੇ ਬਾਵਜੂਦ ਜਾਵੇਦ ਦਾ ਬਚਪਨ ਯਤੀਮਾਂ ਜਿਹਾ ਗੁਜ਼ਰਿਆ। ਛੋਟੀ ਉਮਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਆਂਚਲ ਸਿਰ ਤੋਂ ਉਠ ਗਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਲਖਨਊ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੁੱਝ ਸਮਾਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਨਾ ਨਾਨੀ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਗੁਜ਼ਾਰਨ ਦੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਅਲੀਗੜ੍ਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਾਸੀ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਭੇਜ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਉਥੋਂ ਦੇ ਸਕੂਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਹੋਈ। ਬਾਪ ਨੇ ਦੂਜਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਕੁੱਝ ਦਿਨ ਭੋਪਾਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਤ੍ਰੇਈ ਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਦੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਥੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੋਸਤਾਂ ਦੇ ਭਰੋਸੇ ਹੋ   ਗਿਆ। ਇੱਥੇ ਕਾਲਜ ਦੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਪੂਰੀ ਕੀਤੀ, ਅਤੇ ਜਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੇ ਨਵੇਂ ਸਬਕ ਵੀ ਸਿੱਖੇ।ਜਾਵੇਦ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਵਿਆਹ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਪਤਨੀ ਤੋਂ ਦੋ ਬੱਚੇ ਹਨ - ਫਰਹਾਨ ਅਖਤਰ, ਜੋਆ ਅਖਤਰ।ਫਰਹਾਨ ਪੇਸ਼ੇ ਵਲੋਂ ਫਿਲਮ ਪ੍ਰੋਡਿਊਸਰ, ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ, ਐਕਟਰ, ਗਾਇਕ ਹੈ। ਜੋਆ ਵੀ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਵਜੋਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਕੈਰੀਅਰ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਕਰ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"బాలమురళి మొదటి. సంగీత కచేరిని గురించిన విశేషాలేమిటి ?","answer":"బెజవాడలో సుసర్ల దక్షిణామూర్తి ఉత్సవాలు జరపటానికి నిశ్చయమయింది. కార్యక్రమానికి పదిమంది పేర్లలో బాలమురళి పేరు కూడ చేర్చారు.ఆ రోజు తొలి ఏకాదశి బాలమురళి తొమ్మిదవ పుట్టినరోజు. ఉదయం 8 నుంచి బాలమురళి ఏ గంట సేపో పాడనీచ్చి, తరవాత భోజనాల వేళ దాకా ముసునూరి సూర్యనారాయణ భాగవతార్ గారి హరికథా కాలక్షేపం అనుకున్నారు. కాని, తొమ్మిదేళ్ళ బాలమురళి రెండున్నర గంటల సేపు పక్కా పాటకచేరీ చేసాడు. ఆలాపనా, కీర్తనా, స్వరకల్పనా సమస్త హంగులతో పాడాడు. వింటున్న పండితులకు మతులు పోయాయి.పారుపల్లి రామకృష్ణయ్య పంతులు ఆనందాశ్రువులు రాల్చి తన గురుత్వాన్ని కొనసాగించారు. తన దగ్గర సంగీతం నేర్చుకున్న పిల్లవాడు తనతో సమానంగా కచేరీ చేస్తే మరొక గురువైతే ఆగ్రహించటానికి ఎన్ని కారణాలైనా ఉండవచ్చు. కాని, పారుపల్లివారి గొప్ప మనసును మెచ్చుకోవాలి. బాలమురళి ఒక వంకపాట కచేరీలు చేస్తూ, శిష్యరికం చేసి కీర్తనలు నేర్చుకున్నాడు. మా గురువు లాంటి గురువు ‘నభూతో నభవిష్యతి’ అంటాడు బాలమురళి.ఈ విధంగా అణుబాంబు పేల్చినట్టు బాలమురళి మొదటి పాట కచేరీ చేసినపుడు కుర్తాలం స్వాములవారు విన్నారు."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക. ചോദ്യം: ഞാൻ എങ്ങനെ ശക്തി കണക്കാക്കും?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ന്യൂട്ടന്റെ രണ്ടാമത്തെ നിയമം ഉപയോഗിച്ചാണ് ശക്തി കണക്കാക്കുന്നത്: F = ma, ഇവിടെ F എന്നത് ബലം, m എന്നത് പിണ്ഡം, a എന്നത് ത്വരണം. ഒരു വസ്തുവിന്റെ പിണ്ഡത്തെ അതിന്റെ ത്വരണം കൊണ്ട് ഗുണിക്കുക, അതിൽ പ്രവർത്തിക്കുന്ന ശക്തി കണ്ടെത്തുക."},{"question":"Onye bụ Portia Modise?","answer":"Portia Modise (amụrụ na 20 Junu 1983) bụ onye na-agba bọọlụ South Africa nke ritere onyinye dịka onye kacha agba bọọlụ na 2006 Women's African Football Championship . Ọ nọchitere anya ndị otu mba South Africa na 2012 London Olympics. Ọ ghọrọ onye egwuregwu Afrịka mbụ gbara goolu 100 nke mba ụwa."},{"question":"ඉන්දියාවේ ජාතික ගීතය කුමක්ද?","answer":"වන්දේ මාතරම්"},{"question":"هل مشاعر الجملة التالية سيئة جدا، سيئة، جيدة، جيدة جدا أم ممتازة : أركيلة ممتازة","answer":"مشاعر الجملة السابقة ممتازة."},{"question":"问题：什么是冰？","answer":"回答：冰是水在低温条件下凝固形成的固体物质。"},{"question":"Que tipo de animal é uma “orca”?","answer":"Apesar de comumente acreditar-se que Orca são uma espécie de baleia elas na verdade são uma espécie de golfinho"},{"question":"\\"Адеби жок жигит жүгөнү жок атка окшош ... \\" деген макал-лакапты улантып берчи ?","answer":"Сиз суранган макал-лакаптын жообу мындай болушу мүмкүн : \\"ААдеби жок жигит жүгөнү жок атка окшош, адеби жок аял кабаанак итке окшош.\\""},{"question":"من يتحمل العطش أكثر من الجمل ؟","answer":"الزرافه."},{"question":"Wanene ya jagoranci fim shirya fim din Titanic?","answer":"James Cameron ya jagoranta."},{"question":"Jawablah pertanyaan berikut berdasarkan konteks di bawah ini:Konteks:Tujuan liburan Bima, yaitu Gunung Bromo, terletak 851,3 kilometer (km) dari Jakarta. Berkat Tol Trans Jawa, jarak sejauh ini bisa ditempuh hanya dengan 10-11 jam dengan melewati 17 ruas tol. Tiga dari 17 ruas tol tersebut antara lain: Tol Jakarta-Cikampek, Jalan Layang MBZ Sheikh Mohamed Bin Zayed, Tol Cikampek-Palimanan.Ruas tol yang perlu dilewati Bima untuk mencapai tempat tujuannya adalah sebagai berikut, kecuali?A. Tol Cikampek-PalimananB. Bakauheni - Terbanggi BesarC. Tol Jakarta-CikampekD. Jalan Layang MBZ Sheikh Mohamed Bin ZayedJawaban:","answer":"Ruas tol Bakauheni - Terbanggi Besar tidak disebutkan di dalam paragraf konteks. Jadi, jawaban pertanyaan di atas adalah: B. Bakauheni - Terbanggi Besar."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：哪所大學是美國最古老的公立大學？","answer":"答案：美國最古老的公立大學是威廉與瑪麗學院（The College of William & Mary）。該學院成立於1693年，是美國歷史上第二所成立的大學，也是第一所公立大學。"},{"question":"નીચેના શબ્દસમૂહ માટે એક શબ્દ આપો:સ્પર્શમાત્રથી લોઢાને સોનામાં ફેરવી દેનાર મણિ","answer":"પારસમણિ "},{"question":"Кирпик какпоо","answer":"Уктай албай коюу, уйку бетин көрбөө, уйкусу качуу, чырм этпөө.Чалгынга барган берендер, Чаалыгып кирпик какпады. (Бөкөнбаев)"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي الأجهزة التي ترتبط ارتباطًا مُباشرًا في الحاسب الآلي؟","answer":"الإجابة: تتعدّد الأجهزة التي  نستخدمها بشكل يومي، وأهمّها (الهواتف الذكيّة، وأجهزة التلفاز، وأجهزة الألعاب على اختلاف أنواعها، والأجهزة القابلة للارتداء (الوارليس) بالإضافة للساعات الذكية والسماعات الذكيّة أيضًا)."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Mazoto kamo velona sahala amin'ny akoholahy, ..............................  \\" ","answer":"\\"  Mazoto kamo velona sahala amin'ny akoholahy, mba mifoha maraim-be ihany fa mijanona eo amorom-patana. \\" "},{"question":"তাড়িতচৌম্বক তরঙ্গ কাকে বলে?","answer":"তড়িৎ ও চৌম্বকক্ষেত্রের কম্পনের ফলে সঞ্চালিত শক্তিকে তাড়িতচৌম্বক বিকিরণ বা তাড়িতচৌম্বক তরঙ্গ বলে।পরিবর্তনশীল চৌম্বক ফ্লাক্স তড়িৎক্ষেত্র উৎপন্ন করে এবং পরিবর্তনশীল তড়িৎ ফ্লাক্স চৌম্বকক্ষেত্র সৃষ্টি করে। এ থেকে বোঝা যায় যে, কোনো অঞ্চলে যদি তড়িৎ বা চৌম্বক ফ্লাক্সের পরিবর্তন ঘটে, তাহলে সে অঞ্চলের বাইরে পারিপার্শ্বিক স্থানে আলোর দ্রুতিতে তাড়িতচৌম্বক ক্ষেত্র সঞ্চালিত হবে। এরকম চলাচলকারী তড়িৎ ও চৌম্বকক্ষেত্রকে বলা হয়। তাড়িতচৌম্বক বিকিরণ বা তাড়িতচৌম্বক তরঙ্গ। সুতরাং তাড়িতচৌম্বক তরঙ্গ হলো কোনো স্থান দিয়ে আলোর দ্রুতিতে গতিশীল তড়িৎ ও চৌম্বক আলোড়ন। এ তরঙ্গে তড়িৎ ও চৌম্বকক্ষেত্র সর্বদা সমকোণে থাকে। উভয়ক্ষেত্রই সঞ্চারণের অভিমুখের সাথে সমকোণে থাকে। এ তরঙ্গ তাই আড় তরঙ্গ। কয়েকটি তাড়িতচৌম্বক তরঙ্গের নাম হলো বেতার তরঙ্গ, মাইক্রো তরঙ্গ, অবলোহিত তরঙ্গ, দৃশ্যমান আলো, অতি বেগুনি বিকিরণ, এক্সরে ও গামারশ্মি।অর্থাৎ, শূন্যস্থান দিয়ে আলোর দ্রুতিতে গতিশীল তড়িৎ ও চৌম্বক আলোড়ন, যাতে তড়িৎ ও চৌম্বকক্ষেত্র পরস্পর লম্ব এবং এরা উভয়ে তরঙ্গ সঞ্চালন অভিমুখের সাথে লম্ব থাকে তাকে তাড়িতচৌম্বক তরঙ্গ বলে।"},{"question":"Awa o sọ pe a fẹẹ ṣatilẹyin fun Tinubu o-Ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre","answer":"Yatọ si iroyin kan to n ja ranyin lori atẹ ayelujara laipẹ yii, nibi tawọn kan ti n sọ pe ẹgbẹ awọn agbaagba ilẹ Yoruba nni, Afẹnifẹre ti buwọ lu erongba Aṣiwaju Bọla Tinubu lati jade dupo aarẹ orileede yii ninu eto idibo gbogbogboo to n bọ, ẹgbẹ naa ni iroyin ọhun ki i ṣe ootọ, awọn o fọwọ si Tinubu, bẹẹ lawọn o ti i fọwọ si ẹnikẹni titi dasiko yii.Atẹjade kan ti Alamoojuto eto ibanisọrọ fun ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre, Ọgbẹni Ṣọla Lawal, fi lede lorukọ ẹgbẹ naa lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee yii, sọ pe ọrọ iku ojiji to mu Ọgbẹni Yinka Odumakin to jẹ ọkan pataki oloye ẹgbẹ naa lọ lawọn ṣi n daro rẹ lọwọ, awọn o ba ẹnikẹni sọrọ to jẹ mọ a n dupo aarẹ debi tawọn aa fọwọ si ẹnikẹni.Ṣe laipẹ yii ni ọrọ ọhun fọn sori atẹ ayelujara lẹyin abẹwo ibanikẹdun ti agba oloṣelu ẹgbẹ APC ati gomina ipinlẹ Eko nigba kan nni, Oloye Bọla Ahmed Tinubu, lọọ ṣe si Oloye Ayọ Adebanjọ fun ti ipapoda Yinka Odumakin. Wọn ni Dayọ Adeyẹye to n ṣagbatẹru eto ipolongo fun Tinubu lati dupo aarẹ sọ pe lasiko abẹwo ọhun ni Alagba Fasọranti ti kede pe ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre ti buwọ lu Tinubu fun ipo aarẹ ti wọn lo fẹẹ dije rẹ.Ṣugbọn ẹgbẹ naa ni irọ ni, ko soootọ kan ninu ọrọ naa, tori niṣe lawọn so gbogbo igbokegbodo ati igbesẹ tawọn n ti la silẹ tẹlẹ rọ na, ọrọ ti iku Odumakin lo ṣi ba awọn bayii.Yatọ siyẹn, wọn ni Alagba Reuben Fasọranti tawọn kan sọ pe oun lo fọkan Tinubu balẹ fun ti idije dupo aarẹ ọhun, ti fa ipo aṣaaju ẹgbẹ le Oloye Ayọ Adebanjọ lọwọ lati bii ọsẹ mẹta ṣaaju asiko yii, lẹyin ti wọn ti fọdun mejila tukọ akoso ẹgbẹ naa, ko le waa jẹ awọn ni wọn maa tun sọrọ lorukọ ẹgbẹ lati fọwọ si ẹnikẹni fun ipo aarẹ.Ẹgbẹ ọhun ni iwa ailọwọ ni, iwa aibikita ni, bẹẹ lawọn o si reti iru nnkan bẹẹ pe ki Ọmọọba Dayọ Adeyẹye maa sọrọ nipa ibuwọlu ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre fun eto oṣelu Tinubu niru asiko yii, ti ẹgbẹ naa n sọfọ iku ojiji to mu ẹni wọn lọ.Wọn niṣe lo yẹ ki Adeyẹye si ba awọn kẹdun lasiko yii, ko si fi ọrọ ti oṣelu ati ipolongo eyikeyii rọ na, tori ara ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre ṣaa loun naa nigba kan, ọrẹ lo si jẹ si oloogbe tawọn n ṣedaro ẹ yii."},{"question":" Sheeg Ninkii Ugu Horeeyey Ee Muslimiinta Salaad Jimco Tujiyo","answer":" Wuxu Ahaa Asxaabigii Weynaa Ee Sacad Bin Suraara Rc."},{"question":"\\"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks dari Bahasa Jawa yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke dalam teks Bahasa Indonesia.Srengenge marai alas krasa anget. Kewan-kewan padha metu dolanan.Terjemahan:\\"","answer":"Hari itu adalah hari dengan matahari yang begitu cerah di hutan. Seluruh hewan keluar dari sarangnya dan bermain."},{"question":"e – వ్యాపార వ్యవహారాలలో కలిగే నష్ట భయాలను తెలపండి.","answer":"e – వ్యాపార వ్యవహారాలలో కలిగే నష్ట భయాలు :ఇంటర్నెట్ వాడకములో సమాచారము అనధికారికముగా మార్చివేయబడడం. అనే నష్టభయమున్నది.రహస్యముగా ఉంచవలసిన వ్యక్తిగత సమాచారము మరియు క్రెడిట్ కార్డు వివరాలు, పాస్వర్డ్ లాంటి బ్యాంకింగ్ సమాచారానికి సంబంధించిన నష్టభయాలు.e – వాణిజ్యం ద్వారా జరిగే వ్యవహారాలకు భౌతిక ఆధారాలు లేని కారణముగా చట్టబద్ధతకు సంబంధించిన నష్టభయాలు ఎక్కువ.ఎలక్ట్రానిక్ సమాచారం అందించడములో వైఫల్యం, మొత్తము వ్యాపారము ముగింపుకు దారితీసే నష్టభయాలు.నిర్వాహక వర్గం, e – వాణిజ్య వ్యవహారాలు తన అదుపులో ఉంచుకొని, సరి చూసుకొని మరియు తగిన సమాచార పద్ధతులు ఎంచుకోవడంలోని నష్ట భయాలు.వైరస్లు, హ్యాగింగ్ంటి సాంకేతికపరమైన నష్ట భయాలు."},{"question":"Lông quả cầu lông làm bằng gì có chất lượng tốt nhất?","answer":"Lông ngỗng. Quả cầu lông lý tưởng nhất nên được làm từ lông ngỗng, đôi khi thay thế bằng lông vịt. Quả cầu hình nón, gồm 16 lông vũ gắn vào đế cầu. Những chiếc lông này phải được lấy từ một cánh bên trái của con ngỗng, để cầu bay theo chiều kim đồng hồ, thuận tiện cho các tay vợt. Ngoài lông vũ, cầu cũng có thể làm từ nhựa tổng hợp, miễn là đảm bảo quy chuẩn. Nhưng các giải hàng đầu thường dùng cầu lông ngỗng."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي السورة التي يجب قراءتها في كل ركعة في الصلاة؟","answer":"الإجابة: الفاتحة"},{"question":"Iza no lehiben’ny governemanta araka ny lalàm-panorenana malagasy ary inona no andraikiny?","answer":"Ny praiminisitra notendren’ny Filoham-pirenena no lehiben’ny governemanta ary mitantana ny politikan’ny Firenena. Manana fahefana amin’ny minisitra izy."},{"question":"Maxaa Natan doortaye?","answer":"Naftaan doortayeeDagtay maanka ee Dadka iga xigtaay.Duxda CaashaqiyoDareen igu jiraan kuu daabacaaDaalayoo runtiiAdigaan dartaaduurka ugalee dugsi ii ahawHaygu daawanineDareenka i hayanakaalayoo dawee ila daadahee Hara HR Duruufaha wakhtiga dadku igu nacee igu dayriyana Haka raacin dacalAdna daacadii kuma daynayeedookhiyo naftaan kugu daahayaawaan kuu dirneeDeeq aan helniyodedab iyo aroos u ahaw diyaar                                                    "},{"question":"لدينا الجملتان 'خزانة الملابس أكبر من الخزانة العادية.' و 'الخزانة العادية أكبر من خزانة الملابس.'. هل تدل الجملتان على نفس المعنى؟","answer":"لا، الجملتان السابقتان تحملان معنا متناقض."},{"question":"كم كان عدد المسلمين في غزوة أحد ؟الإجابة: ١٠٠٠ وانسحب منهم عبد الله بن أبي ومن معه من المنافقين ٣٠٠ فأصبحوا ٧٠٠.","answer":"لإجابة: ١٠٠٠ وانسحب منهم عبد الله بن أبي ومن معه من المنافقين ٣٠٠ فأصبحوا "},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මැතිවරණ දිස්ත්‍රික්ක ගණන කීයද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මැතිවරණ දිස්ත්‍රික්ක ගණන විසි දෙකයි. (22) ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ 1978 ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව ප්‍රකාර බහු-මන්ත්‍රී මැතිවරණ දිස්ත්‍රික්ක 22ක් වෙතින් සමානුපාතික නියෝජන මැතිවරණ ක්‍රමයක් මගින් පාර්ලිමේන්තුවේ මන්ත්‍රීවරුන් තෝරා පත් කර ගැනුමට ඉඩ සලසා දී ඇත. ඒවා නම්:1) කොළඹ\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  කොළඹ , පළාත: බස්නාහිර)2) ගම්පහ\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  ගම්පහ , පළාත: බස්නාහිර)3) කළුතර\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  කළුතර , පළාත: බස්නාහිර)4) මහනුවර\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  මහනුවර , පළාත: මධ්‍යම)5) නුවරඑලිය\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  නුවරඑලිය , පළාත: මධ්‍යම)6) මාතලේ\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  මාතලේ , පළාත: මධ්‍යම)7) ගාල්ල\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  ගාල්ල , පළාත: දකුණ)8) මාතර\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  මාතර , පළාත: දකුණ)9) හම්බන්තොට\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  හම්බන්තොට , පළාත: දකුණ)10) අනුරාධපුර\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:අනුරාධපුර , පළාත: උතුරු මැද)11) පොළොන්නරුව\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක: පොළොන්නරුව , පළාත: උතුරු මැද)12) ත්‍රිකුණාමලය\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  ත්‍රිකුණාමලය , පළාත: නැගෙනහිර)13) මඩකලපුව\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  මඩකලපුව , පළාත: නැගෙනහිර)14) දිගාමඩුල්ල\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  අම්පාර , පළාත: නැගෙනහිර)15) බදුල්ල\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  බදුල්ල , පළාත: ඌව)16) මොණරාගල\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  මොණරාගල , පළාත: ඌව)17) වන්නි\\tඅනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  වවුනියා, මුලතිවු සහ (මන්නාරම , පළාත: උතුර)18) යාපනය\\tඅනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  යාපනය සහ (කිලිනොච්චි , පළාත: උතුර)19) කුරුණෑගල\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  කුරුණෑගල , පළාත: වයඹ)20) පුත්තලම\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  පුත්තලම , පළාත: වයඹ)21) රත්නපුර\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  රත්නපුර , පළාත: සබරගමුව)22) කෑගල්ල\\t(අනුරූපී දිස්ත්‍රික්ක:  කෑගල්ල , පළාත: සබරගමුව)"},{"question":"鍾乳洞で、上から垂れ下がっているものを鍾乳石というのに対し、地面からそそり立っているものを何というでしょう？","answer":"石筍（せきじゅん）"},{"question":"Wat weet je over de stad Aberdeen in Schotland?","answer":"Aberdeen is een stad gelegen in het noordoosten van Schotland. Vanaf 2020 had het een bevolking van 200.000 mensen en is het de op twee na grootste stad van Schotland, na Edinburgh (435.000) en Glasgow (610.000). Aberdeen wordt ook wel \\"The Silver City\\" genoemd vanwege het hoge aantal gebouwen in de stad die zijn gebouwd van graniet uit de lokale steengroeve, die op de zeldzame gelegenheid dat het zonlicht de gebouwen raakt, kunnen fonkelen. Sinds de jaren 60 draait de economie van de stad grotendeels om olie en gas vanwege de nabijheid van de Noordzee-olievondst. Aberdeen heeft twee universiteiten; de Universiteit van Aberdeen en de Robert Gordon Universiteit."},{"question":"Quelles sont les principales caractéristiques du mouvement artistique du cubisme ?","answer":"Le cubisme était un mouvement artistique du début du XXe siècle, principalement associé à Pablo Picasso et Georges Braque. Il se caractérise par la représentation d'objets et de sujets sous forme de formes géométriques et de plans multiples. Le cubisme a rompu avec les conventions artistiques traditionnelles en favorisant la représentation simultanée de différents points de vue."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. බිංදු බිංදු මල් වැස්සේ තෙමෙන්නට එපාගලින් ගලට පා තබමින් දුවන්නට එපාගල් මතුපිට ලිස්සනවා පය පැකිලේවී","answer":"බිංදු බිංදු මල් වැස්සේ තෙමෙන්නට එපාගලින් ගලට පා තබමින් දුවන්නට එපාගල් මතුපිට ලිස්සනවා පය පැකිලේවීආල හැඟුම් මං හින්දා හිතෙන්නට එපාදෑස තෙමා ලන දුක් ගිනි නැගෙන්නට එපාදෙමාපියන් පිට ගමකින් මට බහ දේවීනිල් ලන්දේ ගම් මැද්දේ ඉද්ද සමන් ඉපෙනවාවෙල් බැද්දේ වගුරු පුරා කෙකටිය දළු දිලෙනවාගේ මැද්දේ බරණි පුරා වී අස්වනු පිරෙනවාහිත මැද්දේ ලොකු අඩුවක් මගේ සතුට මකනවාආල හැඟුම් මං හින්දා.....ගමෙන් ඈත සිදාදියේ ලොකු නුවරක් තියෙනවාමාල වළලු අරුමෝසම් එහි ඇති බව කියනවාදෙමාපියන් ගමෙන් පිටට මා දෙන්නට හදනවාසිදාදියෙන් කුමාරයෙක් මා බලන්න වඩිනවාබිංදු බිංදු මල් වැස්සේ.....ආල හැඟුම් මං හින්දා.....එඩ්වඩ් ජයකොඩි, නන්දා පතිරණ ගා යනා  කරයි."},{"question":"No anime Fairy Tail, quem é Carla (anteriormente conhecida como Charles)?","answer":"Carla, anteriormente conhecida como Charles, é outro Exceed e é amiga próxima de Wendy Marvell. Ela tem a capacidade de prever o futuro através da leitura de cartas e é uma personagem inteligente e leal à sua guilda."},{"question":"Који су бенефити ЕФТ-а?","answer":"ЕФТ је доказано ефикасан у решавању следећих проблема:Стрес, депресија, страхови и фобије, анксиозност, напади панике, негативне мисли, емоције, ограничавајућа уверења, нервоза, несаница, алергије, мотивација, проблеми у међуљудским односима, физичка нелагодност, бол, проблеми зависности, губитак телесне тежине, финансијске блокаде, недостатак самопоуздања, трауматична искуства и много тога још."},{"question":"نشاۃ ثانیہ کے دوران، تین فنکار—لیونارڈو، مائیکل اینجلو، اور رافیل—اپنے شاہکاروں کے لیے مشہور تھے۔ لیونارڈو کہتے ہیں، \\"مائیکل اینجلو نے ہمیشہ مذہبی مناظر پینٹ کیے تھے۔\\" مائیکل اینجلو کہتے ہیں، \\"رافیل نے کبھی سنگ مرمر کا مجسمہ نہیں بنایا۔\\" رافیل کا کہنا ہے کہ \\"میں نے مشہور سکول آف ایتھنز پینٹنگ بنائی۔\\" کون کس فنکارانہ کارنامے سے وابستہ ہے؟","answer":"لیونارڈو مجسمہ سازی میں مہارت رکھتا ہے، مائیکل اینجلو مذہبی پینٹنگز میں، اور رافیل اسکول آف ایتھنز پینٹنگ کے خالق ہیں۔ اگر مائیکل اینجیلو نے مذہبی مناظر پینٹ کیے تو یہ لیونارڈو کے بیان کے خلاف ہوگا۔ لہذا، لیونارڈو مجسمہ ساز ہے، مائیکل اینجلو مذہبی مصور ہے، اور رافیل اسکول آف ایتھنز کا خالق ہے۔"},{"question":"Qual é a categoria dessa pergunta: Quais as 5 maiores montanhas do mundo que não estão no Nepal, China?.","answer":"Geografia"},{"question":"Qual estado brasileiro tem a sigla RJ?","answer":"Rio de Janeiro."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي أكبر إمارة في الإمارات العربية المتحدة ؟","answer":"الإجابة: إمارة أبوظبي هي أكبر الإمارات"},{"question":"Oro no es, plata no es, ¿qué es? ","answer":"plátano "},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Botswana","answer":"Péeyum réwum Botswana mu ngi tudu Gaborone"},{"question":"Кыргыз накыл кептери англис тилинде жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"No grass grows on his heel – Эмгек менен эл көгөрөт."},{"question":"ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාවේ අගනුවර = කැන්බරා"},{"question":"ውክፔዲያ ምንድን ነው?","answer":"የዕውቀት ማከማቻ ድረ-ገጽ"},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH da Colômbia?","answer":"Em 2021, o Índice de Desenvolvimento Humano (IDH) da Colômbia foi 0,752. Este valor é classificado como \\"alto\\" e coloca a Colômbia no 88º lugar do ranking do IDH."},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp nội dung cho đoạn văn sau: Theo The Star, người phát ngôn của Bộ Ngoại giao Singapore (DFA) Ma. Teresita Daza ngày 31/7 xác nhận thông tin nước này ghi nhận ca mắc đậu mùa khỉ đầu tiên và là người nhập cảnh. Bộ Y tế Singapore cho biết bệnh nhân là người Philippines, 31 tuổi, có kết quả xét nghiệm dương tính với virus đậu mùa khỉ vào ngày 25/7. Ông ta cho biết bản thân bị sốt lần đầu tiên vào ngày 21/7, trước khi xuất hiện vết phát ban trên mặt và cơ thể. Sau đó, ngày 24/7, người này đến khám bệnh tại Bệnh viện Đa khoa Singapore và nhập viện cùng ngày. Bộ Y tế Singapore cho biết tình trạng của bệnh nhân đã ổn định, đồng thời trấn an người dân đậu mùa khỉ không giống Covid-19 lây lan qua không khí. Như vậy, theo Trung tâm Kiểm soát và Phòng ngừa Dịch bệnh Mỹ (CDC), tổng cộng 11 quốc gia, vùng lãnh thổ tại châu Á đã phát hiện ca mắc đậu mùa khỉ, gồm Israel (133), Ấn Độ (4), Thái Lan (2), Đài Loan (2), Qatar (2), Cộng hòa Georgia (1), Hàn Quốc (1), Campuchia (1), Nhật Bản (1), Singapore (1), Philippines (1). Trên toàn cầu, 22,485 ca mắc được ghi nhận ở 79 quốc gia. Đặc biệt, Tây Ban Nha và Brazil đã phát hiện 3 ca tử vong vì bệnh đậu mùa khỉ.","answer":"Đây là những quốc gia đầu tiên bên ngoài châu Phi ghi nhận người tử vong. Ngày 27/7, Giám đốc WHO Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus cho biết cách tốt nhất để bảo vệ khỏi đậu mùa khỉ là \\"giảm nguy cơ phơi nhiễm\\". Ông Tedros đã tuyên bố đậu mùa khỉ là tình trạng khẩn cấp về sức khỏe toàn cầu. Một nghiên cứu được công bố trên tạp chí y học New England cho thấy 98% người nhiễm bệnh là nam giới đồng tính hoặc lưỡng tính, 95% trường hợp lây truyền qua hoạt động tình dục. Nhưng các chuyên gia nhấn mạnh căn bệnh này không được coi là bệnh lây truyền qua đường tình dục. WHO nhiều lần cảnh báo về sự kỳ thị xung quanh căn bệnh này. Kỳ thị có thể ngăn cản những người bị nhiễm bệnh tìm cách điều trị. Tiến sĩ Tedros cho biết: \\"Kỳ thị và phân biệt đối xử có thể nguy hiểm như bất kỳ loại virus nào và có thể làm bùng phát dịch bệnh\\"."},{"question":"ووٹ امانت ہے اس کا صحیح استعمال اسلامی فریضہ بھی ہے","answer":"اس سال انشاء اللہ ملک میں جرنل الیکشن ہونے والے ہیں . پورے ملک میں 18 سال کے افراد جن کا شناختی کارڈ اور اپنے علاقہ میں ووٹر لسٹ میں اپنا نام اندراج کرایا ہوا ہو وہ ان الیکشن میں اپنا قیمتی ووٹ اپنے جو بھی ممبرز ہو اس کو خفیہ بیلٹ کے زریعے ڈال سکتا ہے . اور جن افراد کا جو 18 سال کے ہوگے مگر ابھی تک اپنا نام ووٹر لسٹ میں اندراج نہیں کرایا ہے وہ فورا اپنے علاقہ میں نامزد کردا الیکشن صوبائی الیکشن یا علاقائی آفس میں جاکر اپنا ووٹ اندراج کراسکتا ہے۔ووٹ ایک امانت ہے اور اس کا صحیح استعمال اسلامی فریضہ ہے۔اس اسلامی ذمہ داری کو مفاد پرستی، سڑکوں، گلی کوچوں، کھمبوں، ٹرانسفارمروں اور آلوپیاز کی بھینٹ نہ چڑھایا جائےانتخابات میں ووٹ استعمال کرتے وقت اس کو خالص دنیاوی معاملہ سمجھا جاتا ہے، حالانکہ ووٹ امانت ہے اور اس کا صحیح استعمال دینی فریضہ ہے۔ اگر اہلِ وطن اس دینی امانت اور اسلامی فریضہ کی ادائیگی میں ہمیشہ کی طرح سُستی اور کاہلی برتتے رہے تو نہ ملک کا کوئی طبقہ محفوظ رہے گا اور نہ ہی کوئی مقام الیکشن کمیشن سے زیادہ ذمہ داری عوام ووٹروں کی ہے کہ وہ ووٹ کو امانت اور اسلامی ذمہ داری کے طور پر استعمال کریں ووٹ استعمال کرنے کا مقصد ایسے باکردار لوگوں کو منتخب کرنا ہوتا ہے جو ملک کے خیر خواہ ہوں ، ملکی مفاد، ملک کی بقاء اور استحکام کا درد رکھنے والے ہوںاور نفاذِ شریعت ان کی اولین ترجیح ہو وطن پاکستان کو جسے لاکھوں مسلمانوں نے جان، مال اور عزتوں کی قربانی دے کر اسلامی نظامِ حکومت ، نظامِ معیشت، نظامِ عدالت کے لئے حاصل کیا تھا، اس کی مقننہ اور بااختیار اسمبلی میں غیر مسلم شریک نہ کیا جائے ے۔ ووٹ ایک شرعی شہادت ووٹ نمائندہ کے حق میں شہادت ہے۔معارف القرآن جلد دوم آیت ’’أَنْ تُؤَدُّوْا الْأَمَانَاتِ إِلٰی أَھْلِھَا‘‘کے متعلق لکھا ہے: آیت کانزول اگرچہ ایک خاص واقعہ میں ہے، لیکن حکم عام جس کی پابندی پوری امت کے لئے ضروری ہے۔ ’’إِنَّ اﷲَ یَأْ مُرُکُمْ أَنْ تُؤَدُّوْا الْأَمَانَاتِ إِلٰی أَھْلِھَا‘‘یعنی اللہ تعالیٰ تم کو حکم دیتا ہے کہ امانتیں ان کے مستحقین کو پہنچایا کرو(اسی طرح ووٹ بھی ایک شہادت اور امانت ہے) جس کے ہاتھ میں کوئی امانت ہے، اس پر لازم ہے کہ یہ امانت اس کے اہل و مستحق کو پہنچادے۔حکومت کے مناصب (عہدے) جتنے بھی ہیں، وہ سب اللہ کی امانتیں ہیں،جس کے امین وہ حکام اور افسر ہیں جن کے ہاتھ عزل و نصب کے اختیارات ہیں.ایک حدیث میں ارشاد ہے: جب دیکھو کہ کاموں کی ذمہ داری ایسے لوگوںکے سپرد کر دی گئی جو اس کے اہل نہیں تو (اب فساد کا کوئی علاج نہیں) قیامت کا انتظار کرو قرآن کریم نے لفظ ’’أمانات‘‘ صیغۂ جمع لاکر اس کی طرف اشارہ کر دیا کہ امانت صرف اسی کانام نہیں کہ ایک شخص کا مال کسی دوسرے شخص کے پاس بطور امانت رکھا ہو، بلکہ امانت کی بہت سی اقسام ہیں، جن میں حکومتی عہدے بھی داخل ہیں۔انتخابات میں ووٹ، ووٹر اور امیدوار کی شرعی حیثیت صحیح بخاری شریف کی حدیث میں رسول کریم ا نے شہادت کاذبہ کو شرک کے ساتھ کبائر میں شمار فرمایا ہے ۔ جس حلقے میں چند امیدوار کھڑے ہوں اور ووٹر کو یہ معلوم ہے کہ قابلیت اور دیانت کے اعتبار سے فلاں آدمی قابل ترجیح ہے تو اس کو چھوڑ کر کسی دوسرے کو ووٹ دینا اس اکبر کبائر میں اپنے آپ کو مبتلا کرنا ہے۔ اب ووٹ دینے والا اپنی آخرت اور انجام کو دیکھ کر ووٹ دے، مختصر یہ کہ انتخابات میں ووٹ کی شرعی حیثیت کم از کم ایک شہادت کی ہے، جس کا چھپانا بھی حرام ہے اور اس میں جھوٹ بولنا بھی حرام اور اس پر کوئی معاوضہ لینا بھی حرام، اس میں محض ایک سیاسی ہار جیت اور دنیا کا کھیل سمجھنا بڑی بھاری غلطی ہے۔ آپ جس امیدوار کو ووٹ دیتے ہیں، شرعاً آپ اس کی گواہی دیتے ہیں کہ یہ شخص اپنے نظریے اور علم و عمل اور دیانتداری کی رو سے اس کام کا اہل اور دوسرے امیدواروں سے بہتر ہے۔جس مقصد کے لئے یہ انتخابات ہو رہے ہیں ."},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação para o seguinte parágrafo - Pedernera fez parte da talentosa geração argentina que acabou privada de disputar uma Copa do Mundo por, dentre outros fatores, a ocorrência da Segunda Guerra Mundial, que não deixou condições para que o torneio pudesse ser realizado na década de 1940. Fez sua estreia pela Seleção Argentina em 1940, marcando um dos gols da vitória por 3 x 1 sobre o arquirrival Uruguai. No ano seguinte, integraria o elenco da \\"Albiceleste\\" ","answer":".que sagrou-se campeão sul-americano, o que ele voltaria a ser nas outras duas edições que disputou, em 1942 e 1946"},{"question":"పరాగ సంపర్కానికి తోడ్పడే సహకారాల గురించి క్లుప్తంగా వ్రాయండి.","answer":"పరాసంపర్కం జరగడానికి రెండు నిర్జీవ మరియు జీవ సహకారాల సహాయాన్ని మొక్కలు ఉపయోగించుకుంటాయి. ఎక్కువ శాతం మొక్కలు జీవసహకారుల ద్వారా పరాగ సంపర్కాన్ని జరుపుకుంటాయి.I) నిర్జీవ పరాగసంపర్క సహకారులు :గాలి, నీరు మొదలగునవి సహయపడతాయి.a) వాయు పరాగసంపర్కం :గాలి జరిగే పరాగ సంపర్కాన్ని వాయు పరాగ సంపర్కం అంటారు. ఇది సర్వ సామాన్యమైన నిర్జీవ పరాగ సంపర్కరకం. పుష్పాలు చిన్నవిగా, వర్ణరహితమైన, సువాసన లేకుండా, ద్విలింగకాలై, పుంభాగ ప్రధమోత్పతులు వంటి లక్షణాలు వాయు పరాగ సంపర్కానికి అనుకూలంగా ఉంటాయి.ఉదా : గడ్డి జాతులలో వాయు పరాగ సంపర్కం సర్వసాధారణంb) జలపరాగ సంపర్కం :నీటిద్వారా మొక్కల్లో జరిగే పరాగ సంపర్కాన్ని జలపరాగ సంపర్కం అంటారు. ఇది రెండురకాలు అవి1) ఊర్థ్వజల పరాగ సంపర్కం :వాలిస్ నేరియా వంటి నీటిమొక్కల్లో స్త్రీ పుష్పాలు పొడవైన వృంతాల సహయంతో నీటిపై భాగానికి చేరగా పురుషపుష్పాలు లేదా పుప్పొడి రేణువులు నీటిపై విడుదలవుతాయి. ఇవి నీటి ప్రవాహంతో నిష్క్రియాత్మకంగా కదులుతూ చివరికి కొన్ని, స్త్రీ పుష్పాలను, కీలాగ్రాన్ని చేరతాయి. ఈ విధానాన్ని ఊర్థ్వజల పరాగ సంపర్కం అంటారు.2) అథోజల పరాగ సంపర్కం :నీటి యొక్క అడుగుతతిలంలో జరిగే పరాగ సంపర్కాన్ని అథోజల పరాగ సంపర్కం అంటారు.ఉదా : సముద్రగడ్డిమొక్క జోస్టెరా.II) జీవ పరాగ సంపర్క సహకారులు :దీనిలో కీటకాలు, పక్షులు, గబ్బిలాలు, నత్తలు, జంతువులు మొదలగునవి పరాగ సంపర్కానికి సహాయపడతాయి.a) కీటక పరాగ సంపర్కం :కీటకాల ద్వారా జరిగే పరాగ సంపర్కంఉదా : తేనేటీగలు, చీమలు, పట్టుపురుగులుb) పక్షి పరాగ సంపర్కం (ఆర్నిథోఫిలి) :పక్షులు ద్వారా జరిగే పరాగ సంపర్కం ఉదా : తీతువు పిట్టలు, సన్బర్డ్స్c) కీరోష్టిలిఫెలీ :గబ్బిలాలు వల్ల జరిగే పరపరాగ సంపర్కాన్ని ‘కిరోస్టిలిఫెలీ’ అంటారు.d) తెరోఫిలీ :ఉడుతలు వల్ల జరిగే పరపరాగ సంపర్కాన్ని తెరోఫిలీ అంటారు.e) ఒఫియోఫిలీ :పాములు వల్ల జరిగే పరపరాగ సంపర్కాన్ని ఒఫియోఫిలీ అంటారు."},{"question":"Nyora 8 zvicherwa zvisingaite","answer":"Red Beryl, Paraiba Tourmaline, Alexandrite, Padparadscha Sapphire, Painite, Kashmir Sapphire, Red Diamond, Jadeite"},{"question":"จงเติมคำที่หายไปในประโยค: \\"ตอนนี้ได้เวลา_แล้ว ขอไปนอนก่อน\\"","answer":"คำที่น่าจะเป็นไปได้1. นอน2. พักผ่อน3. งีบ"},{"question":"Dê um exemplo de uma pergunta trivia com essa categoria: história","answer":"Quem era mais jovem quando se tornou Presidente dos Estados Unidos, John F. Kennedy ou Bill Clinton? John F. Kennedy"},{"question":"Doc to summarize: లాక్‌డౌన్‌తో నిర్మానుష్యంగా మారిన ఇండోర్ రోడ్లుదీంతో వివిధ రాష్ట్రాలలోని కొన్ని నగరాల్లో మళ్లీ లాక్‌డౌన్ విధిస్తున్నారు. ఇప్పటికే మహారాష్ట్రలోని కొన్ని నగరాల్లో లాక్‌డౌన్ విధించగా.. తాజాగా మధ్యప్రదేశ్‌లోని మూడు నగరాల్లో ప్రతి  ఆదివారం లాక్‌డౌన్ విధిస్తూ నిర్ణయం తీసుకున్నారు.ప్రస్తుతం ఎక్కడెక్కడ లాక్‌డౌన్, కర్ఫ్యూ అమల్లో ఉంది?జబల్‌పూర్, ఇండోర్, భోపాల్ : మధ్య ప్రదేశ్‌లోని ఈ మూడు నగరాల్లో మార్చి 21న లాక్‌డౌన్ విధించారు. తదుపరి ఆదేశాలు వచ్చేవరకు ప్రతి ఆదివారం ఈ మూడు నగరాల్లో లాక్‌డౌన్ ఉంటుందని ఆ రాష్ట్ర ప్రభుత్వం తెలిపింది. అలాగే, మార్చి 31 వరకు ఈ మూడు నగరాల్లోని అన్ని పాఠశాలలకు సెలవులు ప్రకటించింది.నాగపూర్: మహారాష్ట్రలోని మార్చి 15 నుంచి 21 వరకు లాక్‌డౌన్ ఉంది. అయితే, ఈ సమయంలో అత్యవసర సర్వీసులన్నీ కొనసాగేలా నిర్ణయించారు.ప్రభుత్వ కార్యాలయాలు 25 శాతం సిబ్బందితో పనిచేయాలని ఆదేశించారు.పుణె: మహారాష్ట్రలోని పుణెలో కేసులు పెరుగుతుండడంతో రాత్రి 11 గంటల నుంచి ఉదయం 6 గంటల వరకు కర్ఫ్యూ అమలవుతోంది.మార్చి 31 వరకు కాలేజీలు, స్కూళ్లు అన్నీ మూసివేయాలని ఆదేశించారు. హోటళ్లు, బార్లు, మాల్స్, థియేటర్లను కూడా రాత్రి పూట మూసివేయాలని ఆదేశాలు జారీచేశారు.నాసిక్: మహారాష్ట్రలోని నాసిక్‌లో రాత్రి 7 గంటల నుంచి ఉదయం 7 గంటల వరకు రాత్రి కర్ఫ్యూ అమలవుతోంది.వివాహాలకు 30 మంది కంటే ఎక్కువ హాజరుకారాదని ఆదేశాలిచ్చారు. మార్చి 15 తరువాత హాల్స్‌లో వివాహాలు చేయరాదనీ ఆదేశాలు జారీచేశారు. స్కూళ్లు మూసివేశారు. శని, ఆదివారాలలో ఆలయాలు, ఇతర ప్రార్థనా స్థలాలు మూసివేయాలని ఆదేశించారు.హోటళ్లు ఉదయం 7 నుంచి రాత్రి 9 వరకు తెరిచే అవకాశం ఇచ్చినా సీటింగ్ కెపాసిటీలో 50 శాతం వరకే అనుమతించాలి.డెహ్రడూన్: ఉత్తరాఖండ్ రాష్ట్రం డెహ్రడూన్ జిల్లా మసూరీలోని గాల్వా కాటేజ్ ప్రాంతం, బార్లా గంజ్, ఇతర ప్రాంతాలలో పూర్తిస్థాయి లాక్‌డౌన్ విధిస్తూ ఆ జిల్లా కలెక్టర్ ఆదేశాలు జారీచేశారు. దుకాణాలు, ఆఫీసులు అన్నీ మూసివేయించారు. నిత్యావసరాల కోసం ఇంటికి ఒకరు మాత్రమే బయటకు రావడానికి అనుతిస్తున్నారు.పాటియాలా, లూధియానా, మొహలీ, ఫతేఘర్: పంజాబ్‌లోని పాటియాలా, మొహలీ, లూథియానా, ఫతేఘర్‌లలో ఆ రాష్ట్రం నైట్ కర్ఫ్య్యూ అమలు చేస్తోంది.తాజా పరిస్థితి ఇదీ..దేశంలో గత 24 గంటల్లో 43,846 పాజిటివ్ కేసులు నమోదైనట్లు కేంద్ర ఆరోగ్య, కుటుంబసంక్షేమ మంత్రిత్వ శాఖ తెలిపింది..nSummary in the same language as the doc:","answer":"భారతదేశమంతా జనతా కర్ఫ్యూ ప్రకటించి సోమవారానికి(మార్చి 22) ఏడాదవుతుంది. మరోవైపు దేశంలో కరోనావైరస్ పాజిటివ్ కేసులు మళ్లీ పెరుగుతున్నాయి."},{"question":"هل مشاعر الجملة التالية سلبية ، إيجابية ، أم محايدة : انترنت قوي ومجاني مشي للمحطة 3 دقائق مشي للسوق الصيني 7 دقائق من كاونتر 10 حافلات – حافلة المطار الى محطة السنترال ثم تاكسي الفندق متعاونين تاكسي المحطة الفندق","answer":"مشاعر الجملة السابقة إيجابية."},{"question":"Aiza no misy ny mpanjaka ","answer":"Ny misy ny mpanjakadia any an-dapa"},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk tteokbokki? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah secara terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan Untuk Rice Cakes: Setengah Pack Tepung pulut, 3 sudu besar tepung beras atau gandum, Air, Sedikit garam, Sedikit minyak bijan kalau adaCara Memasak Rice Cakes:1. Satukan bahan di atas2. Letak air sedikit demi sedikit. Jangan lembut sangat atau lembik sangat.3. Kemudian gulung panjang. Potong ikut suka.4. Rebus bahan yang telah dipotong. Kalau sudah naik atas boleh diangkat.5. Tos kan atau masukkan dalam air sejuk.Bahan untuk Sos: 3 sudu besar minyak masak, 5 atau 6 biji cili api dan 4 ulas bawang putih, 2 sudu besar Cili kisar atau serbuk cili (Peda ikut selera. Kalau ingin pedas letak 4 sudu), Satu sudu besar cuka (boleh digantikandengan cuka epal), Sedikit Gula, Sedikit serbuk ikan bilis atau pati ayam, Setengah cawan air masak, Sedikit bijan, Sedikit daun bawangCara Membuat Sos:1. Panaskan minyak.2. Masukkan cili api yang sudah dikisar dengan bawang putih.3. Kalau sudah pecah minyak. Masukkan Serbuk ikan bilis atau ayam.4. Kemudian masukkan air, cuka dan cili kisar atau serbuk cili (kalau pakai serbuk cili pastikan telah dicampur air sedikit).5. Setelah itu letak gula.6. Akhir sekali, Masukkan rice cake yang kita buat tadi.7. Masukkan sedikit daun bawang, kemudian biarkan kuah pekat.8. Hidangkan dengan menaburkan bijan."},{"question":" Ubengeke ahlale kuze kube yilesi sikhathi engadli lapho ekhona. Ubabawazama ukumisa umkakhe isibindi ngokuthi: 'UNkulunkulu akehlulwa yilutho, uzolidalaisu kungekude, ungakhali.'Akekho phakathi kwabo bobabili owayenelisekile ngale nhlalo. Umama wakhala kwazekwasa ethandaza. Okwakumhlupha kakhulu umama ukuthi noma kwakunendlala emziniwakhe, babekwazi ukukha imifino ezaleni badle ukudla okumnandi kwesiZulu balalebenelisekile. Namuhla indoda yakhe ilala ingadlile kodwa yasebenza yafundisa idlaisithukuthuku sayo. Kukubi le ndoda iwa ivuka, yehla yenyuka isebenzela lezi zinganezabo bethi babenza abantu.1. Kungumqondo omuhle yini ukuthi abazali abashadile futhi sebebadalabahlaliswe ngokwehlukana? Sekela impendulo yakho ngamaphuzu AMABILI.","answer":"Kungumqondo ongemuhle.Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo: Umshado usuke uhlanganiswe nguNkulunkulu ngakho-keakubusisekile ukuthi abantu abashadile bahlukaniswe umuntu.  Kuyabahlukumeza abantu abadala ukuqala impilo entshaabangayijwayele.  Uma abantu sebebadala basuke sebefana nezingane benezintoabajwayele ukuzenza ndawonye, ngakho-ke ukubahlukanisakungabafakela ingcindezi. Kungumqondo omuhle.Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo: Kungenzeka ukuthi babebuka iphuzu lokuthi uma bebabili abazalibangaba yizindleko kulabo abazobathatha.  Kungenzeka ukuthi indlu yincane, yayingeke ikwazi ukubathathabobabili.  Kungenzeka ukuthi babezosuke bafune ukushaya umthetho emziniwendodana. (Nokunye okunembayo okuyoshiwo umfundi)"},{"question":"أين تم افتتاح أول بنك للدم في العالم؟ ","answer":"تم افتتاح اول بنك للدم في العالم في مدينة نيويورك، عام 1940م."},{"question":"Sheeg maalintii, bishii iyo  sanadkii ay Soomaaliya ku biirtay ururka Jaamacadda Carabta?","answer":"Waxa ay kusoo biirtay 14kii Febraayo 1974kii."},{"question":" सरकारी नीति वा विधिहरूले उत्सव आयोजनामा कसरी प्रभाव डाल्छन्?","answer":"सरकारी नीति उत्सवको प्रबन्धन, सुरक्षा उपायहरू, वित्तीय समर्थन, र सांस्कृतिक संरक्षण प्रयासहरूमा प्रभाव गर्न सक्छ, जसले उत्सवको कसरी आयोजना गरिएको र कार्यान्वयन गरिएको छ त्यसलाई आकार दिन्छ।"},{"question":"脱色剤を使って、髪内部のメラニン色素を分解して色を抜くことを、ヘアスタイル用語で何というでしょう？","answer":"ブリーチです。"},{"question":"INEC kede ọjọ ti idibo gomina yoo waye l’Ọṣun","answer":"Ajọ eleto idibo orileede yii, INEC, ti kede pe ọjọ kẹrindinlogun, oṣu keje, ọdun 2022, ni idibo gomina yoo waye nipinlẹ Ọṣun.Ninu atẹjade kan ti Akọwe ajọ naa, Rose Oriaran-Anthony, fi sita lo ti ṣalaye pe igbesẹ naa wa nibaamu pẹlu ipin kin-in-ni ati ikeji abala ikejidinlọgọsan-an o din meji ofin eto idibo orileede yii to sọ pe idibo gbọdọ waye nigba to ba ku aadọjọ ọjọ ti asiko ẹni to wa lori ipo yoo wa sopin.Anthony fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe aarin ọjọ kẹrindinlogun, oṣu keji, si ọjọ kejila, oṣu kẹta, ọdun 2022, ni idibo abẹle gbọdọ waye ninu awọn ẹgbẹ oṣelu ti wọn ba fẹẹ kopa ninu idibo gomina l’Ọṣun.O ni ọjọ kẹrindinlogun, oṣu kẹrin, ọdun 2022, ni ipolongo idibo yoo bẹrẹ, ọjọ kẹrindinlogun, oṣu kẹfa, si ni ajọ INEC yoo gbe orukọ awọn oludije jade.Ọjọ kẹrinla, oṣu keje, ọdun 2022, ni gbogbo ipolongo eto idibo gbọdọ wa sopin, nigba ti idibo yoo waye lọjọ kẹrindinlogun, oṣu keje."},{"question":"ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਕੈਂਪਰ ਡਰ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਸੀ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੈਂਪ ਕਾਊਂਸਲਰ ਨੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਭੂਤੀਆਂ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਸੁਣਾਈ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਕੈਂਪਫਾਇਰ 'ਤੇ ਮਾਰਸ਼ਮੈਲੋ ਸੇਕੇ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਕੈਂਪ ਕਾਊਂਸਲਰ ਨੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਭੂਤੀਆਂ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਸੁਣਾਈ।"},{"question":"නෙළුම් කවියක් සඳහා  උදාහරණයක් දෙන්න.","answer":"බොහොම ගන්ට නම් ගොයමෙන්           අස්වනුබොහොම හොදට නෙළුමත් ඕනෑ            වෙනුකොහොම කළත් බෑ නොහෙලා           දැනගනුනෙළුම තමයි අපේ පුරුදුම                  කහවනු"},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 北海道や東北などで20日から雪と強い風　吹雪に気をつけて","answer":"気象庁によると、北海道や東北の日本海側などでは、20日から21日に雪が降って強い風が吹くため、ひどい吹雪になる心配があります。20日は、風速20m以上のとても強い風が吹きそうです。21日はもっと強い風が吹く心配があります。海では5mぐらいの高い波になりそうです。気象庁は、吹雪や高い波、交通などに十分に気をつけるように言っています。来週は、北海道から九州までの広い所に冷たい空気が入ってきそうです。23日ごろから日本海側などで雪がたくさん降って、24日ごろからは太平洋側でもとても寒くなる可能性があります。天気予報をよく見て、気をつけてください。"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Picit perut, keluar benda yang untuk memputihkan gigi anda, apa tu?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah ubat gigi"},{"question":"Кыргызстандын 🇰🇬 желеги жөнүндө эмне айта аласыз?","answer":"🇰🇬 3-март Кыргызстан республиканын мамлекеттик желегинин күнү. 1992-жылы дал ушул күнү желегибиздин сырткы көрүнүшү бекитилген. Ал эми бир күндөн кийин туптуура саат 9да \\"Ак үйдүн\\" үстүнө биринчи жолу жаңы баннер көтөрүлгөн.Баннердин авторлору: Эдил Айдарбеков, Маматбек Сыдыков, Бекбосун Жайчыбеков, Сабыр Иптаров жана Жусуп Матаев."},{"question":"Izinkundla zokuxhumana12Ukusebenzisa izinkundla zokuxhumana kuyinto ethandwa kakhulu kulezi zinsuku. Izinkundlazokuxhumana ezifana no-Tik-Tok, no-Instagram, no-Facebook zisetshenziswa emhlabeni wonkejikelele. Zikhona ezithandwa ngabantu abasha kanti ezinye zisetshenziswa ngabantu abashanabadala ngokufanayo.Izinkundla zokuxhumana ziwusizo esikhathini esiphila kuso. Azigcini nje ngokuba yinto yokuqedaisizungu ngokuxoxa nabangane noma ukudlala imidlalo, kodwa ziphinde zibe yindlela enhlenesheshayo yokuthola ulwazi emhlabeni jikelele ngokucindezela inkinombo nje kuphela. Abantuabasadingi ukuya ezitolo ukuyothenga amaphephandaba namaphephabhuku, noma ukuyaku-inthanethi ukuyobheka izindaba ezisematheni. Abantu abaningi sebezwa izindaba ezintshaku-Twitter. Lo mthombo wolwazi ohleze ukhona uphakela nomkhakha wezemfundo ngoba abafundibayakwazi ukulusebenzisa ngokushesha ukuthola izifundo ezingabalekelela ezifundweni zabo.Kodwa, kumele uqaphele. Kujwayelekile esikhathini samanje ukuthi kube khona abantuabasabalalisa ‘izindaba mbumbulu’ okungaholela kwenkulu inkathazo. Ngakho-ke, kubalulekileukuthi abantu babheke futhi benze isiqiniseko sokuthi abakufundayo kuyiqiniso. Kulula ukufundaindaba bese uyidlulisela kwabanye usebenzisa inkundla yezokuxhumana, okungenza uzitholeususabalalisa indaba engelona iqiniso ungahlosile.Kumele uqaphele ngemininingwane yakho ezinkundleni zikuxhumana ngoba baningi abantuabazithole beyizisulu zobugebengu noma ukukhwabanisa. Isibonelo salokhu, sebebaninganaabantu ababike ukuthi bathenga izinto becabanga ukuthi basebenzisa izitolo ezisemthethweni,kodwa bagcina bengazitholanga izinto abazithengile ngoba lezo zinkampani zingekho. Abantuabasebenzisa izinkundla zokuxhumana kumele baqinisekise ukuthi imininingwane yabo ebalulekileivikelekile ngokuqonda kanye nokusebenzisa izilungiselelo ezifanele eziyimfihlo. Kumele ungafakiyonke imininingwane yakho uma singekho isidingo. Kwesinye isikhathi awazi ukuthi ukhulumanobani futhi lokhu kungaba yingozi.Kodwa, ukuxhumana nabanye ezinkundleni zikuxhumana kungadala amathuba. Abantubangakhangisa imikhiqizo yabo ukuze bathole imali noma baziphilise. Bangakhombisa amakhono abookungaheha nalabo abangagcina bebanika imisebenzi ezinkundleni ezifana no-LinkedIn. Imindeninabangane bayazi ukuthi kwenzekani ezimpilweni zabo ngokubuka izithombe namavidiyo abo,baphawule noma bathumele imiyalezo. Abanye abantu bacabanga ukuthi sesilahlekelwe yikhonolokuxoxa nabangane ngoba uthola abantu behlezi egumbini elilodwa kodwa bengakhulumisaningoba begqolozele omakhalekhukhwini babo. Kubalulekile ukuhlukanisa ngokufanele isikhathiosichitha ezinkundleni zokuxhumana nokubhekana nabantu ubuso nobuso.Akukhathaleki ukuthi ithini imibono yakho ngezinkundla zokuxhumana, zisetshenziswa kakhuluemphakathini wanamuhla futhi aziyi ndawo. Kuliqiniso ukuthi kulukhuni ukucabanga ukuthi impiloingaba njani ngaphandle kwazo.1. Ububi bokusebenzisa izinkundla zokuxhumana:","answer":"Ububi bezinkundla zokuxhumana:1 Ukusabalaliswa kwezindaba ezingelona iqiniso / Kulula ukufunda indababese uyidlulisela kwabanye, okungenza uzithole ususabalalisa indabaengelona iqiniso ungahlosile2 baningi abantu abazithole beyizisulu zobugengu3 Awazi ukuthi ukhuluma nobani4 sesilahlekelwe yikhono lokuxoxa / Zingenza singakwazi ukuxhumananabantu ubuso nobuso"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਜਿਨ ਹਰਿ ਹਿਰਦੈ ਸੇਵਿਆ ਤਿਨ ਹਰਿ ਆਪਿ ਮਿਲਾਏ ॥ਗੁਣ ਕੀ ਸਾਝਿ ਤਿਨ ਸਿਉ ਕਰੀ ਸਭਿ ਅਵਗਣ ਸਬਦਿ ਜਲਾਏ ॥ਅਉਗਣ ਵਿਕਣਿ ਪਲਰੀ ਜਿਸੁ ਦੇਹਿ ਸੁ ਸਚੇ ਪਾਏ ॥ਬਲਿਹਾਰੀ ਗੁਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਜਿਨਿ ਅਉਗਣ ਮੇਟਿ ਗੁਣ ਪਰਗਟੀਆਏ ॥ਵਡੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਵਡੇ ਕੀ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਆਲਾਏ ॥੭॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 303 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕੀਤਾ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਆਪਣੇ ਵਿਚ) ਮਿਲਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈਉਹਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ (ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ) ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਭਿਆਲੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਾਪ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਸਾੜੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ(ਪਰ) ਹੇ ਸੱਚੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਔਗੁਣਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਾਲੀ ਦੇ ਭਾ ਵੇਚਣ ਲਈ (ਭਾਵ, ਸਹਲੇ ਹੀ ਨਾਸ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ) ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਸਾਂਝ ਉਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਮੈਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਹਾਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਜਿਸ ਨੇ (ਜੀਵ ਦੇ) ਪਾਪ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਗੁਣ ਪਰਗਟ ਕੀਤੇ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਜੀਵ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹੀ ਵੱਡੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਵੱਡੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਨ ਲੱਗ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੭।\\""},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండివ్యతికరణం మరియు వివర్తన పట్టీల విషయంలో శక్తి 6. పరస్పరం లంబంగా ఉన్న రెండు పోలరాయిడ్ల మధ్య నిత్యత్వ నియమం వర్తిస్తుందా? వివరించండి.","answer":"వ్యతికరణం, వివర్తనాల్లో శక్తి నిత్యత్వ నియమం :వ్యతికరణం మరియు వివర్తనం దృగ్విషయాలకు శక్తి నిత్యత్వ నియమము అనుసరించబడుతుంది. వ్యతికరణ మరియు వివర్తన పట్టీలలో ద్యుతిమయ మరియు ద్యుతిహీన పట్టీలు ఏర్పడతాయి. వీటిలో శక్తి నిత్యత్వ నియమం వర్తిస్తుంది. ఎందుకంటే ద్యుతిహీన పట్టీ వద్ద కాంతి తీవ్రత ఎంత తగ్గుతుందో, అంతే కాంతి తీవ్రత ద్యుతిమయ పట్టీ వద్ద పెరుగుతుంది. అనగా, వ్యతికరణ, వివర్తన పట్టీలలో కాంతి శక్తి పునర్విభజన మాత్రమే జరుగును. కాని మొత్తం శక్తి స్థిరంగా ఉండును."},{"question":"Lithetha ukuthini igama u\\"Siphokazi\\" ngesilungu?","answer":"Dear gift"},{"question":"Ayat  1: Dia menghabiskan dua pukulan di belakang Bubba Watson dan Louis Oosthuizen dan menyesali bahawa dia tidak memenangi kejohanan itu. Ayat 2: Dia menghabiskan dua pukulan di belakang Louis Oosthuizen dan Bubba Watson dan menyesali bahawa dia tidak memenangi kejohanan itu. Soalan: Apakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Ya, betul."},{"question":" Title: ఉరి తాళ్లను దేశంలో ఆ ఒక్క చోటే ఎందుకు తయారు చేస్తారుnSummary: భారత్‌లో చాలా అరుదైన కేసుల్లోనే దోషులకు ఉరిశిక్షలు పడుతుంటాయి. అంతే అరుదుగా, ఆ శిక్షలు అమలు చేసేందుకు ఉపయోగించే తాడు కూడా దేశంలో ఒక్క చోటే లభిస్తుంది. అదే బిహార్‌లోని బక్సర్ సెంట్రల్ జైలు.nArticle (Max 500 characters):","answer":"గాంధీ హంతకుడు గాడ్సే నుంచి ముంబయి దాడుల్లో దోషిగా తేలిన కసబ్ వరకూ భారత్‌లో ఉరిశిక్షను ఎదుర్కొన్న ఖైదీల చుట్టూ బక్సర్ ఉరితాడే బిగుసుకుంది.10 ఉరితాళ్లు చేయించాలని బక్సర్ జైలు అధికారులకు ఇటీవల ఆదేశాలు వచ్చాయి. దీంతో ఈ జైలు మరోసారి వార్తల్లోకెక్కింది.ఈ తాళ్లు ఎవరిని ఉరి తీసేందుకన్న విషయంపై రకరకాల వదంతులు వ్యాపిస్తున్నాయి.నేషనల్ క్రైమ్ రికార్డ్స్ బ్యూరో సమాచారం ప్రకారం భారత్‌లో ఇప్పటివరకూ దాదాపు 1500 మందికి కోర్టులు ఉరిశిక్ష విధించగా, 21 మందికి దాన్ని అమలు చేశారు."},{"question":"البحر الأحمر","answer":"البحر الأحمر أو بحر القُلْزُم  أو بحر الحبشة. يعدّ هو والخليج العربي مدخل مياه بحر المحيط الهندي، الواقع بين أفريقيا وآسيا. والاتصال مع المحيط في الجنوب من خلال مضيق باب المندب وخليج عدن. وفي الشمال يحده شبه جزيرة سيناء وخليج العقبة وخليج السويس (الذي يؤدي إلى قناة السويس). البحر الأحمر أحد المحميات البيئية التي حددها الصندوق العالمي للحياة البرية وعددها 200.يقع على جزء من الوادي المتصدع الكبير، تبلغ مساحة البحر الأحمر تقريباً 438,000 كم2. وطوله حوالي 1900 كم، وأوسع نقطة فيه تبلغ 355 كم. أقصى عمق 3,040 متراً، ويبلغ متوسط العمق 490 متراً. ومع ذلك، هناك أيضاً أرصفة ضحلة واسعة النطاق تحظى بالكائنات البحرية والشعاب المرجانية. وهو موطن لأكثر من 1000 نوعٍ من اللافقاريات، و200 نوعٍ من الشعاب المرجانية الصلبة واللينة. وهو من البحار التي تقع شمال المنطقة الاستوائية."},{"question":"Orúkọ Àdúgbò ní Ègbá àti Àwórì, Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn, Nàìjíríà","answer":"1. Ìta oseìn: ibi tí àwon ajagun tí màa ń bo soìnmolè tí wón bá fé lò jagun, ni ìgbákìgbá tí wón bá ti boo shin náà wòn maánsègun. 2. Pansekè: igi kan ni tí ó ní èso, tì éso náà bá ti gbe yóò máa dun sékéséké, ibi tí igi na ise ni aso3. Onikólóbo: àdúgbò ti won tí lo kolobo láti gba owó okò ní ayé àtijó4. Aké: àdúgbò orí rún ègbá, ààfin agbogbo ègbá.5. Ìmó: agbolé, tí won tí amò tí ó dára jù légbà6. Àjítàádùn: isé àádùn síse ni emit í ó kókó te àdúgbò náà dó ń se.7. Arule olónì: ní ayé àtijó èni kan wà tí won máa ń sìn ní abúlé yìí8. Ìta Èko: Àdúgbò tí wón tí ń ta èko, ní ìgbà náà ibè nìkan ni wón ti ń ta èko.9. Ìjàyè: Ibi tí àwon ará ìbàdàn tèdó sí ní ìgbà tí won ja ogun àjàyè10. Àgó òwu: Àdúgbò tí ajagun tà kan ní ìlú ìbàdàn tí ó jé akódé tèdó sí.11. Sàpón: Ní ayé àtijó ìyá a kan wà tí ó jé wípé èwà ní ó máa ń tà èyì sì se ànfàń púpò fún àwon àpón tí kòì tí láya, ní ìgbà kígbà tí ó wun àwon àpón yìó ní wón máa ń lo ra èwà tí ó sì jé pé wón á rí ìyá eléwà yìí níbè ìdí éléyìí ni a se ń pè ìyá eléwà yìí ní sàpón lóore.12. Adédòtun: Orúko bale tí ó kókó tèdó sí Àdúgbò yen ní wón fi ń pèé.13. Ìdí Àrà: Igi ńlá kan wàn ní àdúgbò yìí ní ayé àti jó tí ó jé wípé ìgbà túgbà tí àwon àgbè bá ń ti oko bò wón máa ń simi sí abé igi náà nítorí pé ibojì àti atégùn wà ní abé igi náà.14. Ìjógun: Àdúgbò tí àwon àwórì tí ńjagun ní ayé àti jo ìdí ògún ni wón pè ní ìdógun15. Ìmòré: Ní ayé àtijo igi kan wà tí ó ń so èso kan tí à ń pè ni òré, igi yìí pò ní àdúgbò yìí tí ó fi jé pé nígbà tí wón tèdó sí bè ni wón soódi imòòré.16. Ìrobè: Àdúgbò tí awon aborè tí máa ń fi ènìyàn bore, ìdí èyí ni wón fi ń pèé ní ìborè.17. Ojà Àgbó: Agboolé yìí jé ibi tí àwon tí ó kòkòtèdó síbè tí ń sé isé òsìn eran, wón dó ojà sílè tí won ti ńta àgbò, ní torú ìdí èyí ni wón se so ibè ní òjà àgbò.18. Ìlú Gùn: Àdúgbò yìí jé àdúgbò tí ó gùn jù ní gbogbo ègbá.19. Ìjejà: Ní ìgbà kan Oba kan náà ní àdúgbò yìí tí o burú tí ó sì jé wí pé àsé tí ó bá pa ní abé gé. Ó so fún àwon ará ìlú rè ní ojó kan wí pé tí won bá náa ojà sùgbón wok o, Oba pàsè kí wón lo je ojà náà run.20. Láfénwá: Orúko eni tí ó kókó àdúgbò yìí ni oláféniwá ìdí èyí ni wón fi so àdúgbò yìí ni orúko eni tí ó kókó tebè dó.21. Mókóla: Ní ayé ojo un ní ìgbà tí àwon ajagunlà ti ń jagun, wón jagun wón kérú wón kérù, ibi tí wón dé simi tí wón kó àwon erù won sí ni wón sinmi sí ibè tí wón pè ní omokólá.22. Asérò: Abúlé yìí ni àwon kan kókó tèdó sí tí ogun fí léewá, nígbà tí wón dé ibè, bí tí n sì bò ní ibi tí wón lo gégé bí àwon èrò se pò tó ní wón ti sì dé ibi tí wón tèdó sí, ibi tí wón sit i sí kúrò ní wón ń pè ní Asérò23. Ìgbésa: Àdúgbò yìí jé ibi kan tí ó jé pé igbó ni ó pò níbè télè sùgbón ìgbà tí àwon ènìyàn tèdó síbè ní ó di ìlú èyí ni wón se ń pè ní igbésà.24. Ìkujà: Jé abúlé kan tí akínkanjú kan ti kòyá fún àwon ará abúlé lówó àwon adigun jalè Akinkanjú yìí máa ń jà, ìdí èyí ni wón fi ń pè é ní ìkijà.25. Kútò: Ikútòmíwá ni àpè sale orúko yìí ní ìgbà kan okùnrin kan wà ní abúlé kan tí ó jé ohun nìkàn ni ó ń gbé ibè, ní ojó tí eranko búburu kan wá bá ní ibi tí ó ń gbé ni eran kò náà paá je kí ó tó kú ni ó ké tí enìkan fi gbó ohùn rè tí ó si sàlà yé fún ìdí èyí ni wón fi so abúlé ní kútò.26. Olósun: Ení tí ó ti bè dó jé abo òsun tí wón sì ń pèé ni eni tí ó òsun tí ó di Olósun báyìí.27. Ológùn-ún: Ìse Òde ni eni tí ó kókó dé bè n se tí ó sì máa ń bo ògún nígbà tí ó bá ti oko ode dé tí owó si de tí wón sì ń pèé ní ilé eni tí ó ń bo ògún, tí won ń dàpè ni ilé Ológùn-ún báyìí.28. Ìbèrè kòdó: Okùnrin tí won fi ń be àpèjúwe ibí yìí kò dó sí ilé yìí, eni tí ó jé àbúrò rè ni ó wá padà dó sí ilè yìí. Béèrè ni won máa ń pe ègbón ni tiwon gégé bí ó se wà ní àwon ìlú tàbí agbègbè kòòkàn lode òní, tí okùnrin náà sì máa ń so fún òpòlopò ènìyàn pe ibí yìí ló ye kí béérè òun dó sí, sùgbón tí kò dó síbè, òun yóò wá máa pe ibí yìí ni “ìbi tí béérè kò dó sí” tí won ń dà pè ní Ìbèrèkòdó báyìí.29. Ìgbórè: Bàbá kan àti ìyàwó rè ni wón ń rìn kiri tí wón fid é ibi tí àdúgbò yìí wa báyìí, wón gbé erèé lówó wón sì gbo ó ni ibè wón sì fi din àkàrà je, Báyìí ni wón ń se àpèjúwe ibe ni “Ibi tí àwon ti gbo erèé” tí o di Ìgbórè báyìí30. Ìbàsà: Ibí yìí jé ibì kan tí wón tí ń bo àwon àsà ilè Yorùbá ní ayé ìgbà náà, wón sì so ibè ní ilé “ibo àsà tí ó di Ibasa lónìí."},{"question":"Générez un titre pour le texte suivant :Didier Drogba a officiellement déposé samedi sa candidature à la présidence de la fédération ivoirienne de football (FIF). Il s'est rendu accompagné d'une foule de supporteurs au siège de la FIF à Treichville (Abidjan-Sud). Il a promis de contribuer à la renaissance du football ivoirien qui selon l'ex-attaquant vedette de l'Olympique de Marseille et de Chelsea \\"va mal\\". Après le dépôt des dossiers, la commission électorale dispose de cinq jours pour analyser et valider les différents dossiers de candidature. Outre Drogba, Idriss Diallo, ancien 3e vice-président de la FIF, soutenu par l'Association des footballeurs, et l'actuel vice-président de la Fédération et président de la Ligue Sory Diabaté ont déjà déposé leur candidature. Yaya Touré apporte son soutien à Didier Drogba Comment Drogba a aidé à stopper la guerre civile en Côte d'Ivoire Didier Drogba vise la présidence de la FIF Présidence de la FIF : le soutien des clubs ivoiriens à Didier Drogba De nombreux ivoiriens ont partagé sur les réseaux sociaux des messages de soutien au ballon d'or lorsque celui-ci a quitté sa base pour la maison de verre (siège de la FIF). L'ancien capitaine des Eléphants ivoiriens avait subi un coup dur mi-juillet, lorsque l'Association des footballeurs ivoiriens (AFI) avait refusé de le parrainer. La semaine dernière, la Fédération internationale des associations de footballeurs professionnels (Fifpro) a suspendu pour \\"non-respect des textes\\" l'AFI après son refus de soutenir la candidature de Didier Drogba pour la tête de la FIF. Didier Drogba a réussi à obtenir huit parrainages et le soutien d'un des cinq groupements d'intérêt nécessaires pour postuler à l'élection. \\"Ce n'est pas tant être président de la FIF qui m'intéresse, mais c'est la mission qui lie cette fonction\\", a affirmé l'athlète de 41 ans. \\"Notre football va mal (...) nous nous engageons à contribuer à la renaissance du football ivoirien\\", a poursuivi le joueur, qui raccrocher les crampons depuis fin 2018. \\"Je suis de retour et déterminé à apporter ma pierre à l'édifice, au renouveau et au développement du football ivoirien\\" a-t-il ajouté. Il estime par ailleurs qu'il est très important pour lui de rendre au football ivoirien, tout ce qu'il lui a donné.","answer":"Bien sûr, voici un titre pour le texte donné - Didier Drogba officiellement candidat à la présidence de la FIF"},{"question":"இந்தியாவில் வருமானவரி எந்த ஆண்டு வந்தது?","answer":"இந்தியாவில் வருமான வரி இந்தியா விடுதலை பெற்ற பின்பு இந்திய வருமானவரி சட்டம், 1961- இந்திய பாராளுமன்றத்தால் நிறைவேற்றப்பட்டு, 01-04-1962 முதல் இந்திய வருமான வரிச் சட்டம் செயல்படத் தொடங்கியது. வருமான வரி கணக்கை சரிபார்த்தல் மற்றும் வசூலித்தல் ஆகியவற்றை இந்திய அரசின் வருமான வரித் துறையிடம் ஒப்படைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."},{"question":"Приведите пример тривиальной информации в этой категории: книги","answer":"книги состоят из страниц"},{"question":"ઈકબાલ મુન્શી રચિત  કવિતા \\"મનમાં મારા મનમાં\\"  લખો.","answer":"મનમાં મારા મનમાં, કોઈ રૂમઝૂમ કરતું આવે,હળવેથી મને બોલાવે..મારા મનમાં.. મારા મનમાં..મનમાં મારા મનમાં, વરસાદ પહેલો જાણે આવે,વ્હાલમાં મને ભીંજાવે..મારા મનમાં.. મારા મનમાં..ફૂલો બધાં હવે રંગીન છે, હવાઓમાં જાણે સંગીત છે;મોસમની આ કેવી પ્રીત છે,પ્રીતમાં રંગાવાની હવે જીદ છે.મારા મનમાં.. મારા મનમાં.. મનમાં મારા મનમાં..ઝાંઝર વાગે કે વાગે ભણકારા, મીઠા મીઠા લાગે છે હવે ધબકારા;કોઈનાં થવાની આ કેવી બીક છે, કોઈનાં થવાની તોયે જીદ છે.મારા મનમાં.. મારા મનમાં.. મનમાં મારા મનમાં.."},{"question":"Además de Lena Olin, varias otras actrices interpretaron a Irina en el curso de la serie:Además de Irina, varias otras actrices que Lena Olin ha interpretado en el transcurso de la serie.?¿La oración 1 parafrasea la oración 2?. ","answer":"No, la parafrasea. "},{"question":"Эмне себептен лампочкалар кээде жарылып кетет?","answer":"Лампаны жакканыбызда, анын спиралы 2000°С чейин ысыйт. Аба мындай ысыктыктан кычкылданып, бузулууга алып келет. Ошондуктан, лампанын ичиндеги абаны сооруп алышат ( ичинде аба болбойт )Эгер, лампага кичине болсо да аба кирип кетсе, биз аны жакканда лампа батынан ысып, анда давления көтөрүлүп жарылып кетүүсү мүмкүн."},{"question":"Psikologian, nola ulertzen du pertsonalitatearen teoriak gizakien jarrera, emozio eta erreakzioen jatorria, eta nola eragiten du hau gizartearekiko interakzioan?","answer":"Pertsonalitatearen teoriak aztertzen du nola eragiten duten faktore biologikoak, sozialak eta psikologikoak gizakien jarrera, emozio eta erreakzioetan. Honek ulertzen laguntzen du gizakien portaera, emozioen jatorria eta nola eragiten duten gizartearekiko interakzioetan."},{"question":"جنک فوڈ بچوں کو کیسے متاثر کرتا ہے؟","answer":"لندن: بچوں کے لئے ‘جنک فوڈ’ کا استعمال انتہائی خطرناک ہے، ماہرین کا ماننا ہے کہ بچوں کو ہرطرح کے جنک فوڈ سے پرہیز کرایا جائے، کیونکہ کم عمری میں ‘جنک فوڈ’ کے انتہائی منفی اثرات مرتب ہوسکتے ہیں۔غذائی ماہرین کا کہنا ہے کہ زیادہ جنگ فوڈ استعمال کرنے والے بچوں کے استحالے (میٹابولزم) میں منفی تبدیلیاں رونما ہوجاتی ہیں، موٹاپے کے ساتھ ساتھ ان کے خون کا بہاؤ بھی متاثر ہوجاتا ہے۔ کیونکہ جنک فوڈ میں مصنوعی مٹھاس، مضر چکنائیاں اور دیگر اجزاء کو شامل کیا جاتا ہے۔ماہرین کے مطابق جنک فوڈ میں غذائیت کم اور کیلوریز کی مقدار بہت زیادہ ہوتی ہے۔دوسرا یہ کہ کم عمری میں بچوں کے لئے متوازن غذا کی ضرورت ہوتی ہے، جنک فوڈ کا استعمال کرنے والے اور پرہیز کرنے والے بچوں کا موازنہ کیا گیا تو جن بچوں نے جنک فوڈ کا استعمال کیا تھا ان میں موٹاپے کا رجحان بہت زیادہ تھا۔تشویشناک بات یہ ہے کہ جنک فوڈ سے دماغی و ذہنی مسائل میں بھی اضافہ ہوسکتا ہے، مثال کے طور پر شکر کی ذیادتی ڈپریشن اور یاسیت بڑھا سکتی ہے۔ بچوں کو پڑھنے اور توجہ میں بھی مشکلات کا سامنا کرنا پڑ سکتا ہے، آگے چل کر یہ بلڈ پریشر، ذیابیطس، فالج اور امراضِ قلب کا باعث بھی بن سکتا ہے۔دوسری جانب کم عمری میں ناکافی غذا کے منفی اثرات بچوں کی نشوونما پر اثرانداز ہوکر پوری زندگی کے لئے مسائل کھڑے کرسکتے ہیں، کیونکہ ان غذاؤں میں بنیادی وٹامن، ریشے، معدن، اور ضروری اجزا نہیں ہوتے۔"},{"question":"බැඩ්මින්ටන් ඔලිම්පික් ක්‍රීඩාවක් බවට පත් වූයේ කවදාද සහ මුලින් ඇතුළත් වූ ඉසව් මොනවාද?","answer":"පිරිමි කේවල, කාන්තා කේවල, පිරිමි යුගල සහ කාන්තා යුගල යන ඉසව් හතරක් සමඟින් 1992 දී බැඩ්මින්ටන් ඔලිම්පික් ක්‍රීඩාවක් බවට පත් විය. වසර හතරකට පසුව ඔලිම්පික් වැඩසටහනට මිශ්‍ර යුගල එකතු විය."},{"question":"தமிழ்மொழியில் இடம்பெற்ற புள்ளிகளும், எழுத்துகளும் குறித்து எழுதுக.","answer":"(*) எகர ஒகர குறில் எழுத்துகளைக் குறிக்க எழுத்துகளின் மேல் புள்ளி வைக்கும் வழக்கம் தொல்காப்பியர் காலம் முதல் இருந்து வந்துள்ளது. (எடுத்துக்காட்டாக எது என எழுதப்பட்டால் எது என்றும், ஏது என எழுதப்பட்டால் எது என்றும் ஒலித்தனர்.(*) அகரவரிசை உயிர்மெய்க்குறில் எழுத்துகளை அடுத்துப் பக்கப்புள்ளி இடப்பட்டால் அவை நெடிலாகக் கருதப்பட்டன. (க. = கா, த. = தா). ஐகார எழுத்துகளைக் குறிப்பிட எழுத்துகளின் முன் இரட்டைப் புள்ளி இட்டனர். (..க =கை). எகர வரிசை உயிர்மெய்க் குறில் எழுத்துகளை அடுத்து இரு புள்ளிகள் இடப்பட்டால் அவை ஔகார வரிசை எழுத்துகளாகக் கருதப்பட்டன.(கெ… = கௌ, தெ..= தௌ). மகர எழுத்தைக் குறிப்பிட, பகர எழுத்தின் உள்ளே புள்ளி (ப்) இட்டனர். குற்றியலுகர, குற்றியலிகர எழுத்துகளைக் குறிக்க அவற்றின் மேலேயும் புள்ளி இட்டனர்."},{"question":"تى تم تأسيس صندوق النقد الدولي رسمياً؟","answer":"في 27 ديسمبر 1945م"},{"question":"थ्रोन ऑफ ग्लास सीरीज़ की दूसरी किताब कब प्रकाशित हुई थी? इस प्रश्न का सही उत्तर दें।","answer":"इस प्रश्न का सही उत्तर है साल २०१३।"},{"question":"¿Qué país ha dominado los Juegos Olímpicos de Natación Sincronizada con cinco medallas de oro desde su reintroducción en los Juegos en 2000? ","answer":"Desde Sydney-2000, pasando por Atenas-2004 y Pekín-2008, hasta Londres-2012 y Río-2016, los rusos se llevaron a casa todas las medallas de oro de la competición."},{"question":"هل يحمي يوديد البوتاسيوم الأفراد من الإشعاع إجمالاً؟","answer":"كلا. يحمي يوديد البوتاسيوم فقط الغدة الدرقية من التعرّض لليود المشع. فليس كل حالة طوارئ إشعاعية تؤدي إلى انبعاث اليوم المشعّ. والطريقة الأفضل لحماية نفسك من الإشعاع هي اتباع المبادئ الثلاثة المتمثلة في: 1) الاحتماء في الداخل، 2) البقاء في الداخل إلى حين تأكيد مأمونية الخروج، و3) الاستماع إلى قنوات المعلومات المتاحة واتباع الإرشادات الصادرة عن السلطات المحلية والوطنية."},{"question":"Yedlula ngehubo, nayo yashoyabafumba ngezintuli. Abiphe njalo uKaMaseko ephimisa izintuli, ezithintithanasengutsheni yakhe. Kuze kubone noma ubani osesitobhini ukuthi yazeyayikholisa ibhasi le ncwasimende.'Ewu, ungaze uthintithe, yinhle nale thuphisi yakho. Wakuthengelawakwehlula uJiyane,' Kusho uDombi ehleka eze ekhiphela ulimi ngaphandle,luba ngaka.'Yebo phela, wathenga. Kodwa isikhwele sale thuphisi! Uma engangificangiyigqokile nje eqhamuka emsebenzini, ngabe ngivelelwe. Angabuza esefileukuthukuthela ukuthi ngiyifakele ukubukwa ngubani engekho? Awazi wenaukuthi uyikhwelezela kanjani le ngubo yami.''Nale bhasi seyigcina ngakho nje ukusithela ngezintuli, ayisasithathi. Konjewena awuyigibeli ibhasi?''We-a! Ubani? Ngingcoliswe yila mabhasi alapha emakhaya athi uma ehambaabuthe uthuli lugcwale ngaphakathi abantu bangabe besabonananokubonana? ...'1. Ukuba wena wawungumngani kaKaMaseko wawuyomelulekauthini mayelana nobungozi bokugibela izimoto angazazi? Bhalaamaphuzu AMATHATHU.","answer":"Amaphuzu AMATHATHU kwalandelayo: Esikhathini samanje sekukhona ubugebengubokuntshontshwa kwabantu ngakho-ke ukugibela izimotoangazazi kungambeka engozini enkulu.  Izinga lokudlwengulwa kwabesifazane kuleli zwe liphezulukakhulu ngakho-ke kubalulekile ukuthi wonke umuntuwesifazane azigcine ephephile kubenzi bobubi.  Kwakungenzeka ashaywe yizigebengu zimlimaze.  Izigebengu zazingamphuca imali yakhe.(Nokunye okunembayo okuyoshiwo ngumfundi)"},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação para esse trecho - A divisão foi mais uma vez fortemente engajada nas operações no rio Vístula nas ofensivas do inverno de 1944-45. Mais tarde, em 1945, ficou sobrecarregada em Danzigue com parte do Grupo de Exércitos Norte. Foi evacuada de lá, mas mais uma vez perdeu todos os seus veículos e tanques. A 7ª Divisão Panzer participou da Batalha de Berlim","answer":"em Abril de 1945. Alguns de seus membros conseguiram escapar para a frente ocidental onde se renderam às forças Britânicas no setor de Schwerin."},{"question":"有名人をスクープするため、しつこく狙うことで、イタリア語で「しつこい虫」という意味の言葉は何？","answer":"パパラッチです。"},{"question":"عندما توفي قال عنه عمر: مات اليوم سيد المسلمين فمن هو ؟\\t","answer":"أبي بن كعب رضي الله عنه"},{"question":"Бир киши карышкыр, козу, чөп алып келе жатып бир чоң сууга кез болду.Көпүрөдөн бирөөн гана араң алып өтө алат. Карышкырды алып кетсе,козу чөптү жеп коет. Айтор, бир-бирден суунун аркы өйүзүнө алып өтүп, бирибирин жедирбей аман сакташ керек. Бул үчүн кандай жол табууга болот ?","answer":"Биринчиде козуну алып өтүп, экинчиде чөптү ала баруу керек. Анан козуну кайра ала келип, карышкырды өткөрүү керек. Ошондон кийин кайра келип, козуну алып кетүүгө тийиш. Ошентип баары аман калат."},{"question":"कोणत्या जनुकीय रूपांतरीत पीकामध्ये जनुकीय अभियांभिकी तंत्राने अ नीवनसत्त्व निर्माण करणारी तीन जनुके घातली आहेत ?A. कल्याण सोना गहूB.  मधुर ज्वारी C. संकरीत बाजरीD. सुवर्ण तांदुळ","answer":"D. सुवर्ण तांदुळ"},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：人工智能如何应用于智能化交通？","answer":"答案：人工智能可以应用于智能化交通中的车辆识别、交通信号优化、拥堵预测等方面。"},{"question":" 2015- ஆம் ஆண்டு இந்தியப் பிரதமர் மோடி - ரஷிய அதிபர் புதின் ஆகியோரின் பேச்சு வார்த்தை எதை  பற்றியது?","answer":"2015- ஆம் ஆண்டு இந்தியப் பிரதமர் மோடி - ரஷிய அதிபர் புதின் ஆகியோரின் பேச்சு வார்த்தை ஹெலிகாப்டர்களை தயாரிப்பது  பற்றியது."},{"question":"జాతీయ చిహ్నం యొక్క ప్రాధాన్యతను చర్చించుము.","answer":"సారనాథ్ లోని అశోకుని శిలా స్తంభంలోని నాలుగు సింహాల గుర్తును భారత ప్రభుత్వం అధికార జాతీయ, చిహ్నంగా స్వీకరించింది.జాతీయ చిహ్నం అనేది ఒక దేశం యొక్క అధికారిక చిహ్నం. ఇది ఒక దేశం యొక్క సార్వభౌమాధికారాన్ని తెలియజేస్తుంది. 1950 జనవరి 26 నుంచి దీనిని అధికారికంగా జాతీయచిహ్నంగా గుర్తించారు. ఇందులో మూడు సింహాలు పైకి కనపడతాయి. నాల్గవసింహం మాత్రం అదృశ్యంగా దాగి ఉంటుంది. మూడు సింహాలు అధికారం, ధైర్యము మరియు ఆత్మవిశ్వాసం అనే మూడు లక్షణాలకు ప్రతీకలు నాల్గవ సింహం భారతజాతి యొక్క గౌరవానికి ప్రతీక. ఎబాకు మధ్యలో చక్రం ఉంటుంది. అందులో కుడివైపున ఎద్దు మరియు ఎడమవైపున గెంతుతూ ఉన్న గుర్రం ఉంటుంది. ఎద్దు కష్టపడే మనస్తత్వాన్ని తెలియజేస్తుంది. అశ్వము వేగాన్ని మరియు శక్తిని తెలియజేస్తుంది. ఎబాక్కు దిగువవైపున ‘సత్యం జయిస్తుంది’ అని లిఖించబడి ఉంటుంది. ఇది మండూకోపనిషత్ నుంచి గ్రహింపబడింది."},{"question":"የቶማስ ጄፈርሰን ወላጅ እናት ማናት?","answer":"ጄን ራንዶልፍ"},{"question":"مدارک دانشگاه آزاد، جامع علمی کاربردی و پیام نور برای پذیرش دانشجویی اروپا معتبر است؟","answer":"بطور کلی مدارک دانشگاه های ایران اعم از دانشگاه های دولتی و دانشگاه های غیر دولتی بعد از دریافت تاییدیه وزارت علوم، جهت تحصیل در اروپا و کانادا و دیگر کشورها مورد قبول می باشد. باید توجه داشت که معدل نقش مهمی در اخذ بورسیه و اعتبار مدرک تحصیلی دارد."},{"question":"Midika fitokana-monina ny tsy fiankinana amin’ny hafa ve ny fahaleovan-tena?","answer":"Tsy midika fitokana-monina ny tsy fiankinana amin’ny hafa eto. Na mahaleo tena aza ny olona iray dia tsy maintsy mifandray amin’ny hafa, mba hahafahany mampandroso ny zavatra ataony, toy izany koa ny firenena tsy maintsy mifandray amin’ny firenena hafa. Tsy midika hoe miankina amin’ny hafa ny hoe mifandray fa mampivelatra kokoa ny fahaizana amam-pahalalana sy ny fampandrosoana."},{"question":"次のパラグラフを続ける： 「マンガ大賞」は、本屋で働く人などがみんなに読んでほしい漫画を選ぶ賞です。この賞をもらった漫画の多くは、映画やテレビのアニメになっています。","answer":"27日、16回目になる今年の「マンガ大賞」の発表がありました。とよ田みのるさんの「これ描いて死ね」が選ばれました。この漫画は、東京都の島に住む高校生が友達と漫画研究会を作って、喜んだり苦しんだりしながら漫画を描いて成長する話です。 この漫画を描いたとよ田さんは「漫画のタイトルは、いつも自分に言っている言葉です。世の中ひどいことが多いので、この漫画を読んで明るい気分になってもらいたいと思います」と話していました。"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kerana nila setitik, rosak susu sebelanga'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud hanya kerana salah seorang, sekumpulan atau seluruh masyarakat akan turut mendapat nama yang buruk."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en esta categoría: Geografía. ","answer":"¿Qué país obsequió la Estatua de la Libertad a Estados Unidos? Fue Francia. "},{"question":"Жээренче чечен ким болгон?","answer":"Жээренче чечен (XIV - XV кылым, Алтын Ордо) — Түрк элдеринин оозеки чыгармаларындагы чечендик жана акылмандык жагынан элдик мүдөөнү туюндурган санжыргалуу каарман. Жээренче чечен окуяларынын бир даарын алтай, крым, тобол (түмөн) татарларынан В. В. Радлов жазып алып (19-к.) жарыялаган. Көпчүлүк иликтөөчүлөр анын чындыгын тактоого аракеттенгендигине карабастан, чечендин өмүр баяны, ата-теги жөнүндө так маалымат жок. Ал калк оозунда сөзгө устат, чечен, кара кылды как жарган калыс, жандуунун гана эмес, жансыздын да дилин, тилин түшүнгөн олуя, болжолу Жаныбек хандын ордосунда кеңешчи болуп кызмат өтөгөн акылман, кара өзгөй хандын каарына калып, куугунтукка алынган тарыхый инсан катары сүрөттөлөт. Кыргыз фольклору боюнча Жээренче чечен Асан Кайгы, Токтогул ырчы, Толубай сынчынын замандашы болгон. Жээренче чечендин сөзгө чеберлиги, айлакердиги бала кезинде эле байкалган. Ал анын тоо элинен элчиликке барып, хандын бир дооматына чукугандай сөз таап, өз элин бүлгүнчүлүктөн куткарып калгандыгынан ачык көрүнөт. Жээренче чечен окуялары көп катмарлуу. Анда шарттуу түрдө чыгарманын түзүлгөн аймагы жөнүндө маалымат берилген. Бир учурда окуянын түзүлгөн орду катарында Сыр (Сыр-Дарыя) бою көрсөтүлсө, экинчи маалыматта Кыпчак талаасындагы (Дешти-Кыпчак) Жаныбекти баласы Бердибек (бир кабарда иниси) өлтүрүп, ордуна хан болуп, «түрк балдары» колдоого алышы сыяктуу тарыхый окуялар чагылдырылат. Жээренче чечен нускалуу сөздөрү менен калктын көркөм табитинен кеңири өңүт алып, кылым аралап өчпөй келген каарман."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegta Kumuu ahaa asxaabigii Bilaabay Taariikhda Hijriyada?","answer":"Wuxu ahaa Cumar Bin Khadaab Rc."},{"question":"ਬਹੁਪੱਖੀ ਪ੍ਰਤਿਭਾ ਦੀ ਮਾਲਕ ਅਮਿਤਾ ਪਾਠਕ ਕਿਸਮਤ ਦੀ ਵੀ ਧਨੀ ਹੈ। ਅਮਿਤਾ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਕੁਮਾਰ ਮੰਗਤ ਪਾਠਕ ਦੀ ਧੀ ਹੈ। ਅਮਿਤਾ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਾਲ ‘ਹਾਲੇ ਏ ਦਿਲ’ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ’ਚ ਦਸਤਕ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਖਾਸ ਹੁੰਗਾਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਸੀ। ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਅਮਿਤਾ ਨੇ ‘ਸ਼ਿਖਰ’ ਤੇ ‘ਓਮਕਾਰਾ’ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਹਾਇਕ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ। ਫਿਰ ‘ਆਕਰੋਸ਼’ ’ਚ ਛੋਟਾ ਜਿਹਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਇਆ ਤੇ ‘ਅਤਿਥੀ ਤੁਮ ਕਬ ਜਾਓਗੇ’ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਕੀਤਾ। ਹੁਣ ਅਮਿਤਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਤੇ ਭਾਈ ਅਭਿਸ਼ੇਕ ਪਾਠਕ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਬਣਾਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਬਿੱਟੂ ਬਾਸ’ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪੁਲਕਿਤ ਸਮਰਾਟ ਨਾਲ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਵੇਗੀ। ਪੇਸ਼ ਹਨ ਉਸ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੇ ਅੰਸ਼: ਸਵਾਲ: ਆਪਣੇ ਘਰ ਦੀ ਦੂਜੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਕੇ ਕਿਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਲੱਗਿਆ?ਜਵਾਬ:ਅਮਿਤਾ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਤੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਨਿੱਜੀ ਜਜ਼ਬਾਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਥਾਂ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਜਜ਼ਬਾਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਦਰ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਾਂ। ਉਸ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਮੇਰੀ ਚੋਣ ਲਈ ਆਡੀਸ਼ਨ ਹੋਇਆ ਤੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਸੁਪਵਿੱਤਰ ਬਾਬੁਲ ਨੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ’ਚ ਮੇਰੇ ਪੂਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਫਿੱਟ ਬੈਠਣ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਕਹੀ ਸੀ। ਅਸੀਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਲਈ ਬਣਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਤੇ ਕੋਈ ਵੀ ਬਾਪ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਆਪਣੀ ਧੀ ਲਈ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਜਿਹੇ ਕਾਰਜਾਂ ’ਚ ਕਰੋੜਾਂ ਰੁਪਏ ਲਾ ਕੇ ਜੂਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਖੇਡੇਗਾ। ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਮੇਰੀ ਚੋਣ ਯੋਗਤਾ ਦੇ ਆਧਾਰ ’ਤੇ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਬਿੱਟੂ ਬਾਸ’ ਬਾਰੇ ਕੀ ਕਹੋਗੇ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਇਹ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਦੇ ਆਨੰਦਪੁਰ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਇਲਾਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਬੰਧਤ ਹੈ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਬਿੱਟੂ ਬਾਂਸ ਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਚਾਲਾਕ ਤੇ ਹੱਸਮੁੱਖ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਵਿਆਹ  ਸਮੇਂ ਮੂਵੀ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦਾ  ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਇਲਾਕੇ ਦਾ ਸਟਾਰ ਹੈ। ਹਰ ਕੋਈ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਦੀਵਾਨਾ ਹੈ। ਕੁੜੀਆਂ ਉਹਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਫਿਰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਮ੍ਰਿਣਾਲਨੀ ਉਸ ਵੱਲ ਧਿਆਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੰਦੀ। ਉਹ ਬਿੱਟੂ ਬਾਸ ਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ’ਚ ਪੈਸੇ ਦੀ ਅਹਿਮੀਅਤ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੱਸਦੀ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਦੱਸਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸਮਾਜ ’ਚ ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਤੇ ਨਾਂ ਕਮਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਪੈਸਾ ਕਿੰਨਾ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ। ਬਿੱਟੂ ਉਹਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ’ਚ ਪਾਗਲ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਪਿਆਰ ਦੀ ਖਾਤਰ ਪੈਸਾ ਕਮਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਸ਼ਾਰਟ-ਕਟ ਵਰਤਦਾ ਹੈ। ਫਿਰ ਕੀ ਵਾਪਰਦਾ ਇਹ ਤਾਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਆਉਣ ’ਤੇ ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗੇਗਾ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਇਸ ਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਮ੍ਰਿਣਾਲਨੀ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਇਆ ਹੈ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਜੀ ਹਾਂ, ਮੈਂ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਕੁੜੀ ਮ੍ਰਿਣਾਲਨੀ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਇਆ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਇੱਕ ਅਮੀਰ ਘਰ ਦੀ ਪੜ੍ਹੀ-ਲਿਖੀ ਸਮਝਦਾਰ ਤੇ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੀ ਹਕੀਕਤ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਰੱਖ ਕੇ ਜਿਊਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਕੁੜੀ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਬਿੱਟੂ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਪਾਗਲ ਨਹੀਂ। ਜਦੋਂ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਬਿੱਟੂ ਉਸ  ਨੂੰ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਦੂਰ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਬਿੱਟੂ ਨੂੰ ਅਮੀਰ ਬਣਨ ਦੀ ਸਲਾਹ ਦਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਸੁਪਵਿੱਤਰ ਬਾਬੁਲ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਕੇ ਕਿਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਲੱਗਿਆ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਬਹੁਤ ਵਧੀਆ ਲੱਗਿਆ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੁਤੰਤਰ ਤੌਰ ’ਤੇ ਬਤੌਰ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਭਾਵੇਂ ਇਹ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕੋਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਸਨਅਤ ਦਾ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਤਜਰਬਾ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਕੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਸਕੂਟਰੀ ਚਲਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਡਰ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਹੋਇਆ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਪੁਲਕਿਤ ਸਮਰਾਟ ਨਾਲ ਕਿਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਅਨੁਭਵ ਰਿਹਾ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਪੁਲਕਿਤ, ਤਜਰਬੇਕਾਰ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਹੈ। ਸੀਰੀਅਲ ‘ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਸਾਸ ਭੀ ਕਭੀ ਬਹੂ ਥੀ’ ’ਚ ਲਕਸ਼ਯ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਉਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਉਹ ਮਿਊਜ਼ੀਕਲ ਥੀਏਟਰ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜਿਆ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਡਾਂਸ ’ਚ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਮਾਹਿਰ ਹੈ। ਸਾਡੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੈਮਿਸਟਰੀ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਵਧੀਆ ਰਹੀ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਬਿੱਟੂ ਬਾਸ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਕੋਈ ਯਾਦਗਾਰ ਘਟਨਾ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਮੇਰਾ ਪਾਲਣ-ਪੋਸ਼ਣ ਭਾਵੇਂ ਮੁੰਬਈ ’ਚ ਹੋਇਆ ਪਰ ਮੇਰਾ ਜਨਮ ਆਨੰਦਪੁਰ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਦਾ ਹੈ। ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਆਪਣੇ ਜਨਮ ਅਸਥਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਵੇਖਣਾ ਤੇ ਉੱਥੇ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ ਕਰਨਾ ਮਾਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਗੱਲ ਹੈ।ਸਵਾਲ: ਤੁਸੀਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਘੱਟ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋ?ਜਵਾਬ: ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਤੇ ਕਲਾ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਹੈ। ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਮੇਰਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਹੈ। ਪੈਸਾ ਕਮਾਉਣਾ ਜਾਂ ਨੰਬਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਦੌੜ ਲਈ ਮੈਂ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣੀ। ਇਸ ਲਈ ਮੈਂ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਕੰਮ ਨੂੰ ਤਰਜੀਹ ਦਿੰਦੀ ਹਾਂ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਅਮਿਤਾ ਪਾਠਕ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ  ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ‘ਹਾਲੇ ਏ ਦਿਲ’ ਅਮਿਤਾ ਪਾਠਕ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ  ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਹਾਲੇ ਏ ਦਿਲ’ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"ඉන්දියානු ජාතික ව්‍යාපාරයේ පියා ලෙස බුහුමන් ලබන්නේ කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"ඉන්දියානු ජාතික ව්‍යාපාරයේ පියා ලෙස බුහුමන් ලබන්නේ සුරේන්ද්‍රනාත් බැනර්ජි ය."},{"question":"Schrijf een blog over een willekeurig onderwerp:","answer":"Padi duikbrevet: ik leerde duiken in Nederland en raad het jou ook aan!In dit blog vertel ik je waarom ik mijn duikbrevet in Nederland haalde. Waarom zou je leren duiken in het koude donkere water van de Nederlandse duiklocaties als je ook je Padi op een tropische bestemming zou kunnen halen? Ik vertel je er meer over!Ik haalde mijn duikbrevet in Nederland!Mijn allereerste duik ooit, was op Corfu. Na een kleine 10 minuten instructies, gingen we het water in. We zullen niet dieper zijn gegaan dan vijf meter en op een paar visjes na was er niets boeiends te zien, maar ik vond het GE-WEL-DIG! Leren duiken in NederlandFlash forward naar zondag 23 september in Nederland. Het is 07.00 uur ‘s ochtends, niet warmer dan 10 graden en ik heb met net in een loeistrak duikerspak gehesen. Mijn trimvest met duikfles van ongeveer 25 kilo wordt op m’n rug gehesen en dan mag ik het bruine water van de Vinkeveense plassen in. Niet geheel verrassend is het water ijskoud. Oké, het is niet echt ijskoud, het is 15 graden in dit ondiepe stuk, maar het voelt wel echt ijskoud. Waarom deed ik dit ook alweer? Nou dat zal ik je vertellen! Pogin 1 om mijn duikbrevet te halen: op de FilipijnenTijdens onze wereldreis was ik vastbesloten om mijn duikbrevet te halen. We kwamen op zoveel tropische plekken, ik zag mezelf de prachtige onderwaterwereld al tegemoet zwemmen. Dat ging helemaal goed komen. Na drie weken in Japan, vlogen we door naar de Filipijnen. Daar, in een heel klein dorpje, Port Barton, waar het erg warm was, besloot ik een introductie duikdag te doen. Ries ging ook mee en wanneer we het goed vonden gaan, zouden we nog twee dagen les hebben en dan ons Open Water brevet hebben. De eerste duik verliep vlekkeloos. Nou ja, voor mij dan, Ries lukte het niet om te klaren (zijn oren te poppen, wat je ook soms in het vliegtuig doet), het lukte hem niet om te dalen en eenmaal gedaald, gebruikte hij zoveel lucht dat hij halverwege de duik al door zijn tank heen was. Ik genoot in eerste instantie van de prachtige vissen, het koraal en het gevoel gewichtloos te zijn. Maar toen ik merkte hoe lastig het bij Ries ging begon ik me steeds meer te realiseren dat je toch wel heel kwetsbaar bent onder water.En toen ging het mis met duiken…De volgende duik lag ik dan ook een stuk minder relaxed in het water. Hoe dieper we gingen, hoe meer druk ik begon te voelen op mijn voorhoofd. Rond de 15 meter, plopten mijn ogen er bijna uit en was de hoofdpijn niet te langer te hebben. Ik had last van een squeeze; de druk in mijn voorhoofdsholte en achter mijn ogen was anders dan de omgevingsdruk en hoe dieper we gingen hoe groter dit verschil werd. Nadat ik de duikinstructeur seinde, gingen we langzaam terug naar het oppervlakte, maar niet na nog een veiligheidsstop te hebben gedaan van drie minuten op vijf meter diepte. Dat waren drie enorm lange minuten…Greece DivingGeen duikbrevet voor mij…Je begrijpt, daarna was voor mij de lol er wel vanaf. Dus toen Ries de volgende dag op de boot stapte voor lesdag twee, lag ik relaxed op het strand met vrienden Jorine en Tim. Toen hij ‘s middags moest studeren, was ik helemaal content met mijn keuze. Dat had ik toch goed voor elkaar, ik had een gin tonic, hij moest studeren. De volgende dag haalde hij zijn brevet en had ik nog steeds geen spijt van mijn keuze. Ook niet toen hij een aantal weken later dolenthousiast terugkwam van een duik op Bali.Máár toen we eenmaal in Frans Polynesië aankwamen, begon het te kriebelen. Daar kun je namelijk prachtige duiken maken, op het eiland Rangiroa misschien wel de mooiste duiken ter wereld. Ries ging duiken en was helemaal lyrisch. Hij knuffelde met dolfijnen en zag sting rays en prachtige haaien. Ai, dat had ik ook willen doen, maar helaas, ik had geen brevet. We bleven niet lang genoeg op Rangiroa om daar nog duikcursus te doen maar ik nam me voor: ik moet en zal mijn duikbrevet gaan halen.Duiken in een van de populairste duiklocaties van Nederland: de Vinkeveense PlassenEn tja, hier lig ik dan. In het troebele, koude water van de Vinkeveense Plassen. We vertrekken over een maand naar Belize en daar schijn je geweldig te kunnen duiken. Het was dan ook zeker een optie geweest het daar te leren, in warm water en wellicht in iets mildere omstandigheden. Maar achteraf ben ik heel blij dat ik mijn brevet hier in Nederland haal.Drie redenen waarom ik blij ben mijn duikbrevet in Nederland te halen1. Niet zo snel mogelijk leren duiken, zo goed mogelijk leren duiken!Duikmaster Roel kan behoorlijk pittig zijn (hij noemt mij meerdere malen een controlefreak, daar herken ik mezelf écht niet in ;-)), maar er is begrip voor eventuele angst of belemmeringen tijdens het duiken. Ik spreek voor de eerste duikles bijna een uur lang met Roel over waarom ik mijn duikopleiding niet afgemaakt heb in de Filipijnen. Er wordt echt de tijd voor je genomen, ik had vijf lessen nodig, maar er zijn ook leerlingen die acht keer duiken of zelfs vaker. De oefeningen worden net zo vaak gedaan tot je er echt relaxed in zit en alle spanning weg is. Hier geldt dus niet, zoals dit wel het geval kan zijn in het buitenland, zoveel leerlingen, zo snel mogelijk.2. Geen vakantiedagen kwijt aan leren duiken!Ander voordeel: ik hoef nu geen vakantiedagen ‘op te offeren’ om te leren duiken. Wel vijf weekenddagen trouwens… Hoe heerlijk dat ik straks in Belize gewoon wanneer ik maar wil een duik naar het koraalrif kan maken, zonder dat ik eerst nog drie dagen les nodig heb. Ik kijk er nu al naar uit!3. Mijn instelling is: als het hier goed gaat, lukt het duiken in het buitenland ook!Tenslotte nog een laatste reden waarom ik leer duiken in Nederland. Het is behoorlijk spartaans, met weinig zicht, geen mooie vissen, een zware uitrusting en koud water. Maar men zegt niet voor niets dat als je in Nederland leert duiken, je overal kunt duiken. Ik ben totaal niet bang meer wanneer er onverwacht weinig zicht in het water is, of het water ineens koud blijkt te zijn. En hoe mooi gaan al die duiken zijn in prachtig tropisch water, na deze saaie donkere duiken met enkel af en toe een snoek."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"abu dajal\\"? Berikan ayat contoh untuk simpulan bahasa tersebut.","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang jahat yang suka menggangu orang lain. Contoh ayat: Selagi ada Abu Dajal di tepi jalan itu, tiada seorang gadis pun yang berani lalu di situ."},{"question":"tsara ve ny velona ?","answer":"ny velona dia tsara"},{"question":"Підсумуй статтю:  (CNN) -- Чи заслуговує Джон Едвардс на тюремне ув'язнення? Присяжні прийняли рішення, і він вільний. Що б ми не думали про судовий процес Едвардса, одна річ є певною: обвинувачення було безглуздим марнотратством грошей платників податків на справу без злочину. Кому не байдуже, якщо мільярдер хоче дати мультимільйонеру гроші, щоб приховати свою коханку (яка платить податки за подарунок)? Обвинувачення Едвардса ніколи не було стосовно Едвардса, а стосовно Джорджа Холдинга. Стривай, хто такий Джордж Холдинг? І чому нас це має хвилювати? Після перемоги на попередніх виборах, Холдинг, ймовірно, стане наступним конгресменом у 13-му окрузі Північної Кароліни. Він ініціював звинувачення проти Едвардса, коли був прокурором. Але він не заперечував цю справу в суді. Замість цього, після отримання заголовків протягом року (і похвалу республіканців) за звинувачення Едвардса, Холдинг відмовився від позову, щоб балотуватися в Конгрес. Можливо, Холдинг розумів слабкість справи, яка полягала в тому, що Едвардс не повідомив про гроші, які мільярдерська спадкоємка Банні Мелон і інший багатий спонсор дали йому, щоб допомогти приховати свою коханку. Проблема полягає в тому, що якщо Едвардс повідомив про внески, а потім використав їх для особистих витрат, то він був би винним у злочині, оскільки Федеральна виборча комісія забороняє витрачати офіційні кошти кампанії як особисті витрати. Тому, за словами Холдинга, Едвардс програв би , якщо б він це зробив, і також програв, якщо б він цього не зробив. Щоб довести свою позицію, Холдинг повинен був довести, що Едвардс свідомо порушив закон. Але якщо не повідомити про подарунки як про внески в кампанію було б злочином, то повідомлення про такі подарунки як про внески було б порушенням існуючого закону (наслідком того, що Едвардс перетворив внески на кошти особистого користування), але неможливо довести, що Едвардс знав, що він порушує закон, що було б необхідним для засудження. Це не дуже хороші юридичні аргументи, на яких можна спиратися у справі - особливо у справі, яка не подібна до будь-якої іншої, яка була успішно розглянута. І оскільки Холдинг мав доступ до всіх наявних доказів і знав, що немає свідків і ні...","answer":"Суд над Джоном Едвардсом був неефективним, оскільки бракувало доказів скоєння злочину. Обвинувачення Едвардса насправді було на користь Джорджу Холдингу, який балотується до Конгресу. В статті припущено, що Холдинг заскаржив Едвардса з ціллю звернути на себе увагу. "},{"question":"このカテゴリのトリビアの例を挙げてください：スポーツ","answer":"マイケル・フェルプスは、夏のオリンピックで一番多くの個人金メダルを取った記録を持っているんですか? はい"},{"question":"يتم ترتيب وتصنيف الدول العربية من حيث المساحة فما هي الدول الاكبر مساحة؟","answer":"لم أفهم قصدك ، من أي قائمة دول تريد هذا التصنيف ، أرجو التوضيح"},{"question":"Moscou mooy gëblag man réew?","answer":"Moscou mooy gëblag réewum Russie."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి నానార్ధాలు ఇవ్వండి: అంగుష్ఠం","answer":"బొటనవ్రేలు, అంగుళం"},{"question":"キャッチコピーは「EXILEのD.N.Aを受け継ぐガールズ・エンターテーメント・プロジェクト」。２０１３年には紅白歌合戦にも出場したグループと言えば？","answer":"E-girls（イーガールズ）です。"},{"question":"Misy voka-dratsiny ve avy amin'ny fanafody \\"antiretroviral\\"?","answer":"Eny, mety hisy fiatraikany ny fanafody antiretroviral, saingy ny tombotsoa azo avy amin'ny fanafoanana ny VIH dia matetika mihoatra ny loza mety hitranga. Ny safidy ny fitsaboana dia miankina amin'ny lafin-javatra isan-karazany, ary zava-dehibe ny miresaka momba izany amin'ny mpitsabo."},{"question":" Waxaa sheegtaa Saxaabigii arkay Masiixuddajaal waqtigii Nabigaﷺ","answer":" Waxuu ahaa Tamiimuddaari تميم الدارS61aad: Waxaa sheegtaa salaada aan lahayn rukuuda iyo sujuuda"},{"question":"Ọwọ ọlọpaa tẹ awọn afurasi to ji ẹru ko lasiko ifẹhonu han SARS n’Ilọrin","answer":"O kere tan, awọn afurasi ọgọrun-un kan ati mẹrinlelogoji lọwọ ọlọpaa ti tẹ niluu Ilọrin pe wọn ji ẹru ijọba ati tawọn ile itaja nla ko lasiko ifẹhonu han ta ko SARS lọsẹ to kọja.Nigba to n ṣafihan wọn pẹlu awọn ẹru ti wọn ji ko ni olu ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa n’Ilọrin lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, Ọga ọlọpaa, Kayọde Ẹgbẹtokun, ni awọn ba ara ẹru ti wọn ji lakata awọn afurasi naa.Ẹgbẹtokun ṣeleri pe ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa yoo tẹsiwaju lati tọpinpin gbogbo awọn to ji nnkan ko, awọn yoo si gba awọn ẹru naa pada lọwọ wọn.O ni gbogbo kọrọ kọndu ilu Ilọrin ati ipinlẹ Kwara lawọn yoo de lati gbe awọn to ji ẹru ti ki i ṣe tiwọn ko.O ni iṣẹ ọhun lawọn yoo jọ ṣe pẹlu awọn agbofinro yooku lati ri i pe gbogbo awọn ọdaran naa lọwọ tẹ.Ọga ọlọpaa naa gba gbogbo awọn to ba ni ẹru ti wọn ji lakata wọn lati jọwọ rẹ wọrọọwọ ko too di pe pampẹ ofin ba wọn.O ni ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa yoo ṣiju aanu wo gbogbo awọn to ba finu-findọ yọnda awọn ẹru naa."},{"question":"வினா : சத்ரபதி சிவாஜியைப்பற்றி பாரதியார் பாடிய பாடலை எழுதுக.","answer":"விடை:சத்ரபதி சிவாஜியைப் பற்றி பாரதியார் பாடிய பாடல்:ஜயஜய மாதா! ஜயஜய துர்க்கா! வந்தே மாதரம்! வந்தே மாதரம்!சேனைத் தலைவர்காள்! சிறந்த மந்திரிகாள்!யானைத் தலைவரும் அருந்திறல் வீரர்காள்!அதிரத மனர்காள்! துரகத் ததிபர்காள்எதிரிகள் துணுக்குற இடித்திடு பதாதிகாள்!வேலெறி படைகாள்! சூலெறி மறவர்காள்!கால னுருக்க்கொளும் கணைதுரந் திடுவீர்.மற்றுமா யிரவிதம் பற்றலர் தம்மைச்செற்றிடுந் திறனுடைத் தீரரத் தினங்காள்!யாவிரும் வாழிய! யாவிரும் வாழிய!தேவிநுந் தமக்கெலாம் திருவருள் புரிக!மாற்றலர் தம்புலை நாற்றமே யறியாஆற்றல்கொண் டிருந்ததில் வரும்புகழ் நாடு!வேதநூல் பழிக்கும் வெளித்திசை மிலேச்சர்பாதமும் பொறுப்பளோ பாரத தேவி?வீரரும் அவரிசை விரித்திடு புலவரும்பாரெலாம் பெரும்புகழ் பரப்பிய நாடு!தர்மமே உருவமாத் தழைத்த பே ரரசரும்நிர்மல முனிவரும் நிறந்த நன் னாடு!வீரரைப் பெறாத மேன்மைநீர் மங்கையைஊரவர் மலடியென் றுரைத்திடு நாடு!பாரதப் பூமி பழம்பெரும் பூமி;நீரதன் புதல்வர், இந் நினைவகற் றாதீர்!பாரத நாடு பார்க்கெலாம் திலகம்;நீரதன் புதல்வர், இந் நினைவகற் றாதீர்!வானக முட்டும் இமயமால் வரையும்ஏனைய திசைகளில் இருந்திரைக் கடலும்காத்திடு நாடு! கங்கையும் சிந்துவும்தூத்திரை யமுனையும் சுனைகளும் புனல்களும்இன்னரும் பொழில்களும் இணையிலா வளங்களும்உன்னத மலைகளும் ஒளிர்தரு நாடு!பைந்நிறப் பழனம் பசியிலா தளிக்கமைந்நிற முகில்கள் வழங்கும் பொன்னாடு!தேவர்கள் வாழ்விடம், திறலுயர் முனிவர்ஆவலோ டடையும் அரும்புகழ் நாடு!ஊனமொன்றறியா ஞானமெய் பூமி,வானவர் விழையும் மாட்சியார் தேயம்!பாரத நாட்டிசை பகரயான் வல்லனோ?நீரதன் புதல்வர் நினைவகற் றாதீர்!தாய்த்திரு நாட்டைத் தறுகண் மிலேச்சர்பேய்த்தகை கொண்டோ ர் பெருமையும் வன்மையும்ஞானமும் அறியா நவைபுரி பகைவர்வானகம் அடக்க வந்திடும் அரக்கர் போல்இந்நாள் படை கொணர்ந்து இன்னல்செய் கின்றார்!ஆலயம் அழித்தலும் அருமறை பழித்தலும்பாலரை விருத்தரைப் பசுக்களை ஒழித்தலும்மாதர்கற் பழித்தலும் மறைவர் வேள்விக்குஏதமே சூழ்வதும் இயற்றிநிற் கின்றார்!சாத்திரத் தொகுதங்யைத் தாழ்த்துவைக் கங்ன்றார்கோத்தங்ர மங்கையர் குலங்கெடுக் கின்றார்எண்ணில துணைவர்காள்! எமக்கிவர் செயுந்துயர்கண்ணியம் மறுத்தனர, ஆண்மையுங் கடிந்தனர்,பொருளினைச் சிதைத்தனர், மருளினை விதைத்தனர்திண்மையை யழித்துப் பெண்மையிங் களித்தனர்,பாரதப் பெரும்பெயர் பழிப்பெய ராக்கினர்,சூரர்தம் மக்களைத் தொழும்பராய்ப் புரிந்தனர்,வீரியம் அழிந்து மேன்மையும் ஒழிந்து நம்ஆரியர் புலையருக் கடிமைக ளாயினர்.மற்றிதைப் பொறுத்து வாழ்வதோ வாழ்க்கைவெற்றிகொள் புலையர்தாள் வீழ்ந்துகொல் வாழ்வீர்?மொக்குகள்தான் தோன்றி முடிவது போலமக்களாய்ப் பிறந்தோர் மடிவது திண்ணம்.தாய்த்திரு நாட்டைத் தகர்த்திடு மிலேச்சரைமாய்த்திட விரும்பான் வாழ்வுமோர் வாழ்வுகொல்?மானமென் றிலாது மாற்றலர் தொழும்பாய்ஈனமுற் றிருக்க எவன்கொலோ விரும்புவன்?தாய்பிறன் கைப்படச் சகிப்பவ னாகிநாயென வாழ்வோன் நமரில்இங் குளனோ?பிச்சைவாழ் வுகந்து பிறருடைய யாட்சியில்அச்சமுற் றிருப்போன் ஆரிய னல்லன்,புன்புலால் யாழ்க்கையைப் போற்றியே தாய்நாட்டுஅன்பிலா திருப்போன் ஆரிய னல்லன்.மாட்சிதீர் மிலேச்சர் மனப்படி யாளும்ஆட்சியி லடங்குவோன் ஆரிய னல்லன்.ஆரியத் தன்மை அற்றிடுஞ் சிறியர்யாரிவண் உளரவர் யாண்டேனும் ஒழிக!படைமுகத்து இறந்து பதம்பெற விரும்பாக்கடைபடு மாக்களென் கண்முனில் லாதீர்!சோதரர் தம்மைத் துரோகிகள் அழிப்பமாதரர் நலத்தின் மகிழ்பவன் மகிழ்க,நாடெலாம் பிறர்வசம் நண்ணுதல் நினையான்வீடுசென் றொளிக்க விரும்புவோன் விரும்புக!தேசமே நலிவொடு தேய்ந்திட மக்களின்பாசமே பெரிதெனப் பார்ப்பவன் செல்க!நாட்டுளார் பசியினால் நலிந்திடத் தன்வயிறுஊட்டுதல் பெரங்தென உண்ணுவோன் செல்க!ஆணுருக் கொண்ட பெண்களும் அலிகளும்வீணில்இங் கிருந்தெனை வெறுத்திடல் விரும்பேன்.ஆரியர் இருமின்! ஆண்கள்இங்கு இருமின்!வீரியம் மிகுந்த மேன்மையோர் இருமின்!மானமே பெரிதென மதிப்பவர் இருமின்!ஈனமே பொறாத இயல்பினர் இருமின்!தாய்நாட் டன்புறு தனையர் இங்கு இருமின்!மாய்நாட் பெருமையின் மாய்பவர் இருமின்!புலையர்தம் தொழும்பைப் பொறுக்கிலார் இருமின்!கலையறு மிலேச்சரைக் கடிபவர் இருமின்!ஊரவர் துயரில்நெஞ் சுருகுவீர் இருமின்!சோர நெஞ்சங்லாத் தூயவர் இருமின்!தேவிதாள் பணியுந் தீரர் இங்கு இருமின்!பாவியர் குருதியைப் பருகுவார் இருமின்!உடலினைப் போற்றா உத்தமர் இருமின்!கடல்மடுப் பினும்மனம் கலங்கலர் உதவுமின்!வம்மினோ துணைவீர்? மருட்சிகொள் ளாதீர்!நம்மினோ ராற்றலை நாழிகைப் பொழுதெனும்புல்லிய மாற்றலர் பொறுக்கவல் லார்கொல்?மெல்லிய திருவடி வீறுடைத் தேவியின்இன்னருள் நமக்கோர் இருந்துணை யாகும்பன்னரும் புகழுடைப் பார்த்தனும் கண்ணனும்வீமனும் துரோணனும் வீட்டுமன் றானும்ராமனும் வேறுள இருந்திறல் வீரரும்நற்றுணை புரிவர்; வானக, நாடுறும்!வெற்றியே யன்றி வேறெதும் பெறுகிலேம்!பற்றறு முனிவரும் ஆசிகள் பகர்வர்செற்றினி மிழேச்சரைத் தீர்த்திட வம்மீன்!ஈட்டியாற் சிரங்களை வீட்டிட எழுமின்!நீட்டிய வேல்களை நேரிருந்து எறிமின்!வாளுடை முனையினும் வயந்திகழ் சூலினும்,ஆளுடைக் கால்க ளடியினுந் தேர்களின்உருளையி னிடையினும் மாற்றலர் தலைகள்உருளையிற் கண்டுநெஞ் சுவப்புற வம்மின்!நம்இதம், பெருவளம் நலிந்திட விரும்பும்(வன்மியை) வேரறத் தொலைத்தபின் னன்றோஆணெனப் பெறுவோம், அன்றிநாம் இறப்பினும்வானுறு தேவர் மணியுல கடைவோம்,வாழ்வமேற் பாரத வான்புகழ்த் தேவியைத்தாழ்வினின் றுயர்த்திய தடம்புகழ் பெறுவோம்!போரெனில் இதுபோர், புண்ணியத் திருப்போர்!பாரினில் இதுபோற் பார்த்திடற் கெளிதோ?ஆட்டினைக் கொன்று வேள்விகள் இயற்றிவீட்டினைப் பெறுவான் விரும்புவார் சிலரேநெஞ்சகக் குருதியை நிலத்திடை வடித்துவஞ்சக மழிக்கும் மாமகம் புரிவம்யாம்வேள்வியில்இதுபோல் வேள்வியொன் றில்லை!தவத்தினில் இதுபோல் தவம்பிறி தில்லை!முன்னையோர் பார்த்தன் முனைத்திசை நின்றுதன்னெதிர் நின்ற தளத்தினை நோக்கிடமாதுலர் சோதரர் மைத்துனர் தாதையர்காதலின் நண்பர் கலைதரு குரவரென்றுஇன்னவர் இருத்தல்கண்டு, இதயம்நொந் தோனாய்த்தன்னருந் தெய்விகச் சாரதி முன்னர்ஐயனே! இவர்மீ தம்பையோ தொடுப்பேன்?வையகத் தரசும் வானக ஆட்சியும்போயினும் இவர்தமைப் போரினில் வீழ்த்தேன்.மெய்யினில் நடுக்கம் மேவுகின் றதுவால,fகையினில் வில்லும் கழன்றுவீழ் கின்றது.வாயுலர் கின்றது; மனம் பதைக்கின்றது,ஓய்வுறுங் கால்கள, உலைந்தது சிரமமும்,வெற்றியை விரும்பேன், மேன்மையை விரும்பேன்சுற்றமிங் கறுத்துச் சுகம்பெறல் விரும்பேன்,எனையிவர் கொல்லினும் இவரையான் தீண்டேன்,சினையறுத் திட்டபின் செய்வதோ ஆட்சி?எனப்பல கூறியவ் விந்திரன் புதல்வன்கனப்படை வில்லைக் களத்தினில் எறிந்துசோர்வோடு வீழ்ந்தனன், சுருதியின் முடிவாய்த்தேர்வயின் நின்றநம் தெய்விகப் பெருமான்வில்லெறிந் திருந்த வீரனை நோக்கிபுல்லிய அறிவொடு புலம்புகின் றனையால்அறத்தினைப் பிரிந்த சுயோதனா தியரைச்செறுத்தினி மாய்ப்பது தீமையென் கின்றாய்,உண்மையை அறியாய் உறவையே கருதிப்பெண்மைகொண் டேதோ பிதற்றிநிற் கின்றாய்வஞ்சகர், தீயர், மனிதரை வருத்துவோர்,நெஞ்சகத் தருக்குடை நீசர்கள்; இன்னோர்தம்மொடு பிறந்த சகோதரராயினும்வெம்மையோ டொறுத்தல் வீரர்தஞ் செயலாம்.ஆரிய நீதிநீ அறிகிலை போலும்!பூரியர் போல்மனம் புழுங்குற லாயினைஅரும்புகழ் தேய்ப்பதும் அனாரியத் தகைத்தும்பெரும்பதத் தடையுமாம் பெண்மையெங் கெய்தினை?பேடிமை யகற்று! நின் பெருமையை மறந்திடேல்!ஈடிலாப் புகழினாய்! எழுகவோ எழுக! என்றுமெய்ஞ் ஞானம்நம் இறையவர் கூறக்குன்றெனும் வயிரக் கொற்றவான் புயத்தோன்அறமே பெரிதென அறிந்திடு மனத்தனாய்மறமே உருவுடை மாற்றலர் தம்மைச்சுற்றமும் நோக்கான் தோழமை மதியான்பற்றலர் தமையெலாம் பார்க்கிரை யாக்கினன்.விசயனன் றிருந்த வியன்புகழ் நாட்டில்இசையுநற் றவத்தால் இன்றுவாழ்ந் திருக்கும்ஆரிய வீரர்காள்! அவருடை மாற்றலர்,தேரில்இந் நாட்டினர், செறிவுடை உறவினர்,நம்மையின் றெதிர்க்கும் நயனிலாப் புல்லோர்,செம்மைதீர் மிலேச்சர், தேசமும் பிறிதாம்பிறப்பினில் அன்னியர், பேச்சினில் அன்னியர்சிறப்புடை யாரியச் சீர்மையை அறியார்.சத்திரபதி சிவாஜி :முதலாம் சிவாஜி போன்சலே என்பவர் ஓர் இந்திய ஆட்சியாளர் ஆவார். இவர் சத்திரபதி சிவாஜி மகாராஜா என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறார். இவர் மராத்தா சமூகத்தின் போன்சலே குலத்தைச் சேர்ந்தவர் ஆவார். பீஜாப்பூரின் வீழ்ச்சியடைந்து கொண்டிருந்த அதில்ஷாகி சுல்தானகத்திலிருந்து தனது சொந்த சுதந்திர இராச்சியத்தைச் சிவாஜி உருவாக்கினார்.இதுவே மராத்தியப் பேரரசின் தொடக்கமாக அமைந்தது. 1674ஆம் ஆண்டு அலுவல்ரீதியாகத் தனது நிலப்பகுதிகளுக்குச் சத்திரபதியாக இராய்கட் கோட்டையில் முடிசூட்டிக் கொண்டார்.தன் வாழ்நாளில் முகலாயப் பேரரசு, குதுப் ஷாஹி வம்சம், பீஜப்பூர் சுல்தானகம் மற்றும் ஐரோப்பியக் காலனிய சக்திகளுடன் கூட்டணிகளையும் எதிர்ப்புகளையும் சிவாஜி ஏற்படுத்தினார். மராத்தியச் செல்வாக்குப் பகுதிகளைச் சிவாஜியின் இராணுவப்படைகள் விரிவாக்கின. கோட்டைகளைக் கைப்பற்றவும், புதிதாகக் கட்டவும் செய்தன. மராத்தியக் கப்பற்படையை உருவாக்கின. நன் முறையில் கட்டமைக்கப்பட்ட நிர்வாக அமைப்புகளையுடைய ஒரு செயல்திறன்மிக்க முற்போக்கு மனப்பான்மையுள்ள ஆட்சிமுறையை சிவாஜி நிறுவினார். பண்டைய இந்து அரசியல் பாரம்பரியங்கள், அரசவை மரபுகள் ஆகியவற்றுக்குப் புத்துயிர் கொடுத்தார். அரசவை மற்றும் நிர்வாகத்தில் பாரசீகத்தை நீக்கிவிட்டு, மராத்தி மற்றும் சமசுகிருதப் பயன்பாட்டை ஊக்குவித்தார்."},{"question":"Completa la siguiente frase:  En 1981 participó en el Campeonato Sudamericano Sub-20. En 1987 fue llamado a participar en el Torneo Preolímpico en Bolivia. Hizo su debut en la selección absoluta el 5 de marzo de 1987. Fue convocado por primera vez para una competición oficial en la... ","answer":"Copa América de 1987. Hizo su debut en la competencia el 2 de julio en Buenos Aires contra Argentina, jugando como titular. Luego participó contra Perú. Dos años después fue nuevamente elegido para representar a su país en la Copa América. Jugó los cuatro partidos jugados con su selección todos como titular y durante los 90 minutos completos."},{"question":"Iza amin'ny vatana no tompon'andraikitra amin'ny fampidinana ra amin'ny  lalan-drà?a) atidohab) Havokavokad) Fo ","answer":"d) Ny fo no tompon'andraikitra amin'ny fampidinana ra amin'ny  lalan-drà."},{"question":"Değerli element nedir?","answer":"Yüksek ekonomik değere sahip nadir rastlanan metalik kimyasal elementlere kıymetli metal adı verilir. Kimyasal olarak kıymetli metaller diğer elementlerden daha az reaktivite özelliğine sahip olup, parlaklığı (luster/lustre) ve erime noktaları daha yüksektir."},{"question":"Làm sao để lời chúc được trọn vẹn?","answer":"Một lời chúc phúc tử tế, chân thành, chu đáo giống như một dạng ma thuật — nó có sức mạnh làm thay đổi một ngày của ai đó ngay lập tức và khiến họ cảm thấy dễ chịu.Tuy vậy, lời chúc cũng cần có những giới hạn để người tiếp nhận không quá áp lực. Điều đầu tiên, chúng ta nên để ý về cách sử dụng ngôn ngữ.Trong đó những lời chúc mang tính kỳ vọng có từ “phải” thường tạo ra nhiều áp lực hơn cho người nghe. Đơn cử như “Đẹp đôi thế này thì phải hạnh phúc nhé”, “Có năng lực mà, phải thành công nhé”…Từ phía người tiếp nhận, bạn có thể chủ động kiểm soát số lượng thông tin mà mình nhận vào. Chẳng hạn như thông báo một sự kiện quan trọng cho số lượng người giới hạn.Hoặc, bạn cũng có thể thông báo sau khi sự kiện đã diễn ra một thời gian. Điều này sẽ giúp bạn cảm thấy thoải mái hơn khi nhận vì bạn biết rằng nó đều đến từ những người hiểu mình."},{"question":"मटर पनीर कैसे बनाते हैं?","answer":"मटर पनीर बनाने के लिए पनीर को क्यूब्स में काट लें और थोड़े तेल में तल लें। एक पैन में तेल गरम करें, जीरा, बारीक कटा प्याज, अदरक-लहसुन का पेस्ट, टमाटर, हल्दी पाउडर, धनिया पाउडर, गरम मसाला, और मटर डालकर पकाएं। पनीर को इसमें मिलाएं और थोड़ी देर पकने दें।"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి పర్యాయ పదాలని ఇవ్వండి: కొండ","answer":"అద్రి, పర్వతం, గిరి, శిఖరం"},{"question":"2015-ம் ஆண்டில் இந்தியாவில் மத்திய அரசின் உத்தரவுப்படி ஸ்மார்ட் சிட்டியாக்க தேர்வு செய்த மொத்த நகரங்கள் எத்தனை?","answer":"98 நகரங்கள்2015 ஆம் ஆண்டில், மாநில அளவிலான போட்டியின் அடிப்படையில் ஸ்மார்ட் சிட்டி சவாலுக்கு 98 நகரங்கள் மாநிலங்களால் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட்டன. நூறு நகரங்கள் பரிந்துரைக்கப்பட வேண்டும் ஆனால் ஜம்மு காஷ்மீர் மற்றும் உத்தரபிரதேசம் தலா ஒரு இடத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தவில்லை."},{"question":"Qual país da África costumava ser o único lar do extinto pássaro dodô?","answer":"Dodó (ou dodô no português brasileiro) é uma espécie extinta de ave da família dos pombos que era endêmica da República das Ilhas Maurícias (ou República de Maurício no português do Brasil), no Oceano Índico a leste de Madagascar."},{"question":"Isilah titik-titik berikut dengan kata, frasa, atau penggalan kalimat jawaban yang tepat sehingga membentuk kalimat yang sempurna dan relevan dengan konteks yang diberikan.Konteks: Ciri-ciri zat makanan.Ketika makan nasi atau roti, makanan selanjutnya akan dicerna dan diserap tubuh dalam bentuk molekul ... dan jika jumlahnya berlebihan maka selanjutnya ...Jawaban:","answer":"Ketika makan nasi atau roti, makanan selanjutnya akan dicerna dan diserap tubuh dalam bentuk molekul Glukosa dan jika jumlahnya berlebihan maka selanjutnya diubah menjadi glikogen dan disimpan di otot."},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa: Bolivia kasa ce da ba ta da ƙasa a Kudancin Amurka da aka sani da yanayin ƙasa daban-daban da al'adun ƴan asali. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: Gaskiya"},{"question":"Title: అవిశ్వాస తీర్మానం: అంటే ఏమిటి? ఏం జరుగుతుంది?nGiven the above title of an imaginary article, imagine the article.n","answer":"అయితే భారత రాజ్యాంగంలో విశ్వాస తీర్మానం లేదా అవిశ్వాస తీర్మానం అనే ప్రస్తావన ఎక్కడా లేదు. కానీ.. మంత్రి మండలి ఉమ్మడిగా లోక్‌సభకు బాధ్యత వహిస్తుందని 75వ అధికరణ స్పష్టంచేస్తోంది. అంటే.. ప్రధానమంత్రి, ఆయన మంత్రిమండలిని లోక్‌సభలో మెజారిటీ సభ్యులు వ్యతిరేకించరాదని దీనర్థంగా చెప్పుకోవచ్చు. భారతదేశంలో పార్లమెంటు దిగువ సభ, ప్రత్యక్షంగా ఎన్నికయిన పార్లమెంటు సభ్యులు గల లోక్‌సభలో మాత్రమే అవిశ్వాస తీర్మానాన్ని ప్రవేశపెట్టవచ్చు. లోక్‌సభ కార్యకలాపాల నియమావళిలోని 198వ నిబంధన.. అవిశ్వాస తీర్మానం విధివిధానాలను నిర్దేశిస్తోంది. దీనిప్రకారం.. లోక్‌సభ సభ్యుడు ఎవరైనా సరే రాతపూర్వకంగా అవిశ్వాస తీర్మానానికి నోటీసు ఇవ్వవచ్చు. స్పీకర్ ఈ అవిశ్వాస తీర్మానం నోటీసు నిర్దేశిత విధానంలో ఉందని భావిస్తే దానిని సభలో చదవాలి. దీనిని చర్చకు చేపట్టటానికి మద్దతు ఇచ్చేవారందరూ నిలబడాలని కోరాలి. అవిశ్వాసం నోటీసుకు కనీసం 50 మంది ఎంపీలు మద్దతు లభించకపోతే ఆ తీర్మానాన్ని స్పీకర్ తిరస్కరిస్తారు. తీర్మానం ప్రవేశపెట్టటానికి కనీసం 50 మంది ఎంపీలు మద్దతు తెలిపినట్లయితే.. స్పీకర్ తీర్మానాన్ని స్వీకరించి, దానిపై చర్చకు ఒక తేదీ లేదా తేదీలను నిర్ణయిస్తారు. ఆ తేదీ.. నోటీసు ఇచ్చిన పది రోజుల లోపే ఉండాలి. ఈ తీర్మానంపై చర్చలో ప్రసంగాలకు స్పీకర్ అవసరమని భావిస్తే కాలపరిమితి కూడా నిర్ణయించవచ్చు. ఈ చర్చలో అవిశ్వాస తీర్మానం పెట్టిన వారు, దానికి మద్దతు ఇచ్చిన వారు ప్రసంగిస్తారు. ప్రభుత్వంపై వారు చేసిన ఆరోపణలకు సాధారణంగా ప్రధానమంత్రి కానీ, మంత్రి మండలి సభ్యులు కానీ సమాధానం ఇస్తారు.  ఈ చర్చ ముగిసిన అనంతరం అవిశ్వాస తీర్మానంపై స్పీకర్ ఓటింగ్ నిర్వహిస్తారు. మూజువాణి ఓటు ద్వారా కానీ, సభ్యుల విభజన ద్వారా కానీ ఈ ఓటింగ్ ఉండవచ్చు. అందులో మెజారిటీ సభ్యులు తీర్మానానికి అనుకూలంగా ఓటు వేస్తే.. ప్రభుత్వం దిగిపోవాల్సి ఉంటుంది. మెజారిటీ సభ్యులు తీర్మానాన్ని వ్యతిరేకిస్తే తీర్మానం వీగిపోతుంది. మోదీ సర్కారుపై అవిశ్వాస తీర్మానం ఎందుకు? లోక్‌సభలో బీజేపీ సారథ్యంలోని ఎన్‌డీఏ ప్రభుత్వానికి సంపూర్ణ మెజారిటీ ఉంది. అందులో బీజేపీకే సొంతంగా స్పీకర్ కాకుండా.. 274 మంది సభ్యులు (ఇద్దరు నామినేటెడ్ సభ్యులతో కలిసి) ఉన్నారు. ఇది కనీస మెజారిటీకన్నా ఇద్దరు సభ్యులు ఎక్కువ. తాజాగా టీడీపీ వైదొలగినా కానీ.. మిత్ర పక్షాలతో కలిపి మోదీ సర్కారుకున్న బలం 315 మంది సభ్యులు. ఈ పరిస్థితుల్లో మోదీ ప్రభుత్వం అవిశ్వాస తీర్మానం ఎందుకు? "},{"question":"Jubbantil mbind mii:Yéen nit ak jinne yi, danañu leen xalseta àtte","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Yéen nit ak jinne yi, danañu leen xalseta àtte"},{"question":"地球的面积是多少？","answer":"地球的面积约为 5.1 亿平方公里。"},{"question":"Iza no mpanjaka nitondra farany an'i Madagasikara?","answer":"Ny mpanjaka vavy Ranavalona III no mpanjaka nitondra farany an'i Madagasikara. Tamin'ny taona 28 May taona 1897 izy no niala teo amin'ny fitondrana. "},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'genggam bara api, biar sampai jadi arang'?","answer":"Maksud peribahasa tersebut ialah jika melakukan pekerjaan yang susah haruslah dengan sabar sehingga mendapat nikmatnya nanti. "},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa cabitaanno u wanaagsan hurdada oo qofka Ka caawiya Inuu si wacan u seexdo?","answer":"Sida ay ku taliyaan xeeldheereyaasha hurdadu, dadka waa wayn ee ay da’adoodu u dhexeyso 18 illaa 60 jir waxa inay seexdaan ugu yaraan 7 illaa 9 saacadood oo hurdo ah habeen kasta.Hurdo yaraanta iyo hurdada xad dhaafka ah waxay kordhiyaan halista niyad jabka, sonkorowga iyo wadne xanuunka.Warka wanaagsani waa inay jiraan cabbitaanno hurdada keena, kuwaas oo dadka waa wayn ka caawin kara in ay si dhakhso ah u gam’aan. Waa kuwaan cabbitaannada ugu fiican ee hurdada kobciya.Shaaha Chamomile:Chamomile waa geed daweed muddo dheer aadamuhu soo isticmaalayay iyadoo loo adeegsan jiray wanaajinta hurdada, daweynta ifilada, hoos u dhigista hurka (inflammation) iyo daweynta cilladaha maqaarka.Sida daraasaadku ay tilmaamayaan, chamomile waxaa uu wanaajiyaa tayada hurdada, waxaana uu yareeyaa welwelka iyo hurdo la’aanta. Dadka hurdo la’aanta ka cabanaya waxaa lagula taliyaan inay cabbaan shaaha chamomile (chamomile tea), waxaa ku jira walxo dejiya neerfaha.Cabbitaanka miraha chery-ga:Miraha cherries-ka waxay kobciyaan hurdada, sababtunta waa maadada tryptophan ee ku jirta. Tryptophan waa barootiin soo saara hormoonka “melatonin” oo door weyn ka qaata nidaaminta heerarka iyo wareegyada kala duwan ee hurdada aadamaha.Shaaha nacnaaca (peppermint Tea):Shaaha geedka nacnaaca, ma lahan maadada “caffeine”, sidaas darteed xilli kasta ayaad cabbi kartaa, waxaa uu caawiya cunno shiidista, waxaana uu sare u qaadaa dareenka xasiiloonida.Digniin: Haddii aad leedahay xaaladda gaasteri ee keenta in asiidha calooshu hunguriga ku soo noqoto (Gastroesophageal reflux disease – GERD), ka dheerow shaaha nacnaaca.Caanaha diirraan:Shaki kuma jiro in caanuhu ay ka mid yihiin dawooyinka ugu caansan ee kobcinta tayada hurdada. Caanaha waxaa ku jira maadada “tryptophan” oo kordhisa hormoonka “serotonin”, kaas oo masuul ka ah dareenka farxadda iyo xasiiloonida. Serotonin waxa uu horudhac u yahay hormoonka “melatonin” kaas oo nidaamiya hurdada.Wax dhibaato ma lahan inaad tijaabiso caanaha diirran hurdada ka hor, haddii aadan qabin cilladda u dulqaadasho la’aanta laktoos (lactose intolerance) ama xasaasiyadda caanaha. "},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: \\"Từng được biết đến là \\"Đôi bạn 'nắm tay nhau đi khắp Việt Nam', vừa du lịch vừa kiếm tiền siêu giỏi\\", mới đây, để kỉ niệm 18 năm tình bạn -  Nguyễn Loan và Chu Phương Linh (cùng sinh năm 1990, đang sinh sống ở Hà Nội) đã thực hiện hành trình du lịch 19 quốc gia châu Âu như Pháp, Ý, Thụy Sĩ, Đức, Áo... \\"Ban đầu, chúng mình dự định sẽ đi 18 nước nhưng cuối cùng lại \\"nhỡ\\" đến nước thứ 19 - Bulgaria\\", Phương Linh hài hước chia sẻ. Bộ ảnh check-in tại 19 quốc gia của đôi bạn thân đang gây sốt trên mạng xã hội với hàng trăm ngàn lượt tương tác. \\"Mình và Loan chính thức quen nhau năm 15 tuổi, khi cả hai cùng thi đỗ vào trường chuyên Hùng Vương, Phú Thọ. Ngày sinh viên, chúng mình cũng mê du lịch lắm mà không có điều kiện để đi chơi nhiều, chỉ ngồi nhà xem hình ảnh trên mạng và ao ước. Vài năm gần đây, vì yêu cầu công việc, nên hai đứa xách vali đi liên tục. Chúng mình đã đi gần hết các tỉnh thành tại Việt Nam và nuôi giấc mơ du lịch châu Âu cũng nhau. Khi đã sắp xếp được công việc, tài chính, chúng mình lên đường\\", Phương Linh cho biết. Xách 70kg hành lý, mải chơi đến... bong gân Chuyến đi của Linh và Loan bắt đầu từ 1/7 và kết thúc vào ngày 29/7. Đồng hành trong chuyến đi còn có ông xã của Phương Linh và hai người bạn thân của cặp đôi đang sinh sống tại Anh. Phương Linh cho biết, đây là chuyến đi châu Âu đầu tiên của cô và bạn thân nên việc chuẩn bị trước chuyến đi khá vất vả. \\"Chúng mình đi du lịch tự túc nên phải tự xin visa, đặt vé máy bay, thuê xe lái xuyên quốc gia,... Trong đó xin visa là việc quan trọng và tốn nhiều thời gian nhất\\", Linh nói. Linh và Loan đã cùng nhau tìm hiểu thông tin, tự viết thư tay, chuẩn bị bản kế hoạch chi tiết gồm lịch trình di chuyển từng quốc gia (ngày đến, ngày đi), vé khách sạn, vé máy bay... \\"Thật may mắn khi thủ tục visa của chúng mình được thông qua nhanh chóng\\", Linh chia sẻ. Đôi bạn thân bay sang Pháp vào ngày 1/7. Sau đó, họ thuê xe tự lái để tới các 10 quốc gia châu Âu lân cận như Thụy Sĩ, Đức, Áo, Slovakia, Ý, Monaco... Chặng đầu tiên của chuyến đi kéo dài hơn 2 tuần. Kết thúc chặng này, nhóm trở lại Pháp trả xe và bay máy bay đến du lịch các quốc gia Nam Âu như Tây Ban Nha, Hy Lạp, Malta... Vốn đam mê thời trang và cũng kinh doanh trong lĩnh vực này, Linh và Loan đã chuẩn bị hàng trăm bộ trang phục cho chuyến đi. \\"Mỗi đứa mình mang theo vài vali đựng trang phục, nặng tới 70kg\\", Linh kể. Nhưng theo Linh, đây là \\"sai lầm lớn\\" của đôi bạn. \\"Mình phải tìm thuê chiếc ô tô lớn mới có thể xếp được hết các vali. Bên cạnh đó, hầu hết khách sạn mình thuê đều là các khách sạn cổ, không có thang máy hiện đại. Việc mang vác những vali quần áo nặng trịch trở thành ác mộng\\", Linh kể. Phương Linh khuyên du khách nên hạn chế mang nhiều đồ dùng khi du lịch châu Âu để tránh mất sức, tránh thất lạc. \\"Ở đây đồ thời trang của các thương hiệu rất rẻ so với Việt Nam. Chúng mình đi đúng mùa giảm giá nên nhìn vào món nào cũng muốn mua. Nhưng hành lý quá nặng rồi nên hai đứa đành tiếc nuối rời khỏi trung tâm thương mại\\", Phương Linh chia sẻ. Vác đến 70kg hành lý, nhưng \\"hành trang quý giá nhất\\" của 2 cô gái là... chai tương ớt và lọ muối chấm. Vốn không hợp đồ ăn châu Âu nên đây trở thành gia vị quan trọng với họ trong suốt hành trình. Linh và Loan thừa nhận, mỗi quốc gia châu Âu đều có những vẻ đẹp thiên nhiên, văn hóa khác nhau khiến họ vô cùng hưng phấn. \\"Khi tới Santorini, mình như vỡ òa trước hòn đảo đẹp như tranh. Mình như đứa trẻ, tung tăng chạy khắp nơi chụp ảnh... và không may trượt chân ngã, bong gân\\", Phương Linh nhớ lại. Cô mang theo chiếc chân đau đi thêm 4 quốc gia nữa mới trở về Việt Nam. Linh hài hước cho biết, cô còn định làm bộ ảnh \\"xách nạng gỗ đi khắp châu Âu\\" để ghi lại kỉ niệm nhớ đời này.  28 ngày chinh phục 19 quốc gia Đôi bạn di chuyển chủ yếu trong khối Schengen nên khá thuận lợi. \\"Chúng mình chỉ cần chuẩn bị sức khỏe thật tốt để thay nhau lái xe là được\\", Phương Linh nói. Nơi họ ở lại ngắn nhất là \\"quốc gia tí hon\\" - San Marino. Giống như Vatican, San Marino cũng nằm hoàn toàn trong lãnh thổ nước Ý và lệch về phía đông bắc quốc gia này. San Marino rộng khoảng 61 km2. Linh và Loan ở đây khoảng 2 giờ. Quốc gia họ lưu trú lâu nhất là Ý - quốc gia thứ 10 trong hành trình, với 3 ngày khám phá. Tại Ý, cả nhóm dành nhiều thời gian tham các điểm đẹp khắp Venice, thưởng thức ẩm thực, chụp bộ ảnh kỉ niệm... \\"Mình mê mẩn vẻ đẹp nước Ý nên chắc chắn sẽ quay lại đây. Ba ngày là quá ít để mình khám phá thỏa thích\\", Phương Linh cho biết. Trước khi đến mỗi quốc gia, họ sẽ xem bản đồ để tìm cung đường thuận lợi, đi qua nhiều điểm nổi tiếng. \\"Ông xã mình hỗ trợ nhiều về việc sắp xếp lịch trình và đặc biệt còn có vợ chồng bạn thân - cặp đôi từng tới 100 quốc gia gợi ý, chia sẻ kinh nghiệm và dẫn đường cho hai đứa\\", Phương Linh chia sẻ. Vài ngày sau khi đã trở về Việt Nam, hai cô gái vẫn chưa hết nhung nhớ chuyến đi. Họ vẫn mê mẩn khoảnh khắc lái xe trong chiều hoàng hôn, xuyên qua những khu rừng già, ngắm mặt hồ mờ sương Thụy Sĩ lúc bình minh... \\"Có nhiều đêm chúng mình về đến khách sạn thì đã mệt phờ, không đủ sức tắm nữa. Thế mà sau một đêm, cả nhóm lại tràn đầy sức lực, tiếp tục lên đường\\", Linh nói.\\"","answer":"Đi 18 nước kỷ niệm tình bạn 18 năm, đôi bạn Hà Nội xinh đẹp khiến dân tình 'phát sốt'"},{"question":"Berikan penerangan ringkas untuk Universiti Malaya dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 60 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Universiti Malaya (UM) ialah universiti penyelidikan awam Malaysia. Terletak di pinggir bandaraya Kuala Lumpur, ia merupakan institusi pengajian tinggi Malaysia tertua dan berpangkat tertinggi menurut dua agensi penarafan antarabangsa, dan juga satu-satunya universiti dalam pasca-kemerdekaan Tanah Melayu. Lima orang Perdana Menteri Malaysia, dan tokoh politik, perniagaan dan budaya terkenal negara yang lain telah menamatkan perngajian di universiti tersebut."},{"question":"Ọwọ tẹ mẹwaa ninu awọn to n fọ ọpa epo bẹntiroolu ati ọkọ ti wọn n lo l’Arepo","answer":"Ọpẹlọpẹ awọn araalu ti wọn fura, ti wọn si tete ta awọn agbofinro lolobo loru ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọse yii, awọn ni wọn jẹ kọwọ ba awọn afurasi ọdaran mẹwaa kan ti wọn fẹsun kan pe wọn lọọ bẹ agba epo labẹlẹ lati ji epo wa, ọwọ si tẹ ọkọ mẹsan-an ti wọn fi n gbọn epo sa lọ.Agbegbe kan ti wọn n pe ni Arepo, nipinlẹ Ogun, niṣẹlẹ naa ti waye loru ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, si fẹẹrẹ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii; gẹgẹ bii Ajọ Akoroyinjọ ilẹ wa (NAN), ṣe wi.Rear Admiral Daji Ọladele tileeṣẹ ologun oju omi, to tun jẹ ọga  fun Ikọ Ọpureṣan AWATSE sọrọ lori iṣẹlẹ naa, o ni inu oun dun fun bawọn olugbe agbegbe ti wọn gbe paipu epo kọja labẹlẹ ṣe wa lojufo, ti wọn si tete kan sileeṣẹ awọn.Loju ẹsẹ lo lawọn ti lọọ ka awọn janduku naa mọ, nigba tawọn debẹ, awọn ba mọto tirela mẹfa ti wọn kọ akọle DANGOTE sara meji ninu wọn, pẹlu awọn ọkọ mẹta mi-in. Wọn n loodu epo bẹntiroolu sinu wọn lọwọ.O ni bawọn janduku naa ṣe ri awọn ṣọja ni wọn ya danu, ṣugbọn ọwọ papa tẹ mẹwaa ninu wọn, wọn ti ko wọn lọ si bareke ologun ni Marina.O tun sọ pe awọn olowo kan lo fori pamọ sibi kan ti wọn n ran awọn janduku wọnyi niṣẹ, ṣugbọn awọn maa ri i daju pe gbogbo wọn fimu kata ofin.Awọn oṣiṣẹ ileeṣẹ NNPC ti wa lagbegbe naa lati ṣatunṣe si paipu ti wọn bẹ ọhun, paapaa lati dena ewu ijamba ina to ṣee ṣe ko ṣẹlẹ.Mejọ Jẹnẹra Godwin Umelo naa ṣọrọ, o ni gbogbo mọto tawọn gba lọwọ awọn afurasi arufin wọnyi ni lawọn maa gbẹsẹ le, bẹẹ lo si rọ awọn eeyan lati maa ta awọn lolobo, ki awọn le ṣegun awọn ọbayejẹ ẹda to n ṣakoba fọrọ aje wa."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo endrika isehoan'ny tendry, ary iza avy no afaka manendry?","answer":" Tsy miankina amin’ny sitrapo sy ny safidy ny tendry, ka tsy azo lavina, fa tsy maintsy ekena sy zakaina satria avy amin’Andriamanitra ny tendry. Mety ho ratsy ny tendry raha mampietry voninahitra aman-kasina. Tsy afa-misaraka amin’ny vintana, anjara, lahatra ny tendry. Avy amin’ny solon-tenan’Andriamanitra toy ny Vahoaka. Misy koa nefa ny olona no manendry tena. Ny tendry dia mety ho tsara ary mety ho ratsy ihany koa"},{"question":"O que é a Nubank?","answer":"O Nubank é um banco brasileiro que oferece serviços digitais, incluindo cartões de crédito, contas e empréstimos."},{"question":"Bu paragrafın devamını yazın: Hugo Alvar Henrik Aalto Kuortane, Finlandiya'da dünyaya geldi. Babası Johan Henrik Aalto Fince konuşan bir haritacı, annesi Selly (Selma) Matilda (evlilik öncesi soyadı Hackstedt) İsveççe konuşan postane müdiresiydi. Aalto 5 yaşındayken ailesi Alajärvi'ye, sonra da Orta Finlandiya'daki Jyväskylä'ya taşındı. Burada Jyväskylä Lisesi'nde okudu ve temel eğitimini 1916'da tamamladı. Bu yıldan sonra Helsinki Teknoloji Üniversitesi'nde mimarlık okumaya başladı. Çalışmaları, uğruna savaştığı Fin İç Savaşı","answer":"yüzünden aksadı. Sonrasında eğitimine devam etti ve 1921'de mezun oldu."},{"question":" تخيل أنك تتحدث مع عميل غير راضٍ عن المنتج الذي اشتراه منك. أنشيء اجابة لتخفيف الموقف.","answer":"\\"أنا آسف لسماع أنك غير راضٍ عن المنتج الذي اشتريته. يهمنا جدًا رضا عملائنا، ونحن هنا لمساعدتك في حل هذه القضية. هل يمكنك مشاركتي المزيد من التفاصيل حول القضية التي واجهتها؟ سنعمل جاهدين لفهم مخاوفك والعمل معًا على إيجاد حلاً يرضيك.\\""},{"question":"Budapest no renivohitr'i Romania . Marina sa diso?","answer":"Diso. Budapest dia renivohitr'i Hongria . Bucarest no renivohitr'i Romania."},{"question":"Apibendrinti straipsnį:  Buvęs jūrų pėstininkas penktadienį buvo nuteistas kalėti iki gyvos galvos užsikabinti žmoną ir išmesti jos kūną į upę 2013 metų rugpjūtį. 26 metų Kalebas Kru iš Virdžinijos pripažino kaltu nužudęs savo žmoną, 31 metų Andrią Kru ir išmesdamas jos kūną į Occoquan upę. \\"The Washington Post\\" praneša, kad Andrei šeima iš Kolumbijos atvyko į penktadienio nuosprendį. Dešimtys žmonių užpildė teismo salės sėdynės, o kai kurie liudijo. Casey Lingan, vyriausiasis valstybės prokuroras, kalbėdamas apie Kalebo veiksmus, sakė, kad jis buvo \\"grynas blogis\\". Važiuok žemyn vaizdo. Buvęs jūrų pėstininkas, 26 metų Caleb Crew, penktadienį buvo nuteistas kalėti iki gyvos galvos už savo žmonos, 31 metų Andrea Crew, pasmaugimą ir jos kūno išmesimą į upę 2013 metų rugpjūtį, nes ji grasino paskambinti policijai. Vaikai: Pora turi du vaikus, ketverių metų Belą (aukščiai kairėje) ir vienerių metų Betaniją (aukščiai dešinėje). Blogis, kuris pasireiškė vyro, kuris sugebėjo pažvelgti savo žmonai į akis ir tada užgniaužti gyvybę iš jos kūno. Crew atskleidė siaubingas savo žmonos nužudymo detales detektyvams tik tris dienas po jos mirties; du dienas po to, kai jis pranešė apie jos dingimą, pasak NBC. Pareigūnai rugpjūčio 7 d. kreipėsi į teismą, kur Andrea atsisakė kaltinimų dėl smurto šeimoje Kalbo atžvilgiu, praneša \\"Post\\". Jie važiavo namo, kai abu susipyko, o Andrea grasino paskambinti policijai. Kaip praneša NBC, įrašytame prisipažinime Calebas sakė detektyvams, kad 'nenorėjo susidurti su dar vienu skambučiu į pagalbos tarnybą', todėl ištraukė iš žmonos rankos telefoną, patraukė ją į savo SUV galinę sėdynę ir pradėjo ją pasmauginti. \\"Pirmas dalykas, kurį pasakiau, buvo \\"pasisveikinimas\\", - sakė Kalebas detektyvams. Žinojau, kad kai nuėjau tuo keliu, nebegaliu grįžti atgal. Ji pasakė: \\"Prašau, Kalebai\\". Aš pradėjau verkti, bet negalėjau sustoti. ","answer":"26 metų Kalebas Kruvas penktadienį buvo nuteistas kalėti iki gyvos galvos už savo žmonos Andreos Kru nužudymą ir jos lavono išmetimą į upę. 2013 m. rugpjūčio mėn. Pora susipyko, o Andrea grasino, kad paskambins policijai, todėl jis ją pasmaugė. Jis sakė detektyvams, kad negalėjo sustoti, nes kai tik 'eidavo tuo keliu', jis 'negali grįžti atgal'"},{"question":"\\" ના છડિયા હથિયાર\\" લોકગીત લખો.","answer":"અલ્લાલા બેલી, અલ્લાલા બેલી, અલ્લાલા બેલીના છડિયા હથિયાર, અલ્લાલા બેલીના છડિયા હથિયાર, મરણે જો હકડીવારદેવોભા ચેતો,  ના છડિયા હથિયારમૂળુભા બંકડા, ના છડિયા હથિયારપેલો ધીંગાણો પીપરડી જો કિયોઉતે કીને ન ખાધી માર, કીને ન ખાધી મારદેવોભા  ચેતો,  કીને  ન ખાધી મારમૂળુભા બંકડા, ના છડિયા હથિયારહેબટ લટૂરજી મારું રે  ચડિયું બેલીઝલ્લી માછરડેજી ધાર, ઝલ્લી માછરડેજી ધારદેવોભા ચેતો, ઝલ્લી માછરડેજી ધારમૂળુભા બંકડા, ના છડિયા હથિયારજોટો સ્કૂલ હણે છાતીએ ચડાયો નારહેબટ લટૂર મુંજો ઘાદેવોજી ચેતો,  હેબટ લટૂર મુંજો ઘામૂળુભા બંકડા, ના છડિયા હથિયારડાબે તે પડખે ભૈરવ બોલે જુવાનોધીંગાણે મેં લોહેંજી ઘમસાણદેવોજી  ચેતો,     લોહેંજી ઘમસાણમૂળુભા બંકડા, ના છડિયા હથિયારઅલ્લાલા બેલી, અલ્લાલા બેલી"},{"question":"من هو أول نبي قام بسرد الشعر ؟\\t","answer":"سيدنا آدم"},{"question":"Àwọn ọ̀rẹ́ ló kọ́ mi láti fa ìfàkufà lásìkò tí ìṣòro dé, mo sì kábàámọ̀ - Toyin Abraham","answer":"Gbajumọ osere tiata ni ede Yoruba ati Oyinbo ni Toyin Abraham jẹ, to si jẹ ẹni ti o lokiki lawujọ, paapaa ni ẹka amuludun ilẹ wa.Toyin Abraham ti wa ba BBC Yoruba sọrọ lori igbe aye awọn osere tiata, isẹ tiata lapapọ, bo se nira lati tọ awọn ọdọ si oju ọna ati awọn ohun to ti la kọja sẹyin.Toyin Abraham, ti ọpọ ololufẹ rẹ n pe ni Mama Ire salaye pe oju oun ti ri to lagbo tiata, o si ni ọpọ iriri naa ko ni ko se fi ẹnu sọ.Bakan naa ni o tun salaye nipa awọn sinima to nira fun pupọ lati kopa nitori awọn ohun ti oju rẹ ri nibẹ.“Igba kii fi gbogbo ara dun fun awa osere, A n jẹ sanabọn iya”Nigba to n sọrọ lori oju ti ọpọ araalu fi maa n wo awọn osere tiata pe olowo ni wọn, Toyin Abraham ni eyi ko ri bẹẹ rara.Toyin ni nigba miran, kii se gbogbo igba ni owo maa n wa lọwọ awọn, koda, igba miran wa ti awọn kiini kọbọ lọwọ.O ni ọpọ awọn osere lo n jẹ sanabọ iya sugbọn nitori pe ọ̀pọ eeyan mọ awọn ni wọn se n fi oju olowo wo awọn.“A maa n mu ki aworan wa dun wo, lati jẹ oju ni gbese ni, tawọn eeyan yoo si ro pe asọ olowo nla la n wọ.”Eyi si lo ni o mu ki wọn maa fi oju ọlọrọ wo awọn.Bakan naa lo fi kun pe o ti pe ogun ọdun ti oun ti n sisẹ tiata amọ ko tii pe ọdun mẹfa ti oun n ri owo ninu isẹ naa.“Awọn ọrẹ ti mo ni kọ mi lati maa fa ifakufa lasiko isoro, mo ti se awọn nnkan kan ti mo kabamọ”Toyin Abraham tẹsiwaju pe oun ni awọn iriri kan ti ko se fẹnu sọ lagbo tiata, ti oun si ti se awọn nnkan ti kii se ẹjọ oun.“Awọn ọrẹ mi kọ mi lati maa fa orisirisi ifakufa nigba ti isoro de amọ kii se ẹjọ mi.Aimọye nnkan miran ti n ko le sọ nitori o le bi ibikubi jade.Inu mi ko dun si igbe aye mi lakoko naa nitori idile onigbagbọ ni mo ti wa.”Bakan naa lo fikun peo nira lati pe ọmọ to ba n fa ifakufa pada pẹlu imọran lasan amọ ki awọn obi maa gbadura, ki wọn si maa tọ awọn ọmọ naa sọna.O tun ni oun kabamọ pe oun ya tatoo si ara oun eyi ti oun fẹ nu danu nitori o tako ẹsin igbagbọ.“Sinima Elevator Baby, Ijakumọ ati Malaika lo gbo mi julọ, mo n sunkun laidakẹ ninu Malika nitori idaduro ọrọ ọmọ bibi”Gbajumọ osere tiata naa salaye pe awọn sinima mẹta kan lo mi oun lomi julọ lati igba ti oun ti n sisẹ tiata.Awọn sinima naa ni Elevator Baby, Ijakumọ ati Malaika.“Mo ni oyun osu mẹj nigba ti mo bawọn kopa ninu sinima Elevator Baby yii amọ wọn tọju mi.Sugbọn nigba ta n ya sinima Malaika ti ko ni pẹ jade yii, se ni mo n sọkun laidakẹ, ti wọn ba ti ni ka bẹrẹ ere sise naa.Idi ni pe oun to ti sẹlẹ si mi ri ni eyi to nii se pẹlu idaduro ọmọ bibi, ọpọ obinrin si lo n la iriri naa kọjha lai ri ohun ti wọn le se si.”“Omotola Jolaade Ekeinde ni Awokọse mi lagbo tiata, o ni ọkọ, o bimọ, igbeyawo rẹ ko si daru”Toyin Abraham salaye pe ni Naijiria , agba osere tiata lobinrin, Omotola Jolaade Ekeinde ni awokọse oun amọ ni agbaye, Angelina Jolie ni.Osere tiata naa ni oun fi Omotola, ti ọpọ eeyan mọ si “Omo Sexy” se awokọse, ti oun kii si tiju lati sọ fun ọpọ eeyan.“Omotola ni idile alayọ, o ni ọkọ, o tun bimọ, bi emi naa se fẹ niyi nitori isẹ kekere kọ ni ki eeyan jẹ gbajumọ osere tiata, ko si tọju awn ọmọ lai yawọ."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo tetika mahomby mba hijanonana ho mazoto rehefa miatrika asa sarotra?","answer":"Maro ny paikady mahomby mampazoto rehefa miatrika asa, anisan' izany ny fanaparitahana ny asa ho dingana kely kokoa, azo fehezina, fametrahana tanjona mazava, ary fitadiavana hevitra na tanjona manokana amin'ny asa."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe horohoron-tany?","answer":" Ny horohoron-tany dia horohoron-tany vokatry ny fihetsehana manaraka ny lesoka ao amin'ny voron-tany."},{"question":"إنشيء عنوان للمقال التالي:حضارة الأولمك هي أول أول حضارة كبرى في غواتيمالا والمكسيك بعد التطور التدريجي في منطقة سوكونوسكو والأراضي المنخفضة في غواتيمالا الحديثة.[1][2][3][4] كانوا يعيشون في المنخفضات الاستوائية في جنوب ووسط المكسيك، في ولايات فيراكروز وتاباسكو الحديثتين. ويعتقد أن حضارة الأولمك تستمد جزئيا من ثقافات موكايا وميكسي زوكي المجاورتين.","answer":"حضارة الأولمك."},{"question":"NaOH kullanıldığında sıvı sabun elde edilir mi?","answer":"Sabun yapımı sırasında iki farklı kostik kullanılır. Kalıp (katı) sabun için kullanılan kostik sodyum hidroksittir. Sıvı sabun yapmak için ise potasyum hidroksit kullanılması gerekir."},{"question":"Sino ang nag-imbento ng pagkain Bicol Express?","answer":"Ang Bicol Express ay pormal na tinawag ng taga-Laguna na si Cely Kalaw, bilang resulta ng kanyang karanasan sa kompetisyon sa pagluluto noong 1970s sa Malate, Manila. Nilikha niya ang bagong ulam na ito bilang tugon sa mataas na interes ng kanyang mga customer para sa isang maanghang at mainit na pagkaing taro."},{"question":"வினா : திருக்குறள் —- கரத்தில் தொடங்கி —- கரத்தில் முடிகிறது?","answer":"விடை: அ, ன "},{"question":"కింది పదాలను ఉపయోగించి సొంతవాక్యాలు రాయండి.అ) పొద్దస్తమానంఆ) చమత్కారంఇ) సాన్నిధ్యంఈ) కష్టఫలంఉ) కడుపులు మాడ్చుకొనుఊ) అడుగున పడిపోవు","answer":"అ) పొద్దస్తమానం : పొద్దస్తమానం పనిచేస్తే, ‘రాత్రి బాగా నిద్ర పడుతుంది.ఆ) చమత్కారం : చమత్కారంగా మాట్లాడే వారంటే నాకిష్టం.ఇ) సాన్నిధ్యం : భక్తులు దేవుని సాన్నిధ్యంలో ఆనందపడతారు.ఈ) కష్టఫలం ” : ఎవరి కష్టఫలం వారికి మధురంగా ఉంటుంది.ఉ) కడుపులు మాడ్చుకొను : కొంతమంది కడుపులు మాడ్చుకొని పిల్లలను చదివిస్తారు.ఊ) అడుగున పడిపోవు : జ్ఞానం విషయంలో అడుగున పడిపోవడం పనికిరాదు."},{"question":"hadhimo","answer":" wexey lamid tahay  qado"},{"question":"\\"Nahita poketra very feno vola tao amin'ny toeram-pivarotana i Sarah.\\"Fanontaniana: Inona no hitan’i Saraha, ary taiza no nahitany izany?","answer":"Nahita poketra very feno vola tao amin'ny toeram-pivarotana i Sarah"},{"question":"பள்ளிக்கூடத்தில் பயிற்றுவிப்பதை தெரேசா விரும்பினாலும் கல்கத்தாவில் அவரைச் சூழ்ந்துள்ள பகுதிகளின் வறுமை நிலை அவரை அதிகமாய் கலங்கச் செய்தது. 1943-ன் பஞ்சம்","answer":"துயரத்தையும் சாவையும் அந்நகரத்துக்குக் கொணர்ந்தது என்றால் 1946-ன் இந்து/முஸ்லிம் வன்முறை அந்நகரத்தை நம்பிக்கையின்மையிலும் அச்சத்திலும் ஆழ்த்தியது."},{"question":"வினா: முதற் சங்கம் அமைவிடம் எது?","answer":"விடை: தென் மதுரை "},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ੴ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ॥ਰਾਗੁ ਗਉੜੀ ਵਾਰ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀਉ ਕੇ ੭ ॥ਬਾਰ ਬਾਰ ਹਰਿ ਕੇ ਗੁਨ ਗਾਵਉ ॥ਗੁਰ ਗਮਿ ਭੇਦੁ ਸੁ ਹਰਿ ਕਾ ਪਾਵਉ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਆਦਿਤ ਕਰੈ ਭਗਤਿ ਆਰੰਭ ॥ਕਾਇਆ ਮੰਦਰ ਮਨਸਾ ਥੰਭ ॥ਅਹਿਨਿਸਿ ਅਖੰਡ ਸੁਰਹੀ ਜਾਇ ॥ਤਉ ਅਨਹਦ ਬੇਣੁ ਸਹਜ ਮਹਿ ਬਾਇ ॥੧॥ਸੋਮਵਾਰਿ ਸਸਿ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਝਰੈ ॥ਚਾਖਤ ਬੇਗਿ ਸਗਲ ਬਿਖ ਹਰੈ ॥ਬਾਣੀ ਰੋਕਿਆ ਰਹੈ ਦੁਆਰ ॥ਤਉ ਮਨੁ ਮਤਵਾਰੋ ਪੀਵਨਹਾਰ ॥੨॥ਮੰਗਲਵਾਰੇ ਲੇ ਮਾਹੀਤਿ ॥ਪੰਚ ਚੋਰ ਕੀ ਜਾਣੈ ਰੀਤਿ ॥ਘਰ ਛੋਡੇਂ ਬਾਹਰਿ ਜਿਨਿ ਜਾਇ ॥ਨਾਤਰੁ ਖਰਾ ਰਿਸੈ ਹੈ ਰਾਇ ॥੩॥ਬੁਧਵਾਰਿ ਬੁਧਿ ਕਰੈ ਪ੍ਰਗਾਸ ॥ਹਿਰਦੈ ਕਮਲ ਮਹਿ ਹਰਿ ਕਾ ਬਾਸ ॥ਗੁਰ ਮਿਲਿ ਦੋਊ ਏਕ ਸਮ ਧਰੈ ॥ਉਰਧ ਪੰਕ ਲੈ ਸੂਧਾ ਕਰੈ ॥੪॥ਬ੍ਰਿਹਸਪਤਿ ਬਿਖਿਆ ਦੇਇ ਬਹਾਇ ॥ਤੀਨਿ ਦੇਵ ਏਕ ਸੰਗਿ ਲਾਇ ॥ਤੀਨਿ ਨਦੀ ਤਹ ਤ੍ਰਿਕੁਟੀ ਮਾਹਿ ॥ਅਹਿਨਿਸਿ ਕਸਮਲ ਧੋਵਹਿ ਨਾਹਿ ॥੫॥ਸੁਕ੍ਰਿਤੁ ਸਹਾਰੈ ਸੁ ਇਹ ਬ੍ਰਤਿ ਚੜੈ ॥ਅਨਦਿਨ ਆਪਿ ਆਪ ਸਿਉ ਲੜੈ ॥ਸੁਰਖੀ ਪਾਂਚਉ ਰਾਖੈ ਸਬੈ ॥ਤਉ ਦੂਜੀ ਦ੍ਰਿਸਟਿ ਨ ਪੈਸੈ ਕਬੈ ॥੬॥ਥਾਵਰ ਥਿਰੁ ਕਰਿ ਰਾਖੈ ਸੋਇ ॥ ਜੋਤਿ ਦੀ ਵਟੀ ਘਟ ਮਹਿ ਜੋਇ ॥ਬਾਹਰਿ ਭੀਤਰਿ ਭਇਆ ਪ੍ਰਗਾਸੁ ॥ਤਬ ਹੂਆ ਸਗਲ ਕਰਮ ਕਾ ਨਾਸੁ ॥੭॥ਜਬ ਲਗੁ ਘਟ ਮਹਿ ਦੂਜੀ ਆਨ ॥ਤਉ ਲਉ ਮਹਲਿ ਨ ਲਾਭੈ ਜਾਨ ॥ਰਮਤ ਰਾਮ ਸਿਉ ਲਾਗੋ ਰੰਗੁ ॥ਕਹਿ ਕਬੀਰ ਤਬ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਅੰਗ ॥੮॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 344 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਭਗਤ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਮੈਂ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਉਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਅੱਪੜ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ ਉਹ ਭੇਤ ਲੱਭ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਸਕੀਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਣ ਦਾ ਸਹੀ ਤਰੀਕਾ ਹੈ) ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(‘ਬਾਰ ਬਾਰ ਹਰਿ ਕੇ ਗੁਨ’ ਗਾ ਕੇ, ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਭਗਤੀ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਰੀਰ-ਘਰ ਨੂੰ ਥੰਮ੍ਹੀ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਦੇਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਫੁਰਨਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਹਾਰਾ ਦੇਂਦੀ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਗਿਆਨ-ਇੰਦ੍ਰੇ ਅਤੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਫੁਰਨੇ ਭਟਕਣੋਂ ਹਟ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ) ਭਗਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਸੁਗੰਧਤ ਹੋਈ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸੁਰਤ ਦਿਨ ਰਾਤ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਜੁੜੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਤਦੋਂ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ (ਮਾਨੋ) ਇੱਕ-ਰਸ ਬੰਸਰੀ ਵੱਜਦੀ ਹੈ ।੧।(‘ਬਾਰ ਬਾਰ ਹਰਿ ਕੇ ਗੁਨ’ ਗਾਵਣ ਨਾਲ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ) ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਠੰਢ ਦਾ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਵਰ੍ਹਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਇਹ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ) ਚੱਖਣ ਨਾਲ ਮਨ ਤੁਰਤ ਸਾਰੇ ਵਿਕਾਰ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ,ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤ ਨਾਲ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ) ਰੋਕਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਮਨ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈਅਤੇ ਮਸਤ ਹੋਇਆ ਮਨ ਉਸ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਨੂੰ ਪੀਂਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।(‘ਬਾਰ ਬਾਰ ਹਰਿ ਕੇ ਗੁਨ’ ਗਾ ਕੇ) ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਦੁਆਲੇ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦਾ, ਮਾਨੋ, ਕਿਲ੍ਹਾ ਬਣਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਕਾਮਾਦਿਕ ਪੰਜ ਚੋਰਾਂ ਦਾ (ਹੱਲਾ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ) ਢੰਗ ਸਮਝ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਾਰ ਹੋਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇਂਦਾ)ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਤੂੰ ਭੀ (ਐਸੇ) ਕਿਲੇ੍ਹ ਨੂੰ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਬਾਹਰ ਨਾਹ ਜਾਈਂ (ਭਾਵ, ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਬਾਹਰ ਭਟਕਣ ਨ ਦੇਈਂ),ਨਹੀਂ ਤਾਂ ਇਹ ਮਨ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਪੈ ਕੇ) ਬੜਾ ਦੁਖੀ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ ।੩।(‘ਬਾਰ ਬਾਰ ਹਰਿ ਕੇ ਗੁਨ’ ਗਾ ਕੇ, ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਪਣੀ) ਸੂਝ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਚਾਨਣ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਹਿਰਦੇ-ਕਮਲ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਿਵਾਸ ਬਣਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ; ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਆਤਮਾ ਤੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਬਣਾ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਲ) ਪਰਤੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਸ ਵਿਚ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁਖ ਕਰ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।(‘ਬਾਰ ਬਾਰ ਹਰਿ ਕੇ ਗੁਨ’ ਗਾ ਕੇ, ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਮਾਇਆ (ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ) ਨੂੰ (ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਵਾਹ ਵਿਚ) ਰੋੜ੍ਹ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਤਿੰਨੇ ਹੀ (ਬਲੀ) ਗੁਣਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਦੀ ਯਾਦ) ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਕਰ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਜੋ ਲੋਕ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ) ਖਿੱਝ ਵਿਚ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀਆਂ ਤ੍ਰਿ-ਗੁਣੀ ਨਦੀਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ (ਗੋਤੇ ਖਾਂਦੇ) ਹਨ, ਦਿਨ ਰਾਤ ਮੰਦ-ਕਰਮ (ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਤੋਂ ਵਾਂਜੇ ਰਹਿਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਧੋਂਦੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਨ ।੫।(‘ਬਾਰ ਬਾਰ ਹਰਿ ਕੇ ਗੁਨ’ ਗਾ ਕੇ, ਮਨੁੱਖ ਇਸ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ) ਨੇਕ ਕਮਾਈ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਦਾ) ਸਹਾਰਾ ਬਣਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਔਖੀ ਘਾਟੀ ਉੱਤੇ ਚੜ੍ਹਦਾ ਹੈਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨਾਲ ਲੜਾਈ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਮੁੜ ਮੁੜ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ ਰੋਕਦਾ ਹੈ)ਪੰਜਾਂ ਹੀ ਗਿਆਨ-ਇੰਦ੍ਰਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਸ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ,  ਤਦੋਂ (ਕਿਸੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਭੀ) ਕਦੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਮੇਰ-ਤੇਰ ਦੀ ਨਿਗਾਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦੀ ।੬।ਰੱਬੀ ਨੂਰ ਦੀ ਜੋ ਸੁਹਣੀ ਜਿਹੀ ਨਿੱਕੀ ਜਿਹੀ ਜੋਤ ਹਰੇਕ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ (‘ਬਾਰ ਬਾਰ ਹਰਿ ਕੇ ਗੁਨ’ ਗਾ ਕੇ, ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਉਸ ਜੋਤ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਸਾਂਭ ਕੇ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਉਸ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦੇ) ਅੰਦਰ-ਬਾਹਰ ਜੋਤ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਤੇ ਸਾਰੀ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਵਿਚ ਭੀ ਇਕੋ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਜੋਤ ਦਿੱਸਦੀ ਹੈ) ।ਇਸ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਅੱਪੜ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ (ਦੇ ਸੰਸਕਾਰਾਂ) ਦਾ ਨਾਸ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੭।(ਪਰ) ਜਦੋਂ ਤਕ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਦੁਨੀਆਵੀ ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਆਦਿਕ ਦੀ ਵਾਸ਼ਨਾ ਹੈ, ਤਦ ਤਕ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ ਕਬੀਰ ਆਖਦਾ ਹੈ—ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਤਦੋਂ ਸਰੀਰ ਪਵਿੱਤਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੮।੧।\\""},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన గేయానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు భావం రాయండి:తగటు బంగరు చీరెకట్టికురుల పువ్వుల సరులు జుట్టీనుదుట కుంకుమ బొట్టు పెట్టిసొంపు పెంపారన్,","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :తగటు = జరీ, జలతారుబంగరు = బంగారు రంగు కలచీరె కట్టి = చీరను కట్టుకొనికురుల = తలవెంట్రుకలకుపువ్వుల సరులు = పూలమాలలుచుట్టి = చుట్టుకొనినుదుట = నుదుటి మీదకుంకుమబొట్టు – కుంకుమబొట్టుపెట్టి = పెట్టుకొనిసొంపు = అందంపెంపు + ఆరన్ = ఇనుమడించగాభావం :కన్యక జరీ అంచు గల బంగారు రంగు గల చీర కట్టుకున్నది. తలలో పూల మాలలు చుట్టుకున్నది. నుదుటి మీద కుంకుమబొట్టు పెట్టుకున్నది. ఈ అలంకారాలతో ఆమె అందం ద్విగుణీకృతం అయింది."},{"question":"கேள்வி: தமிழ்நாட்டில் பாயும் மிக நீண்ட ஆறு எது?","answer":"பதில் : காவிரிகாவிரி கர்நாடக மாநிலத்திலுள்ள மேற்கு தொடர்ச்சி மலையில் உள்ள குடகு மாவட்டத்தைச் சேர்ந்த தலைக்காவேரி என்ற இடத்தில் 4400 அடி உயரத்தில் தோன்றுகிறது. இதன் நீளம் 800 கிமீ. கருநாடகத்தில் குடகு, ஆசன், மைசூர், மாண்டியா, பெங்களூர் ஊரகம், சாமராசநகர் மாவட்டங்கள் வழியாவும் தமிழ்நாட்டில் தருமபுரி, சேலம், ஈரோடு, நாமக்கல், கரூர், திருச்சி, தஞ்சாவூர், மயிலாடுதுறை மாவட்டங்கள் வழியாகச் சென்று பூம்புகார் என்னும் இடத்தில் வங்காள விரிகுடாக் கடலில் கலக்கிறது.காவிரி ஆறு தான் செல்லுமிடமெல்லாம் சோலைகளை விரித்துச் செல்லுவதால் காவிரி எனப்பெயர் பெற்றது.தமிழ் இலக்கியங்களில் பொன்னி ஆறு என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. இந்தியாவின் பிற பகுதிகள் போலவே தமிழகத்திலும் ஆறுகளின் பெயர்கள் பெண்பால் பெயர்களாக இருக்கின்றன. அவை காரணமாகவே 'பொன்னி' என்ற பெயர் காவிரிக்கு வந்திருக்கக்கூடும் எனலாம். அந்த ஆறு சோழ நாட்டை செழிக்கச் செய்கிறது.. பொன்படு நெடுவரையில் (குடகு மலை) தோன்றிப் பாய்வதாலும் பொன்னி என்னும் பெயர் வந்தது.துணை ஆறுகள்கபினி, ஏமாவதி, ஆரங்கி , லட்மண தீர்த்தம் , ஆர்க்காவதி, சிம்சா, சொர்ணவதி ஆகியவை கருநாடகப் பகுதியில் பாயும் துணை ஆறுகள். பவானி, அமராவதி, நொய்யல், திருமணிமுத்தாறு ஆகியன தமிழகப் பகுதியில் பாயும் துணை ஆறுகள் ஆகும்.இவற்றில் சொர்ணவதி என்னும் ஆற்றைச் சிலப்பதிகாரம் பொன்னி என்னும் தூய தமிழ்ப்பெயரால் குறிப்பிடுகிறது. 'பொன்படு நெடுவரை'ப் பகுதியில் இது தோன்றுவதால் இதற்குப் பொன்னி என்று பெயர். சங்ககாலப் புலவர் ஆவூர் மூலங்கிழார் பாடல் (புறநானூறு 166) இதனைத் தெளிவுபடுத்துகிறது."},{"question":"Allocation-தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்","answer":"ஒதுக்கீடு"},{"question":"Anong ang nanalo ng Game of the Year noong 2022?","answer":"Napanalunan ng video game na Elden Ring ng FromSoftware ang titulong Game of the Year sa The Game Awards 2022. Maliban dito, napanalunan din nito ang Best Game Direction at Best Role Playing Game. Ang mga larong nominado para sa Game of the Year ay ang A Plague Tale: Requiem, God of War Ragnarok, Horizon Forbidden West, Stray, at Xenoblade Chronicles 3."},{"question":"IMidlalo Yama Olympic yaba ngamuphi unyaka eHelsinki?","answer":"Ngo1952."},{"question":"ਆਦਮੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਭਰਵੱਟੇ ਉੱਤੇ ਚੁੱਕੇ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਹ ਹੈਰਾਨ ਰਹਿ ਗਿਆ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸਨੂੰ ਨਿਰਾਸ਼ਾ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਹੋਈ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਹ ਹੈਰਾਨ ਰਹਿ ਗਿਆ।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"awak yang payah membelah ruyung, orang lain yang beroleh sagunya\\"?","answer":"Orang lain yang bersusah payah, orang lain pula yang mendapat faedahnya. "},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?කසල ","answer":"නිකසල"},{"question":"Hint: మీనకోట శ్రీకాకుళం జిల్లా, సీతంపేట మండలంలోని గ్రామం. ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన సీతంపేట నుండి 36 కి. మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన రాజాం నుండి 35 కి. మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 15 ఇళ్లతో, 55 జనాభాతో 17 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 26, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 29. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 0 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 47. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 580017[1].పిన్ కోడ్: 532460.విద్యా సౌకర్యాలుబాలబడి పాలకొండలోను, ప్రాథమిక పాఠశాల చినపల్లంకి లోను, ప్రాథమికోన్నత పాఠశాల సామరెల్లిలోను, మాధ్యమిక పాఠశాల దోనుబాయిలోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప జూనియర్ కళాశాల, ప్రభుత్వ ఆర్ట్స్ / సైన్స్ డిగ్రీ కళాశాల సీతంపేటలోను, ఇంజనీరింగ్ కళాశాల రాజాంలోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వైద్య కళాశాల శ్రీకాకుళంలోను, మేనేజిమెంటు కళాశాల, పాలీటెక్నిక్‌లు రాజాంలోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వృత్తి విద్యా శిక్షణ పాఠశాల, అనియత విద్యా కేంద్రం సీతంపేటలోను, దివ్యాంగుల ప్రత్యేక పాఠశాల రాజాం లోనూ ఉన్నాయి.వైద్య సౌకర్యంప్రభుత్వ వైద్య సౌకర్యంఒక సంచార వైద్య శాలలో డాక్టర్లు లేరు. ముగ్గురు పారామెడికల్ సిబ్బంది ఉన్నారు. ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం, ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య ఉప కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. పశు వైద్యశాల గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉంది. సమీప సామాజిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం, మాతా శిశు సంరక్షణ కేంద్రం, టి. బి వైద్యశాల గ్రామం నుండి 10 కి.మీ. కంటే ఎక్కువ దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. అలోపతి ఆసుపత్రి, ప్రత్యామ్నాయ ఔషధ ఆసుపత్రి, డిస్పెన్సరీ, కుటుంబ సంక్షేమ కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 10 కి.మీ. కంటే ఎక్కువ దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి.ప్రైవేటు వైద్య సౌకర్యంగ్రామంలోఒక ప్రైవేటు వైద్య సౌకర్యం ఉంది. డిగ్రీ లేని డాక్టరు ఒకరు ఉన్నారు.తాగు నీరుబావుల నీరు  గ్రామంలో అందుబాటులో ఉంది. తాగునీటి కోసం చేతిపంపులు, బోరుబావులు, కాలువలు, చెరువులు వంటి సౌకర్యాలేమీ లేవు.పారిశుధ్యంగ్రామంలో మురుగునీటి పారుదల వ్యవస్థ లేదు. మురుగునీటిని నేరుగా జలవనరుల్లోకి వదులుతున్నారు. గ్రామంలో సంపూర్ణ పారిశుధ్య పథకం అమలవుతోంది. సామాజిక మరుగుదొడ్డి సౌకర్యం లేదు. ఇంటింటికీ తిరిగి వ్యర్థాలను సేకరించే వ్యవస్థ లేదు. సామాజిక బయోగ్యాస్ ఉత్పాదక వ్యవస్థ లేదు. చెత్తను వీధుల పక్కనే పారబోస్తారు.సమాచార, రవాణా సౌకర్యాలుపోస్టాఫీసు సౌకర్యం, సబ్ పోస్టాఫీసు సౌకర్యం, పోస్ట్ అండ్ టెలిగ్రాఫ్ ఆఫీసు గ్రామం నుండి 10...","answer":"None"},{"question":"Maliki tun lọọ jale lẹyin to tẹwọn de ni Ṣaki","answer":"Ogbologboo afurasi ọdaran kan, Kazeem Maliki, ẹni ọdun mẹtadinlogoji lọwọ ọlọpaa ti tẹ, to si ti n jẹjọ nile-ẹjọ Majisreeti kin-in-in to wa laduugbo Idi Araba, niluu Ṣaki, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, latari ẹsun ole jija ti wọn fi kan an, bẹẹ o ṣẹṣẹ de lati ẹwọn lori ẹsun ole jija ni.Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ to kọja yii, ni igbẹjọ bẹrẹ ni kootu ọhun, ibẹ lọkunrin naa ti jẹwọ pe ọmọ bibi ilu Agọ-Arẹ loun, iṣẹ awakọ loun si n ṣe.Nigba ti Agbefọba, Inspẹkitọ AbdulMumuni Jimba, n ka ẹsun mẹta ti wọn fi kan an si i leti, o ṣalaye pe ni deede aago mẹfa aabọ aṣaalẹ ogunjọ, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun yii, ni wọn ka afurasi yii mọ yara oniyara to wa ni agboole Baba Oge, laduugbo Iya, niluu Ṣaki, nibi to ti n ji aṣọ alaṣọ ko pẹlu awọn nnkan ẹṣọ oriṣiiriṣii.Aropọ owo ẹru ti wọn ka mọ ọn lọwọ jẹ ẹgbẹrun lọna ojilelaaadọrin naira. Matthew Ojo ni wọn lo ni awọn dukia ọhun. Ẹsun keji ati ikẹta ni wiwọ ile onile lọna aitọ ati ole jija.Maliki ko tiẹ fakoko ṣofo nigba ti won bi i boya o jẹbi tabi ko jẹbi, loju ẹsẹ lo ti gba pe oun jẹbi ẹsun mẹtẹẹta.Adajọ I. O. Uthman waa bi i leere boya igba kan wa to ti wa sile-ẹjọ naa ri fun ẹsun iwa ọdaran, tori oju rẹ jọ ẹni toun mọ. Asiko yii ni agbefọba salaye pe olujẹjọ ti maa n paara awọn ile-ẹjọ agbegbe ọhun, latori ẹsun kan si omi-in. O ni ẹẹkẹta ree ti afurasi ọdaran naa yoo gba idajọ lori ẹsun ole jija yii kan naa.O tẹ siwaju pe olujẹjọ yii wa lara awọn ti Adajọ agba ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Munta Abimbọla, foju aanu wo lọdun 2019, lakooko ti wọn ṣabẹwo sawọn ọgba ẹwọn kaakiri ipinlẹ Ọyọ. Inspẹkitọ Jimba ran adajọ leti pe lọdun 2020 kan naa ta a wa ninu rẹ yii, afurasi ọdaran naa ti gba idajọ ẹwọn oṣu mẹta lori ẹsun ole jija, abọde ẹwọn ọhun lo tun lọọ fọle onile tọwọ tun fi ba a yii.Jimba waa ni kile-ẹjọ fun oun laaye lati le ṣa awọn ẹsun ọdaran naa papọ, kile-ẹjọ le mọ ijiya to tọ lati fun un, tori iwa ọkunrin yii ti fihan pe o ti jingiri ninu ole jija.Ẹbẹ agbefọba yii lo mu ki adajọ paṣẹ pe ki wọn ṣi fi afurasi naa sahaamọ awọn ọlọpaa titi ọjọ kẹẹẹdọgbọn, oṣu kọkanla yii, ti igbẹjọ yoo maa tẹ siwaju."},{"question":"No anime Boku no Hero Academia, quem é Eijiro Kirishima (Red Riot)?","answer":"Eijiro Kirishima é um estudante da U.A. High School e membro da turma 1-A. Seu Quirk, \\"Hardening,\\" permite que ele endureça seu corpo, tornando-se praticamente invulnerável. Kirishima é conhecido por sua personalidade extrovertida, sua aparência robusta e sua determinação em proteger os outros. Ele admira Katsuki Bakugo e é um dos amigos próximos de Izuku Midoriya."},{"question":"ജപ്പാന്റെ കറൻസി എന്താണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: യെൻ"},{"question":"السؤال: كيف تتأثر قوة الجاذبية بين الأجسان مع المسافة ؟","answer":"الإجابة: كلما زادت المسافة بين جسمين تقل قوة الجاذبية بينهما"},{"question":"A = {2, 4, 6, 8, 10}, B = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6} అయిన n(B – A) ని కనుగొనుము.","answer":"B – A = {1, 3, 5}n(B – A) = 3"},{"question":"Pemain badminton manakah antara berikut yang bukan dalam pasukan kebangsaan ketika memenangi Piala Thomas? Pilih jawapan yang betul dari pilihan berikut. A. Rashid Sidek B. Jalani Sidek C. Razik Sidek D. Misbun Sidek","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah D. Misbun Sidek. Misbun, yang merupakan abang sulung dalam lima adik beradik jaguh badminton negara sebaliknya bersama pasukan kebangsaan yang mengalahkan Indonesia ketika Malaysia menang Piala Thomas pada 1988. Beliau seterusnya bersara sebagai pemain pada 1989."},{"question":"Zein da Euskal Herriko hiriburua?A) BilbaoB) DonostiaC) Gasteiz","answer":"C) Gasteiz"},{"question":"ایس ایم ظفر کون ہے","answer":"سید محمد ظفر (6 دسمبر 1930ء - 19 اکتوبر 2023ء)، پاکستان کے انسانی حقوق کے کارکنوں میں سے ایک تھے وہ ایک مشہور وکیل (سینئر ایڈووکیٹ سپریم کورٹ) اور ایک سیاست دان اور سینیٹ آف پاکستان کے رکن تھے۔ وہ کچھ عرصہ تک پاکستان مسلم لیگ (ق) سے وابستہ رہے۔[3]ابتدائی زندگی اور تعلیمان کا مکمل نام سید محمد ظفر تھا اور 6 دسمبر 1930ء کو رنگون، برما میں پیدا ہوئے۔ ابتدائی تعلیم رنگون میں حاصل کی۔[4] وہاں کے حالات کشیدہ ہوئے تو پنجاب آ گئے، شکر گڑھ کے نزدیک چک قاضیاں ان کا آبائی علاقہ تھا، شکر گڑھ سے 1945ء میں میٹرک کیا ، بعد ازاں انٹر اور قانون کی تعلیم لاہور سے حاصل کی، گورنمنٹ کالج لاہور میں قیام پاکستان سے دو سال پہلے داخلہ لیا اور قیام کے دو سال بعد گریجویشن مکمل کی اور 2002ء میں اولڈ رارین ایسوسی ایشن کے صدر بھی رہے۔سیاسی زندگی1950ء میں وکالت شروع کی۔ 1965ء کی پاک بھارت جنگ کے دوران پاکستان کے وزیر قانون تھے۔ 19؍ستمبر 1965ء کو اقوامِ متحدہ کی سیکورٹی کونسل میں اُنہوں نے جنگ بندی کی قرارداد کو مسئلہ کشمیر کے حل سے مشروط کرایا۔ انہوں نے اقوامِ متحدہ کے ہیومن رائٹس کمیشن سے بھی خطاب کیا۔[5]وہ 35 برس کی عمر میں ایوب کابینہ میں قانون و پارلیمانی امور کے مرکزی وزیر بنے۔ کئی اہم ملکی اور بین الاقوامی مقدموں میں کامیابی حاصل کی۔ 2003ء سے 2012ء تک سینٹ کے ممبر رہے۔ 2004ء سے 2012ء تک ہمدرد یونیورسٹی کے چانسلر کی ذمہ داریاں بھی ادا کیں۔ [6]اعزازات2011ء میں انہیں صدارتی ایوارڈ نشان امتیاز سے نوازا گیا۔[7]وفاتایس ایم ظفر 19 اکتوبر 2023ء کو 92 سال کی عمر میں انتقال کر گئے۔[8]تصانیفمیرے مشہور مقدمےعدالت میں سیاستعوام، پارلیمنٹ اور اسلام’[9]سینیٹر ایس ایم ظفرکی کہانیڈکٹیٹر کون؟تذکرے اور جائزےپاکستان بنام کرپشنعوام کی عدالت میںغیب سے مضامین“Be a Competent Lawyer” ‘ “Through the Crisis (1971)”‘ “Haj- AJourney in Obedience” ‘ “Understanding Statues(1997)” “Dialouge on the political chess Board”"},{"question":"Dokończ następujący akapit: Po wybuchu II wojny światowej brał udział w kampanii wrześniowej, zmobilizowany wcześniej w 10 Dywizjonie Taborów w Radymnie. Po agresji ZSRR na Polskę z 17 września 1939 został aresztowany przez Sowietów i wywieziony do ZSRR. Na mocy układu Sikorski-Majski z 30 lipca 1941 odzyskał wolność, po czym wstąpił do formowanej Armii Polskiej w ZSRR gen. Władysława Andersa. Wraz z 2 Korpusem Polskim przebył szlak przez Bliski Wschód (Iran, Irak, Palestyna, Egipt) do Włoch. Brał udział w kampanii włoskiej. W stopniu kaprala uczestniczył w walkach w bitwie o Monte Cassino, bitwie o Ankonę i","answer":"bitwie o Bolonię, Piedimonte. Służył w szeregach 6 Pułku Pancernego „Dzieci Lwowskich” w składzie 2 Brygady Pancernej. W chwili zakończenia wojny 8/9 maja 1945 przebywał we Włoszech pod Bolonią. Dosłużył stopnia sierżanta rezerwy. Po wojnie do 1947 przebywał w Wielkiej Brytanii, po czym w tym samym roku powrócił do Polski."},{"question":"Q:Yintoni umahluko phakathi kwekatala nentlanzi? A: Awukwazi ukuloba ithoni! n Ucinga ukuba yintoni eyona nto ithethwa ngulo mqhulo ingasentla?","answer":"Inkcazo:Iintlanzi zeTuna? Akunjalo, yiba yintlanzi. Uyabona, ukuze isiginkci sivakale kakuhle, kufuneka usilungelelanise. Intlanzi ayinakulungiswa... kodwa kukho intlanzi ebizwa ngokuba yi-tuna. Le ngxubakaxaka iyahlekisa kuba u-tuna  uvakala njengo-tuna. Nantsi ividiyo yentlanzi etyiwayo enengoma emnandi ekupheleni kwayo: IVIDIYO"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bayar nyawa\\"? Berilah contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud mengorbankan diri. Mak Melur sanggup bayar nyawa untuk mendapatkan hak penjagaan anak lelakinya daripada bekas suaminya."},{"question":" Sheeg Buurta Somaliya Ugu Dheer Magaalada Iyo Gobolka Ey Ku Taalo?","answer":"Waxay Ku Tallaa Magaalada Ceerigaabo Ee Gobalka Sanaag"},{"question":"แปลประโยคหรือย่อหน้าต่อไปนี้จากภาษาอังกฤษเป็นภาษาไทย:Azul Tequila has slightly lower ratings but you can eat al fresco.","answer":"ร้าน อาซุล เตกิลล่ามีอันดับต่ำหน่อย แตคุณสามารถกิน อัล เฟรซโก้ได้"},{"question":"\\"ටජ් මහලක් තනවන්න නෑ මට\\" ගීතයේ ඉතිරි පද සම්පූර්ණ කරන්න.","answer":"ටජ් මහලක් තනවන්න නෑ මටඔබෙ සෙනෙහසට හිමීහිස් අහසේ ගෑවෙන්න තරමටගී සෑයක් බඳිමීසිහිකර ඔබ ගැන බවුන් වඩයි මනඅන්ධය දෙනයන බිහිරිය දෙසවනටජ් මහලක්...මගේ උදානය අමිල නිධානයඔබමය ජීවය මිහිරිය දෙසවනටජ් මහලක්...තිමිර එළිය කෙරු මගෙ ලොව දිනිසුරුතරුපති සහකරු ඔබය මියෙන තුරුටජ් මහලක්...එච්. ආර්. ජෝතිපාලකරුණාරත්න අබේසේකරසරත් දසනායක"},{"question":"Cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Cuándo nació el director de Harry Potter (2007)?. ","answer":"El tema principal de esta pregunta es identificar la fecha de nacimiento del director de la película Harry Potter. "},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här - Higashi tävlade i Skid-VM 1989 i Lahtis i Finland. Han blev nummer 20 i normalbacken och nummer 55 i stora backen. Under Skid-VM 1991 i Val di Fiemme i Italien startade han i den individuella tävlingen i stora backen och blev nummer 10. Han tävlade också i VM i Val di Fiemme 2003","answer":"då han blev nummer 38 i den individuella tävlingen i stora backen. I Lagtävlingen vann han en silvermedalj tillsammans med lagkamraterna Kazuyoshi Funaki, Hideharu Miyahira och Noriaki Kasai. I sitt hittills sista VM, i Oberstdorf 2005 blev han nummer 18 i normalbacken och nummer 9 i lagtävlingen i stora backen."},{"question":"السؤال: شكون هي اول دولة صنعات العملة الورقية؟","answer":"الإجابة: الصين"},{"question":"CH3 – CCl2 – CBr2 – CH = CH2 యొక్క IUPACA) 2, 2-డై క్లోరో-3, 3-డై బ్రోమో పెంట్-1-ఈన్B) 3, 3-డై బ్రోమో పెంట్-1-ఈన్C) 3, 3-డై బ్రోమో-4, 4-డై క్లోరో పెంట్-2 ఈన్D) 3, 3-డై బ్రోమో-4,4-డై క్లోరో పెంట్-1-ఈన్","answer":"D) 3, 3-డై బ్రోమో-4,4-డై క్లోరో పెంట్-1-ఈన్"},{"question":"السؤال: اذكر أهم مُسببات إصابات العمل؟","answer":"الإجابة: الغبار الصناعي"},{"question":"Cồn cát đứng yên cao nhất thế giới nằm ở đâu?","answer":"Sa mạc Badain Jaran ở phía bắc Trung Quốc có những cồn cát cao khoảng 500 m, tiêu biểu như đỉnh Bilutu cao hơn 500 m tính từ chân tới đỉnh, là cồn cát cố định cao nhất thế giới. Những cồn cát nhỏ thay đổi liên tục theo mô hình gió nhưng các cồn cát lớn (cao hơn 200 m) đã đứng yên trong hàng chục nghìn năm. Nhờ độ ẩm bên trong cao, các cồn cát ở đây bị nén chặt, hình thành cát cứng và sa thạch (cát kết), chỉ có lớp cát trên bề mặt là liên tục thay đổi theo gió . Các cồn cát Badain Jaran còn nổi tiếng bởi hiện tượng cát hát. "},{"question":"So ìtàn nípa Ìjàmbá ìtúká èbúté Bèírùtù ní ọdún 2020.","answer":"Ní ìrọ̀lẹ́ ọjọ́ kẹrin, oṣù Ògún, ọdún 2020, àwọn ìjàm̀bá ìtúká aláriwo olóró méjì ṣẹlẹ̀ ní èbúté ìlú Bèírùtù, tó jẹ́ olúìlú orílẹ̀-èdè Lẹ́bánọ́ọ̀nù. Ìtúká aláriwo kejì lágbára tó bẹ́ẹ̀ tó, ó fa ikú àwọn ènìyàn tó pọ̀ tó 207, ìpalára àwọn ènìyàn tó tó 6,500, ìbàjẹ́ àwọn ohun ìní tí iye owó wọ́n tó bílíọ̀nù mẹ́ẹ̀wá sí mẹ́ẹ̀dógún ní iye owó dọ́là, ó sì sọ àwọn ènìyàn tó pọ̀ tó 300,000 di aláìnílé. Ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ yìí ṣẹlẹ̀ nítorí 2,750 tonnes (3,030 short tons; 2,710 long tons) àmóníọ́mù onínáítrójínì – tí agbára rẹ̀ tó 1.2 kilotons of TNT (5.0 TJ) – tí ìjọba Lẹ́bánọ́nù ti gbẹ́sẹ̀lé látọwọ́ ọkọ̀ ojú-omi akẹ́rù \\"MV Rhosus\\", tí wọ́n sì kó pamọ́ sí apá kan ní èbúté náà láì sí àbò àti ìṣọ́ra tó yẹ fún ọdún mẹ́fà."},{"question":"Кимдин агасы падышанын кайын агасы болгон? ","answer":"Англиянын тактысына Вильгельм Жеңүүчүгө каршы чыккан талапкерлердин бири Эдгар Ателинг акыры Шотландияга качкан. Шотландиянын королу Малколм III Эдгардын эжеси Маргаретке үйлөнүп, Шотландиянын түштүк чек арасын талашып-тартышкан Вильгельмге каршы чыккан. Уильям 1072 - жылы Шотландияга басып кирип, Абернетиге чейин барып, ал жерден кемелери менен жолугушкан. Малколм баш ийген, Уильямга таазим кылган жана уулу Дунканды барымтага алган, Шотландиянын корону Англиянын королуна берилгендик көрсөтүүгө милдеттүүбү деген бир катар талаш-тартыштарды баштаган."},{"question":"Ìbéèrè: ta ló kópa nínú eré orí tẹlifíṣọ̀n Remington Steele Ìdáhùn?","answer":"Pierce Brosnan ni."},{"question":"２０１２年のAKB総選挙で1位を獲得したのは誰？","answer":"大島優子です。"},{"question":"Inona no dikan'ny hoe rain'ny reninao na ny rainao?a) Dadatoab) Dadabed) Rahalahye) Ray","answer":"b) Dadabe no dikan'ny hoe rain'ny reninao na ny rainao"},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Rubuta ɗari biyu da casa'in da shida a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 296"},{"question":"what important event is this text about: Dahlkvist fk sin debut for Sveriges landshold i 2008 og har spillet over 130 landskampe. Hun har spillet for sit land ved VM i fodbold for kvinder i 2011 og 2015, ved sommer-OL 2012 og ved EM i fodbold for kvinder i 2009, 2013 og 2017. Hendes far, Sven \\"Dala\\" Dahlkvist, spillede for AIK og spillede 39 kampe for Sveriges fodboldlandshold mellem 1979 og 1985.","answer":"The wording \\"event\\" is wrong since the input text clearly describes a Swedish female soccer player named Dahlkvist."},{"question":"Yiyiphi kwezi zinto zilandelayo ngokuqhelekileyo ekhula kuqala kwilitye elingenanto? - Khawucinge ngoku. Iinketho: I-lichens; Imifuno; Imithi; Iibhulukhwe;","answer":"I-lichens."},{"question":"ما هو أكبر بحار العالم ؟ ","answer":"الجواب : البحر الأبيض المتوسط"},{"question":"Σε ποιο σημαντικο γεγονός αναφέρεται το κείμενο: Πολλοί μελετητές θεωρούν ως απαρχή του Ολοκαυτώματος τις αντιεβραϊκές ταραχές της «Νύχτας των Κρυστάλλων» («Kristallnacht») στις 9 Νοεμβρίου 1938, όταν οι Εβραίοι και οι ιδιοκτησίες τους έγιναν στόχος επιθέσεων σε ολόκληρη τη Γερμανία. Περίπου 100 Εβραίοι δολοφονήθηκαν κι άλλες 30.000 στάλθηκαν σε στρατόπεδα συγκέντρωσης, ενώ 7.000 καταστήματα που ανήκαν σε Εβραίους και 1.574 Συναγωγές (σχεδόν το σύνολο των Συναγωγών στη Γερμανία) καταστράφηκαν μερικά ή ολοσχερώς. Παρόμοια γεγονότα έγιναν ταυτόχρονα και στη Βιέννη.","answer":"Την \\"Νύχτα των Κρυστάλλων\\""},{"question":"Content: ఎన్నో ఏళ్లుగా ఇది వారికి ఆచారంగా వస్తోంది. శవయాత్ర సందర్భంగా ఇప్పటికీ ఇలాంటి కార్యక్రమాలు ఏర్పాటు చేస్తున్నారు. శవయాత్రలు, పెళ్లిళ్లు, ఆలయ ఉత్సవాల్లో అశ్లీల నృత్యాలు చేయడాన్ని ఈ ఏడాది ప్రారంభంలో చైనా నిషేధించింది. కానీ ప్రజలు మాత్రం ఆ సంప్రదాయాన్ని కొనసాగిస్తూనే ఉన్నారు. శవయాత్రలో అశ్లీల నృత్యాలు ఎందుకు?అంత్యక్రియల్లో చాలా మంది పాల్గొనేలా అందర్ని ఆకర్షించేందుకు ఇలాంటి అశ్లీల నృత్యాలు ఏర్పాటు చేస్తారని ఒక కథనం ప్రచారంలో ఉంది. అంత్యక్రియల్లో ఎంత ఎక్కువ మంది పాల్గొంటే చనిపోయిన వ్యక్తికి అంత గౌరవం ఇచ్చినట్లు అని అక్కడి ప్రజలు భావిస్తారు. ఇది మానవ ప్రత్యుత్పత్తి ప్రక్రియను ఆరాధించడమని మరికొందరు చెబుతుంటారు. 'స్థానిక ఆచారాల ప్రకారం అంత్యక్రియల్లో శృంగార డాన్సర్లతో నృత్యం చేయించడమంటే చనిపోయిన వ్యక్తి దీవెనలు అతని బంధువులకు అందించడం' అని ఫుజియాన్ నార్మన్ యూనివర్శిటీ ప్రొఫెసర్ హువాంగ్ జియాంగ్సింగ్ గ్లోబల్ టైమ్స్‌ వార్తా సంస్థకు చెప్పారు. వాస్తవానికి తమ హోదా, అంతస్తు ప్రదర్శించడం కోసమే ఇలాంటి అశ్లీల నృత్యాలు ఏర్పాటు చేస్తారని మరికొందరు చెబుతున్నారు. చైనాలో ఈ ఆచారం మామూలేనా?చైనాలోని గ్రామీణ ప్రాంతాల్లో ఈ ఆచారం ఎక్కువగా ఉంది. కానీ తైవాన్‌లో ఇది మరింత ఎక్కువ. నిజానికి ఇది అక్కడే పుట్టింది. 1980ల్లో అంత్యక్రియల సమయంలో అశ్లీల నృత్యాలు ఏర్పాటు చేయడమనేది తైవాన్‌లో విస్తృత ప్రాచుర్యం పొందిందని యూనివర్సిటీ ఆఫ్ సౌత్ కాలిఫోర్నియా ఆంత్రోపాలజిస్ట్ మార్క్ మోస్కోవిట్జ్ బీబీసీకి చెప్పారు. తైవాన్‌లో ఇది సర్వసాధారణం. కానీ చైనాలో ప్రభుత్వ నియంత్రణ అధికంగా ఉంటుంది. కాబట్టి చాలా మంది చైనీయులు ఈ సంప్రదాయం గురించి విని ఉండరు. అయితే, తైవాన్‌లో కూడా ప్రధాన పట్టణాల్లో ఈ సంప్రదాయం అంతగా కనిపించదు. ఇది చట్ట వ్యతిరేకం కాబట్టి నగర శివార్లలో ఇలాంటి కార్యక్రమాలు ఏర్పాటు చేసుకుంటారని మోస్కోవిట్జ్ తెలిపారు. గతేడాది తైవాన్‌ చియాయి పట్టణంలో ఒక రాజకీయ నాయకుడి శవయాత్రలో 50 మంది పోల్ డాన్సర్లు జీప్ టాప్‌ఇప్పుడు నియంత్రణ ఎందుకు?చైనా ప్రభుత్వ తాజా నియంత్రణ చర్యలు కొత్తేమీ కాదు. అంత్యక్రియల సందర్భంగా అసభ్య నృత్యాలు చేయకుండా ప్రజలను చైతన్య పరచాలన్న ప్రచారంలో భాగంగానే ప్రభుత్వం ఈ చర్యలు తీసుకుంటోంది. ఇలాంటి నృత్యాలు అనాగరికమని చైనా సాంస్కృతిక మంత్రిత్వ శాఖ చెబుతోంది. ","answer":"శవయాత్రలో అశ్లీల, అసభ్య నృత్యాలు చేయడం చైనాలోని కొన్ని ప్రాంతాల్లో సంప్రదాయంగా వస్తోంది."},{"question":"අව විසේනිය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"අව විසේනිය යනු චන්ද්‍ර මාසයක අව පක්‍ෂයේ පස්වන (5) තිථිය වෙයි. එසේම අව විසේනිය යනු සිංහල මාස ක්‍රමයේ දී අව ජලවක තිථියට පසු සහ අව සැටවක තිථියට පෙර යෙදෙන මාසයේ විසිවන (20) තිථිය යි."},{"question":"எழுதும்போது ஏற்படும் பிழைகளை எவ்வாறு வகைப்படுத்தலாம்? எழுத்துப் பிழைக்கு முதன்மையான காரணம் யாது?","answer":"எழுதும்போது ஏற்படும் பிழைகளை பின்வருமாறு வகைப்படுத்தலாம்: எழுத்துப்பிழை, சொற்பொருட்பிழை, சொற்றொடர்ப் பிழை, பொதுவான பிழைகள் சில என வகைப்படுத்தலாம்.ஏல்லா இடங்களிலும் பேச்சுத்தமிழை எழுத முடியாது. பேசுவதைப் போலவே எழுத எண்ணுவதே எழுத்துப்பிழைக்கு முதன்மையான காரணம் எனலாம்."},{"question":"Çalışma izni ücreti ne kadar?","answer":"Yurt içinden yapılan çalışma izni başvurularında 4.635,30 TL Harç ücreti ve 356,00 TL kart ücreti bulunmaktadır, fakat yurt dışı başvurularında çalışma izni harç ücretleri karşılıklık esasına göre farklılık gösterebilmektedir, yurt dışı başvurularda ödemeler bulunan ülkenin para birimiyle yapılmaktadır."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Joe Biden. ","answer":"Is é Joseph Robinette “Joe” Biden, Jr., a rugadh ar 20 Samhain 1942, 46ú hUachtarán na Stát Aontaithe. Rugadh Biden in Scranton, Pennsylvania. Bhog seisean agus a theaghlach go Delaware sa bhliain 1953 agus é 10 mbliana d'aois. Is de shliocht Éireannach é ar thaobh a mháthar (a rugadh de mhuintir Uí Fhinneagáin) agus de shliocht Éireannach, Sasanach agus Úgónach ar thaobh a athar. Caitlicigh iad na Bidens.Rinne sé staidéar ag Ollscoil Delaware (B.A. i stair agus eolaíocht pholaitiúil, 1965) agus ina dhiaidh sin bhain sé céim dlí (Juris Doctor) amach ó Ollscoil Syracuse i Stát Nua-Eabhrac sa bhliain 1968. Bhí Biden ina sheanadóir ar son Delaware ón bhliain 1973 ar aghaidh leis an bPáirtí Daonlathach.Bhí sé ina leasuachtarán Stáit Aontaithe Mheiriceá faoin uachtarán Barack Obama (2009–2017). Is mór an taithí agus eolas a bfhuair séle linn na tréimhse seo sa réim gnóthaí eachtracha go háirithe."},{"question":"Qual estado brasileiro tem a sigla GO?","answer":"A sigla \\"GO\\" corresponde ao estado de Goiás, que está localizado na região Centro-Oeste do Brasil. A capital de Goiás é Goiânia. Este estado é conhecido por sua diversidade geográfica, que inclui planícies, serras e áreas de cerrado, e também é uma importante região agrícola e pecuária do país."},{"question":"ලෝකයේ පළමු පැන්සල හැදුවේ කවුද?","answer":"1560 දී පමණ, සිමෝනියෝ සහ ලින්ඩියානා බර්නාකෝටි නම් ඉතාලි යුවළක් නවීන, ලීවලින් ආවරණය කරන ලද වඩු පැන්සල සඳහා පළමු සැලැස්ම විය. ඔවුන්ගේ අනුවාදය පැතලි, ඕවලාකාර, වඩාත් සංයුක්ත පැන්සලක් විය. ඔවුන්ගේ සංකල්පය වූයේ ජුනිපර් ලී කූරක් සිදුරු කිරීමයි."},{"question":"What and where is Jiaozuo?","answer":"Jiaozuo is a prefecture city in the north of Henan Province, People's Republic of China. Jiaozuo is located on the river Huanghe. It borders Zhengzhou to the south, Xinxiang to the east, Jiyuan to the west, Luoyang to the southwest and Shanxi province to the north."},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Cách làm bê xào sả ớt đơn giản","answer":"Thịt bê chọn thịt ba chỉ có cả da, dùng dao sắc thái ngang thớ mỏng. Ướp thịt bê với 2 thìa cà phê dầu hào, 2 thìa cà phê tương bần, 1 thìa cà phê dầu ăn, 1 thìa cà phê hạt nêm, 1 thìa cà phê hạt tiêu. Trộn đều và ướp trong 10 phút. Sả thái lát vát, ớt thái lát. Ớt chuông xanh, ớt chuông đỏ rửa sạch, thái con chì. Hành tây thái múi cau. Tỏi đập dập, hành lá thái khúc. Phi thơm tỏi và 1/2 lượng sả, cho thịt bê vào xào trên lửa lớn. Đảo đều tay, khi thịt bê chín tái thì cho hết phần sả còn lại vào đảo đều. Cho ớt chuông đỏ, ớt chuông xanh, hành tây vào đảo đều trên lửa lớn cho vừa chín tới. Cuối cùng cho hành lá, rau ngổ (tùy chọn) vào đảo đều. Nêm nếm lại gia vị cho vừa miệng. Tắt bếp, rắc chút hạt tiêu và múc ra đĩa thưởng thức. Yêu cầu thành phẩm: Thịt bê mềm ngọt, không chảy nước, dậy mùi thơm của sả, chút the cay từ ớt, rau củ quả chín tới giòn ngon. Chú ý: Các loại thịt đỏ (như thịt bê, thịt bò) không nên ướp muối vì bởi quy tắc ''muối tách đường giữ'' trong ẩm thực sẽ làm thịt ra nước và khi xào bị dai. Nên xào trên lửa lớn để thịt bê mềm ngọt, không bị ra nước. Các rau củ quả chỉ xào chín tới để giữ độ giòn ngon. Tương bần hợp với thịt bê, khi ướp cho một chút vào sẽ dậy mùi thơm."},{"question":"এই লেখাটি কোন গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ঘটনা সম্পর্কে ?শহীদ শাহ আবদুুল মজিদ হলেন বাংলাদেশের একজন প্রখ্যাত মুক্তিযোদ্ধা ও সমাজসেবক। মুক্তিযুদ্ধে অনন্য সাধারণ অবদানের জন্য ২০১৬ সালে তাকে “স্বাধীনতা ও মুক্তিযুদ্ধে স্বাধীনতা পুরস্কার” প্রদান করা হয়।","answer":"মুক্তিযুদ্ধ |"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki ini?  Masuk satu lubang terbesar, keluar tiga lubang yang kecil.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah baju."},{"question":"Differentiate between a hash table and an array.","answer":"While both store elements in contiguous memory, a hash table uses a hash function to map keys to indices, providing efficient access and search operations."},{"question":"Op welke (nieuwe) manier werden in het eerste kwartaal van dit jaar meerdere keren racistische kreten geuit?","answer":"Dit gebeurde door het projecteren met lasers van racistische leuzen op bruggen (Erasmusbrug in Rotterdam) en gebouwen (UWV kantoor in Venlo en het Anne Frank Huis in Amsterdam). "},{"question":"Willie Reid (bọọlu afẹsẹgba, ti a bi ni ọdun 1884)","answer":"William Reid (3 May 1884 - 13 May 1964) jẹ agbabọọlu agbabọọlu agbaye ti ilu Scotland ati oluṣakoso, ti o ṣere bi ikọlu .OlogbaBibi ni Baillieston, Lanarkshire, Reid bẹrẹ iṣẹ agba rẹ ni ọdun 1903 pẹlu Morton, ẹniti o darapọ mọ Baillieston Thistle. O gba awọn ibi-afẹde Ajumọṣe 11 ni awọn akoko meji ṣaaju gbigbe si Lanark Kẹta ni Oṣu Kẹrin ọdun 1906; irisi osise rẹ nikan fun ẹgbẹ naa wa ni ijatil ipari ipari Scotland Cup si Hearts nigbamii ni oṣu yẹn. Gbigbe kan si Motherwell tẹle, nibiti o ti gba awọn akoko aadogbon ni awọn akoko meji ṣaaju akoko awin kan ni England pẹlu Portsmouth .Reid pada si Scotland ni Oṣu Kẹrin ọdun 1909 nigbati Rangers fowo si, nibiti akọkọ rẹ tun wa ni ipari ipari Ife Scotland kan (ninu ọran yii atunwi iṣẹlẹ ti 1909 eyiti o tẹle nipasẹ rudurudu nipasẹ awọn oluwo ti o ni idaduro idije) ṣugbọn eyi akoko ti o duro pẹlu rẹ titun club fun igba pipẹ, ati ki o gba meta otelemuye Ajumọṣe. O jẹ agbaboolu agba bọọlu fun awọn akoko itẹlera mẹfa laarin 1910 ati 1916. Iṣẹ bọọlu afẹsẹgba rẹ ni idilọwọ nipasẹ Ogun Agbaye akọkọ, lakoko eyiti o ṣiṣẹ bi ibon ni Royal Field Artillery 52nd Lowland Division ati ṣere ni ẹẹkan fun Rangers ni ọdun mẹta, ti o pada lati ṣe alabapin si aṣaju miiran ni ipolongo 1919 – 20 .Ni ọdun 1920 Reid gbe lọ si Albion Rovers bi oluṣakoso ẹrọ orin, nibiti o ti pari iṣẹ ṣiṣere rẹ pẹlu awọn ibi-afẹde Ajumọṣe erindinlogoji fun ẹgbẹ naa.Reid wa ni ibi-afẹde oke kẹrin ti gbogbo akoko ninu ọkọ ofurufu oke ilu Scotland pẹlu awọn ibi-afẹde 270. Ninu iwọnyi, 188 ni o gba wọle lakoko akoko rẹ ni Rangers.OkeereReid gba gbogbo awọn fila rẹ fun ẹgbẹ orilẹ-ede Scotland lakoko ti o wa pẹlu Rangers. O ṣe akọbi ilu Scotland rẹ ni iyaworan meji si meji pẹlu Wales ni ọdun 1911 ati pe o jere fila ikẹhin rẹ ni ọdun mẹta lẹhinna, lodi si England . O tun ṣe aṣoju Ajumọṣe Bọọlu Scotland XI, ti o gba wọle ni igba mẹwa ni awọn ifarahan mẹjọ, o si ṣe ifarahan akoko ijade laigba aṣẹ fun awọn ara mejeeji.Reid ṣe ipa ti akowe / oluṣakoso pẹlu Albion Rovers ṣaaju ki o to di oluṣakoso Dundee United ni ọdun 1931. Reid ko lagbara lati tọju United ni atẹle igbega wọn o si lọ ni ọdun 1934 pẹlu ẹgbẹ ni wahala inawo. O jẹ ipo ikẹhin rẹ ni bọọlu agba."},{"question":"Жүүнү бош","answer":"Болбураган, жоош, чыйрак эмес, тың эмес, өлжүрөп колунан эч нерсе келбеген.Суук кабарды угузуп алышып, Максаттын жүүнү боштугуна кейишти, аяшты."},{"question":"What does the ggpairs() function from the GGally package show?","answer":"It displays pairwise relationships between multiple variables in a dataset."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: എക്കാലത്തെയും മികച്ച ക്രിക്കറ്റ് താരം ആരാണ്? ഉത്തരം:","answer":"എക്കാലത്തെയും മികച്ച ക്രിക്കറ്റ് കളിക്കാരൻ ആരെന്ന ചോദ്യം ആത്മനിഷ്ഠമാണ്, വ്യക്തിപരമായ അഭിപ്രായങ്ങളും മാനദണ്ഡങ്ങളും അനുസരിച്ച് വ്യത്യാസപ്പെടാം. പല ഇതിഹാസ ക്രിക്കറ്റ് താരങ്ങളും തങ്ങളുടെ അസാധാരണമായ കഴിവുകളും നേട്ടങ്ങളും കൊണ്ട് കായികരംഗത്ത് മായാത്ത മുദ്ര പതിപ്പിച്ചിട്ടുണ്ട്. \\"മികച്ച\\" ക്രിക്കറ്റ് കളിക്കാരനെ കൃത്യമായി നിർണ്ണയിക്കുന്നത് വെല്ലുവിളിയാണെങ്കിലും, ചർച്ചകളിലും സംവാദങ്ങളിലും പലപ്പോഴും പരാമർശിക്കപ്പെടുന്ന ചില പേരുകൾ ഉണ്ട്. സർ ഡോൺ ബ്രാഡ്മാൻ (ഓസ്ട്രേലിയ): ക്രിക്കറ്റ് ചരിത്രത്തിലെ ഏറ്റവും മികച്ച ബാറ്റ്സ്മാൻമാരിൽ ഒരാളായി പരക്കെ കണക്കാക്കപ്പെടുന്ന ബ്രാഡ്മാന്റെ ടെസ്റ്റ് മത്സരങ്ങളിൽ 99.94 എന്ന അതിശയിപ്പിക്കുന്ന ബാറ്റിംഗ് ശരാശരി ഇപ്പോഴും സമാനതകളില്ലാത്തതാണ്. സച്ചിൻ ടെണ്ടുൽക്കർ (ഇന്ത്യ): എക്കാലത്തെയും മികച്ച ബാറ്റ്‌സ്മാൻമാരിൽ ഒരാളായി സച്ചിൻ കണക്കാക്കപ്പെടുന്നു. ടെസ്റ്റിലും ഏകദിനത്തിലും (ODI) ഏറ്റവും കൂടുതൽ റൺസ് ഉൾപ്പെടെ നിരവധി റെക്കോർഡുകൾ അദ്ദേഹത്തിന്റെ പേരിലാണ്. സർ വിവിയൻ റിച്ചാർഡ്സ് (വെസ്റ്റ് ഇൻഡീസ്): ആക്രമണാത്മക ശൈലിക്ക് പേരുകേട്ട ഒരു തകർപ്പൻ ബാറ്റ്സ്മാനാണ് റിച്ചാർഡ്സ്. 1970 കളിലെയും 1980 കളിലെയും പ്രബലമായ വെസ്റ്റ് ഇൻഡീസ് ടീമുകളുടെ വിജയത്തിൽ അദ്ദേഹം ഒരു പ്രധാന പങ്ക് വഹിച്ചു.സർ ഗാർഫീൽഡ് സോബേഴ്‌സ് (വെസ്റ്റ് ഇൻഡീസ്): ബാറ്റിംഗിലും ബൗളിംഗിലും ഒരുപോലെ മികവ് പുലർത്തിയിരുന്ന ഒരു ഓൾറൗണ്ടറായിരുന്നു സോബേഴ്‌സ്. എക്കാലത്തെയും ബഹുമുഖ ക്രിക്കറ്റ് കളിക്കാരിൽ ഒരാളായി അദ്ദേഹം പലപ്പോഴും കണക്കാക്കപ്പെടുന്നു.ഷെയ്ൻ വോൺ (ഓസ്‌ട്രേലിയ): ക്രിക്കറ്റ് ചരിത്രത്തിലെ ഏറ്റവും മികച്ച സ്പിൻ ബൗളർമാരിൽ ഒരാളായി കണക്കാക്കപ്പെടുന്ന വോണിന്റെ വൈദഗ്ധ്യവും കൗശലവും ലെഗ് സ്‌പിന്നിലൂടെ ബാറ്റ്‌സ്മാനെ ബാംബൂസിൽ ആക്കാനുള്ള കഴിവും അദ്ദേഹത്തെ കായികരംഗത്തെ ഇതിഹാസതാരമാക്കി.ഈ ലിസ്റ്റ് സമഗ്രമല്ല എന്നത് ശ്രദ്ധിക്കേണ്ടതാണ്, കൂടാതെ കായികരംഗത്ത് കാര്യമായ സംഭാവനകൾ നൽകിയ മറ്റ് നിരവധി ക്രിക്കറ്റ് താരങ്ങളുണ്ട്. വ്യക്തിഗത മുൻഗണനകൾ, സ്ഥിതിവിവരക്കണക്ക് നേട്ടങ്ങൾ, കളിയിലെ സ്വാധീനം, അവർ കളിച്ച കാലഘട്ടം തുടങ്ങിയ ഘടകങ്ങളെ ആശ്രയിച്ച് \\"മികച്ച\\" ക്രിക്കറ്റ് കളിക്കാരന് വ്യത്യാസപ്പെടാം."},{"question":"\\"Адамдан улуу ат жок ...\\"  деген макал-лакапты улантып берчи! ","answer":" \\"Адамдан улуу ат жок, нандан улуу аш жок.\\""},{"question":"జీర్ణక్రియలో ఏ ఏ జీవక్రియల సమన్వయం పరిశీలించవచ్చు?","answer":"మన శరీరంలో అనేక జీవక్రియలు పరస్పరం సమన్వయంతో పనిచేస్తాయి.ఉదా : జీర్ణక్రియ జరగటానికి నాడీవ్యవస్థ, అంతస్రావీ వ్యవస్థ, రక్తప్రసరణ వ్యవస్థ, కండర వ్యవస్థలు సమన్వయంగా పనిచేస్తాయి."},{"question":"ජන වහරේ \\"බින්නකාරයෝ \\" යන පදයේ අර්ථය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"බින්න යන්නට බොරුව, සහෝදරී, බෙදුණු යන අරුත් යෙදේ.බින්න විවාහය යනු බිරිඳගේ නිවසේ සැමියා පදිංචි වීමයි. ඔහු හැඳින්වුයේ බිනි මිනිහා ලෙසයි.බින්නකාරයා, ගජබින්නකාරයා යන්න,විශේෂයෙන්ම අනුන් භේද කරවීමේ අදහසින්, බොරු කියන්නන් සඳහා යෙදූවකි. නමුත් වත්මනේදී නම් ඕනෑම බොරුකාරයෙක් බින්නකාරයෙකි."},{"question":"यदि सन्ति गुणाः पुंसां विकसन्त्येव ते स्वयं |न हि कस्तूरिकामोदः शपथेन विभाव्यते ||","answer":"जर माणसाच्या अंगात चांगले गुण असले तर त्यांचा आपल्याआप विकास (आणि प्रसार) होतो. कस्तुरीचा सुगंध कुणी शपथपूर्वक सांगावा लागत नाही, तो स्वतःच दरवळतो आणि सर्वांना समजतो. अंगात गुण बाळगणे महत्वाचे आहे, त्यांची जाहिरात करण्याची गरज नसते."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo anarana ifampiantsoana ao anaty fianakaviana?","answer":"Ireo anarana ifampiantsoana ao anaty fianakaviana:-Dada sy Neny : ireo ray an-dreny niteraka.-Zanaka: ireo zaza naterak’ireo ray aman-dreny, taranaka voalohany na antsoina ihany koa hoe masondranony, masom-boly.-Dadabe sy Nenibe : no iantsoan’ny zanaka ny ray aman-drenin’i Dada sy ray aman-drenin’i Neny, izany hoe raibe sy reniben’ny zanaka,"},{"question":"Como é chamado o grupo de animais exclusivamente marinhos dotados de um endoesqueleto calcário?","answer":"O grupo de animais exclusivamente marinhos dotados de um endoesqueleto calcário é chamado de \\"Equinodermos\\". "},{"question":"கேள்வி : இடைச்சொற்களின் இயல்புகள் யாவை?","answer":"பதில்: பெயர்ச் சொற்கள், வினைச் சொற்கள் ஆகியவற்றைப்போல இடைச்சொற்கள் தமிழில் மிகுதியாக இல்லை. ஆயினும், இடைச் சொற்களே மொழிப் பயன்பாட்டை முழுமையாக்குகின்றன.இடைச்சொற்கள் பெயரையும், வினையையும் சார்ந்து இயங்கும் இயல்பை உடையன. தாமாகத் தனித்து இயங்கும் இயல்பை உடையன அல்ல."},{"question":"Me ya jawo juyin mulki a kasar Nijar?","answer":"Wadanda sukayi  juyin mulki a Nigér sun dora laifin rashin tsaro da rashin cigaban tattalin arziki. Sun bayyana cewa shiga tsakani ya zama dole don gujewa rushewar kasar "},{"question":"Cén fáth a n-úsáideann daoine VPNanna? ","answer":"Tá VPNanna an-úsáideach chun do sheoladh IP a cheilt ar an idirlíon, ionas gur féidir leat breathnú cosúil go bhfuil tú in áit ar bith ar domhan, agus ionas go bhfuil tú anaithnid. Is féidir iad a úsáid freisin chun do ghníomhaíocht brabhsála ar líne a cheilt ó dhaoine eile. Tá go leor cineálacha VPNanna ann, lena n-áirítear na VPNanna poiblí a úsáidtear go forleathan ar an Idirlíon. Ach tá VPNanna príobháideacha ann freisin, a cheadaíonn duit oibriú le cuideachtaí nó rialtais."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගංගාවන් අතරින්, වාර්ෂිකව වැඩිම ජල ප්‍රමාණයක් මුහුදට ගෙනයන ගංගාව කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගංගාවන් අතරින්, වාර්ෂිකව වැඩිම ජල ප්‍රමාණයක් මුහුදට ගෙනයන ගංගාව වන්නේ කලු ගඟ වේ."},{"question":"Năm 2020 tôi có chuyển phôi tại Bênh viện phụ sản Hải Phòng đến tuần thứ 6 thì phôi ngừng phát triển không rõ nguyên nhân. Hiên tôi còn trữ 5 phôi dự kiến chuyển trong năm nay. Cho tôi hỏi, tôi muốn chuyển phôi tại bệnh viện Tâm Anh có được không? Trước khi chuyên muốn tôi muốn làm xét nghiệm di truyền học có được không, tổng thể chi phí chuyển phôi hết bao nhiêu. Xin trân trọng cảm ơn.","answer":"Chị có thể đưa phôi từ nơi khác về để thực hiện chuẩn bị niêm mạc và chuyển phôi tại Tâm Anh. Tuy nhiên, chị cần cân nhắc rủi ro ảnh hưởng đến chất lượng phôi có thể phát sinh trong quá trình di chuyển phôi giữa các cơ sở lưu trữ. Ngoài ra, dựa trên chất lượng và tình trạng phôi, cũng như hồ sơ bệnh án của chị, các bác sĩ sẽ tư vấn thêm cho chị về chỉ định làm xét nghiệm di truyền học. Xin cám ơn!"},{"question":"句子1: 它是夏威夷的特有物种, 现在仅限于夏威夷岛, 句子2: 它是夏威夷的特有物种, 现在只在卡瓦伊岛上, 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"不同"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Sesuatu yang dilihat atau dialami dalam tidur, jika berakhir ianya tidak boleh disambung.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah mimpi. Mimpi ialah suatu pengalaman bawah sedar yang melibatkan penglihatan, pendengaran, pemikiran, perasaan, atau deria lain ketika tidur."},{"question":"السؤال: شحال من سورة في القرآن الكريم تسمات باسم نبي وشنو هي؟","answer":"الإجابة: عدد سور القرآن الكريم التي تسمات بأسماء الأنبياء وفيها السيرة ديالهم والعبرة التي نزلت بها هي ستّة ديال السور، وهي؛ سورة يوسف، سورة نوح، سورة يونس، سورة محمد، سورة إبراهيم، سورة هود."},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 高知市で4日、すばらしい秋田犬を選ぶ大会がありました。日本のいろいろな所から170匹ぐらいが集まりました。秋田犬は、国の天然記念物になっています。秋田犬保存会が、秋田犬を大切にして増やしていきたいと考えて、毎年大会を開いてます。大会では、しっぽがきれいに巻いているか、耳がまっすぐ立っているか、歯がきれいに並んでいるかなどをチェックしました。年齢や雄か雌かで分けて、1番を選びました。会場には、秋田犬が好きな外国人も来ていました。見に来た女性は「このようにたくさんの秋田犬を見ることはあまりないので、楽しむことができました」と話していました。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。"},{"question":"Ilaina ve ny rivotra mba hahavelona ny olombelona?","answer":"Eny, ilaina ny rivotra mba hahavelona ny olombelona."},{"question":"広島県のものは昭和２９年３月３１日に、東京都のものはその翌日に誕生した、まったく同じ名前の市といえば何市でしょう？","answer":"府中市です。"},{"question":"අලි - මිනිස් ගැටුම් හේතුවෙන් , වාර්ෂිකව වැඩිම මිනිස් ජීවිත ගණනක් අහිමිවන රට කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ඉන්දියාව"},{"question":"Apakah yang dimaksud dengan masyarakat multikultural?Jawablah pertanyaan berikut dengan membuat paragraf pembahasan singkat. Usahakan paragraf tersebut menjawab beberapa aspek pertanyaan berikut:- Apa itu Masyarakat multikultural?- Bagaimana individu dan kelompok dengan latar belakang kebudayaan yang berbeda dapat membentuk satu kesatuan?Jawaban:","answer":"Masyarakat multikultural merupakan suatu kondisi masyarakat yang terdiri dari kelompok-kelompok sosial dengan ciri khas kebudayaan tersendiri namun membentuk satu kesatuan. Masyarakat multikultur diwarnai dengan kelompok kebudayaan yang sangat beragam jenis dan jumlahnya. Konsep kebudayaan bukan hanya merujuk pada suku bangsa dan adat istiadat, namun juga mencakup nilai, kebiasaan, pengetahuan, keyakinan, hukum dan lain sebagainya.Wilayah Indonesia yang dihuni oleh sebanyak kurang lebih 267.000.000 penduduk dari 1.340 suku bangsa mencirikan bentuk masyarakat multikultural. Meskipun masing-masing individu yang menempati wilayah Indonesia memiliki latar belakang budaya, adat istiadat serta bahasa yang berbeda namun individu-individu tersebut tetaplah diidentitfikasi sebagai satu kesatuan yaitu bangsa Indonesia. Hal tersebut mengingatkan kita kepada semboyan bangsa Indonesia, Bhineka Tunggal Ika, yang artinya berbeda-beda tetap satu jua.Jadi, individu dan kelompok dengan latar belakang kebudayaan yang berbeda dapat membentuk satu kesatuan karena adanya konsep negara bangsa (nation state). Negara bangsa merupakan suatu kondisi dimana terdapat sekelompok individu yang bersatu diatas landasan persamaan latar belakang sejarah, persamaan nasib dan penderitaan masa lalu dan cita-cita masa depan."},{"question":"प्रविधिले सामाजिक मान्यता र शिष्टाचारको विकासलाई कसरी प्रभाव पारेको छ?","answer":"प्रविधिले डिजिटल सञ्चार र सामाजिक व्यवहारको वरिपरि नयाँ मापदण्डहरूको नेतृत्व गर्दै, मानिसहरूले कसरी सञ्चार गर्ने, जानकारी साझा गर्ने, र अनलाइन अन्तरक्रिया गर्ने भनेर आकार दिएर सामाजिक मान्यताहरू र शिष्टाचारहरूलाई प्रभाव पारेको छ।"},{"question":"Araka ity lahatsoratra ity, inona no azo atao mba hamahana ny olan'ny tanora nahavita fianarana eo amin'ny sehatry ny asa?Tsy anisan' ny zatovo nahazo vatsim-pianarana na avy amin'ny fanjakana na avy amin' ny fikambanana ny tena. Ho sarotra ny ahita asa any amin'ny fanjakana avy hatrany amin' izao fotoana izao toy izay miseho isan'andro. Ho tsara kokoa ny manangana asa mahaleo tena sao dia voarohirohy amin' ny asam-birao mandavan-taona ka any aoriana any tsy hitady afa tsy ny fiandrasan-karama hisondrotra isan-taona. Ho fanetribe izany, indrindra raha tsy hifanentana amin'izay fianarana natao ny asa hosahanina. Raha mba mahazo toerana ambonimbony ka omena andraikitra mifanitsy amin'ny fari-pahaizana kosa dia « akohokely notsipazam-potsimbary aho ary hotratrariko ny lanitra raha ho tratrako ! ».Raha mba tonga ny andro ankehitriny ka izay nahavita fianarana dia azo antoka fa hahazo asa avy hatrany dia hiadana ny sarambabem-bahoaka, handry ivohon'ny vato ny tanora vao misondrotra. Asa rahoviana no ho tonga izany ? Raha tsy tonga amin'ny androko dia iriko indrindra mba ho tonga amin'ny andron-janako atsy ho atsy kokoa. « Afaka hifandrindra koa ve ny raharaham-barotra izay hampivezivezy ahy sy ny asan' ny mpampivelona izay antsoina andro dia andro, antsoina alina dia alina? Atao ahoana ny ankizy ? » Tsy maintsy haka mpanampy izahay satria tsy ho zakany no sady tsy atao ny mandevin-talenta ka hamono ny asa izay efa niomanany an-taona maro. Aina ny asa, iankinan'ny aina ny asa, esory amin'ny olona ny asa raha tianao ny hamono azy.","answer":"Ny azo atao mba hamahana ny olan' ny tanora nahavita fianarana eo amin' ny sehatry ny asa dia ny manao asa mahaleo tena mifanentana amin' ny fianarana natao fa tsy hanantena asam-birao amin' ny fanjakana. "},{"question":"Kuo vardu amerikiečių režisierius, sukūręs \\"Žvaigždžių karai\\" filmų seriją?","answer":"Fantastikos filmų seriją sukūrė scenaristas, prodiuseris ir režisierius Džordžas Lukasas (George Lucas). Džordžui Lukasui „Žvaigždžių karų“ idėja kilo XX a. aštuntojo dešimtmečio pradžioje. Filmuojant kilo daug problemų, todėl dauguma kritikų bei žiūrovų baiminosi visiško filmo žlugimo, tačiau 1977 m. pasirodęs filmas „Žvaigždžių karai“, vėliau gavęs „Epizodo IV – naujos vilties“ pavadinimą, tapo tikra sensacija. „Žvaigždžių karų“ serijos istorija pasibaigė 2005 m. gegužės 19 d. trečiojo epizodo pasirodymu."},{"question":"Pasitọ luyawo ẹ pa, wọn loogun awọro lo fẹẹ fi i ṣe","answer":"Njẹ ẹyin gbọ nipa olori ijọ Omega World Global Ministries? Pasitọ Ukachukwu Enoch Christopher, ti ṣọọṣi rẹ wa nipinlẹ Akwa-Ibom, ẹni to lu iyawo ẹ pa lọsẹ to kọja.Ohun meji naa la gbọ pe o fa a ti ọkunrin ẹni ọdun mọkandinlaaadọta (49) yii fi lu obinrin to bimọ marun-un fun un pa. Akọkọ ni pe Pasitọ Enoch fẹsun agbere kan iyawo rẹ torukọ ẹ n jẹ Patience, o ni obinrin naa n yan ale, bẹẹ lo si tun n fi ogun ja aye oun pẹlu iwa iṣekuṣe to n ṣe kiri.Ohun keji tawọn eeyan tun fidi ẹ mulẹ, ti wọn ni Pasitọ Ukachukwu funra ẹ sọ, ni pe ko si ero to ni ṣọọṣi oun yii. Wọn lo sọ pe awọn ọmọ ijọ ko tan nnkan, eyi ko si jẹ koun maa rowo na, nitori ko le si nnkan gidi fun pasitọ ti ko ni ero lẹyin, owo gidi kan ki i si lọwọ iru wọn.Airowo naa yii la gbọ pe o fa a ti Pasitọ Enoch fi fọrọ lọ babalawo kan niluu wọn ti i ṣe Ikọt Abia, ni Akwa Ibom nibẹ. Babalawo yii ni wọn lo sọ fun pasitọ pe to ba le fi iyawo rẹ silẹ fun igbedide ṣọọṣi naa, ero yoo pọ ju yẹẹpẹ ilẹ lọ nibẹ, agbara buruku yoo si tun kun ọwọ rẹ pẹlu, ohun to ba n sọ yoo maa ṣẹ ni.Ki i ṣe pe ki Enoch fa iyawo ẹ silẹ bẹẹ ni babalawo n wi, o ni ko jẹ kawọn lo o fun awure ọla ni.Nitori ija to ti wa nilẹ tẹlẹ laarin pasitọ ọhun ati iyawo ẹ, ati ẹsun agbere to fi n kan an, nigba ti ija tun ṣẹlẹ laarin wọn lọsẹ to kọja lọhun-un, Pasitọ Ukachukwu lu obinrin naa kọja aala, nibi to si ti n lu u lo ti ṣubu yẹgẹ, lo ba ku mọ ọkọ rẹ lọwọ.Ọkunrin yii mọ pe ọran nla loun da bawọn eeyan ba fi le mọ ohun to ṣẹlẹ, lo ba gbẹlẹ koto ninu ọgba ile wọn nibẹ, o si sin obinrin to bimọ marun-un naa fun un sibẹ, o ṣoju furu bii pe kinni kan ko ṣe.Ọmọ keji ti oloogbe naa bi, to jẹ ọkunrin, lo jẹ kawọn eeyan mọ pe iya awọn ko si laye mọ, o si lọwọ kan baba awọn ninu o. Ọrọ pada di tọlọpaa, wọn wa sile pasitọ naa, nibẹ ni wọn ti ri ibi kan ti wọn sin oku si, wọn beere bo ṣe je lọwọ Pasitọ Ukachukwu, o si jẹwọ pe Patience, iyawo oun, ẹni ogoji ọdun to doloogbe, lo wa ninu saaree naa.O fi kun un pe ọwọ oun lo ku si nigba tawọn n ja, oun lu u pa a ni.Awọn ọlọpaa hu oku obinrin naa lọ fun ayẹwo, wọn si mu Pasitọ Enoch lọ satimọle.Alukoro ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Akwa Ibom, Odiko Macdon, fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ. O ni ọjọ kẹrindinlogun, oṣu kẹfa, lọwọ ba pasitọ, to si jẹwọ pe niṣe loun luyawo oun pa."},{"question":"Question: ఆర్ నారాయణమూర్తి నటించిన మొదటి చిత్రం ఏది ?Answer the question with Yes or No. If it is not possible then answer None.Hint: రెడ్డి నారాయణమూర్తి, (జ. డిసెంబరు 31,[1] 1953[2]) తెలుగు సినిమా నటుడు. ఎర్రసైన్యం, చీమలదండు మొదలైన విప్లవ ప్రధానమైన సినిమాల నిర్మాత, నటుడు, హేతువాది, అవివాహితుడు.విద్యాభ్యాసంనారాయణమూర్తి, తూర్పుగోదావరి జిల్లా రౌతులపూడి మండలంలోని మల్లంపేట గ్రామంలో ఒక పేదరైతు కుటుంబంలో జన్మించాడు. అమ్మ పేరు రెడ్డి చిట్టెమ్మ నాన్న పేరు రెడ్డి చిన్నయ్య నాయుడు [3]. వీరిది అతి సాధారణ రైతు కుటుంబం. రౌతులపూడిలో 5వ తరగతి వరకు చదివాడు. రౌతులపూడిలో ఒక సినిమా థియేటర్ ఉండేది. చిన్నతనం నుండి సినిమాలలో ఆసక్తితో ఎన్టీయార్ మరియు నాగేశ్వరరావుల సినిమాలు చూసి, విరామ సమయంలో వారిని అనుకరించేవాడు. అక్కడే తన నటనా జీవితానికి పునాది పడిందని చెప్పుకున్నాడు.[4] శంఖవరంలో ఉన్నత పాఠశాలలో చేరాడు. అక్కడే నారాయణమూర్తికి సామాజిక స్పృహ కలిగింది. సామాన్య ప్రజలకు జరిగే అన్యాయాలను గమనించి, విప్లవ ఉద్యమాలవైపు ఆకర్షితుడయ్యాడు.పెద్దాపురంలో బి.ఏ చదవడానికి కాలేజీలో చేరాడు. అక్కడ రాజకీయాలతో ప్రభావితుడై, సినిమాలు, రాజకీయాలు మరియు సమాజిక బాధ్యత అనే మూడు వ్యాసంగాలపై ఇష్టాన్ని ఏర్పరచుకున్నాడు. కళాశాల ఈయన విద్యార్థిసంఘానికి అధ్యక్షుడిగానే కాకుండా కళాశాల లలిత కళల విభాగానికి కార్యదర్శిగా కూడా ఉన్నాడు. అంతేకాక తను ఉంటున్న ప్రభుత్వ హాస్టలు యొక్క విద్యార్థిఅధ్యక్షునిగానూ, పేద విద్యార్థుల నిధి సంఘానికి కార్యదర్శి గానూ పనిచేశాడు. స్థానిక రిక్షా కార్మికులు ఈయనను మద్దతుకోసం సంప్రతించేవారు. నారాయణమూర్తి పట్టణ రిక్షాసంఘం అధ్యక్షుడుగా కూడా ఉన్నాడు. ఎమర్జెన్సీ కాలంలో క్రియాశీలకంగా పనిచేస్తున్నందువలన పోలీసులు ఈయన్ను తీసుకునివెళ్ళి ఇంటరాగేట్ కూడా చేశారు. అంతేకాక నారాయణమూర్తి సినిమా నటి మంజులతో ఒక ప్రదర్శన ఏర్పాటు చేయించి నూతన కళాశాల నిర్మాణానికి నిధుల సేకరణ ప్రారంభించాడు. అప్పట్లో బీహార్లో వరదసహాయానికి తగిన విధంగా తోడ్పాడ్డాడు. సహవిద్యార్థులు నారాయణమూర్తిని కాలేజీ అన్న</i>గా వ్యవహరించేవారు.సినీరంగ ప్రవేశంనారాయణమూర్తి సినిమాల్లో హీరో కావాలనే జీవితాశయం ఉండేది. సినిమా పిచ్చి తోటి 1972 లోనే ఇంటర్మీడియట్ పరీక్షలవ్వగానే ఎలాగైనా పరీక్షలో తప్పేది భాయం అనుకుని మద్రాసు వెళ్ళిపోయాడు. అప్పటికి ఇతడికి 17-18 ఏళ్ళ వయసు. మహానగరంలో ఎవరూ తెలీదు. మనసులో ఉందల్లా సినిమాల్లో వేషాలు వెయ్యాలని అంతే.. పక్కా సినిమా కష్టలు మొదలయ్యాయి.తిండి లేదు.వసతి లేదు. ఐనా ఏదో మూల ఆశ.అక్కడక్కడ తింటూ, లేని రోజు పస్తుంటూ, గడిపారు. ","answer":"None"},{"question":"Ajao ji jẹnẹretọ, ni wọn ba fẹẹ dana sun un l’Akurẹ","answer":"Diẹ lo ku ki wọn dana sun ole kan tọwọ tẹ lọsan-an gangan, nibi to ti fẹẹ ji jẹnẹreto gbe lẹgbẹẹ ṣọọbu itaja kan to wa nitosi South Gate, ni fasiti imọ ẹrọ to wa niluu Akurẹ, lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ to kọja.ALAROYE gbọ lati ẹnu ọkan lara awọn araadugbo tiṣẹlẹ naa ti waye pe ọmọkunrin ọhun to porukọ ara rẹ ni Ajao lawọn eeyan kọkọ lu ni alubami, lẹyin eyi lo ni awọn tinu n bi ọhun bẹrẹ si i ko taya ọkọ jọ eyi ti wọn fẹẹ fi dana sun un kawọn agbaagba kan too ba a bẹbẹ, ti wọn si rọ wọn ki wọn fa a le awọn ọlọpaa lọwọ.Ajao ni wọn ní kó niṣẹ meji tó n ṣe ju ko ja awọn eeyan lole lọ, ọjọ sì ti pẹ diẹ to tí ń ji ẹrọ amunawa awọn onisọọbu to to wa lagbegbe naa, ṣugbọn ti ko sẹni to ri i gba mu lọrun ọwọ ninu gbogbo awọn to n ṣọ ọ.Awọn agbaagba adugbo to gba a silẹ lọwọ iku ojiji la gbọ pe wọn ṣeto bi wọn ṣe gbe e lọ si tesan ọlọpaa to wa nitosi, nibi ti wọn ti n fọrọ wa a lẹnu wo lọwọ."},{"question":"中国的国花是什么？","answer":"中国的国花是牡丹。"},{"question":"¿Qué beneficios tiene el yoga?","answer":"El yoga es mucho más que una rutina de ejercicios para ponernos en forma, porque además de tonificar el cuerpo reconecta la mente; es una disciplina dos por uno que consigue renovarnos por fuera y resetearnos por dentro sin que apenas nos cueste. Porque el yoga es ese deporte tranquilo y sosegado donde los músculos trabajan y se tonifican -y mucho- casi sin que te cueste. \\"Tiene el poder de conectar cuerpo, mente y respiración, ayuda a trabajar las articulaciones y la parte muscular, a ganar más flexibilidad y a relajar el cuerpo para tener un sueño más reparador y poder descansar mejor"},{"question":"من أول من ذهب إلى الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم ليفاوض ويعرض عليه المال والشرف والملك والطب\\t","answer":" عتبة بن ربيعة"},{"question":"ફિફા વર્લ્ડ કપ વિષે જણાવો..","answer":"ફિફા વર્લ્ડ કપ  રમતના વૈશ્વિક સંચાલક મંડળ, ફેડરેશન ઇન્ટરનેશનલ ડી ફૂટબોલ એસોસિએશન (ફીફા) ના સભ્યોની વરિષ્ઠ પુરુષોની રાષ્ટ્રીય ટીમો વચ્ચે આંતરરાષ્ટ્રીય એસોસિએશન ફૂટબોલ સ્પર્ધા છે.1930 માં ઉદઘાટન ટૂર્નામેન્ટ પછી દર ચાર વર્ષે ટૂર્નામેન્ટ યોજવામાં આવી છે, બીજા વિશ્વ યુદ્ધને કારણે 1942 અને 1946 ના અપવાદ સાથે.શાસક ચેમ્પિયન આર્જેન્ટિના છે, જેમણે 2022 ની ટૂર્નામેન્ટમાં ત્રીજો ખિતાબ જીત્યો હતો.હરીફાઈ લાયકાતના તબક્કાથી શરૂ થાય છે, જે ટૂર્નામેન્ટના તબક્કા માટે કઈ ટીમો લાયક છે તે નક્કી કરવા માટે અગાઉના ત્રણ વર્ષમાં થાય છે.ટૂર્નામેન્ટના તબક્કામાં, 32 ટીમો લગભગ એક મહિના દરમિયાન યજમાન રાષ્ટ્રની અંદરના સ્થળોએ ટાઇટલ માટે સ્પર્ધા કરે છે. યજમાન રાષ્ટ્ર (ઓ) આપમેળે ટૂર્નામેન્ટના જૂથ તબક્કા માટે લાયક છે.આગામી ફિફા વર્લ્ડ કપ 2026 ટૂર્નામેન્ટ માટે 48 ટીમોમાં વિસ્તૃત થવાના છે.\\""},{"question":"\\"Y\\" යනු ඉංග්‍රීසි හෝඩියේ කී වෙනි අකුර ද?","answer":"\\"Y\\" යනු ඉංග්‍රීසි හෝඩියේ විසි පස් වන අකුර යි."},{"question":"Belu ආරම්භ කළේ කවුද?","answer":"Belu 2004 දී චිත්‍රපට නිෂ්පාදක රීඩ් පැජට් විසින් ආරම්භ කරන ලදී. බෝතල් කළ ජල ව්‍යාපාරයක් ලෙස වෙළඳපොලේ ඇති අනෙකුත් බීම සඳහා පරිසර හිතකාමී විකල්පයක් වීමේ අරමුණින්. Belu දියත් කිරීමට පෙර, පැජට් ව්‍යාපාරික ප්‍රජාවන්හි දැඩි පරිසරවේදියෙකු වූ අතර, මූලාශ්‍ර, නිෂ්පාදනය සහ ඇසුරුම්කරණයේ පාරිසරික බලපෑම සලකා බැලීමට බීම කර්මාන්තයේ අනෙක් අය දිරිමත් කළේය. Belu හි මුල් අවධියේ ආයෝජකයින් අතර Body Shop සම-නිර්මාතෘ Gordon Roddick, පරිසරවේදී Ben Goldsmith සහ හෙජ් අරමුදල් කළමනාකරු Chris Cooper-Hohn ඇතුළත් විය."},{"question":"Apakah pembelajaran mesin?","answer":"Pembelajaran mesin ialah suatu bidang sains komputer yang menggunakan kaedah-kaedah statistik membolehkan sistem komputer \\"mempelajari\\" (yakni, mengingkatkan prestasi mengerjakan sesuatu tugasan tertentu) dengan data tanpa diprogramkan secara terang-terangan. Aplikasi ini datangnya daripada kajian pengecaman pola dan teori pembelajaran pengkomputan dalam kecerdasan buatan.Pembelajaran ini meneroka pengkajian dan pembinaan algoritma yang boleh dipelajari serta peramalan data – algoritma sebegini melepasi arahan program yang tegar dengan membuat ramalan atau keputusan berdasarkan data, melalui pembinaan model daripada input contoh. Ia dipakaikan dalam pelbagai tugasan pengkomputan di mana perekaan dan pembinaan algoritma yang jelas sukar mahupun tidak boleh dibuat; misalnya penapisan e-mel, pengesanan unsur penceroboh yang membocorkan data, pengecaman ciri optik (OCR) dan sebagainya."},{"question":"پہلی جنگ عظیم میں نئی ٹیکنالوجیز نے کیا کردار ادا کیا؟","answer":"پہلی جنگ عظیم نے جنگ میں تکنیکی انقلاب کا مشاہدہ کیا۔ ٹینکوں، مشین گنوں، زہریلی گیسوں اور ہوائی جہازوں جیسی ایجادات نے میدان جنگ کی حرکیات کو بدل دیا۔ ٹینکوں نے موبائل اور محفوظ فائر پاور کی ایک نئی شکل فراہم کی، جبکہ مشین گنوں نے پیدل فوج کی حکمت عملی میں انقلاب برپا کردیا۔ زہریلی گیس، جو ابتدائی طور پر کیمیائی ہتھیار کے طور پر استعمال ہوتی تھی، نے جنگ میں ایک خوفناک جہت کا اضافہ کیا۔ جاسوسی کے لیے ہوائی جہازوں کا تعارف اور بعد میں لڑاکا طیاروں نے فضائی جنگ میں ایک نئے دور کا آغاز کیا۔ ان تکنیکی ترقیوں نے فوجی حکمت عملیوں، حکمت عملیوں اور خود تنازعات کی نوعیت کو تبدیل کر دیا، جس سے ہلاکتوں کی بلند شرح اور پہلی جنگ عظیم کی مجموعی بربریت میں اضافہ ہوا۔ ."},{"question":"ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਵੱਧਦੇ ਕ੍ਰਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਿਖੋ :269, 781, 683, 453, 239","answer":"ਹੱਲ:239, 269, 453, 683, 781"},{"question":"ब्राम्हण, क्षत्रिय, वैश्य व शूद्र हे प्राचीन भारतातील कोणत्या व्यवस्थेचे प्रकार आहे ?","answer":"वर्णव्यवस्थेचे"},{"question":"*كم سنا للسلحفاة ؟","answer":"صفر من الأسنان"},{"question":"యుగాలు ఎన్ని?Passage about చతుర్యుగాలు: హిందూ సంప్రదాయముననుసరించి కొన్ని సంవత్సరములు కలిపి ఒక యుగము గా కాలమానము లెక్కింపబడుతున్నది. అలా నాలుగు యుగాలు చెప్పబడ్డాయి.","answer":"నాలుగు"},{"question":"Chọn câu trả lời đúng cho câu hỏi sau: Cơ quan ngôn luận của Hội Việt Nam Cách mạng Thanh niên là cơ quan nào?A. báo Búa liềm.B. báo Thanh niên.C. báo Đỏ.D. báo Nhân dân.","answer":"Đáp án là b. báo Thanh niên.Báo Thanh Niên là một tờ nhật báo Việt Nam có trụ sở tại Thành phố Hồ Chí Minh. Đây là một trong những tờ báo có số lượng phát hành lớn nhất Việt Nam với 300.000 bản/ngày (có thời điểm phát hành hơn 400.000 bản).Ngày 3 tháng 1 năm 1986, báo ra số đầu tiên với tên gọi Tuần tin Thanh Niên trực thuộc Hội Liên hiệp Thanh niên Việt Nam. Trước đây, ngày 21 tháng 6 năm 1925, cũng có một tờ báo mang tên Thanh Niên do Nguyễn Ái Quốc sáng lập nhưng không phải là tiền thân của tờ Thanh Niên ngày nay"},{"question":"ما هو الحيوان الذي إذا تغير دمه أصبح طاهر ؟\\t","answer":"دم الغزال"},{"question":"दिए गए प्रश्न का उत्तर दीजिए।संयुक्त राष्ट्र का शासकीय रूप से अस्तित्व १९४५ की किस तिथि पर हुआ ?","answer":"उत्तर :  संयुक्त राष्ट्र २४ अक्तूबर १९४५ में शासकीय रूप से अस्तित्व में आया।"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ਘਰੁ ੧ੴ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ॥ਹਉ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵੀ ਆਪਣਾ ਇਕ ਮਨਿ ਇਕ ਚਿਤਿ ਭਾਇ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਮਨ ਕਾਮਨਾ ਤੀਰਥੁ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੋ ਦੇਇ ਬੁਝਾਇ ॥ਮਨ ਚਿੰਦਿਆ ਵਰੁ ਪਾਵਣਾ ਜੋ ਇਛੈ ਸੋ ਫਲੁ ਪਾਇ ॥ਨਾਉ ਧਿਆਈਐ ਨਾਉ ਮੰਗੀਐ ਨਾਮੇ ਸਹਜਿ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੧॥ਮਨ ਮੇਰੇ ਹਰਿ ਰਸੁ ਚਾਖੁ ਤਿਖ ਜਾਇ ॥ਜਿਨੀ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਚਾਖਿਆ ਸਹਜੇ ਰਹੇ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਜਿਨੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵਿਆ ਤਿਨੀ ਪਾਇਆ ਨਾਮੁ ਨਿਧਾਨੁ ॥ਅੰਤਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਰਸੁ ਰਵਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਚੂਕਾ ਮਨਿ ਅਭਿਮਾਨੁ ॥ਹਿਰਦੈ ਕਮਲੁ ਪ੍ਰਗਾਸਿਆ ਲਾਗਾ ਸਹਜਿ ਧਿਆਨੁ ॥ਮਨੁ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਹਰਿ ਰਵਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਪਾਇਆ ਦਰਗਹਿ ਮਾਨੁ ॥੨॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵਨਿ ਆਪਣਾ ਤੇ ਵਿਰਲੇ ਸੰਸਾਰਿ ॥ਹਉਮੈ ਮਮਤਾ ਮਾਰਿ ਕੈ ਹਰਿ ਰਾਖਿਆ ਉਰ ਧਾਰਿ ॥ਹਉ ਤਿਨ ਕੈ ਬਲਿਹਾਰਣੈ ਜਿਨਾ ਨਾਮੇ ਲਗਾ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥ਸੇਈ ਸੁਖੀਏ ਚਹੁ ਜੁਗੀ ਜਿਨਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਅਖੁਟੁ ਅਪਾਰੁ ॥੩॥ਗੁਰ ਮਿਲਿਐ ਨਾਮੁ ਪਾਈਐ ਚੂਕੈ ਮੋਹ ਪਿਆਸ ॥ਹਰਿ ਸੇਤੀ ਮਨੁ ਰਵਿ ਰਹਿਆ ਘਰ ਹੀ ਮਾਹਿ ਉਦਾਸੁ ॥ਜਿਨਾ ਹਰਿ ਕਾ ਸਾਦੁ ਆਇਆ ਹਉ ਤਿਨ ਬਲਿਹਾਰੈ ਜਾਸੁ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਦਰੀ ਪਾਈਐ ਸਚੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਗੁਣਤਾਸੁ ॥੪॥੧॥੩੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 26 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਮੈਂ ਇਕਾਗ੍ਰ ਮਨ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਇਕਾਗ੍ਰ ਚਿੱਤ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਪੇ੍ਰਮ ਨਾਲ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਮਨ ਦੀਆਂ ਇੱਛਾਂ ਪੂਰੀਆਂ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਤੀਰਥ ਹੈ (ਪਰ ਇਹ ਸਮਝ ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ) ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ (ਗੁਰੂ ਆਪ) ਸਮਝਾਏ(ਗੁਰੂ ਪਾਸੋਂ) ਮਨ-ਇੱਛਤ ਮੰਗ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜੋ ਇੱਛਾ ਧਾਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹੀ ਫਲ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ(ਪਰ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਸਿਮਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ (ਗੁਰੂ ਪਾਸੋਂ) ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਮੰਗਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ, ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਿਆ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੇ ਨਾਮ) ਦਾ ਸੁਆਦ ਚੱਖ, (ਤੇਰੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਾਲੀ) ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਏਗੀ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ 'ਹਰਿ ਰਸ' ਚੱਖਿਆ, ਉਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਨੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਲਈ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੇ (ਸਭ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਦਾ) ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਨਾਮ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਰਚ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਦਾ ਕੌਲ-ਫੁੱਲ ਖਿੜ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਲੱਗ ਗਈ ਹੈਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ (ਹੋ ਚੁਕਾ) ਮਨ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਵਿਚ ਆਦਰ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਪਰ) ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਉਹ ਬੰਦੇ ਵਿਰਲੇ ਹਨ ਜੇਹੜੇ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨਜੇਹੜੇ ਹਉਮੈ ਨੂੰ ਤੇ ਮਲਕੀਅਤ ਦੀ ਲਾਲਸਾ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਰ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਟਿਕਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਮੈਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਹਾਂ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਪੇ੍ਰਮ ਬਣਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹਉਹੀ ਬੰਦੇ ਸਦਾ ਸੁਖੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਾਸ ਕਦੇ ਨਾਹ ਮੁੱਕਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਨਾਮ (ਦਾ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ) ਹੈ ।੩।ਜੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲ ਪਏ ਤਾਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ) ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ ਮਨ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੀ ਯਾਦ) ਨਾਲ ਇਕ-ਮਿਕ ਹੋਇਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਤ-ਕਾਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੀ (ਮਾਇਆ ਵਲੋਂ) ਉਪਰਾਮ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਮੈਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਵਾਰਨੇ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਸੁਆਦ ਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਤੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਨਾਮ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੧।੩੪।\\""},{"question":"ما هو الفرق بين الاحتباس الحراري وتغير المناخ؟ ","answer":"الفرق الرئيسي بين الاحتباس الحراري وتغير المناخ هو أن الاحتباس الحراري يستخدم للإشارة إلى زيادة متوسط ​​درجة حرارة العالم بسبب زيادة الغازات المحبوسة في الغلاف الجوي، بينما يستخدم تغير المناخ لوصف التغيرات المعقدة في درجة حرارة العالم والأمطار وأنماط الرياح وعوامل أخرى ناتجة عن الأنشطة البشرية."},{"question":"வால் நீண்ட குருவிக்கு வாயுண்டு. வயிறில்லை. அது என்ன?","answer":"விடை: அகப்பை"},{"question":"Sau 10 năm sinh sống, thấy nhà có nhiều dấu hiệu xuống cấp nên tôi có lên kế hoạch cải tạo. Nhưng khi thuê một đơn vị thầu đến khảo sát, họ cho biết nhà tôi chung móng, tường, hệ thống cột và mái với 2 hộ bên cạnh (tôi mua lại căn nhà nên đến nay mới biết việc này). Nhà thầu cũng nhấn mạnh, với trường hợp này, việc cải tạo tương đối khó khăn và tốn kém.Tôi đang cân nhắc 2 phương án như sau:Một, tiếp tục tìm đơn vị tư vấn để có phương án cải tạo nhà phù hợp. Với lựa chọn này, tôi rất băn khoăn về tính hiệu quả và chi phí.Hai là rao bán ngôi nhà và chuyển sang nơi khác. Nhưng với khả năng tài chính hiện tại, tôi chỉ có thể chọn nhà đất ở vùng ven, hoặc mua căn hộ chung cư.Rất mong nhận được tư vấn của các chuyên gia và độc giả!","answer":"Việc quyết định giữ lại hay bán ngôi nhà cần dựa vào nhiều yếu tố, bao gồm tình hình tài chính của bạn, ưu tiên cá nhân và tính hiệu quả của từng phương án. Dưới đây là một số khía cạnh bạn nên xem xét:Tình hình tài chính:Bạn cần xem xét khả năng tài chính hiện tại của mình để xác định liệu bạn có đủ khả năng chi trả cho việc cải tạo ngôi nhà hay mua một nơi mới.Nếu việc cải tạo yêu cầu một số tiền lớn mà bạn không có khả năng chi trả, việc bán nhà có thể là một lựa chọn hợp lý.Tình trạng ngôi nhà hiện tại:Nếu ngôi nhà đã xuống cấp nghiêm trọng và việc cải tạo gặp nhiều khó khăn do chung móng với các căn nhà khác, bạn cần xem xét kỹ lưỡng khả năng cải tạo thành công và lâu dài.Một sự cân nhắc quan trọng là liệu việc cải tạo có đảm bảo rằng ngôi nhà sẽ không gặp vấn đề trong tương lai gần.Lựa chọn mới:Nếu bạn quyết định bán nhà, hãy xem xét cẩn thận vị trí mới bạn muốn chuyển đến. Đảm bảo rằng nơi mới có các tiện ích và điều kiện sống tốt hơn hoặc phù hợp với nhu cầu của bạn.So sánh giá trị của căn nhà hiện tại và giá trị của nơi mới để đảm bảo bạn đang đưa ra quyết định hợp lý.Phân tích chi phí:Nếu bạn quyết định cải tạo, bạn cần thực hiện một phân tích chi phí chi tiết. Điều này bao gồm cả việc tham khảo các đơn vị tư vấn khác để có nhiều phương án để so sánh.Đảm bảo tính toàn diện bằng cách tính toán cả chi phí cải tạo và các chi phí phát sinh khác như thiết bị, vật liệu, lao động, v.v."},{"question":"Isilah titik-titik berikut dengan kata, frasa, atau penggalan kalimat jawaban yang tepat sehingga membentuk kalimat yang sempurna dan relevan dengan konteks yang diberikan.Konteks: Ciri-ciri zat makananKetika makan nasi atau roti, makanan tersebut selanjutnya akan dicerna dan diserap tubuh dalam bentuk molekul ... Jika jumlahnya berlebihan, maka zat makanan tersebut selanjutnya ...Jawaban:","answer":"Ketika makan nasi atau roti, makanan tersebut selanjutnya akan dicerna dan diserap tubuh dalam bentuk molekul Glukosa.Jika jumlahnya berlebihan, maka zat makanan tersebut selanjutnya diubah menjadi Glikogen dan disimpan di otot."},{"question":"川端康成の『伊豆の踊り子』で、主人公が踊り子に出会ったのは何という峠でしょう？","answer":"天城峠です。"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"berbuat salah\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud melakukan kejahatan."},{"question":"David Mark","answer":"David Alechenu Bonaventure Mark (bíi ní Oṣù kẹrin Ọdún 1948) jẹ́ ológun tí ó ti fẹ̀hìntì àti olóṣèlú ọmọ orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà tí wọ́n dìbò yàn wọlé gẹ́gẹ́ bí aṣojú Ìpínlẹ̀ Benue ní ilé ìgbìmọ̀ aṣòfin àgbà ti ilẹ̀ Nàìjíríà. Ó jẹ́ aṣojú ní ilé ìgbìmọ̀ aṣòfin lẹ́yìn tí ó wọlé látàrí ètò ìdìbò ti oṣù kẹrin ọdún 2007 lábẹ́ ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú People's Democratic Party. Ó jẹ́ ààrẹ ní ilé ìgbìmọ̀ aṣòfin.A bí Mark si ìlú Otukpo ní ìpínlè Benue ni osù kerin odun 1948. O lo si ilé-ìwé St. Francis Catholic Practicing ko to look since ilé-ìwé àwon ologun. Léyìn náà, o tun lo kàwé ni Nigeria Defense Academy. Wón so di 2nd Lieutenant ni odun 1970, wo si tun so di Captaini ni odun 1971, ótún padà di alaga Abandoned Properties implementation Committee ni iwo ilà oòrùn ni odun 1976.Mark jé olori Ministry of Communication àti àwon èka rè: Nigerian Telecommunications Limited(NITEL) àti Nigerian Postal Service(NIPOST).A yan Mark gégé bi ààré ilé ìgbìmò asofin àgbà ti Naijiria ní ojó kefa, osu Kefa odun 2007.David tún díje fun Senato agbègbè Benue South lekan si ni osu kerin odun 2011, a si yan fun isejoba kerin. David so pe idibo àwon eniyan ni o gbé depo, o si so fún àwon olutako rè láti sisé papò láti tún Nàìjíríà se.Nígbà ti àwon ilé ìgbìmò asofin un tún òfin Nàìjíríà se, Mark so fun àwon Senato tó kù rè láti fi àwon omo Nàìjirià si wajú ara won.Léyìn ìgbà ti àwon orílè-èdè United Kingdom satako si Nàìjirià, won si so pé wón ma se idaduro si àwon iranlowo ti wón un fun Nàìjirià. Mark so pe ki wón fi iranlowo won pa mó.Ni osu kesan odun 2018, Mark ni ipinu láti díje fun ipò ááre orílè-èdè Nàìjirià, o si yan Zainab Abdulkadir Kure ati Abba Ejemni si egbe ti o ma sé idari ipolongo ìdíje rè.O feran eré idaraya golf, tennis àti Squash. O je Christieni, èyà Idoma sì ni èyà rè. O ni ìyàwó merin sí marun.Mark ni ilé àti Helicopter ati ìbi ibalesi fún Helicopter."},{"question":"قم بإنشاء قصيدة قصيره من بحر مخلع البسيط.","answer":"وَمِن عَجيب الأُمور عِنديإِظهار ما تُضمر القُلوبتَأبى نُفوسٌ نُفوس قَوموَما لَها عِندَها ذُنوبوَتَصطَفي أَنفُسٌ نُفوساًوَكُلَها لَو تَرى عُيوبما ذاكَ إِلّا لِمضمراتيَعلَمها العالمُ الرَقيب"},{"question":"Trả lời câu hỏi sau bằng cách chọn câu trả lời phù hợp trong các câu dưới đây.Câu hỏi: Trạng nào từng đưa con cháu tới khu vực Long Biên ngày nay để định cư?A. Lương Thế VinhB. Lê Văn ThịnhC. Nguyễn Bỉnh Khiêm","answer":"Câu trả lời đúng là C. Nguyễn Bỉnh KhiêmGiải thích: Vào thời nhà Mạc, Trình quốc công trạng nguyên Nguyễn Bỉnh Khiêm ra làm quan ở Thăng Long đã đưa con cháu tới định cư, mở rộng làng Thanh Am, nay thuộc phường Thượng Thanh, quận Long Biên, thành một vùng trù phú. Do có nhiều công đức với dân làng nên sau khi mất, Nguyễn Bỉnh Khiêm cùng hai vị tướng của Hai Bà Trưng là Đào Kỳ - Phương Dung được tôn thờ làm Thành hoàng làng Thanh Am. Đình Thanh Am, nơi thờ Nguyễn Bỉnh Khiêm, hiện còn lưu trữ được một hệ thống di vật cổ có giá trị như cuốn thần phả, một quyển Sấm Ký của Nguyễn Bỉnh Khiêm."},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Tanzanie","answer":"Péeyum réwum Tanzanie mu ngi tudu Dodoma"},{"question":"පහත ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළේ තේරුම කුමක්ද?ඇඟෙන් ඇටයක් ගියා වගේ ","answer":"බොහෝ අකමැත්තෙන් යමක් දීම."},{"question":"నాగమ్మ తన వద్ద ఉన్న బాతుగుడ్లను, కోడిగుడ్లతో కలిపి పొదగేసింది. పొదిగిన తరువాత బాతు పిల్లలు కూడా కోడినే తమ తల్లిగా భావించాయి. దాని వెంటే తిరుగుతున్నాయి. దీనిని ఎలా వివరిస్తావు? ","answer":"బాతు పిల్లలు, కోడి పిల్లలు గుడ్ల నుండి బయటకు వచ్చిన వెంటనే నడవగలుగుతాయి.బాతు పిల్లలు గుడ్ల నుండి బయటకు వచ్చిన వెంటనే కదులుతున్నది ఏదైనా కనిపిస్తే దాని వెనకే పోతాయి.బాతు పిల్లలు ఆ జీవితో గడుపుతూ దానినే తల్లిగా భావిస్తాయి.అనుసరణ అనే లక్షణం వలన బాతుపిల్లలు చిన్న వయసులోనే ఆ బాతుని తమ తల్లిగా భావించాయి."},{"question":"« Nofelahin’ilay vazaha ity Rangahy mba nandroaka ny ombiny hiala teo amin’ny lalana nandehanan’ny fiarany. Nolazainy fa tsy mahay miarahaba Vazaha no sady natsipiny ny satrok’ilay Rangahy. »Inona no fihetseham-po fonoson’io fanambarana eo ambony io ?","answer":"Io fanambarana io dia maneho fihetseham-po miiba satria  misy fanambaniana sy fikasian-tanana ataon’ny vazaha."},{"question":"Jeffrey Walker og Fat Mike, hvilket fælles erhverv har de?","answer":"De er begge sangere."},{"question":": Waxaad sheegtaan 3 Waqti (ama maalmo ah,) oo la reebay in la soomo???","answer":":    maalinta ciidul-atxaa    maalinta ciidul fidr ah.    maalmaha Sabtiga iyo Jimcada, haddii aaynan taxana aheen?    "},{"question":"Mphe mohlala wa ditaba tšeo di sa rego selo sehlopheng se: dipapadi tša bidio","answer":"Madden 22 e tšweleditšwe neng?"},{"question":"Apakah syarat-syarat untuk memulakan bisnes francais di Malaysia? ","answer":"Antara syarat-syarat untuk memulakan bisnes francais, sesebuah syarikat itu perlulah:1. Telah beroperasi lebih daripada 3 tahun2. Berdaftar sebagai syarikat Sdn. Bhd. di Suruhanjaya Syarikat Malaysia (SSM)3. Melengkapkan manual operasi dan manual latihan4. Pendaftaran francais perlu dibuat di Bahagian Perkembangan Francais, KPDNKK"},{"question":"Buatlah jawaban atas pertanyaan rumit ini: Kapan gaya tarian rakyat, Liebeslieder Waltzes karya Johannes Brahms, menjadi gaya tarian paling populer?","answer":"akhir abad ke-18"},{"question":"Yintoni ingqele.","answer":"Ingqele sisiphumo sukubanda."},{"question":"HEESTII Habooney Naftaydan IYO FANAANKII XASAN AADAN SAMATAR","answer":"sida hogasha roobkaama hilaaca guyoo da’ayhobaan bislaatiyoharo wada biyeysanoo lagu hayaamohubaal sahan kii uu raraywaxuu si hintiqiyabahada qadacsi loo jirohaboonay naftaydaanhigsi baad ku noqatooadaa ii hiraayeehadaad diido hadalkaygahabeen wacan nasiibkaygahalkaygaan ku sugayaahanfi iyo dabayl baaisu kay hadheeyoosida hawd dulhamaganhabaqa iga baxayaahadaan haysto taladaahiboy kaama hiisheenkuu hoodo sheegteehaween haygu noqoninewaxaan hiilay noqon laahalista iyo dhibtaan qaboadoo iga horjoogsadahadaad diido hadalkaygahabeen wacan nasiibkaygahalkaygan ku sugayaahanaankiyo quruxdaanhiboy kugu jeclaadeehablahaad u sidataahaybadiyo asluubteesahamiyey dartaayohabeen socod ku waashowaxan eega dhaafaahawadaa sareeteewaxaan hiilay noqon laahalista iyo dhibtaan qaboadoo iga horjoogsadahadaad diido hadalkaygahabeen wacan nasiibkaygahalkaygan ku sugayaa"},{"question":"VRAI ou FAUX?Pour éviter d’être accusé de plagiat dans un travail écrit, l’étudiant doit mettre entre guillemets (« ») et donner la référence de tous les propos, écrits ou idées qui ne viennent pas de lui.","answer":"TOUT DÉPEND.Les guillemets (« ») sont requis si l’étudiant a repris les propos, les écrits ou les idées d’autrui textuellement (mot à mot).Les guillemets (« ») ne sont pas requis si l’étudiant a paraphrasé (reformulé en ses propres mots) les propos, les écrits ou les idées d’autrui.Dans un cas comme dans l’autre, la référence complète aux sources est requise."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'buah kalam'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud hasil tulisan atau karya. Contoh ayat: Novel itu adalah buah kalam Hamid yang pertama."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--आवळा देऊन कोहळा काढणे","answer":"आपला स्वार्थ साधण्यासाठी एखाद्या व्यक्तीला लहान वस्तू देऊन मोठी वस्तू मिळविणे."},{"question":"வினா:உலக செம்மொழி இலக்கியங்கள் யாவை ?","answer":"விடை:உலகில் செம்மொழியாக கருதப்படும் மொழிகள் மொத்தம் 8 ஆகும்.கிரேக்கம், சமஸ்கிருதம், இலத்தீன், பாரசீகம், அரபு, எபிரேயம், சீனம் மற்றும் தமிழ்.செம்மொழித் தகுதிஒரு மொழிக்கு செம்மொழி என்ற தகுதி அம்மொழியில் இடம் பெற்றிருக்கும் இலக்கியத் தரத்தின் அடிப்படையில்தான் முடிவு செய்யப்படுகிறது. இருப்பினும் செம்மொழி என்பதற்கு அம்மொழியில் இடம் பெற்றிருக்கும் முக்கியமான இரண்டு சிறப்புகள் தேவையாய் இருக்கிறது.1. இலக்கியப் படைப்புகள்2. கலைப் படைப்புகள்இந்த இரு படைப்புகளைக் கொண்டே அந்த மொழி செம்மொழிகளாக அறிவிக்கப்படுகின்றன.உலகச் செம்மொழிகள்இன்று உலகில் செம்மொழிகளாகக் கருதப்படும் மொழிகள் 8 ஆக இருக்கின்றன.இந்தோ-ஐரோப்பிய மொழிகள்:கிரேக்க மொழிசமஸ்கிருதம்இலத்தீன்பாரசீக மொழிஆபிரிக்க-ஆசிய மொழிகள்:அரபு மொழிஎபிரேயம்திராவிட மொழிகள்:தமிழ்சினோ-திபெத்திய மொழிகள்:சீன மொழி"},{"question":"Aṣiri tu pata: Eyi ni iye eeyan tawọn ṣọja yinbọn pa ni Lẹkki","answer":"Wọn ko mọ pe ẹnikẹni ri awọn, ṣugbọn awọn eeyan ri wọn, nitori aye ti yatọ si tatijọ. Wọn ri ọkọ agbarigo meji to jẹ tawọn ṣọja to n jade ni baraaki awọn ologun ti wọn n pe ni Bonny Camp. Awọn ṣọja kun inu ọkọ naa fọfọ, beeyan si ri wọn, yoo mọ pe ibi ijangbọn kan ni wọn n lọ. Bi ko jẹ awọn ni wọn n lọọ bẹrẹ ijangbọn naa, yoo jẹ wọn n lọọ da si ijangbọn kan to ti wa nilẹ ni, nitori ṣọja ki i lọ sode suuru kan, afi ode jagidijagan. Bi mọto naa ti jade ni wọn fidio ẹ, wọn si fi fidio ọhun tẹle wọn titi ti wọn fi jade si Opopona ti wọn n pe ni Ozumba Mbadiwe Street, ni adugbo Victoria Island, l’Ekoo, ṣe siriiti yii lo fori sọ Dodan Barack yii, beeyan ba si duro siwaju baraaki awọn ṣọja yii, siriiti ti yoo maa wo iwaju rẹ labẹ biriiji nibẹ, Ozumba Mbadiwe ni. Siriiti ti mọto awọn ṣọja mejeeji dori kọ ree, tawọn mọto mejeeji si n lọ lẹlẹẹlẹ.Ni deede aago mẹfa kọja iṣẹju mọkandinlọgbọn lawọn mọto yii jade o, ọjọ ṣẹṣẹ n bora diẹdiẹ ni, ilẹ n ṣu bọ, aago mẹfa aabọ irọlẹ ku iṣẹju kan. Bi awọn mọto yii ti n rin lọ, bẹẹ ni awọn ajọ ajafẹtọọ-agbaye, Amnesty International, fi ẹrọ igbalode tẹle wọn, bo tilẹ jẹ oju kan bayii lawọn jokoo si, sibẹ, wọn n ri awọn mọto yii bi wọn ti n lọ. Ori irin ti wọn wa yii ni awọn mọto bii tiwọn meji mi-in ti tun dara pọ mọ wọn, ni mọto awọn ṣọja yii ba di mẹrin, wọn si tẹle ara wọn lẹyin, wọn n lọ.  Bi wọn ti n tẹle ara wọn lọ yii, wọn kọja niwaju ileeṣẹ to n ṣoju awọn orilẹ-ede wọn, iyẹn awọn ẹmbasi loriṣiiriṣii.  Wọn kọja niwaju Ẹmbasi Australia ati Ẹmbasi Japan. Nigba naa, wọn ko ya sọtun-un wọn ko ya sosi mọ, lori titi Ozumba Mbadiwe yii ni wọn wa ti wọn n ba lọ, ṣe titi naa lo fori sọ Too-geeti (Toll-gate) Lẹkki.Ni bii iṣẹju mẹẹẹdogun lẹyin eyi ni fidio naa tun gbe mọto awọn ṣọja yii, mọto naa si ti di mẹfa bayii, nigba tawọn meji mi-in tun darapọ mọ wọn, ẹni kan ko ri wọn. Ṣugbọn mọto ti di mẹfa, mọto awọn ologun, wọn si n lọ si Too-geeti yii. Ni Too-geeti yii, awọn eeyan ti jokoo lọ rẹpẹtẹ ni tiwọn, ọdọ ni gbogbo wọn, wọn ko si mu ohun ija kankan bayii dani, abẹla ati awọn nnkan to le riran mi-in ni wọn n lo, nitori lojiji ni wọn kan ri i pe wọn ti mu ina gbogbo agbegbe naa lọ.  Ina gbangba kan ti i maa a riran nibẹ, wọn ti pa a, nigba ti yoo si fi di bii aago meje, agbegbe naa ti ṣokunkun dudu. Asiko ko-ri-ni-ko-mọ-ni yii ni awọn ṣọja to wa ninu mọto mẹfa yii bọ silẹ ninu ọkọ wọn, wọn ko si ba ẹnikẹni sọrọ ninu awọn ti wọn n ṣewọde yii, wọn kọ lu awọn ọdọ naa tijatija nitori niṣe ni wọn doju ibọn kọ wọn.Bi wọn ti n yin wọn nibọn, bẹẹ ni ọrọ di bo o lọ o yago, kaluku bẹrẹ si i sa asala fun ẹmi ẹ, nitori titi di asiko naa, niṣe ni kaluku wọn ro pe ko si ṣọja tabi agbofinro kan ti yoo doju ibọn kọ awọn ero to to bayii, bi wọn yoo ba tilẹ ṣe kinni kan fawọn, wọn yoo kọkọ gbọ tẹnu wọn na. Ṣugbọn awọn ṣọja ti wọn wa ko ba alaye kankan wa, wọn wa pẹlu ija rẹpẹtẹ ni, ija naa ni wọn si gbe ko awọn eeyan yii loju, ti wọn dana ibọn fun wọn. Bi wọn ti n ṣe iṣẹ buruku yii, bẹẹ ni awọn kọọkan ti wọn ribi duro si n ya fidio awọn ṣọja naa, ti wọn si n pariwo, ti wọn si n ṣalaye bi wọn ti n pa awọn eeyan to, ati bi awọn ṣọja ṣe doju ibọn kọ awọn. Fidio yii lo lọ kiri kari aye, ti gbogbo eeyan si n beere pe iru awọn ṣọja wo lo wa ni Naijiria yii, ti wọn n doju ibọn kọ awọn ọdọ, iro ibọn naa si n wọ inu fidio naa, gbogbo aye lo n gbọ ‘tako-tako’ ibọn wọn.Nigba ti awọn ṣọja yii lọ tan lẹyin ti wọn ti paayan silẹ, adugbo naa da paro, ṣugbọn awọn kan ninu awọn ti wọn n ṣewọde naa tun pada sibẹ, ko si tun pẹ ti awọn agbofinro fi le awọn yii naa lọ. Nigba ti ilẹ mọ ni ọjọ keji, ti awọn araalu n pariwo pe awọn ṣọja ni o, awọn ṣọja taku, wọn ni ko si ohun to jọ bẹẹ, ki lawọn yoo wa lọ sibi ti wọn ti n yinbọn. Wọn ni awọn kọ o. Awọn eeyan bẹrẹ si i gbe e kaakiri pe ogunlọgọ awọn eeyan lo ku, pe wọn ti pa awọn eeyan pupọ o, ṣugbọn ọpọ awọn eeyan ko fẹẹ gba ọrọ naa gbọ rara, nitori wọn ko ri oku awọn eeyan rẹpẹtẹ loootọ, wọn ko si ri awọn eeyan nilẹẹlẹ ti wọn n joro iku, yatọ si awọn meji mẹta kan ti wọn ti fi fidio ya nigba ti kinni naa n ṣẹlẹ lalẹ, ko tun si ẹni to tete mọ ohun to ṣẹlẹ. Awọn ajafẹtọọ-ọmọniyan, Amnesty International yii, lo kọkọ kede pe yoo to awọn eeyan mẹrindinlọgọta to ba iṣẹlẹ naa lọ.Ṣugbọn ko sẹni to fẹẹ gba wọn gbọ, nitori wọn o ri oku awọn eeyan loootọ. Ọmọbinrin oṣere kan ti wọn n pe ni DJ Switch (Obianuju Catherin gan-an lorukọ ẹ), lo kọkọ ṣalaye ohun to ṣẹlẹ nibẹ fun gbogbo aye, nitori bo tilẹ jẹ pe oun naa wa nibi iṣẹlẹ yii, ko kuro nibẹ titi ti awọn ṣọja fi pa awọn ti wọn pa, to si tun sa jade nibi to sa pamọ si, to lọọ ba ọga awọn ṣọja naa, to si beere lọwọ ẹ pe ki lo de ti wọn n pa awọn. Ọmọbinrin yii ati awọn diẹ ninu wọn gbe oku awọn ti wọn pa yii, wọn si gbe wọn siwaju awọn ṣọja naa. Awọn ṣọja yii ko ṣe meni wọn ko ṣe meji, wọn yaa ko awọn oku naa, wọn rọ wọn da sinu mọto wọn, wọn si ko gbogbo wọn lọ. Nitori bẹẹ, ni ọjọ keji ti DJ Switch ṣalaye fun gbogbo aye pe awọn eeyan ku nibẹ gan-an, ẹrin lawọn ṣọja n fi i rin, wọn ni bi eeyan ba ku nibi iṣẹlẹ naa, ko gbe oku wọn jade.Ori fidio lọmọbinrin olorin naa ti n ṣe gbogbo eleyii, o si sọ pe kinni naa ko ṣe ẹyin oun, oju oun lo ṣe, gbogbo oku to ku ti wọn n wi yii, awọn ṣọja lo ko wọn lọ. O ni lẹyin ti awọn ṣọja ti lọ tan paapaa, awọn ọlọpaa adugbo naa wa, awọn ni wọn ṣẹṣẹ waa pari ọrọ naa. Koda, awọn SARS ti wọn n tori ẹ ja naa wa sibẹ, awọn naa si tun ba wọn ṣe ninu iṣẹ naa.  Ọmọbinrin yii ni oku sun loootọ, oun si le fi Ọlọrun bura. Ṣugbọn koko to wa nibẹ ni pe ko si oku kan nilẹẹlẹ, ọrọ naa si ka gomina ipinlẹ Eko lara ti oun naa fi sọ pe ki wọn yee sọ ohun ti ko ṣẹlẹ, bi oku ba ku, tabi to ba jẹ ṣọja yinbọn ni, gbogbo aye ni iba foju ri iye oku to ku. Lọjọ keji to sọ eyi lo tun pada wa, o ni awọn eeyan meji pere lo ku, ẹni kan ku soju ija yii, ẹni keji ku si ọsibitu. Sibẹ DJ Switch ni irọ to n purọ funrọ ni, awọn eeyan to ku ju bẹẹ lọ.Lẹnu ibi ti oun ti n ba wọn fa ọrọ yii lọwọ, nibẹ ni Amnesty International ti gbe iwadii wọn jade. Iwadii yii fihan pe loootọ ni awọn ṣọja lọ si Too-geeti, wọn si yinbọn nibẹ, ki wọn yee purọ kan fun wa. Nigba naa ni awọn ṣọja jade ti wọn si jẹwọ, wọn sọ ootọ kan, wọn si fi irọ bii marun-un bo ootọ naa mọlẹ. Wọn ni loootọ lawọn lọ si too-geeti Lẹkki yii nigba ti awọn ijọba ipinlẹ Eko ranṣẹ sawọn, ṣugbọn ko si ẹmi ẹnikan to ti ọwọ awọn bọ, nitori awọn ko yinbọn ẹyọ kan bayii nibẹ. Wọn ni gbogbo eyi ti wọn n ri yẹn, ti awọn eeyan n gbe sori fidio ati ikanni wọn, ofuutufẹẹtẹ lasan ni, nitori bi awọn ba yinbọn nibẹ, oku yoo pọ rẹpẹtẹ ni o. Wọn ni ẹni to ba ri oku awọn eeyan to ku nibẹ ko gbe e jade, bi awọn ba ti ri oku yii, nigba naa ni awọn yoo le wadii ẹni to pa wọn. Ṣugbọn bi ko ba si oku ko si ọrọ, irọ lawọn eeyan n pa mọ awọn.Nigba naa ni awọn oniroyin ileeṣẹ iwe iroyin Premium Times to jẹ ti ori ẹrọ ayelujara jade, wọn gbe iṣẹ iwadii nla dide, iwadii naa lo si tu aṣiri ọpọlọpọ nnkan tẹni kan ko mọ, o si fi han pe loootọ lawọn ṣọja paayan, ati pe iye awọn ti wọn pa yoo le ni aadọta daadaa. Bẹẹ ọdọ ni gbogbo wọn. Sodiq Adeoye to n ṣiṣẹ pẹlu ileeṣẹ oniwadii kan, SBM Intelligence, lo sọ fun ọkan ninu awọn oniroyin Premium Times pe awọn araadugbo awọn olowo ti wọn n pe ni Admiralty Way sọ pe awọn ri oku to lefoo soju omi lẹyinkule awọn, awọn si fura pe oku naa le jẹ lara awọn ọdọ to ku si Too-geeti Lẹkki yii, ṣe Admiralty Way ti wọn n wi yii, iwaju too-geeti yii gan-an lo wa, bii kilomita meji sibẹ ni.Eti were ni ti ekute ile, ilakọsin o ni i gbọ ohun ọmọ rẹ ko duro, abiyamọ ki i gbọ ẹkun ọmọ rẹ ko ma ta eti were, bi oniroyin ba ti gbọ finrin nibi kan, iṣẹ de niyẹn. Kia ni Premium Times gbe awọn eeyan dide, ni wọn ba lọ si adugbo naa, ohun ti wọn ri nibẹ si ya wọn lẹnu. Ni bii aago mẹfa aarọ ni Deji Aṣiru, ti ileeṣẹ iwe iroyin naa gbera, lo ba kọri si ibi ti wọn ti ri oku to lefoo loju omi. Wọn gba odidi ọkọ oju omi kan, wọn ni ko gbe awọn yipo ibẹ, ki wọn le mọ ibi ti oku naa ti lefoo gan-an. Bi wọn ti n lọ loju omi yii, oniroyin naa ri awọn ile gẹrẹjẹ gẹrẹjẹ kan, awọn ile onipako ti wọn maa n kọ si eti okun, ile naa si pọ diẹ, abule kekere ti awọn apẹja ati ọlọkọ oju omi n gbe ni. Abule yii wa lori omi nibẹ, lẹyin otẹẹli kan ti wọn n pe ni Oriental Hotel. Ẹyin Too-geeti Lẹkki yii gan-an ni abule awọn apẹja yii wa, bi eeyan ba n bọ lati ọna Victoria Island wa si Lẹkki ni yoo ri i daadaa.Bi akọroyin yii ti ri i ni ọkan ẹ sọ fun un pe ko si bi iru iṣẹlẹ bayii yoo ti ṣe ṣẹlẹ ti awọn ara abule ori omi yii ko ni i mọ, paapaa nigba to jẹ ẹyin Too-geeti ti iṣẹlẹ naa ti waye ni wọn n gbe. Lo ba ni ki ẹni to gbe wọn ninu ọkọ oju-omi naa ya sibẹ. Bi wọn ti debẹ, afi bi igba ti awọn ara ileto yii ti n reti ẹni ti yoo waa gbọ tẹnu wọn ni. Ko ma ti i beere rara ni, awọn eeyan naa bẹrẹ si i tu kẹkẹ ohun to ṣẹlẹ ati eyi ti wọn foju ri fun un. Boya ohun to n ka awọn ara abule yii lara ni pe ninu awọn naa ti wọn ko si ni oju ija fi ara gba ọta ibọn. Awọn gan-an ni wọn kọkọ fi ẹṣẹ ọrọ ti obinrin DJ Switch n sọ mulẹ pe loju awọn lo ṣe korokoro, awọn ri awọn ṣọja ti wọn n gbe oku awọn ti wọn pa sinu mọto wọn, ti wọn si ṣe bẹẹ wa wọn lọ. Bi wọn ti beere pe ṣe loootọ lawọn ṣọja paayan nibi, ẹni kan dahun fara, “Haa, gbogbo awa ti a wa nile la riyẹn, ṣebi ẹni kan wa to jẹ oju wa nibi ni wọn ṣe yinbọn pa a, ti wọn si gbe oku ẹ lọ!”Ẹni kan ninu awọn ara aba naa to n jẹ Ray ni, “Ẹ wo o, orilẹ-ede mi niyi, ko si ibi ti mo fẹẹ sa lọ, bi wọn ba fẹẹ waa gbe mi ki wọn tete maa bọ. Ohun ti awọn ṣọja ati ọlọpaa ṣe nibi lọjọ yẹn buru o. Abi kin ni wọn maa waa yinbọn lu wa si nigba ti a n ṣe iwọde wọọrọ!” Wọn beere lọwọ Ray pe ṣe o ri oku awọn eeyan, o ni, “Daadaa, mo ri oku rẹpẹtẹ, ṣebi awọn ṣọja yii ni wọn waa fi mọto wọn ko wọn lọ! Ki lo de ti Sanwoolu gan-an n purọ! Ṣebi lọjọ iṣẹlẹ yii, oun naa sare wa laaarọ ki ilẹ too mọ, ṣebi o ṣi ri oku awọn eeyan nilẹ nibẹ! Ki lo wa n sọ pe ko sẹni to ku si.” Awọn araadugbo mi-in naa da si i, awọn yii ni wọn si ṣalaye pe lẹyin ti awọn ṣọja ti lọ, awọn ọlọpaa de, awọn ọlọpaa agbegbe Victoria Island nibẹ, Ganiyu si ni DPO to ṣaaju wọn jẹ, awọn ni awọn mọ ọn daadaa. Wọn ni Ganiyu yii naa ati awọn eeyan rẹ yinbọn pa awọn kan nigba ti wọn wa.Awọn ara aba yii ni wọn ṣalaye bi ọrọ naa ti ri gan-an. O ni lọdọ awọn ni pupọ ninu awọn ti wọn n ṣe iwọde na sa wa nigba ti ariwo ibọn bẹrẹ, ibọn si ba ọpọlọpọ wọn. Koda, obinrin kan ni ninu ibi ti oun wa nibẹ, ibọn ba ọmọ oun naa lapa, o si fi apa rẹ han awọn oniroyin, bẹẹ ni awọn mi-in ko ajoku ọta ibọn ti wọn ri lọdọ wọn nibẹ jade. Wọn ni awọn mi-in sa wọnu omi lọ ni, to si jẹ wọn ko jade laaye, bẹẹ ni ọta ibọn ti ba awọn mi-in ki wọn too de ọdọ awọn rara. Wọn ni awọn ṣe iranlọwọ fun awọn ti awọn le ṣe e fun, ọkunrin apẹja kan to si n jẹ Agboọla Kapko sọ fawọn Premium Times yii pe ọkọ oju omi loun fi n ko ọpọ eeyan sọda si odikeji nibi ti wọn ti le ribi ba sa lọ, bẹẹ ọpọ ninu awọn yii ti fara gbọta.Kapko nawọ si ọọkan bayii, o ni “Ibi ti emi wa niyẹn nigba ti wọn bẹrẹ si i yinbọn ni too-geeti, n lawọn eeyan ba bẹrẹ si i sare ko somi. Mi o le fi wọn silẹ bẹẹ, nitori ẹ ni mo ṣe sun mọ wọn ti mo n fa awọn ti wọn ba ti fẹẹ ri jade kuro ninu omi, ti mo si n fi ọkọ mi gbe wọn lọ si apa ibomi-in, ti awọn mi-in si n ba ibẹ sa lọ ni tiwọn.” Iyawo Kapko gan-an fi ẹsẹ ẹ to wu han, o ni nibi ti oun ti n sare lọ nigba ti ibọn bẹrẹ si i ro, ti ọta ibọn naa si n wọ ọdọ awọn ni oun ti ṣubu lulẹ, ti oun si fi ẹsẹ ṣeṣe. Ohun to mu ọrọ naa yanju lati ọdọ awọn eeyan yii ni pe gbogbo wọn lo ri oku, wọn ri awọn ṣọja ti wọn yinbọn pa wọn, wọn ri awọn ọlọpaa to pada waa palẹ to ku mọ, ti wọn si tun yinbọn pa awọn mi-in, wọn ri awọn SARS funra wọn ti wọn wa, wọn si ri i bi wọn ti rọ oku sinu mọto kaakiri. Awọn yii fi ẹsẹ rẹ mulẹ pe ki ẹnikẹni ma sọ pe ko sẹni to ku nibi iṣẹlẹ yii mọ o, nitori awọn oku ti wọn ku ko niye. Tabi ṣe awọn ti wọn ku somi leeyan yoo sọ ni tabi ti awọn ti wọn yinbọn pa.Ọrọ yii gan-an fẹẹ da wahala silẹ laarin awọn ṣọja ati ijọba Eko. Ijọba Eko ti gbe igbimọ kan dide lati wadii ohun to ṣẹlẹ gan-an, ati lati mọ bi awọn eeyan ti ku to loootọ, bo ba si jẹ awọn eeyan ku rẹpẹtẹ bẹẹ, nibo ni wọn ko wọn si. Olobo ta awọn igbimọ yii pe bi wọn ba fẹẹ mọ ibi ti awọn ṣọja ko awọn eeyan naa si, ki wọn lọ si ile igbokuu-si awọn ṣọja gan-an, o ṣee ṣe ki wọn ba wọn nibẹ. Ki ọrọ ma di pe awọn ṣọja yoo ti tun ko awọn eeyan naa kuro ni moṣuari wọn ni wọn ṣe ja lu wọn lojiji ni ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, to kọja yii. Wọn ni ki wọn jẹ ki awọn wo mọṣuari wọn. Ṣugbọn awọn ṣọja ẹnu ọna yari, wọn ni awọn ko le jẹ ki wọn wọle, koda, awọn yoo yinbọn fun wọn ti wọn ko ba tete kuro niwaju awọn. Gbogbo alaye ti awọn ọmọ igbimọ to lọ si Ọsibitu awọn ṣọja n’Ikoyi yii ṣe ko wọ ẹnikẹni leti, wọn le wọn tefetefe.Lẹyin ọpọlọpọ arọwa ati ọrọ suuru ti ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ igbimọ naa, Ẹbun Olu-Adegboruwa, sọ ni wọn too gba wọn laaye lati wọ ibẹ.Kinni kan ti fidi mulẹ bayii ṣaa o, iyẹn naa ni pe gbogbo aye ti mọ, awọn ṣoja naa ti mọ, ijọba ti mọ, pe awọn ṣọja paayan ni Too-geeti Lẹkki, ati pe iye awọn ti wọn pa ki i ṣe kekere rara. Ohun ti yoo wa ṣẹlẹ lati ọdọ awọn alagbara agbaye ti wọn gbeja awọn ọdọ ti wọn yoo si fiya jẹ awọn ologun to ba pa araalu lai nidii, ati ohun tijọba Naijiria funra wọn yoo ṣe, lo ku ti gbogbo aye n reti bayii o."},{"question":"این متن در مورد چه رویداد مهمی صحبت می کند:  \\"... و شکل‌گیری جمهوری دموکراتیک افغانستان، در زمان حاکمیت حفیظ‌الله امین، سفیر افغانستان در ایران شد. در حکومت ببرک کارمل به عنوان رئیس خدمات امنیت دولتی برگزیده گردید و یکی از اعضای شاخهٔ حزب دموکراتیک خلق افغانستان بود.انقلاب ثورنجیب‌الله پس از ...\\"","answer":"انقلاب ثورنجیب الله"},{"question":"Вопрос: Кто был президентом индийского национального конгресса в 1890 году? Ответ:","answer":"Ферозеша Мехта был президентом индийского национального конгресса в 1890 году. Он был один из основателей Индийского Национального Конгресса, представитель умеренного крыла ИНК, сторонник сохранения британской власти в Индии."},{"question":"வினா :கூத்தர்களை ஆற்றுப்படுத்தும் விதம் பற்றி மலைபடுகடாம் கூறுவன யாவை?","answer":" விடை:  கூத்தர்களை ஆற்றுப்படுத்தும் விதம் பற்றி மலைபடுகடாம் கூறுவன:நன்னனைப் புகழ்ந்து பாடிப் பரிசில் பெற்ற கூத்தர், பரிசில் பெறப்போகும் கூத்தரைக் கானவர்களின் வளம் நிறைந்த சிறிய ஊர்களில் தங்கி உணவு பெறுவதற்கு வழிப்படுத்துதல்.பகலில் இளைப்பாறிச் செல்லுங்கள்.இரவில் சேர்ந்து தங்குங்கள்.பூங்கொத்துக்களைச் சுற்றத்தோடு அணிந்து கொள்ளுங்கள்.சிவந்த பூக்கள் கொண்ட அசோக மரங்களை உடைய பொருத்தமான பாதையில் செல்லுங்கள்.அசையும் மூங்கில்கள் ஊசை எழுப்பும் கடினப்பாதையில் சென்று மலைச்சரிவில் உள்ள சிற்றூரை அடையுங்கள்.பகைவரைப் பொறாமல் போர் செய்யும் வலிய முயற்சியும் மானமும் வெற்றியும் உடைய நன்னனின் கூத்தர்கள் என்று சொல்லுங்கள்.உங்கள் வீட்டிற்கு போவது போலவே அவர்களுடைய வீட்டிற்குள் நுழையுங்கள்.உறவினர் போலவே அவர்கள் உங்களுடன் பழகுவர்.நீண்ட வழியைக் கடந்து வந்த உங்களின் துன்பம் தீர இனிய சொற்களைக் கூறுவர்.அங்கே, நெய்யில் வெந்த மாமிசத்தின் பொரியலையும் தினைச்சோற்றையும் உணவாகப் பெறுவீர்கள்."},{"question":"Kush e fitoi FIFA Kupën e Botës në vitin 2014?","answer":"FIFA Kupën e Botës në vitin 2014 e fitoi Gjermania."},{"question":"සැවැන්දරා  ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න ","answer":"පොදු නාමය : සැවැන්දරාකූලය : ග්‍රැමිනේ (Graminae)උද්භිද විද්‍යාත්මක : වෙටිවේරිආ zසිzසැනියෝඩ්ස් (Vetiveria Zizaniodes)කඳුකර ප්‍රදේශවල බහුල වශයෙන් දක්නට ලැබෙන තෘණ පඳුරක් වගේ ශාකයක් තමයි \\"සැවැන්දරා\\" කියන්නේ. මේ ශාකයේ වෙනත් ශාකවලට වඩා පස් ඇතුළට මුල් ගමන් කිරීම ප්‍රබලයි. ඒ නිසාම මේ ශාකය පාංශු ඛාදනය වළක්වන පසට හිතකර ශාකයක් ලෙසත් පිළිගන්න පුළුවන්.\\"සුගන්ධි මූල\\", \\"ශීත මූල\\" වැනි නම් වලිනුත් හඳුන්වන සැවැන්දරා මුල් සුවඳ විලවුන් සාදන්නත් යොදා ගන්නේ මේ මුල්වල පවතින සුවිශේෂී සුවඳ නිසයි. ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව, අප්‍රිකාව සහ දකුණු ඇමෙරිකාව වගේ රටවලත් සැවැන්දරා යොදාගනිමින් විවිධ නිෂ්පාදන සකස් කරනවා. සැවැන්දරා නිස්සාරණය කිරීමේ ක්‍රමවේදයක් හරහා සුගන්ධවත් තෛලයක් ලබාගන්න පුළුවන්. තෙල් නිස්සාරණය කිරීමේ යන්ත්‍ර මඟින් පමණයි සැවැන්දරා තෙල් ගන්න පුළුවන්.ඖෂධීය වටිනාකම:සුගන්ධිත-සුවඳවත් චර්ම රෝග -සැවැන්දරා මුල් ඇල්දියෙන් අඹරා ගෑම හිස බර ගතිය-සැවැන්දරා මුල් දූම නාසයට ඇදීමව්‍යවහාරික රෝග අවස්ථා :-මුර්ජා,අග්නිමාන්ද්‍ය,අජීර්ණ,කාස,හික්කා,චර්ම රෝග,ව්‍රණ,කාමලාව,සන්නිපාත ජ්වර ලපටි පත්‍ර ස්ත්ව ආහරයකි.පාංශු ඛාදනයට එරෙහිව වගා කෙරේ.ග්‍රීස්ම කාලෙදි ඇඟ දැවිල්ල, දහදිය බිබිළි දැමීම වැනි සමේ ආසාදන හට ගැනීම වැඩියි. එවිට සැවැන්දරා මුලක් මඳ අවුවේ වියළාගෙන කුඩුකර ඒ කුඩු උණු වතුර එකකට මිශ්‍ර කර කෝපි වගේ බොන්න. එහෙමත් නැතිනම් තැඹිලි ගෙඩියක ඇස්ස කපා එයට සැවැන්දරා මුල් කුඩු ස්වල්පයක් මිශ්‍රකර ඇස්ස වසා රැයක් පින්නේ තබා ඒ තැඹිලි වතුර එක පෙරා උදෑසන පානය කරන්න. දිනපතා මෙය සතියක් පමණ කළොත් සමේ ආසාදනවලින් මිදී දිනපතා සිසිලසක් ලබන්න ඔබට පුළුවන්.සැවැන්දරා තෙල් හිසේ ආලේප කළොත් හිසරද තත්ත්ව ඉක්මනින් සුව කර ගන්න පුළුවන්. ඒ වගේම හන්දි වේදනා, හන්දි ඉදිමුම්, තැළීම්වලටත් සැවැන්දරා තෙල් ආලේප කිරීමෙන් සුවයක් ලබන්න පුළුවන්.අජීර්ණ තත්ත්ව, බඩේ වේදනාව වැනි උදරාශ්‍රිත රෝගවලට සුවයක් ලබාගන්න පුළුවන් ඔෟෂධයක් සැවැන්දරාවලින් සාදාගන්න පුළුවන්. .පත්පාඩගම්, වියළි ඉඟුරු. ඉරිවේරිය සහ සැවැන්දරා කළං 3 බැගින් අරගෙන මුට්ටියකට දමා එයට වතුර පත 8ක් මිශ්‍ර කර පත එකට සිඳුවා උදේ පත භාගයක් සවස පත භාගයක් බැගින් උදේ සවස බොන්න. මෙය දින 6ක් පමණ අඛණ්ඩව සිදු කළොත් අම්ලපිත්ත වැනි උදරය ආශ්‍රිත සෑම රෝගයකටම ගුණදායකයි.ඒ වගේම ඇඟ දැවිල්ල, තදබල හිසේ වේදනාව වැනි තත්ත්වවලදී සැවැන්දරා මුල් සිසිල් දියෙන් අඹරා කල්කයක් සාදාගෙන එය නළලේ ආලේප කරන්න. හිසේ වේදනාවක් නම් හිසේ ආලේප කරන්න. ඇඟ පත වේදනාවලදී ඇඟේ ආලේප කරන්න. ඔබට එවිට ඉක්මන් සුවයක් ලබාගන්න පුළුවන්.විටින් විට වමනය යෑමේ රෝග තත්ත්වයන්ගෙන් පෙළෙන පුද්ගලයන් සැවැන්දරා, සුදු හඳුන්, ඉරිවේරිය, ආඩතෝඩ සහ වියළි ඉඟුරු කළං තුන බැගින් අරගෙන එයට වතුර පත අටක් දමා පත එකට සිඳුවා උදේ සවස පානය කරන්න. මෙය වේල් කිහිපයක් පානය කිරීමෙන් වමනය රෝගී තත්ත්වයෙන් මිදෙන්න පුළුවන්."},{"question":"Kanus-a ka huling nag-attend og relihiyosong serbisyo?","answer":"Miaging Domingo ko huling nag-attend og relihiyosong serbisyo sa simbahan."},{"question":"70 को 0.7 द्वारा विभाजित नतिजा पत्ता लगाउनुहोस्।","answer":"70 भाग 0.7 बराबर 100 हो।"},{"question":"இந்த உரை என்ன முக்கியமான நிகழ்வைப் பற்றியது:இயேசுவின் தாயான மரியா, உலகின் பல நாடுகளில் வாழும் மக்களிடையே தோன்றி இயேசுவின் மீது நம்பிக்கை கொள்ளுமாறு அழைப்பு விடுத்துள்ளார். அவர் தோன்றிய இடங்களின் பெயரால், லூர்து மாதா, பாத்திமா மாதா, குவாடலூப்பே மாதா என்று பல்வேறு பெயர்களால் அழைக்கப்படுகிறார். உலகின் பல இடங்களில் தோன்றிய அன்னை, இந்தியாவில் தமிழகத்தின் வேளாங்கண்ணியில் காட்சி அளித்ததால் வேளாங்கண்ணி மாதா என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறார். வேண்டுதல் செய்யும் அனைவரின் உடல், உள்ளக் குறைகளைத் தீர்ப்பதால் ஆரோக்கிய அன்னையாக திகழ்கிறார்.","answer":"இந்த உரை  லூர்து மாதாவை பற்றியது."},{"question":"Muhammad Ali","answer":"Muhammad Ali (orúko àbíso Cassius Marcellus Clay, Jr.; January 17, 1942 - June 3, 2016) jẹ́ ajẹ̀sẹ ará Amẹ́ríkà tó ti fẹ̀yị̀ntì àti onídárayá àkọ́kọ́ ágbáyé fún wúwotówúwo ní ẹ̀ẹ̀mẹta.A bi Ali si Louisville, Kentucky osi dagba si be pelu. O bẹrẹ ikẹkọ bi afẹṣẹja amateur ni ọjọ -ori 12. Ni ọdun 18, o ṣẹgun goolu kan ni pipin iwuwo iwuwo ina ni Awọn Olimpiiki Igba Irẹdanu Ewe 1960 ati pe o di alamọdaju nigbamii ni ọdun yẹn. O di Musulumi lẹyin ọdun 1961. O bori ni aṣaju iwuwo iwuwo agbaye lati ọdọ Sonny Liston ni ibinu nla ni ọjọ Kínní 25, 1964, ni ọjọ -ori 22. Ni Oṣu Kẹta ọjọ 6, 1964, o kede pe oun ko ni mọ mọ Cassius Clay ṣugbọn bi Muhammad Ali. Ni 1966, Ali kọ lati jẹ ki o wa sinu ologun, ni sisọ awọn igbagbọ ẹsin rẹ ati atako ihuwa si Ogun Vietnam. O jẹbi pe o yago fun kikọ silẹ nitorina o dojuko ọdun marun ninu tubu ati pe o gba awọn akọle Boxing rẹ. O duro kuro ninu tubu bi o ti bẹbẹ fun ipinnu si Ile -ẹjọ Adajọ, eyiti o yi idajọ rẹ pada ni ọdun 1971, ṣugbọn ko ti ja fun o fẹrẹ to ọdun mẹrin o padanu akoko iṣẹ ṣiṣe giga bi elere idaraya. Awọn iṣe Ali gẹgẹ bi alatako-ọkan si Ogun Vietnam jẹ ki o jẹ aami fun iran counterculture ti o tobi, ati pe o jẹ eeyan ti o ga pupọ ti igberaga ẹlẹyamẹya fun awọn ara Amẹrika Amẹrika lakoko gbigbe awọn ẹtọ ara ilu ati jakejado iṣẹ rẹ. Gẹgẹbi Musulumi, Ali ni ajọṣepọ lakoko pẹlu Elijah Muhammad's Nation of Islam (NOI). Nigbamii o kọwọ si NOI, ti o faramọ Islam Sunni, ati atilẹyin iṣọpọ ẹya bi onimọran iṣaaju rẹ Malcolm X. O kopa ninu ọpọlọpọ awọn ere -idije boxing ni pataki julọ awọn ija rẹ pẹlu Joe Frazier, pẹlu Ija ti Ọdun (iṣẹlẹ afẹṣẹja ti o tobi julọ titi di igba naa), Thrilla ni Manila, ati ija rẹ pẹlu George Foreman ti a mọ si The Rumble ninu Jungle, eyiti o jẹ wiwo nipasẹ igbasilẹ ti a fojusi awọn olugbohunsafefe tẹlifisiọnu ti awọn oluwo bilionu 1 ni kariaye, di igbohunsafefe tẹlifisiọnu laaye julọ julọ ni agbaye ni akoko yẹn. Ali ṣe rere ni iranran ni akoko kan nigbati ọpọlọpọ awọn onija jẹ ki awọn alakoso wọn sọrọ, ati pe o jẹ igbagbogbo ni imunibinu ati ajeji. O jẹ olokiki fun sisọ ọrọ idọti, ati igbagbogbo ni aṣa-ara pẹlu awọn eto orin ati ọrọ ewi ọrọ, ifojusọna awọn eroja ti hip hop. Ni ode oruka, Ali ti ṣaṣeyọri bi oṣere olorin ọrọ, nibiti o ti gba awọn yiyan Grammy meji. O tun ṣe ifihan bi oṣere ati onkọwe, dasile awọn itan -akọọlẹ ara ẹni meji. Ali ti fẹyìntì lati afẹṣẹja ni ọdun 1981 ati idojukọ lori ẹsin, alanu ati ijajagbara. Ni ọdun 1984, o ṣe agbekalẹ iwadii aisan ti Parkinson's syndrome, eyiti diẹ ninu awọn ijabọ ṣe ikawe si awọn ipalara ti o ni ibatan Boxing, botilẹjẹpe oun ati awọn dokita alamọja rẹ tako eyi. O jẹ eniyan ti n ṣiṣẹ lọwọ ni kariaye, ṣugbọn ni awọn ọdun igbẹhin rẹ ṣe awọn ifarahan gbangba diẹ bi ipo rẹ ti buru si, ati pe idile rẹ tọju rẹ. Ali ku ni Oṣu Èbìbí, ọjọ kẹta, ọdun 2016."},{"question":"\\"යුද්ධය සහ සාමය\\" කෘතියේ  කතුවරයා  කවුද?","answer":"\\"යුද්ධය සහ සාමය\\" කෘතියේ  කතුවරයා ලියෝ  ටෝල්ස්ටෝයි වේ. "},{"question":"රිවෝල්වරය නිපදවූයේ කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"රිවෝල්වරය සොයාගැනීමේ ගෞරවය හිමිවන්නේ ඇමෙරිකානු නව නිපැයුම්කරුවෙකු වන සැමුවෙල් කෝල්ට් වෙතය. ඔහු 1836 දී එක්සත් ජනපදයේ ඔහුගේ නිර්මාණයට පේටන්ට් බලපත්‍රය ලබා  ගත්තේය. කෝල්ට්ගේ නවෝත්පාදනය වූයේ කැරකෙන සිලින්ඩර සැලසුම වන අතර, එය එක් එක් වෙඩි තැබීමෙන් පසු නැවත පූරණය කිරීමේ අවශ්‍යතාවයකින් තොරව තනි ගිනි අවියකින් වට කිහිපයක් වෙඩි තැබීමට ඉඩ සලසයි. මෙය ගිනි සීඝ්‍රතාවය සැලකිය යුතු ලෙස වැඩි කළ අතර ගිනි අවි ඉතිහාසයේ රිවෝල්වරය ඉතා  ප්‍රචලිත අවියක් බවට පත් කළේය. "},{"question":"యానాది రూపాన్ని వర్ణించండి.","answer":"యానాదుల కళ్లు నిర్మలంగా ఉంటాయి. వీరి కనుబొమ్మలు విల్లుల వలె ఒంపులు తిరిగి ఉంటాయి. వీరిది ఉంగరాల జుట్టు. వీరి పెదవులు సన్నగా ఉంటాయి. వీరు సన్నగా ఉంటారు. వీరు చాలా వేగంగా పరుగెత్తడానికి అనువైన లేసైన కాలిపిక్కలు కలిగి ఉంటారు. సన్నని నడుములు కలిగి ఉంటారు. చిరునవ్వుతో జీవిస్తారు. ఆదివాసులందరిలో యానాదులే అందగాళ్లని కొంతమంది పరిశోధకుల అభిప్రాయం."},{"question":"“విద్యనేర్చినయేని వివేకియగును” అన్న విషయాన్ని సమర్థిస్తూ రాయండి","answer":"దేశంలో ఎందరో విజ్ఞానవంతులు ఉన్నారు. వారు అందరూ పాఠశాలల్లోనో, గురువుల వద్దనో చదువుకున్నవారే. చదువుకోకపోతే ఎవరూ జ్ఞానం సంపాదించలేరు. పుట్టగానే తెలివైన వారిగా ఎవరూ పుట్టరు. ఎంత రత్నమైనా సాన పెట్టనిదే ప్రకాశించదు. దున్నకపోతే పొలంలో పంటలు పండవు. కాబట్టి ఎంత అజ్ఞాని అయినా, చదువుకొంటే తప్పక వివేకి అవుతాడు."},{"question":"De maneira concisa, defina a palavra \\"honestidade\\".","answer":"Honestidade significa dizer a verdade e agir de maneira justa e íntegra."},{"question":"Alankhula Chichewa Ndani?","answer":"Anthu ndi MbiriChichewa/Chinyanja ndi chilankhulo cha banja la Bantu, ndipo ndi choncho chimodzi mwa zilankhulo zodziwika bwino za anthu olankhula Bantu kum'mwera kwa Africa. Oposa 65% mwa anthu 11 a Malawianthu mamiliyoni ambiri ali ndi mphamvu yolankhula Chichewa, mwinanso ambiri popeza 80% ali ndi chidziwitso cha chilankhulo. Ku Mozambique, mwa anthu 18 miliyoni, pafupifupi 3.3%, makamaka muChigawo cha Tete kumunsi kwa Zambezi Valley ndi Niassa Province kumpoto chakum’mawa kwa dziko, lankhula Chinyanja. Ku Zambia, ndi chiwerengero cha anthu 10 miliyoni, pafupifupi 16% ndi mbadwaolankhula, ndipo amakhala makamaka ku Eastern Province, pafupi ndi malire ndi Malawi. Komabe, Chinyanja chimalankhulidwa kwambiri kupitirira Eastern Province, ndipo akuti pafupifupi 42% ya Anthu a ku Zambia ali ndi luso loyankhulana m’chinenerochi.Anthu olankhula Chichewa kapena Chinyanja amadziwika kuti aChewa kapena a-Nyanja. Kuyambira pakati pa khumi ndi zisanu zana, angapo a etholinguistically ogwirizana magulu kuphatikizapo a-Chewa, a-Nyanja, ndi a-Mang’anja, otsogozedwa ndi mtsogoleri amene ankatchedwa Kalonga, anasamuka kuchokera kumunsi kwa Congo m’zigawo za Lake Malawi ndi Shire River Valley.A Kalonga ndi otsatira ake adatcha malo kumadzulo kwa Nyanja Malawi komwe adakhazikika \\"Malawi,\\" kutanthauza \\"malawi,\\" pambuyo pake masomphenya a moto wonyezimira amene munthu anawona pamwamba pa nyanja mu kutentha kwa tsiku. Atakhazikika pafupi ndi nyanja yokongola, ena mwa iwo gululo limadzitcha a-Nyanja, kapena \\"anthu akunyanja,\\" “nyanja” kukhala liwu la Chichewa/Chinyanja/Chimang’anja \\"nyanja.\\" Enanso anasintha pang’ono dzinali kuti asiyanitse okha, akudzitcha a-Mang’anja. M'njira izi, a kubalalitsidwa ndi kufalikira kwa Chichewa/Chinyanja anthu olankhula anachititsa kuti chinenerocho chifalikire dera.Dr. Kamuzu Banda, pulezidenti woyamba wa dziko la Malawi, anasankha Chichewa monga chinenero cha dziko mu 1968 mwachiwonekere pofuna kugwirizanitsa dziko la chinenero chimodzi. Komabe chinenero cha dziko ndondomeko inalinso yotsutsana, chifukwa imalimbikitsa chinenero kukhala cholankhulidwa ndi a-Chewa, omwe amakhala ku Central Malawi, pamtengo wa Mabaibulo ena onse a chinenerocho komanso zinenero zina wa Malawi. Choncho, kuyambira kumapeto kwa utsogoleri wa Dr. Banda mu 1994, Dziko la Malawi lakhazikitsa ndondomeko ya zilankhulo zomwe zimalimbikitsa madera onse zilankhulo komanso Chingerezi muzofalitsa, masukulu ndi kulenga ntchito. Ngakhale zili choncho, Chichewa ndicho chimalankhulidwa kwambiri chinenero ku Malawi."},{"question":"Why is the logarithm of housing prices considered in the analysis instead of the actual median prices?","answer":"To normalize the data, reduce variability, make the distribution more symmetrical, and allow for easier interpretation in terms of percentage changes."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'hidung tak mancung, pipi tersorong-sorong'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud suka ikut campur dalam urusan orang lain, dan menonjol-nonjolkan diri."},{"question":"ఛ అక్షరంతో మొదలయ్యే పదాలు మరియు వాటి అర్ధాలు ఇవ్వండి","answer":"ఛాత్రులు = శిష్యులు, విద్యార్థులుఛిన్నభిన్నమవు = ముక్కలు ముక్కలు ఆవు, చెల్లాచెదురవు, తునాతునకలవు"},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε την ακόλουθη φράση: Μετά το τέλος του","answer":"πολέμου της Αλγερίας, το 1962, πολλοί Γάλλοι κάτοικοι της Αλγερίας και οι οικογένειές τους επαναπατρίστηκαν και εγκαταστάθηκαν στο έδαφος της κοινότητας. Έτσι δημιουργήθηκε η περιοχή Νειγί-Νεμούρ καθώς και ένας δασικός οικισμός."}]`),B={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:M},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:C,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},I={class:"search-container"},x={class:"card-container"},O=["disabled"],P={key:0},D={key:1};function L(e,a,s,k,t,u){const m=b("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",I,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),w(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=r=>t.searchQuery=r),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[y,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",x,[(i(!0),o(c,null,p(u.filteredPoems,(r,d)=>(i(),j(m,{key:d,poem:r},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),u.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...r)=>u.loadMore&&u.loadMore(...r))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",D,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",P,"See more"))],8,O)):v("",!0)])}const K=g(B,[["render",L],["__scopeId","data-v-1f423bec"]]),R=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"chatai/7.md","filePath":"chatai/7.md"}'),H={name:"chatai/7.md"},G=Object.assign(H,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),o("div",null,[f(K)]))}});export{R as __pageData,G as default};
